It's hard to contain my rage.
There we go.
Are you mad?
Just get glad.
Hey!
Remove that.
Oh, yeah.
I should fix my camera.
Okay.
I'm so happy my voice isn't worse.
Also, thank you guys so much for all the subs and donations and stuff doing this.
Really appreciate it.
ASMR stream?
Yeah.
Man, do you think there's sickness ASMR streams?
100%?
100%.
Will sis survive through the interview?
Yeah, it is unfortunate that I'm sick.
Obviously, we can't really postpone it.
Hopefully, this is okay.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't plan to be sick.
I even, like, tried not to stream or talk to make sure my voice would work.
You sound good?
Yeah, I just...
I hate coughing.
I get so, like, annoyed.
Just don't cough on him.
True.
I'm trying to cough a lot now to, like, clear a little bit.
Am I getting sick?
What a bitch move.
Beta.
Beta is fuck.
Alright, they're calling.
Hello.
How are you doing?
How's it going?
Oh, okay.
Just, you know.
Just got back from Korea.
Oh, wow.
Let's see.
Let me just do a quick audio check.
How does he sound compared to me, chat?
Loud.
Okay, I'll turn.
Testing.
Testing, one, two, three.
A bit loud, okay.
Okay, I put it down to 75%.
How's that?
Testing, one, two, three.
I'm Jonathan Rogers.
Low?
Is that all right?
Hopefully, we're okay.
Too low.
Okay.
Let's try.
Okay, I'm going to try.
One sec.
Okay, try that.
85.
All right.
Hopefully, that's a lot better.
Sounding okay.
Testing, one, two, three.
Okay, perfect.
Excellent.
All right.
And I just need to quickly set up our cameras, and we are good to go.
Oh.
How are you doing?
Well, as I said, just okay, but just, you know, got back from Korea, still a little bit
tired.
They, my flight got canceled.
Oh.
Which is always a pain.
Yeah.
So, I'm a day late, and maybe a little bit tired, tired, than I would have otherwise been
on this call, but that's all right.
Yeah, I bet.
Damn.
Well, thank you so much for taking time to speak with us and answer questions.
No problem.
You've been doing, like, a lot of, a lot of these now.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, you know, the, right at the end, it's like suddenly my job is doing marketing, basically.
Yeah.
So, but, oh, well, that's how it is.
I, it's, it's crazy how many I've done now.
Let's see, almost ready.
Let's see.
There.
I think we are potentially good to go.
That look okay for everybody?
All right.
I think, I think we're good.
So, I do want to apologize real quick.
I'm a little bit sick, so I might be coughing a little bit, and.
That's okay.
Yeah.
Are we coughing as well?
I'll try not to cough on you.
Yeah.
But yeah, awesome.
Thank you so much for joining.
Welcome, everybody.
I am joined here today by Jonathan Rogers, director on Path of Exile 2.
Thank you so much for, for being here.
No problem.
I mean, you know, it's always good to talk to you.
We've done a number of these interviews, and I honestly, I'm always happy just to talk to whoever's got good questions for me, honestly.
Yeah, I've tried to do just that.
So, I've sent Jonathan some of the questions ahead of time, just so he could prepare.
We could have a little bit less dev check.
And yeah, I've tried really hard to not have any repeat questions, except for a few that I really want to push back a little bit on and talk a little bit about.
Sure.
But yeah, it was honestly, it's been so many things that's been changing.
So while I'm making questions with Chad, it's been a little bit like, have they answered this?
So like, it's, yeah, but very excited for this.
So I want to start with an interesting question for me personally, because PeeWee 2 is so different than PeeWee 1.
And I don't know how familiar you are with World of Warcraft, but a big event there for me was the Gates of Ankara's opening with like, basically the server coming together and working on something and that affecting like a little bit of the future outcome.
So have you ever thought of doing a league like that, where the future of the league or how it goes core depends on how us as players perform during the league?
As a quick example, like maybe we lose the war towards Breach or we win the war and that like changes a future league.
It's something interesting.
I feel like we did something like this before, but I'm trying to remember which thing it was.
Wasn't it like Tempest, actually?
Like, I feel like Tempest had a mechanic like this, but maybe it was like really not obvious.
Like, it's actually the kind of thing I am interested in doing.
We just haven't really kind of ended up with a league design that kind of wanted to do it.
Because you have to be really careful with that stuff that you don't, like it can be frustrating for players just because, okay, probably not the thing you're referring to because that's the whole like coming together and actually like towards a single goal over the long term.
But we've had a few mechanics where playing the league affected before and I think Tempest was one of them where like, I think it was that one, where the more people who farmed something, after a certain number of people had farmed it, it actually, the mechanic moved us to another location.
Oh, that's cool too.
And yeah, yeah.
So that was kind of interesting, but like, I think that we sort of decided for that particular case that we weren't like that happy with it.
Because I kind of had this thing of like, you know, the idea of unfairness of like, you know, oh, you have to like, someone says like, oh, this happened in the middle of the night.
You need to wake up and do this.
And so we kind of weren't happy with that.
But I mean, like, I mean, the thing you were saying there about the gates, I mean, like, that's pretty cool.
I just like, I guess you then you have to be prepared for like both, both outcomes and then exactly what you're going to do in both cases.
Like, it needs to actually feel like it had a meaningful impact.
Yeah, but it doesn't have to be the follow up league.
All right.
It could be something that you do half a year later or something.
Like, say you say that we have to kill like six billion monsters.
And if we don't, like the league will be different.
Right.
But yeah.
I guess I'm also kind of into the idea, although maybe people aren't, of like, you create like a thing that once you've achieved it, unlock something for all players.
Like that kind of stuff could be potentially fun.
So I mean, there's stuff you could do there, but I don't have any plans for it in particular.
Like, I haven't actually thought too much about this kind of stuff.
But yeah, like, I don't know.
It's kind of interesting.
I'll keep it in mind when we're doing the next league design for sure.
Nice.
Cool.
So I have a few questions about stash tabs.
The first one is for things that don't have a PoE2 equivalent, like let's say Blight, right?
Are we just not getting a tab at all?
Or are we going to instead get like a regular premium tab or something like that?
Yeah.
So currently you don't get anything.
And basically that's because we still want to be able to potentially add that content later.
And then at that point, that tab will be, you know, for that league.
So if we gave you something now, then we'd have to like, I guess, read only the other.
If we gave you a bonus tab now, we'd have to like give you a read only one or something like that.
And effectively, the main thing is that we're trying to just make it so that where it makes sense, the thing you bought before will work.
So, yeah, I don't, I think that for something, the particular one you mentioned there.
Yeah.
I suspect that in the future, there'll be a time when that will work again.
And so you're kind of going to be good in that regard.
Okay.
But I guess, I guess there, I guess it might be, it is worth bringing up though, that if we get to the point of like, literally, we're never going to use this ever in P2, I suppose we could consider like having a replacement tab or something like that.
But at least for the time being, like we still intend that a lot of that stuff still gets used anyway.
That makes sense.
Now, the next question is also about stash tabs.
And I remember at some point, there was a big discussion about consolidating normal tabs and letting people make quad tabs.
Now, if I recall correctly, the reason this didn't go through is there was a big issue with like database problems because we already have stuff in remove only tabs, right?
P2 doesn't have this issue.
Is there a chance that we can like, for example, there's quite a lot of people like me that have a hundred normal stash tabs and would like to merge four at a time into a quad stash tab?
Is that something that could be an option now with P2?
Um, let me think about that.
So it's certainly not something that we've done.
I suppose we could potentially do that.
I have to say that I'm personally not a huge fan of the quad tab overall, just because like, I understand the like gameplay utility of it, but it's just, I don't know.
There's something about it that sucks a little bit to me of just about the way that it just, you don't really, I feel like you don't appreciate the items the same way.
Now, admittedly, if you're just playing the game and you're like, you know, like you don't care about this at all, right?
Like I understand that you don't.
And so it's fine.
We've got that option.
But, um, yeah, it's just one of those things that I've kind of never really loved about it.
Um, like it kind of makes the items just look a bit lame, but, uh, you know, whatever, as I said, I understand that in practice, like for a gamer, it's like, you don't care about this.
Um, but, uh, yeah, like, I guess it's one of those that we just, I, we haven't done this.
I, uh, guess we theoretically might be able to do that, but yeah, I, as I said, it's just not something we've done.
Yeah.
I'm, I'm a very big fan of the quad tabs and I actually, uh, it's funny you brought up Tempest.
That's actually where I ended up buying a hundred normal tabs because, um, the radiating Tempest and the 20XLs, I was like, and, and I was new at the time.
And, you know, when you're new to the game, you don't want to get rid of everything.
So, uh, the next question is, uh, we've seen on the PUE health bar that there are numbers now, right?
So we have basically damage numbers in the game.
Um, so I wanted to bring up, have you thought about letting us have a literal target dummy?
Okay.
So we've thought about this for sure.
Um, the concern that came up the moment we discussed the target dummy is okay.
What resistance does it, what resistances does it have?
What's like, you know, like what, like, like all this kind of stuff, like basically they'd have to be stateful.
Like how much armor does it have?
How much evasion does it have?
Like all these things.
So then we started getting into, okay, um, uh, like you'd have to have some way to set these values, right?
You'd have to be able to be like, okay, I'm going to set up a target dummy with this particular amount of armor or whatever to simulate whatever boss it was.
And then we're kind of like, okay, should we then have a thing where you can like select like, okay, here's, here's a boss that it's going to be equivalent to.
And then like, that would be how we could do stuff like this.
And then we're kind of like, well, hang on.
At some point you just got the actual boss itself.
You might as well just use that.
And then we're kind of like, well, like maybe the target dummy kind of then is like, not quite of like, it starts to lose its utility then, you know?
So the whole chain of reasoning kind of came from all of that stuff.
Like I do understand like where you're coming from though, if you're saying that's not good enough.
I think you're overcomplicating it a little.
Yeah.
Right, right.
So you reckon target dummy with no stats, so then you're good?
Literally a target dummy with no stats.
Like, and like, if you really, like, if you don't want to overcomplicate it, you could even have two, right?
One that's the equivalent of like, let's say shaper, right?
Or literally just like one boss and one normal monster.
But even if all you give us is a target dummy with no resistances and no nothing, that is like already a lot better in my opinion.
Right.
I mean, I'm definitely, like, I'm actually kind of like probably fine with this.
But like, as I said, the main concern was that, so it's funny because like anytime you're discussing a feature like this, there's always all the questions of like, okay, so then what are people going to immediately ask for the moment we add this?
And so that's how we end up down the path of like, oh, it's like going to require this or this or this or this and then all these things.
Then that suddenly the feature is killed because of like the feeling of overcomplexity.
So I guess that's just sort of explain like how that sort of stuff occurs.
But yeah, I mean, look, if you're saying it's fine with no, like with no stats at all, like maybe it's something we could consider doing.
Like I'm not really opposed to it, to be honest.
Yeah.
I know a lot of people want it.
There is a lot of people that don't as well.
But yeah, I figured I'd bring it up.
I'm just out of interest.
So to hear the case for people who don't want it, like what do you think is really the behind that?
Because I mean, I've heard this argument from some GGG people before.
But as far as people in the community, like what do you reckon is the reason for like no target dummies?
Let's see.
I'm seeing so many people say I don't, or sorry, I do want it.
Someone said we have POB, don't need dummy.
It would feel too competitive.
Right, right, right, right.
Misleading numbers.
I'm trying to like pick up.
Well, they shouldn't be misleading.
So long as the target dummy actually emulates a real monster, the numbers wouldn't be misleading, right?
Yeah.
So then that's the argument therefore.
And then that exact thing there is like, oh, well, that's why you have to have the ability to simulate a given actual enemy.
Sometimes less info is better.
I don't know.
It's hard to see like reasons for why not.
Yeah.
Fair enough.
The next topic is going to be a bit of a longer one and a bit of a discussion.
I want to talk about what the current state of portaling out at bosses is and then talking a little bit about pausing and logging out as well.
Yeah, yeah.
So basically, yeah, so you can't port a lot of boss fight.
This was something that we tried for a while to make it so that you could port a lot of boss fights.
But like, you know, you put timers and stuff like that.
But eventually we're just kind of like, you know what?
Why are we even trying to do this?
Let's just completely ban it.
And then that way we don't have to worry about like all the potential kind of like rules and weird stuff about like, oh, you stand at this location.
The boss can't hit you like random stuff like that.
Like it just effectively removed a lot of a lot of potential exploits.
And I think that probably was just a straight up improvement.
You know, there's been actually a few other changes we've made.
Like this is something probably people will never notice, but you can no longer swap your gear in the middle of a boss fight either.
That's been now disallowed to.
And like a few other things like this, like these are just things that like, once again, people probably won't normally run into if they're not trying to do some kind of exploit.
But effectively, like we just want to make sure that like when you're actually in for a boss fight, you actually have like a proper experience.
You have to actually overcome the boss without some kind of weird, a weirder forms of cheese that you might otherwise try to do.
So what happens if let's say that a hardcore player goes in, they get 60% through the fight and they realize they can't do this.
What happens if they log out and wait until the next day?
So you can always you can always log out like resurrected checkpoint effectively or like log out and or log out and just wait for time.
So like it's possible to get out of a boss fight, right?
Like you're not locked into that forever.
So that being the case, like effectively, like, you know, like if you know you're if you know that you can't do it, you can get out.
And this is sort of an interesting question, because I know there are people who are kind of be like, oh, it would be nice if like once you've decided to do something, you're kind of committed to that action.
But I just think that we probably didn't want to really go down that path because it would mean that like I feel like that would kind of probably feel a bit bad, I think.
OK, so the concern then.
Yeah.
So just from understanding.
So from from the first thing you said, I was under the impression that if I go into a boss fight, let's say I'm going to fight the shaper.
Right.
Yeah.
Either the shaper dies or I die.
But but then that's not the case.
No, no, that's not the case.
So you can actually like you can bail.
That is the case.
You can't portal, but you can choose to restart at checkpoint or like log out to back.
Like if you if you if you log out.
OK, so if you just order for right, what will happen is when you log back in, you'll be in exactly the same place you were, which is like.
But that's more that the feature there is more about like trying to make sure that you don't like lose your place when you're just playing.
Right.
And you just connect for a reason.
Yeah.
But if you but if you want to choose to leave the fight, you can decide to do that.
Like that is OK.
OK.
And just another thing with that, by the way, is like I believe that the feature where if you lag that the game gets paused, I believe that did get done, which means that even if you just have like Internet lag, the actual server will pause while the lag is happening.
So then regardless of whether you get disconnected or not, you're not going to die during the middle of an Internet lag spike.
And I believe that it might be like 100 milliseconds or something like that is like like basically if you're like if your clients not responding for that amount of time, then if the whole instance just pauses and like we'll just wait until until you're good before we keep going again.
Yeah.
So that's how that works, basically.
But yes, you can leave.
Yeah.
So could you walk me through the difference real quick?
So will I be will I have to log out and wait 15 minutes or will it be hitting escape and then clicking like leave fight?
Yeah.
So if you hit escape, there's a button there called respawn at checkpoint.
And effectively, that will just mean that you can get at any time you can choose to do that.
Now, obviously, the concern with that, like and we actually discuss this quite a lot internally about like should that be OK, because there was like a whole discussion with this of like the fact that there's just a button you can do to press this kind of like would mean that like, oh, you it's like if even if you see like a slam coming, you'd be able to like push escape and just like push that button before it arrives.
And that is the case.
But the thing is, if we required you to log out and wait 15 minutes, that would kind of be lame, too.
Like, I don't really want to like and the counter argument to that one was like, oh, but like that's at least more friction to actually doing this.
And it's like, well, yeah, but then do you really want the strategy to be that you have to log out and wait 15 minutes?
Like, it's just kind of lame.
So in the end, we kind of decided to do the more, I guess, what I would call player friendly thing of just like, you know, that option is there for you.
You can leave if you want.
So effectively, yeah, in some sense, I suppose you could say that that's kind of equivalent to the old F4 you could do in POE1.
Yeah.
But, you know, it's that's kind of where we ended up anyway.
So just to confirm this, this does not kill you on hardcore, right?
Oh, I lost audio.
Wait, wait, no, no, it doesn't.
Sorry.
Yeah, it doesn't.
OK, but let me just think about this because I feel like I'm just I'm just getting a memory suddenly of us talking about that as well.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that that's yeah.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that that's fine.
Yeah.
But I feel like I remember the concern I would have there of why that would be a bad thing.
And I know a lot of people are against Logout Macro.
Right.
And I actually thought it would be something like a two second portal you'd have to cast and then it would fully reset the fight and you have to go again.
And the reason personally, I'm not a big fan of like having to commit is that you end up over farming so hard to the point where you go in and you know there's a zero percent chance of you dying.
Right.
Like normal shaper for now.
Whereas like if you can die, it's a lot more fun being able to go in before you're ready.
So that's awesome.
I'm very, very happy with that answer.
I will I will mention, by the way, that there is a very old league flag.
I don't know if it's exposed on the on the private league interface.
It probably isn't, honestly.
But there's a very old league flag that actually does enable a timer when you disconnect before you actually get disconnected.
And so if we wanted to run a league that had that functionality of where like you have to commit to everything when you do it, like because you'll stay in game, we actually could turn on a flag that would allow that.
So I don't know if you ever want to run a gauntlet like that sometime where you actually have to commit to something like that.
That would be cool for a gauntlet.
Yeah.
So that's something we could do.
That'd be perfect.
I think that's really good for a gauntlet.
All right.
A quick question as well.
In PeeWee 1, we have the six second disconnect timer.
Is that accounted for with the hundred millisecond lag thing you talked about?
OK, so effectively, the six second disconnect timer is still like that is just like after six seconds of like you not being in game, then we just terminate the socket and you're gone.
But because of the hundred millisecond pause thing existing now, effectively, the six second thing doesn't like really matter anymore because it's only important.
Like because the instance is frozen anyway.
So all that's doing is just making it so that like, look, at some point we have to give up on the fact that you're not going to actually be able to come back again.
In theory, we could actually increase that time now because like there's really no downside to it being that long or even longer.
So that would give longer for the internet to recover.
But I mean, I guess we just haven't kind of done one thing or the other.
But the thing that's going to matter to you really is just the fact that after 100 milliseconds, instances paused, you're not going to die.
And how long it takes before we like actually time your whole connection out is kind of not really as relevant anymore.
Awesome.
That's super cool.
I can't remember in whose interview you were talking about it, but you expressed some interest in racing again and saying that that's something you considered revisiting now.
But obviously you're cognizant of the fact that it's not necessarily what's going to like bring people back or bring revenue to the company, right?
And you are a company.
So I wanted to suggest, have you thought about having a specific like battle pass maybe or even one singular item for racing and telling people, look, if there's interest, we'll bring back things like descent, etc.
Based on how much it sells for, then like the racing community can literally contribute as much or as little and as there is interest.
I think that's pretty interesting.
I actually did have another idea like a long time ago, which I don't know.
So this is a different idea, but we'll just see.
I'm just going to pitch to see what you think about it.
Because we never actually did this, but it was a thing that I was interested in.
And that was the idea of like effectively like pay to enter races where it would be like, you know, like some number of cents to enter a race.
And then effectively sort of similar to the thing that you were talking about there, I guess, except that instead of being for a whole season, it was just like individual races.
And that was kind of an interesting idea that I was thinking that maybe people would be interested in.
But I wasn't quite sure whether people in the community would like that or not.
Like it kind of wasn't clear to me.
And so we're thinking like, oh, like five points to enter a race.
And then because of the fact that the rewards.
So then effectively the rewards of the race would have to be like cosmetics, right?
Because obviously we can't give you rewards in the form of anything that would be player power, given that you need to pay MTX currency to enter.
But effectively the like the original race rewards were alt art uniques anyway.
And like effectively if we remove the actual part where you get the actual unique out of it, we could do like like skins and stuff like that as part of the rewards.
So we kind of discussed that.
But I wasn't like whether I wasn't really I was just like very uncertain about whether the community would like to hate this.
So I'm kind of curious to hear your idea about what you think of it.
I mean, the battle pass is similar, except that it's more of a like one time purchase for a whole season, I assume.
Yeah, it's also I was thinking more of like, like, even if even if it starts out with like a cloak that you buy that isn't like this wouldn't depend on you being able to play or not.
This is like if you want to see more of this in the future.
I'm more of a fan of free entry and then having a way for people to support and just being open with like, if this is something you guys are interested in, this is how you can show that you're interested in it.
If not.
Right, right.
I well, the battle pass thing, the battle thing is sort of interesting because it already kind of is similar to how the racing structure was anyway.
We get points and then like certain thresholds you get, you know, you get cosmetic.
So it actually probably doesn't match more into it.
I just mentioned the other one because it's something I thought of ages ago.
I thought it would be interesting to see.
But, you know, that is an interesting idea.
Like the racing battle.
It's a it's actually a pretty cool idea.
Like I'm interested in this for sure.
The main the main issue really with that is just that the amount of bandwidth we have for making microtransactions, which is what we need to make for this is honestly surprisingly low.
Like we're so like it's so ridiculous in some ways that like for a company that makes money from cosmetics that we don't have more people just working on that stuff.
Yeah.
But, you know, the we need to be able to create more stuff like that.
And it's like to already get more people for making existing existing cosmetics.
So, you know, if we had infinite resources to make that stuff, I would absolutely do something like that.
I think that's pretty interesting.
Yeah.
So it's just a question of, you know, where we get the time.
Yeah, that's fair.
Awesome.
That's just I'm such a big fan of racing and I know a lot of people are.
Right, right.
Wanted to bring that up.
It is fun.
I have a question from a community member in full caps lock.
How do character names work?
Is it the same as PeeWee1 or is it hashtag 1254 where multiple people can be the same name?
So obviously like our accounts are hashtag now.
Are our names still unique?
So we decided to just keep the names the same way they worked before in PeeWee1 for now at least.
And the reason why is because so with account names, you never really have to refer to account names very much while actually typing.
Yeah.
So we wouldn't have had to worry about all the concerns that come around having to like know people's discriminators and having to like, you know, worry about all that sort of thing.
With character names, there's a few other details.
So one of them is that they expire.
So you don't have the problem where the space just, you know, exists.
I assume you knew that about character name expiration.
I thought that was just done in waves.
It's not done in waves.
So effectively one year after the character name is, sorry, after the character has not been logged into, it goes into a pool of names that someone else could create if they want to.
And if they then do that, then the name gets expired for you.
So effectively, like the, over time, like names will free up again.
So that's the way that that works.
It's actually just a, as I said, it's just as soon as you haven't logged into a character for a year, that's when it's no longer.
The character.
Discriminator.
Wow.
Okay.
So I believe, I believe that's how it, at least I think so.
It's been a little while since I thought about this, but yeah, I'm pretty sure that that's the way that one works.
And yeah, so because of that, like characters don't have quite exactly the same problem as account names do.
And as I said, the discriminator on character names would be more annoying because that's kind of how you know, that's kind of how you refer to people within, within the league.
So we kind of decided to do that.
That being said, if it became like a real problem, I'm open to the idea of doing the whole discriminator on character name thing.
It's just that it would mean that you'd have to then have a situation where it's like, whenever you're doing a whisper, you'd have to like, no, like, because you have to have like autocomplete for this, right?
Like you can't have discriminated autocomplete.
And then that means you have to have all the whole thing of like, okay, are they in a friends list?
Are they in the guild?
Are they in your party?
Have they talked in chat recently?
Have they whispered you recently?
Like all of that stuff would have to go in the pool of things that you autocomplete for.
And I mean, look, it's like how discord used to be, right?
When, when it had stuff.
So there's basically just a bunch of work that you'd have to do there.
And I mean, we could do that stuff if we felt like we needed to, but we're going to try without for the time being and see how that goes.
And, you know, like if, if it's like a real problem, then we can always change it.
There are some audio issues, by the way.
I don't know if the mic's too far away or something, but you're cutting out a little bit.
I'll, I'll try that.
Hopefully that did.
Sorry about that.
I'm not sure.
It's not too bad.
It's just a lot of people are cutting on it.
Fair enough.
Awesome.
So another question with that are like, for example, I have the name Zizarin right now in PeeWee 1.
Will I have that in PeeWee 2 or is it like fresh start from everyone and there will be a character in PeeWee 1 and a character in PeeWee 2?
Yeah.
So the characters are separated in PeeWee 1 and 2.
The databases are just completely, completely independent.
So you'll have to race to get that one, I guess.
All right.
I'm not getting that one.
Cool.
So a few other questions about runes.
So runes, they're obviously like replacing the crafting bench.
Sure.
Yep.
In a way.
And can you override them?
Like, can I put in a new one over it if I want to change later?
You can't.
So that's something that's...
I guess we could potentially do, though.
Like, I don't think I'm against it.
I'd actually have to talk to Rishi and Mark about whether or not we'd want to allow that.
But currently you can't at least.
So, yeah.
I'm very curious about this because from my understanding, one of the main reasons that you wanted to remove sockets from gear was that you really wanted to have this new thing where you find a gear upgrade.
You don't need to 16K.
You don't need to, like, get it exactly how you need it to be.
You can just equip it.
But I feel like...
I actually love the concept of runes, but I feel like a little bit about how they systematically work sort of ends up cancelling this, right?
Where I will not be able to actually pick up an item and, wow, this is an upgrade.
I will have to fix my runes.
Maybe I have to farm them.
I see what you mean.
But I don't think it's the same because the thing with...
So, a couple of things with this.
One of them is that when we're talking about the whole, like, pick up an item and having to change stuff, what that was mostly around is the idea that, okay, like, socket colors and so on, right?
Like, it meant that you had to change, like...
Either you have to chromatic stuff until the point where, like, you've actually got exactly what you had before, or you have...
Which is, like, definitely way more annoying than having to just use a couple of currency items on your item, right?
Like, chromatic-ing to get to the right state, like, could be very difficult.
But the other thing you might have to do is just rearrange everything in your character and, like, oh, this goes here, that goes there.
I like to use different supports or something like that, right?
So, to me, that was, like, a much more arduous process than what this is.
Because, effectively, you're going to have the currency that allows you to add sockets to items.
It's not hard to get that currency.
Like, in the early game, it's a little bit more restricted.
But, effectively, you're definitely going to...
As you go through the game, you're going to have that currency in abundance, I would say.
So, I don't think it's, like, necessarily a problem, like, doing that.
But, sorry, I felt like you were about to say something there.
Yeah, so, especially with resistances and stuff, I'm still a little bit worried about this.
Because you don't have the ability to change that later.
So, effectively, in terms of fixing resistances, the sockets are more of a thing that you would be worried about early game for those kinds of stats.
Like, when I say early game, I kind of mean, like, during the campaign, right?
Because during the campaign, you're like, okay, I've got low on this resistance.
I want to get another one of those.
To me, at least, I've found that it's kind of not something that I'm too worried about overall, like, as I'm changing items and going up.
Because as you're going through the campaign, you're finding new base types, you're getting new things, you're kind of constantly upgrading.
And it kind of hasn't really ended up being a thing where I'm worried about that.
If you equip a new item and you're like, I've lacked this resistance, generally speaking, I'm like, okay, well, I'll add another socket or two to this.
And then I'll get the resistance rune out of my stash and use that.
So, it's kind of ended up being a thing where, like, just fixing that resistance tends to be a problem that you do after deciding to upgrade anyway.
So, that's kind of been okay.
And it's worth mentioning that with the runes, because they're kind of like, so at early game, they're more powerful than they are at late game because the values, there's only one value for each type.
Yeah.
So, that means is that, like, early game, the resistances you're getting from one of these resistance runes is, like, extremely huge relative to the other resistance sources you would get.
But as you get later into the game, the runes are less effective at solving that problem because the numbers are not stacking up compared to the mods you could get.
And so, as you get towards the later game, the things that you're going to be wanting to be socketing are more of the soul cores, which have the, like, different mods that aren't kind of designed to fix those early game problems.
And also, your character has more mods overall and is generally kind of, like, more in a good place.
So, it really is, like, in terms of, like, fixing problems you have, it's more of a, like, you know, first sort of 30, 40 levels kind of type deal rather than after that, if you know what I mean.
So, I think for that purpose, they work really, really well.
And as for changing them, I suppose we could allow it.
I don't actually see a reason why we couldn't do that, although, as I said, I haven't talked to Mark and Rishi about it.
But I guess the feeling here is that because you got to choose it, it's not quite the same as feeling like you need to be able to remove the mod that you would have from one of the random sources where we have, like, some random ways to get rid of it.
So, that was kind of the reason why we're thinking that it can go the way that it has.
But as I said, I don't think there's necessarily a downside to allowing you to replace it.
So, maybe that is fine.
I just haven't thought all through all the repercussions of that yet.
Yeah, I mean, for example, like, I normally play SSF.
Well, I actually have been playing a little bit more trade lately, and especially for trade, right?
You could see, like, a perfect item you want to buy of somebody, but they've, like, got these, like, garbage runes in it.
So, I could see that being an issue as well.
It's definitely, like, I'm trying to go into PeeWoo, too, with the approach, like, I haven't played it enough.
I'll see how it is.
But that is definitely something I'm very worried about, and hopefully something you'd be open to feedback with when we actually try it.
Right.
I mean, I'm definitely always open to the feedback of that.
But as I said, I think from actually trying it myself, that hasn't been a problem I've run into particularly.
But, you know, I guess we'll see how it goes.
Yeah.
That's fair.
How rare are, like, the...
How rare are the rarest runes, basically?
So, the runes themselves are not particularly rare.
You get them fairly often.
Like, I mean, you'll get...
I mean, in Act 1, you'll find four or five of them, probably.
And then it only increases from there as you get more monster density and so on.
So, like, you're finding them.
And generally speaking, like, if you're in Act 2, like, maybe there'll be a rune that you want that you don't have.
But then by the time you're in Act 3, I would say you probably have the runes that you need.
Like, they're generally available.
It's really the soul cores that are the ones that are, like, the, you know, oh, it's actually a struggle to find the ones you need of these.
Like, because that's where the kind of, you know, the higher level gameplay is.
Right.
And would you say there are soul cores that are at the rarity of, like, Eternal Orb, Divine Orb, like, that type of stuff?
I don't know the actual numbers, but I would definitely think so.
Like, there's definitely...
There are definitely hard to find ones, for sure.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah.
Cool.
Awesome.
Next up, how does, like, stacking ailment works for, like, stacking multiple of the same?
Right.
So, effectively...
So, okay.
So, in general, ailments don't stack, right?
In order to get the ability to stack them, there has to be some kind of mechanic you're getting.
Yep.
Usually that mechanic will have some kind of...
That mechanic may have some kind of explanation for, like, any specific details you have to be aware of.
But I guess the main thing to understand is that if you're doing something like stacking poison, the way that that works is that
all of the...
So, all of the poisons that you do will always be on the monster.
Yep.
And they're all running.
But whatever...
If you've got the ability to stack two poisons, then whatever the two largest poisons that you currently have that are on there,
those will be the active ones.
And then when one of those falls off, then the next largest will take its place, effectively.
So, that kind of means that, like...
That's kind of, I believe, sort of generally how the...
Like, buffs work in PoE, where you've got, like, you know, whatever...
If you can have multiple buffs on a thing, but only one of them is active at a time.
So, in the case where you're allowed to have more than one, it's just, effectively, whatever the highest in buffs are that are on the character,
that's the ones that you get, effectively.
Cool.
Well, that's good.
Yeah.
So, I don't know if there's anything else you want to know about that, but...
No, not that I can think of. I think that answers that. That's pretty good.
Fair enough.
Another question from the community.
Does mana and elemental leech exist?
So, mana leech is a thing, but only for attacks.
Yeah.
And elemental leech, I believe, is a thing.
There are probably...
I believe there are probably, like, various mechanics around that will give you elemental leech.
It's definitely going to be a lot harder.
But what we're trying to avoid is mana leech for spells, because that can kind of, like, defeat a lot of mechanics and so on.
So, effectively, that's the main thing.
Everything else is fair game, but we just have to, you know, like, it just depends on where it comes from.
So, yeah, that's kind of the basic idea.
Okay, cool.
Yeah.
I know a lot of people are hoping for a spell mana leech, so...
Yeah, that's the thing we don't want to do.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, next up, questions about...
A few questions about crit, actually.
In PeeWee 1, it's almost like when you're building a crit build, you're supposed to be 100% crit.
Is that the same in PeeWee 2?
I would say that it's kind of more like earlier PeeWee 1 how it used to be, where it's like you can get there with various mechanics.
But I would say that it's like it may not be the most optimal thing to do, just because, like, the stuff you're sacrificing might be too much in order to do that.
Especially when you've got, like, conditional crit mechanics.
Getting to 100% isn't so bad, but, like, you're not always going to be meeting those conditions, if you know what I mean.
So, yeah, I would say that, like, we've tried to kind of keep things a little bit more in line in terms of having more, like, as I said, just, like, controlling the sources a little bit better and kind of making sure that, like, getting to 100% is actually, like, a real, like...
As I said, possible, but kind of not expected.
So I imagine this sort of expected crit would be a bit lower than that.
And, yeah, trying to increase beyond that is kind of not hugely valuable.
Okay.
What's the main reason there in difference?
Is that just to, like, retain player power and not let it get out of control early?
I wouldn't say that exactly.
I think it's more just that, like, we...
Ideally, every mechanic...
So, like, I'm just a general...
I am generally in favor of the idea that, like, there's...
The decision to not increase something more is not because you run out of sources of it, but because, like, there's a...
A...
Like, a reason that you don't want to do that because the trade-offs are too much.
And so effectively by keeping the values that you're kind of, like, can easily get to to a sort of certain midpoint, you just avoid the...
Like, you just sort of make it so you get that trade-off, like, you have to make that trade-off towards the end of the range.
So it's effectively like that.
So I think that's kind of really the main reason.
Like, it's been a little while since I talked about this with anyone, but, yeah, like, that's kind of really what it came down to.
We just kind of wanted to make 100% crit more of a, like, this is a very unusual situation rather than this is a common situation.
Okay.
And do you think part of that is as well that, at least in Pee-wee 1, crit feels like the endgame.
Like, you should go crit at some point and you kind of want to avoid that as well?
Is that part of it at all?
Well, we're certainly trying to make it so that crit is not the only build.
There was actually a thing that we changed.
So, you know, here's a random thing for you.
We actually had the change for a little while where the...
So crit modifies, and I need to get this correct.
Like, there are various crit suffixes in Pee-wee 1.
And so there was this feeling that in Pee-wee 1 that if you're a crit build, you've got, like, you can make your build more powerful than what non-crit builds can because the suffixes that are available to you as a crit build are, like, more powerful than what the suffixes are available to you as a not crit build.
Yeah.
And so because of that, we actually decided initially to move crit stuff all to be prefixes as well to effectively compete with the other prefixes that you could get that all increase damage, right?
And so we did this for a while.
And we actually found that, like, it actually made weapon rolling way less fun.
Like, in theory, what it was doing was making it so that, okay, you could get a crit weapon or you could get, like, a not-crit weapon, and, like, they were kind of competing with each other.
And we did all the math, and we're like, hey, look, now we've made it so that crit builds and non-crit builds are more in line with each other, and they have the same level of power and items and so on.
And we kind of thought that we'd done a good thing there.
And then at some point we just realized, like, why is it the weapons just don't feel as fun to find in Pee-wee 2 as they do in Pee-wee 1?
And then we realized that, like, this is actually part of the problem.
So we actually reversed that decision and moved the crit stuff back to be suffixes again.
And we've kind of tried to make sure that the suffix pull is actually reasonable in other ways for the other builds, like making sure that the suffixes are actually, like, make sense and there's powerful versions of, like
Like, ideally it's, like, there should be anlike, there should be a level that each suffix can get to that is exciting, right?
And so, like, the question we have to ask ourselves is, like, what is the amount of strength that if you got that as a suffix that you'd be excited about that?
Yeah.
And so effectively, like, we're trying to make sure that there's actually, like, at the high end there are suffixes that are actually really good.
And so hopefully we've restored some of the, like, possible power that you sort of can get from weapons.
And I think that's sort of aI think it's in a better place.
I don't really remember exactly how this was related to the original question anymore, but it was just something that came up in my mind.
Does that mean that at the high end you don't want dead suffixes?
Like, I remember life regen for a long time and thorns, right, would be literally dead suffixes?
You still want to have suffixes where when you get them, you need to have bad roles, right?
But at the same time, we did say that, like, okay, whateverwhen you've got the higher tier roles, that there are actually things thatlike, the highest tier of something needs to be something you actually would be excited to see.
And there are actually a couple of cases whereso wethe tiering system for modssorry, for rares, like, you know how when you've got, like, you know, T2, 3, 4, 5just goes up to 5like, T5 rares.
When you actuallyif you actually get a T5 rare, it's actually possible because we haven't got some of the mods, like Light Radius, for example.
They don't actually have an eye level.
There's no Light Radius mod that's higher than eye level, like, 60-something, I think it is.
It's probably like the highest one.
It's actually possible that on the highest tier content
With a tier 5 rare
That the dead mods like that are actually cut out
Of the mod pool completely
So it's actually possible for that to be
Now tier 5 rares are like rare as hen's teeth
They're actually like incredibly
Incredibly rare
So when you get one of those
You know the mods on those are going to be really really good
Because you know the eye level of the mods you're going to get
I'm so excited for that
Okay so that means that there are
Just like really
Some really good stuff up there
But yeah it's
Once again I can't remember where I was going with this
But this is like a thing that
Exists for the rare system
So that can mean
That some of the rares you can get
On the higher tiers can be
Very good
Awesome very very cool
I'm very excited to hear that
Items is like my favourite thing in ARPGs
So definitely looking forward to that
I want to continue asking about crit
Enemy crit in Path of Exile 1
Can be a little bit weird
With especially like let's say multi
Like the Volspark from like Tynevin
Or whatever he's called
Or the Shaper Balls and stuff
Because either the entire ability crits
Or none of it crits
Is enemy crit functioning similar in PeeWee 2
Or is it to the individual projectile?
So I don't think we've made any changes here
But I believe that the way that that works
Is determinable by the designers
As they're working on it
But I suspect it's one of those things
That they probably don't necessarily
Always think about
Because it's kind of pretty
It's sort of somewhat invisible
You know like so it's one of those things
That just probably just doesn't come up
In their minds
So we can control that
And I don't know whether or not
And as I said the system works fundamentally
The same as PeeWee 1 did
I just don't know whether to what extent
They've actually like used the features
That allow them to control one or the other
And what situations that they would want
To use one or the other
Yeah
Like out of interest
Do you prefer the like every mechanic crits
Or do you prefer just every projectile?
I assume every projectile is what you'd prefer
I'd way prefer every projectile
Obviously now I usually will end up building
For crit immunity instead
And that's fine
Right right
But I remember when I was a new player
To Path of Exile
And suddenly I'd be standing next to
The Volspark Exile
And it would just explode
And I'm like
What just happened?
And somebody would like watch my clip
And they're like
Oh yeah he crit you
You're gone
Right right
I have a feeling that
I mean I suppose the question would be
Whether we should make per projectile
The default option
It's one of those things
That like I don't see a reason why we wouldn't
I'd have to talk to Mark about it
But yeah that's probably reasonable
I think that the
I think that the whole ability
Critting all at once
Is actually
Is the default for some reason
Yeah
I think
So I'm pretty sure
That if you run into that
It's because the designer
Forgot to add the stat
That makes it so that
It's just every projectile
To that particular ability
So yeah that's just kind of
One of those random things
But for player skills
It's like one of those things
That we really have to think
Very carefully about
Yeah
Because there are kind of
Reasons and not
I mean like one of the ones
That is tricky for this
Is Reign of Arrows
Yeah
It's like should every
Should every projectile crit
Or should every projectile not crit
Now because right now
Every projectile has its own crit role
It means that if you use
Like Sniper's Mark
On a monster
And then you do
Reign of Arrows on that monster
Then you're almost guaranteed
To crit it at some point
Just because it hits so many times
Yeah
And that means that effectively
The Sniper's Mark
Is like using it with
Reign of Arrows
Is just like a complete win
Because you're just
Incredibly likely to actually
Trigger that
And so then it's kind of like
Well should we make it instead
So that ability is like crit
The whole ability crits
Or doesn't crit
But then the problem with that is
That it just feels super weird
Like there's something odd
About the feeling of like
Do a critical Reign of Arrows
And then you start to think
Should it look different
So you can see that the whole
Reign of Arrows is critting
I don't know
It kind of just has some
Weird implications
So we kind of decided
Not to do it in the end
But yeah
There is a reason why we have
Both the abilities
To do in different situations
Yeah I get that
I mean
I'm definitely a lot less concerned
About the intricate workings
Of how player crit works
Because like
The monsters aren't going to
Complain
Yeah
No it's a tricky one
Definitely would be a fun
I would be interested
I should talk to Mark
About whether or not
We should just have a policy
In general
Just everything a monster does
Is always individual roles
Like
There might be a reason
He's against that
But I'd be interested to find out
I'm curious how you feel
About
Bosses especially
Critting at all
Personally
I'm a big fan
Of like everything being static
Right
And like not having mods
And not being necessarily variable
Because like
There are some abilities
That like
You know
You're
Basically effectively
Mapping out
What you can tank
And then suddenly
You're gonna knock you
With a big crit
And you're like
Oh never mind
So yeah
I'm just curious
How you feel about that
Like
Mods and crits
On bosses
Yeah I'm just thinking about
Well okay
So mods
I think it's nice
To have mods
Personally
I think
Because I like to have
Situations
Where you've got the ability
To
Like
It gives us an access
To
Because
What having mods does
Like on maps and so on
Is the ability to make it
So that a boss fight
Can feel different
From a different time
You fought it
Just based on what
The mods were
So I think that stuff's important
That being said
We did like
The idea of having
The static bosses
For the
Top
Pinnacle content
Just because
That is a measuring stick
That players can use
Against each other
So having that
Be like a static thing
Is kind of nice
So that's why
I like the mods
As for the crits
I can see your point
For sure
Like that is an interesting point
Like should we
Crit at all
For bosses
Yeah that's just curious
I guess I don't really have a
I just don't really have
Like I honestly
Don't really have an argument
For why they should
To be honest
I guess the main thing
Would be just to make sure
You've got the variance
But then the answer would be
Why the players
Probably don't want the variance
So you know
Yeah I don't know
I find that to be interesting
It's not something
That I've really thought about
Too much
I have to admit
And yeah
Like I see your point
About not wanting to have
The crits for sure
So yeah
It's probably something
That I'll have a chat
To Mark about
Yeah I was just very
Very curious about the answer there
Because obviously
Like we can just get
Create immunity
But the feeling for me there
Is that it almost
Makes it mandatory
Right
And I feel like in general
Whenever something
Feels mandatory
Like remember the
Castle Nemesis
Taken
Immortal Call Days
And stuff like that
Like it usually gets
Like changed or removed
Right right
So
I suspect that the answer
Against this
Would involve
Basically
Like it's another
Like it's an axis
Of character development
That we're removing
Like that's probably
The argument that would
Be made against it
So then the question is
Yeah but I agree with you
That if something's mandatory
Then it's kind of like
You know
Maybe why should it
Necessarily exist
So yeah I mean
Point taken right
Like I'm
This is an interesting one
To me
And I'll talk to the guys
About it
Ziki wrote something
Really cool that I like
Let me see if I
Where did it go
Enemy crit should be
Conditional buffs
You can see to
And react to
I think that would be
Really cool
Like
Let's say that there's
Let's use Shaper Slam
As an example right
That if the Shaper Slam
Is about to crit
It like changes the animation
And becomes maybe a bit slower
Right right right
That would be really cool
That
Because that does change the fight
But like I love that
Yeah yeah yeah
That would be way cooler
That's interesting
Okay
It's for me the
I guess for me the big thing
Is that like
They look exactly the same
You have no idea
If it's going to crit or not
Yeah yeah yeah
No I agree
I agree
You know
And that's a very good argument
Like it is a very good point
I'd be interested to hear
If
Yeah
If Mark has any particular
Reason against that
Maybe he doesn't
Like it's
It is a very interesting point
Yeah
Cool
More questions about
Monsters
Do they still get charges
And if so
How do they work
So charges don't have
Any inherent bonus anymore
Yeah
So therefore
Monsters don't currently get charges
I suspect it's the kind of thing
Where we might come up with
Some interesting thing
To use them for
In the future
But currently
There's just no reason
For them to exist
So they just don't get them
Cool
A lot of people are curious
About support characters
And how they fit into
Path of XL2
For those that want to
Play with their friends
And make OP combos together
So I would say
It's sort of interesting right
Because what we don't have
Is the support character
And the way that
POE1 had it
Where it was like
Just a literal kind of
AFK
You walk around behind them
You don't really do anything
So I would say that
For that
We still have things like that
You've got scepters
And stuff like that
That can give people bonuses
But I would say that
Support characters
In POE2
Are more along the lines of
I'm debuffing monsters
Actively
Or I'm
Setting up things
That don't need to worry
About the damage
In order for someone else
To take advantage of them
Like these kind of things
So like you can make
A support character
That's kind of like
Ultra slow all the enemies
You can make a support character
That will do things like
Place
Like place objects
That other people can use
Or like
Or for example
Like make a character
That's like
Armor breaking
Lots of monsters
So that other people
Can take advantage of that
Things like that
So I'd say that
That's kind of the role
Of that kind of stuff more
But what we don't have
Is just like
I just reserve everything
And like
You know
I'm just like an aura
Like just a bunch of auras
On my character
And that's kind of all I'm doing
So that's the kind of thing
That we don't really
Have in the same way
Cool
Awesome
I think that generally
Answers that
Next up
A little bit of a discussion
Of something that was
Brought up in a previous podcast
I have in my notes there
Talk about respeccing ascendancies
I don't know if that's something
You've like
Thought about
Or talked about more
After the podcast
With I believe it was
Unfortunately I haven't
Had a chance to
To talk more about this
But I mean look
As I said
It's still on my mind
Is something that I know
Players are concerned about
So like it will
We will definitely have
Another conversation about it
For sure
Yeah
But I don't think
There's really anything else
To say about it at the moment
Perfect
Alright
Yeah that's it
I'm obviously very
Pro-Respecting ascendancy
So
Yeah
My argument
Would just be
It's a very early place
To make a permanent decision
Sure
I understand
Yeah
Okay cool
On to
Endgame like mapping
And things like that
How much more rewarding
Should a difficult map mod
Like you know
Penetration
Or something like that
Be compared to
Chill ground
Or monster variety
So
I believe
That
So
It's a very different situation
In PeeWee 2 than PeeWee 1
For this stuff
Because
The rewards
From
Difficult mods
Are not necessarily
Like
The
The rewarding part
Of the map mods
Because we've got the thing
Where the prefixes
Are like
The rewards mods
And the suffixes
Are the like
Bad mods
It means it's kind of
Separated those two things
Out a little bit more
Yeah
Now there is still
A thing where the
Harder mods have
Waystone
Drop rate
Increases on them
And so I believe
And I believe
That the
Harder mods there
Do affect that
But I don't think
That that is like
Quite so much
Of a big deal
Compared to
How it was in PeeWee 1
Where like
The item drops
Were heavily
Changed by that stuff
So like
I don't know
That like
As I said
It's a very different
Situation
Now it's gonna
This is one of those
Things that I'm like
I really hope it works
But I don't know
If it will
So I guess
We'll sort of
See after see
Like the dynamics
Of what people
Choose to roll
And how people
Respond to that
Are going to be
Very interesting
So like
Yeah
I guess we'll
Just see how that
Goes
But what it does
Mean at least
With the current
Way the system
Works
Is that
It doesn't matter
Quite so much
What the
Like the numbers
We choose
For how difficult
Those things
Are relative to
Like the rewards
They give
Because as I said
The rewards being given
Are mostly from the
Prefixes anyway
So yeah
I guess that's
Kind of related to that
Cool
Yeah no I was
I was just curious
Because somebody
Brought up the point
That I think
I think it was
Penetration and
Monster Variety
Had basically
The same rewards
So I was
Curious there
So that'll be
Interesting to see
How that changes
What about
Things like
Slash Ladder
Is that going
To be the same
Or different
It's the same
For now
Look we could
Probably do better
With this
Like you know
It's funny
Because before
We
Slash Ladder
Was a temporary
Cheat we added
Before PeeWee 1
Was released
As a temporary
Thing before we
Added the ladder
Screen
And then
And now we're
Releasing PeeWee 2
And we still
Haven't implemented
The ladder screen
Like it's kind of
Absurd
How that works
But yeah
We originally
Intended to have
An in-game
Ladder screen
And then I guess
The website
Kind of had it
And then we
Just never got
Around to
Actually implementing
UI for it
Like so all I
Could say is
Like okay
It's been 15
Years but we're
Still intending
To make a
Ladder screen
In-game one
Day
So
15 years
From now
Yeah
Sure
At some point
We'll get
Around to that
Cool
Okay good to
Know
And in a
Similar vein
What about
Would it be
Possible at all
For the community
To get a more
Detailed
API
For things
Like that
Like Ladder
And like
Making your
Own tools
So I'm
Curious what
More you'd
Want out of
The Ladder
For the
API
Because effectively
I believe
That the
API we have
Right now
Just gives you
A full dump
Of the first
Like I don't
Remember how
Many it is
Is it like
10,000 or
Something people
Something like
That there's
Like some
Number of
People in
The Ladder
That it
Gives you
And as far
As I know
It gives you
Everything you
Would need
To have
So yeah
What else
Do you want
Right
Well
Like if you
Want something
Else
So you can
Add it
Yeah okay
Oh my god
We can get
You a list
So obviously
Like I'm
Yeah it's a long
Time since I
Started computer
Science so I
Don't have a list
In front of me
But things I
Can think of
Off the top
Of my head
Would be
Boss kills
For example
Right for the
Events we do
That is one of
The biggest
Things we want
Like what
Oh so you want
A ladder for
When
Oh you want
Like a different
Ladder for when
People have
Killed a boss
Not necessarily
Part of the ladder
Just like an
API we can
Access for if
Somebody kills
A boss or
Something
So you mean
Like but
So like
Do you want
How many times
They've killed
A given boss
Or do you want
Like like like
Like have they
Killed the boss
At all yet
Yeah have they
Killed the boss
At all yet
I think that we
Do have
Support for
Ladders of when
People killed a boss
Because like don't
We have that for
Certain events
I thought we did
Only for the
First person I
Believe
I just I have a
Feeling that the
Way that's implemented
Internally is there's
Just a like
Effectively the
Amount of time until
You kill the given
Boss like as a
Separate ladder
Effectively
And then that
Would mean that
Like you could
Effectively dump a
Ladder of that
Of like when
Was the who was
The first person
To kill a given
Boss
So that's something
We could probably
Do like relatively
Easily I will say
We haven't like
Thought about this
For a long time
So I can get you
Like from like
The guy who made
Peewee racing and
Stuff I can get you
A list of like
API things that
Would be huge for
So obviously I'm
Very involved in
Loving and wanting
To do events
Right right
As I said I think
We do have actually
Like boss time
Like time to kill
A specific boss
But I'm pretty sure
That what it is
Is that like
That had to be
Specifically implemented
For each boss
That we wanted to do it
Because I'm pretty sure
That the reason why
We had that was for
Like the original race
Seasons we did
Where we sometimes
Had like different
Objectives
Things like yeah
First to kill
Ex-boss
So I think it's
Still lurking around
In there somewhere
So we might be able
To like resurrect that
And like it would
Be pretty cool to
Have a ladder for
Like first person to
Kill the pinnacle
Encounters in
Peewee 2 when it
Comes out for example
We might be a little
Bit too close to
Be able to actually
Implement something
Like that but like
It's possible that
It's just like a
Matter of like
Resurrecting some
Piece of code
That's been sitting
There and turning
It on so I'll
Actually look into
That because that's
Kind of interesting
Yeah is there going
To be any form of
Like yellow text
Announcements for
Like first to level
First to new areas
And stuff
Yes so I think
That we have
So the leveling one
I think we only do
It every five levels
At least for the first
While just because
We don't want it to
Be like super spammy
And for first to
Enter area
I think that
I don't remember
Exactly how that
Was going to be
I think because
There was also
Some concern
I mean look there
Is definitely going
To be stuff like
That but I think
That we just wanted
To try and reduce
The spam a little
Bit in some cases
Certainly you want
Like first to reach
Level like past
Level like 65 or
Something you probably
Want like everything
Above that to be
Like every single
Level I would say
Just because like
You know that's
Like that's pretty
Important race and
It takes a bit
Longer up there
So we've got
Something like that
I don't think
There's any first to
Kill well maybe
There are first to
Kill bosses for
The act bosses
Or something
I don't remember
The exact situation
But there's
There's definitely
Some of that stuff
We just wanted to
Make sure it
Doesn't seem like
Completely incomprehensible
For like a bunch
Of new players
So seeing all the
Stuff for the first
Time so yeah we
Just kind of
Want to limit
It a little bit
Very cool
I love to hear that
A question from
My community was
Are there going to
Be free respikes
During the EA
If there's a big
Enough change
Like right now if
There's a huge
Steel tree change
On standard
You get like
The free respike
Yeah yeah yeah
So I'd say
It's probably going
To be the same
As that effectively
Like when we do
A big change
Everyone will get
A free respike
And it'll work
That way pretty much
Yeah
Cool yeah
Somebody was
Particularly concerned
Because if it's
Respiking is
Is it only gold
Or do you have
Silver guy orbs
I can't remember
No regret anymore
It's just gold
Yeah so
The guy was asking
Was what if
A big change happens
And your build is
Bricked and you've
Just used your gold
You just log in
And you're like
Cool
Generally speaking
Yeah it'll be
The
Yeah like
The big patches
That do the big
Balance stuff
We should get
Now that being said
Like
I'm not going to
Say that every single
Like there will
Probably be patches
Where we nerf
Some particular thing
And then like
You know that could
Hit certain characters
Like that
That'll probably happen
Yeah
Just because you know
I'm hoping not
But you never know
Yeah
So yeah like
That might then
Cause a situation
Where you don't have
A free respike
For that reason
Because what we don't
Have the ability to do
Is like targetedly
Respec
Like certain builds
Or anything like that
Like so it's
Effectively all or nothing
So because of that
The
Yeah like it would
Have to be
A more global change
To like you know
Oh look we've redone
The skill tree
In various ways
And then we'd
Probably do it
Yeah
I'm guessing you can't
Go in negative gold
Right you can't
Like okay
Mr. Respec man
I'll pay you back later
No no no no
Yeah no doubt
Cool
Another question
From the community
Is we've learned
That ascendancies
And items
Can be supported
So a logical follow up
Is how many sockets
Do those start with
Do ascendancy skills
Start with five sockets
And do items with skills
Show you how many sockets
They have
So if you have
Stuff that's inherent
To your character
So that is to say
Like ascendancy
And ascendancy skills
Do count as that
Or things like
So for example
Default attack
Being also
Supportable skill
These things
Level get sockets
Based on your
Character level
Now I don't remember
What the level is
That you get
It's like late 80s
There's like
That's the one
Where you get five sockets
For all of those
Things
Effectively as you level up
You'll get more sockets
For that stuff
The ones that are
Inherent to
To items
Those ones get
Sockets based on
The eye level of the item
So effectively
A higher eye level
Base
If that base comes
With a socket
That high level
Eye level base
Will have the thing
So I don't know
If the trade site
Will show it correctly
Yet or not
But it is based
Entirely on eye level
Which you can see
The trade site
Needs like
Like
The
That will probably
Take some time
To fully be like
100%
Like every single thing
About it
Looking exactly the same
As in game
Just because there's
Like a whole bunch
Of work there
But we definitely
Want to make sure
The trade site
At least shows you
Everything that you
Sort of need to know
So I don't know
Whether or not
They will be showing
The sockets
In
That are in
Skills in gear
And I have a feeling
It probably won't
Because I know
That skills in general
On the trade site
Are kind of like
A bit
Because there's
Like a ton of work
To make them work
The same as in game
I think we're just
Going to be showing
Like names and levels
So it probably won't
Show the sockets
On the site
But you can know
That effectively
There's just certain
Eye levels
That the item is
When it does that
And then later on
We'll like improve
Support on the trade site
And get everything
Rendering exactly the same
As in game
And that'll be fine
But there certainly
Should be nothing
On the trade site
Which you know
You can't know
About something that's
Important for trade at least
Even to start with
Awesome
Quick follow up
On ascendancy questions
A lot of people
Ask me to ask
Regardless of the answer
Are we going to have
Like
Be able to see
The full ascendancies
Before launch
Good question
I
Don't know whether
That's in the spoiler list
Or not actually
What we're not
Going to have
Is like
Support for
On the website
Which we were
Planning on doing
Because we wanted
People to have
All that stuff there
But I think
We didn't quite
Get time to
Implement all that
Stuff on the website
To get that working
It's possible
We can still
Get them to post
The ascendancies early
I'll have to talk
To the community team
And see whether
Or not that's planned
We can probably
We might be able
To do that
Yeah I'll talk
To the community team
And see what
Their plan is for that
It is pretty much
A 50-50 by the way
On whether or not
People want that
Oh yeah a lot of
People don't want it
Right right
I think
We did show quite a lot
About their ascendancies
Already so like
In some ways
Just filling out
The remaining stuff
Yeah
So yeah
I think the argument
From people that do
Want it is that
Since it is like
A hard lock thing
They want to like
Have a little bit
Of info there
And obviously
Most people really
Are appreciating that
Like there's
We're going in blind
And that's pretty awesome
Sure sure
Fair enough
I'll talk to
The community team
And see how they
Feel about it
So yeah
We might do it
We might not
Maybe just throw up
A poll and see
What more people want
But yeah
Another question is
Is lowlife 50%?
No it's 35%
And it's actually
Back to how it used
To be
And the reason is
Because that was
Changed up to 50%
Mostly because of
All the reservation
Related stuff
In POE1
Which is not a concern
Anymore
So that means
Lowlife can be 35% again
And that restores
That to how it was before
Okay interesting
I was really curious
About that
And we were trying
To figure out
What it was
Cool
Force move
Is that something
That can be a keybind
Instead of taking up
A skill slot?
So it works the same way
As POE1
I guess that the
Thought behind
With that
Is just like
Most people probably
Want force move
On left click anyway
Right?
Not necessarily
I mean
I guess maybe not
Like I suppose
We could change that
But hang on
Can't you
Okay
So
Can't you change
Like
Because you know
The skillbinds
That are like
Control W
And stuff like that?
Yeah
Like you can
You can change those
To not be using
Control right?
Yes you can change
All your keybinds
The main issue
For a lot of people
Right now
Is
They would like to have
In just keybind settings
Force move
To be like
Whether you put it
On mouse button 1 or not
Right now
It's costing you
A skill slot
And we're already
A little bit
For some builds
Short on that
I would
I would have thought
That when you include
The control
Like they're more inconvenient
But like the control Q
Control W
That kind of stuff
Those ones
Like
Are you really using
All of those as well?
Because I feel like
You could just use
The like skill slot
10 or whatever
Whatever the last one is
Like at the end there
And then use that one
As your force move
And then just rebind it
To something that doesn't
Require prison control
And then if you do that
You should be able to use that
But like I mean
I guess there's no real reason
We couldn't change it
To not use a skill slot
Potentially but
I guess I figure that
It's not usually a problem
At the moment
If you're able to do that
A lot of people want that
For sure
Okay
Interesting
Well I mean look
I'll table it with the UI guys
And see if they want to do it then
Yeah
Also pretty small sample size
But I polled the people
Watching on Twitch right now
And 77% are saying
They do want to know
I actually thought it would be
More people against
Interesting
Yeah so
Do with that what you will
That's an interesting
Point to have
Yeah
Yeah curious
Right
I would like to hear
A little bit more
About towers
And like buffing
The maps
And like
Yeah yeah sure
If you can talk about that
A little bit
Because before
The vibe I was getting
As a player
It's felt
A little bit
Like synthesis like
Where I would be like
Trying really hard
To maximize
My area
And buffing it up
And that could
Maybe sound a little tedious
So yeah
I would love to hear you
Talk about towers more
Yeah so effectively
So you unlock towers
The towers are
There's quite a few around
So you can always like
And the radius
Is actually quite large
And what that means
Is that generally speaking
The amount of
Things that get added
Like the amount of breaches
For example
That you add
When you use a breach tablet
Generally speaking
You're going to be
Add
There's more in radius
That could receive the breach
Than the number that
Than the number
That it's going to be adding
Okay
So for that reason
Like
I know there was some concern
Like there was some concern
That we had initially
That like
Because you have to
Like run maps
To get to the tower
In the first place
You're effectively consuming
Some of the maps
You would have been able to use
You know
That would have gotten buffed
And that is true
But because the radius
Is so large
And because like
The number that will add
Of breaches
That might add
Might be like six or something
Or you know
Six, seven
Something like that
It means that
Generally speaking
There will always be more maps
In the radius
Even ones you haven't run yet
Than what you add
Okay
In terms of adding them
To overlapping stuff
Like
Because there's overlapping towers
You can still get a situation
Where
Like you want to try
And maximize this
Yeah
But
And yes
You can only add one
Use each tower one time
So effectively
Like you know
You want to
Find the tower
Like go to it
Add whatever mechanic
You're adding
Find some nearby towers
Potentially
If there are nearby ones
Use those as well
Like add them all
And then once you've done that
You get the overlapping radii
For the mods
And then
Then you run them
So effectively
It works like that
Okay
So yeah
I mean if you've got
Any specific questions
About it
I can certainly answer them
Well can you use towers
Multiple times?
No you can't
So just one time each
Honestly
It's hard
Because again
I haven't played
Which I love
I love that I haven't played
I would just like
Do you like it?
Like is it fun?
Like is it something
You're confident
That you think people will enjoy?
I mean
I think it's pretty fun
Yeah
But it's kind of like
Look it's one of those things
We'll just have to see
How it works in some ways
Like I
What we don't really know
Is like what the long term
Feel of it is
Like when you actually
Really ramp everything
To like max
And with
You know
Like
But
Like what's the steady state like
Once you've reached the like
Point of just grinding forever
And that I sort of
Have a hard time knowing
Like we
We haven't done
Like
The amount of time
We need to invest
To be able to really test that
Is like more than what we have
So it's kind of hard
For us to know that
But the actual
Just like when you just
Play it normally
Like it's cool
Like it does work well
And I'm enjoying that
The hard part
Yeah as I said
The hard part to know
Will be like
Once you've got infinite resources
And you can just like
You know
You've got as much
Will it feel bad then
And I'm not sure about that
I'm hoping not though
There are generic tablets
As well by the way
That don't
Relate to a specific mechanic
And those ones
Like add more general mods
That just sort of
Affect all maps
So that's another thing as well
Just so you know
So yeah yeah
So we've got that too
That's very fun
And I'm sure
I am sure that we're going
To be playing around a lot
With the mod pulls
And other things like this
And sort of like
You know
Like affecting the
Juicing experience
Is definitely something
That needs a lot more
Actual testing
To really know
Like how well that
How far that goes
And how well it works
So I'm sure
That will be an area
That receives heavy balance
As we're going through EA
Yeah
I mean that's the beauty
Of doing early access
I guess
I was yesterday
On a podcast
Called Dropped Frames
And
Ko and JP asked
Ezekiel
To make them a question
For today's podcast
That I said
I would ask them
And Ezekiel asked
Why was it a conscious choice
To make the game
More difficult than Pee Wee 1
So
See I guess I
Don't know that I would say
That the conscious choice
Was to make the game
More difficult
As the
Because that makes it sound
Like the goal
Is we're going to make
It more difficult
Whereas what the goal was
Was to make the combat
More engaging
And on some level
That did make the game
More difficult
But I wouldn't say
That was like
This is what we're
Setting out to do
If you know what I mean
It's like we're setting out
To make the combat good
And
To me at least
Good combat
Yeah
Involves some level of challenge
And so that's kind of
What you end up with
So yeah I guess
That's kind of what I
That's what it really
Comes down to
It's just yeah
Like that's just
It's a natural part of that
Cool
I think that yeah
I think that really
That's really what it is
Yeah
Engaging combat
That makes sense
A cat in the community asked
Will every attack
From rapid fire
Give stacks of tailwind
So it currently does
I know there was a discussion
Happening about this
One of the designers
Was unhappy about it
And so
I think that
I know there was
A discussion recently
That I haven't heard
The result of
About what's going on
With that
So I don't
I actually can't answer
What the final state
Will be because
Yeah I don't know
It depends on what
They went off and did
But yeah there was
A discussion about it
For sure
It was a balanced concern
That's what I know
Yeah
I think that's why
They were curious
I've seen a lot of
Theory crafting and stuff
Yeah
Yeah so we
We have a few more
Reddit questions here
I think we have
A few thousand questions
From Reddit
So I've just tried
Calling them
This was one I found
Very interesting
And it was
It's pretty rare
To see someone so motivated
After doing something
For so long
Can you talk about
What makes you so motivated
I guess for me
I just want to make
Like
I want to actually
Make a game I'm happy with
And
Until I've actually done that
I think I won't be happy
You know what I mean
Like I just want to keep going
Like I
I was
I was never fully happy
With PeeWee 1
There was always more to do
It's always like
You know like
We're still in a good place yet
And yeah
I just
I want to make that
Perfect action RPG
So
I'll
That's
I'll just keep going
Until I've achieved that
Right
And maybe that
Maybe that's impossible
To like make something
Really truly perfect
But like
I
I guess I'm just
Ultimately motivated
To fix things
Like I want
You know
I just want everything
To be perfect
And so
You know
The
We keep going
Until we get to that point
Which maybe is impossible
As far as I know
That's what's driving me really
Yeah
That's awesome
That's a great answer
I mean it's very
There's like
Talking to you as well
It's very fun
So it's
It's great
Keep it up
Next question
Is
Does hardcore
Still go to softcore
Yes
It works the same
As POE1
So
Effectively
I was thinking about
Actually starting
Softcore this time
But I could effectively
Just start playing
On hardcore
Die and just continue
On softcore then
Yeah
Absolutely
Okay
I'll do that then
Yeah sure
I mean
Hopefully that will happen
By the time you're
Like three areas in
Okay
But we'll see
We'll see
Damn
Alright
Oh wow
So
So like
Yeah
How hardcore
Vival do you think
It is for your first time
I think that would be
I think
I think it probably
Would really not be
Hardcore viable
Just because there's
Going to be mechanics
On bosses that you're
Going to need to learn
That being said
Look I mean
You can
With enough grinding
And like you know
If you're just
If you really over
Prepare for everything
Right
You obviously can be
Very
You know
You can
You can be successful
But yeah
Like if you're
Playing at a regular pace
Like you know
Bosses will kill you
Just due to like
You know
Learn the mechanics
Like there are
There are things
That are subtle
About them
And you know
You have to work them out
Or you know
Like obviously
Like you've never seen
Like everything
Is very well telegraphed
But like if you don't know
What is telegraphing
You know
Like until you've seen
The ability one time
You know
What I would say is
If you were like
Playing behind someone
And every single boss fight
You like watched a video
Of someone playing it first
Before you
Before you fought it
In hardcore
Yeah
I think you could probably
Do it that way
But where's the fun
On that right
Like you want to experience
All the stuff
For the first time yourself
So that I would say
You can do
So yeah
That's
I would say
Play softcore your first time
Or at least play hardcore
And die
And then play softcore
The rest
And you should be alright
Yeah
No I was actually
Like bouncing between
Which one I should do
And then it was finally
Ben that convinced me
That I should play softcore
Because of server issues
And I think that
Obviously
That is something
We're all concerned about
So
I have a feeling
Like if there are
Server issues
It probably won't be
That like
It's like lag server side
On the individual
Like on an individual
Instance
It's much more likely
To be like
Backend problems
Which like boot off
You know
100,000 people
Get booted off
Kind of thing
That's kind of
Like a different type
You know
Rather than like
A you know
Like oh it's just like
Just crappy performance
Like I would hope anyway
I mean you never really know
But like I just have a feeling
It was much more likely
To be those kinds of problems
Like the like
Horrible back end issue
That I have to get up
Before at 2am
To work out
Rather than the like
Just slow grind
Yeah
Hopefully we're able
To solve that issue
How confident are you feeling?
Um
Like
It's hard
Apparently not very
If I'm
Yeah
If I'm saying like that
The issue is
Is just like
You know
I really have no idea
How many people
Will turn up on day one
Like we can look
At supporter pack sales
And we can say like
Okay well there's at least
There's at least this number
But on day one
You know
We're not sure
And the other thing as well
Is that there are things like
What's console gonna be like
I just don't know
Really
Like how many people
Will turn up there
It's really hard to say
Um
The
Uh
Yeah
I
It's very hard to feel confidence
Even though we're doing
A bunch of testing
And things like that
Just because like
You know
As I said
It's a new game
You never know
What's gonna happen
Like
Launches are just like
Notorious
For like
Random issues
Right
And um
It's not for lack
Of people trying
Uh
To make sure
Like
You know
It's not like
We're like
Oh you know
Just cheaping out
On servers
Or something like that
Right
Like we
We will do our best
To get as much
As we can
But you just
It's
You just never know
Uh
What kind of
Random performance
Or should go wrong
And the
The sucky thing about it
Is like
You can make some
Really subtle mistakes
Somewhere
And it results
In like
A huge amount
Of chaos
For the players
Because like
You know
You go over
Some weird threshold
And you get
Some deadlock
Or some
Some
Some random thing
Happens
And it just
It just
Everything dies
And so
Yeah
That kind of stuff
Really sucks
Um
I just
Yeah
I really
I really hope
We can do well
I mean
The nice thing
Is at least
Is that
You know
It's all based
On POE1
Back and stuff
Like that's been
Tested to a
Pretty reasonable
Degree by this point
Yeah
You know
I think we can do okay
But in the other
On the other hand
We may get more players
Than what our back end
Has ever dealt with before
And I think it's very
Very likely at this point
That that will happen
Um
So uh
You know
As I said
You can never really know
I don't know if you're like
Have to be sharing a number
You're prepared for
But like
Um
Are you prepared for like
A million players for example
If that's something you're
Well a million
A million is how many
Uh
Is what we're prepared for
As far as instance capacity goes
Okay
Um
We also
Uh
Prepared to increase that
As well
Like in terms of just like
Talking to cloud vendors
And stuff like that
About like you know
What if we go over this
Like do we have a plan
For how we're gonna scale up
Like that kind of stuff
So a million is the capacity
That we'll have on day one
Uh
Like before we know
How many people we're gonna get
Um
And my hope is that that'll be enough
Cool
I'm pretty sure that that
I'm pretty sure we'll get it
In a million
I don't think it's gonna go
I think the chance of going above
A million is pretty low honestly
Um
But uh
You never know
Um
Uh
You never know
Yeah
I think as I said
I think the chance to go
Above that is pretty low
Um
Just because bear in mind
It is paid right
It's not like
Yeah
Like okay
Let me say this
On our full release
When it's free
Like I think the numbers
Will be much higher than a million
I think that's gonna be
Very very high
Um
Like absurdly high
But uh
For a paid
Uh
Early access
I think getting to a million
Would be a very good success
Um
Uh
Like that would be
That would be crazy
Um
But yet I think that we might be
On the way to it
For sure
Um
And uh
Yeah
As I said
Million is what we're
Because of the fact
That we're like
We want to make sure
We don't screw this up
A million is what we're getting
For instance capacity
When I say instance
By the way
I'm talking about
The actual servers
That individual players play on
As opposed to like
The back end
Which is like
Where all the
Um
You know
Which is the
The scaling challenge
That's much more
Hard to know
Cool
Now as far as like
Testing
Uh
Like
Like testing the back end
And making sure it can work
The hard part there
Is like
Can you simulate
Player numbers
Uh
Like
Correctly enough
To actually know
What's going on
So we've got
A synthetic test
That goes up to
1.6
1.6 million
In the back end
Before it falls over
Um
And we want to try
And improve that
To 2 million
Before we launch
Just so that we
Like can be like
Okay
But the thing is
Is that
That's a synthetic test
Right
Like we don't
Like we write a bot
That simulates
What a player does
But like
What if we're just
Wrong about that
And like people
You know
And there's all sorts
Of numbers
That you can play around
With like
How often do people
Change areas
And how often do people
Like how many items
Do people pick up
We don't really know
The numbers for that
Yeah
We can look at
PWE1
And we can kind of
Assume that they're similar
And we can try and
Kind of like get things
To like some kind of
Real world situation
But then it'll just be
Some other random thing
We don't even think about
That like players
End up doing
That we just don't even
That that can cause the issue
So um
Uh
The other thing as well
Is like
What if we just
Didn't like
Okay so sure
We wrote it to
To that many players
Like as a test
But uh
There could be like
Even more subtle elements
Like
Here's a random example
We did think about
But like um
Just to sort of
Give you an example
Of the kind of subtlety
That happens here
So um
We have processes
In the backend
Called instance managers
Which like deal with
Um
Uh
Like effectively
They just like know
Where all the instances
Are
Like all the game instances
And like if they
Fall over
You know like
If they
They're keeping track
Of them effectively
And um
The uh
We've got more than
One of these
But like
To know which one
To contact
You need to know
Like you need to have
Something to work out
Like what
What is the thing
That like
That will tell you
Like which instance manager
I should be talking to
Whenever I'm going to
Go to a new area
And so we shard this
Based on the
Um
The area
Yeah
The area index
And the thing that we
Realized uh
Recently was that like
When everyone plays
The game
Initially
They're all going to be
In the same area
Starting in uh
In what's called
G11
Which is like
The first area of the game
And then
A bunch of those people
Like there'll be a very
Similar amount of time
That people will take
To get from there
To the next area
Yeah
And so that means
That everyone will go
From there to like
The next area
And so that means like
All the load's going to be
On one of these
Instance managers
And then all the load's
Going to move to a
Different instance manager
If it's all going to
Happen at the same time
Which means there's
Actually like
The thing with having
More of these
Is like completely defeated
By just the way
That that will happen
On launch
And like that's not
Something that our load
Test would immediately
Notice because like
We kind of have to think
About how the actual
Players will actually
Be behaving on release
Day to be able to
See that kind of issue
So like that's what
We did think of
But like there could be
200 other things like
That that we didn't
Think of that like
You know could result
In problems and so
This is the kind of
Stuff that like you
Know as I said that
You just never expect
In the back end so
This is probably like
Way too much detail
And like I'm being
Way too general here
I love the transparency
It's really great
But okay but anyway
That's the kind of issue
So I'm hoping that
Whatever it is
Is like really obvious
Like whatever problem
We do run into
Is like really obvious
To us so we can
Just fix it
But it's because
The part that really
Sucks is like
The thing fell over
Like there's no crash
There's no like thing
It's just a bunch of
People got disconnected
There's no logs
There's nothing for us
To even latch onto
And that's like the
Really horrible type of
Issue that I really
Hope we don't run into
But yeah
You know I
You never know
We'll see what happens
I'm hoping it will be okay
Yeah I mean to be free
You could just do
A surprise launch
Right now
Then there will be
Like no one's expecting it
And just
Well there would be
Somehow I don't think
That's a good idea
So I guess what will be
Really interesting to see
Is how big do the queues get
On
Like I
Yeah
That could be scary
But I think it'll be okay
I think it'll be okay
I'm excited
I'm very hyped
Awesome
Thank you so much
For the transparency there
That was more in depth
Than I was expecting
And yeah
Love it
A question about
ExileCon
Are there going to be
More ExileCons
Will there be one
Before or after release
Like what's the vibe there
So we were actually
Originally planning to have
One next year
And
As it got closer
We were just like
Man
Do we really want to
Are we really
Really wanting to
Be having to deal
With another ExileCon
This close
Like it's
Like you know
We're pretty tired
It's a lot of work
I don't know if I can actually
And it is like a huge amount of work
So we're kind of like
You know what
We're not going to do one in 2025
So we'll think about the year after that
But
We
As I said
We actually originally
Had made a booking and everything
Of like the venue
And we were like
We were actually keen
But then
When we really looked at it
We were like
I worry that we're going to be
Like close to
Like to
Like if we're like
Really close to the release
At that point
When that would have been scheduled
That could just like
Just be really
Like too much load
On our studio
All at one time
Because running an ExileCon
Really is like
It is a crazy amount of work
For the whole studio
Like it's just a huge amount
Of stuff
So
Look
I am almost certain
We'll have another one
I just don't think
We're going to have
We're just not going to have one next year
Just because it's
It's going to be too much
Going on I think
For our studio
Because you know
It's really fun to run them
Like
Even though it's all that work
Like it is really fun to run them
And like having all the community
Like it's a huge
It's a really fun thing
And like
If we had infinite resources
Then having ExileCon
Right before the full release
Would be like
The most amazing
Marketing opportunity
Right
Like that would be great
But then the idea
Of having to do all of that
And also get the release out
At the same time
It's just like
It's just too much
I just don't think
We'd be able to do it
That makes sense
Makes sense
It's a lot of work
Question again
About bosses
Is every single boss
Going to be
You die once
And it's over
Like you know
You collect 300
Zesh Duelas
Blinters or whatever
Right right
So we had
We've actually had
Quite a lot of conversations
About this topic
With the 300 splinters
Thing just to
By the way
It's like
They do come in stacks
So it's not like
You have to fight
300 breaches to do that
But
This was definitely
A question
Should we allow
More portals
For some of these bosses
Because like
You know
It's like the first time
That you save up
The first time
You're going to fight it
And then you just
Die instantly to some ability
And like
Is that okay
And
There were definitely
Some arguments about this
But we eventually
Decided that
Yeah
We are going to leave it
As one death
For those bosses
Just because
We just want to make sure
That there's integrity
In the
You know
Like in the boss fight
That you actually
Like did actually
Have to kill it
From top to bottom
It is one of those things
Though that like
If
It really was a problem
I guess we could
Readdress it
But like
I think we're pretty keen
To go with just one death
Even for those
For the time being
Cool
But yes
Yeah
Very interesting
There was a lot of
Argument about it for sure
Yeah I mean
Obviously like
I'm going to be
Hardcore hopefully
Most of the time
Once I figure the game out
So I was just
Mostly asking for
Softcore players
I'll be very curious
How they feel about it
Cool
Okay another question
How do you feel
About safe mechanics
Like Toda
Like obviously
RuneScape is probably
The game that comes to mind
Where you can
Very very much
More than any game
I can think of
Tailor
Exactly what type of content
You want to be doing
Right
Like
If you want to
You can do completely
Safe content
Or you can focus
On like a really hard
Boss fight
Where it takes
All of your focus
So yeah
What are your thoughts
On like being able
To tailor your custom content
So I mean
I would say that
PoE is pretty strong
In this regard as well
Right
Like you've got the ability
To change the degree
To which like
How many mods
You put on maps
And then like
How much you're juicing
Things with mechanics
For the towers
And all sorts of stuff
Like that
So I would say
That PoE is one of the games
Where you do actually
Have quite a lot of control
So like you can definitely
Get like look
If you're running a white map
There's not a huge amount
That's just going to
Randomly kill you
If you're like
If you're powerful enough
To deal with that
You should be okay
It really is the other
Like the other extra difficulty
You add
That makes it so that
You're
So that you're more
That you're more safe
And like especially now
That the bosses
Have been moved out
Of the regular map
So that you've
Like you can choose
Whether you're doing them
Or not
Like you have
Even that choice as well
So yeah
I'm a fan of
Tailoring content difficulty
And that is the goal
For us as well
Right
Just like make sure
That you can
You can decide that
Awesome
Yeah
No me too
I'm a big fan of that
Very cool
So talking about
Playing hardcore
And pausing and stuff
So let's say that
I've opened an expensive
Boss fight
It took me a while to farm
And I'm halfway
Through the fight
And I'm like
Oh this is not going well
This is not going down well
But I don't want to leave either
Can I pause the fight
And be like
Steel mage
I need help
Right now
Please come get me
And can he then like
While
While I'm paused
Can you come help me
So
I
Okay so
Currently
You actually can't
Like do things
Like accept invites
And everything
While you're paused
Now we actually had planned
We actually had planned
To allow you to do
Way more stuff while paused
There was this whole
Pause rework we were going to do
We were going to change the interface
You can pause the game
And still be able to like
Look at the rest of the interface
And like kind of
Do certain things
While paused or not
And then we could just
Make the decision of like
What's allowed when paused
And what isn't
Yeah
But we never got it
We unfortunately didn't get time
To do it
So right now
The
You wouldn't be able to
Accept a challenge while paused
But that being said
You could like pause the game
Message your friend
He sends you an invite
You unpause quickly
Click accept
And then pause again
Right like it is kind of possible
Right
And so there's kind of
Really no reason to like
Not allow you to accept
An invite while paused
For that reason
Because like you can
Just kind of do that
So like that would be possible
Cool
And ultimately
That would mean
That you can kind of do that
The question then is like
Can you get to the person
In a fight
And that depends on the context
Yeah
Now I don't actually know
100% of all the rules
About this
About exactly what goes on
I believe that when you
Seeshell to someone
As the players call it
That it's
The
That you go to the
Checkpoint of the last
Like you go to the
Physical location of the
Most recent checkpoint
The player has
Yeah
And then from there
You can go into the boss fight
So during campaign
You can certainly
Just like get into
Someone's boss fight
Very easily
Yeah
What I don't know is
Is what the situation is
With regard to maps
And exactly how that works
So I would have to check on that
To work out exactly
What you could do there
Yeah
I am sure there's going to be
All sorts of like exploits
And like random issues
Around pausing
And checkpoints as well
And like all of those things
Like I just have a feeling
That there's going to be
Stuff like we obviously
Do our best to think of these
But I'm sure there's going to be
Some stuff
So there might have to be
Some tweaks to the rules
Later on here
But as far as I know
You can do that
Like I believe
So I'm pretty sure
What should happen
Is I think that for maps
The last checkpoint
Is like still in the map room
Yeah
Because there's no checkpoints
In maps
So I'm pretty sure
What would happen is
Is they'd go outside the map
They would be standing
Where the portals are
And if there's a portal available
They'll be able to go
Through that portal
And so if you moved the portal
Close to the boss fight
Before you went into it
Because you can't use the portal
While in the boss fight
Then that would mean
They'd be outside the boss fight
And so long as there's a way
To get into the boss fight
After the fact
It should work
So as far as I know
That should be how it works
At the moment
But as I said
There might be individual rules
That we can add
Or remove or whatever
Like there'll probably be
Tweaks to this I'm sure
Cool
Also chat really wants me
To correct you
And say we call it swirly
What?
Okay
For some reason
People around here
Call them seashells
Seashelling
Right
I don't know where that
Maybe that's just
In GGG slang for this
That's funny
Yeah I mean
Apparently it looks like a seashell
That is really cool
Though I'm obviously
A little bit biased
Like I would love to run
Like a boss service
Where I'm like
Coming to rescue people
So
That'd be very fun
Well as far as I know
That should be possible
Right now
But as I said
We might tweak the rules
Cool
A little bit of like
A more random cutesy question
With
How do you feel about
Like mini games
Like fishing
Or just like
Things to do that
Aren't necessarily
Like the core game
I don't know
Like
Some people find that stuff fun
Maybe
I mean I guess
I see the mini games
In POE
As more like
The different league mechanics
So you know
Like
Those are the things
That we're probably
More likely to add
But you know
I know people have been
Wanting a fishing mini game
For a long time
I guess
Look we have boat support now
Right
I know
Like from the hideout
So you know
You never know I guess
Cool
Two factor authentication
Is that something
We can see improvements of
In POE too
So
This is one of those things
Where like
It's trivially easy
To add two factor authentication
The hard part is
All the support policy
Around
What happens when people
Lose their second factor
And
It's like
Like
Okay
So like
How do you verify someone
Who's lost their second factor
And then like
That's a whole thing
That's all
Drama around this
And then like
You open yourself up
To like
All sorts of like
Support mistakes
You could be making
With that kind of stuff
And like
It's notoriously
That you have
So this thing
And then people say
Oh
You should just tell people
That if they had two factor
Then if they had the second factor
They're just
They're just hosed
And it's like
Well you can say that now
You say that right up
To the point
You do lose your second factor
And then you're like
Why is there no recovery process
For this
You know what I mean
Like
There has to be a recovery process
And then
It's like
Okay
So then how do we verify it
So then people are like
Oh you know
You could like
Take government ID
And it's like
Okay well now there's like
GDPR and privacy implications
Of this
And it's like
It's just kind of
An endless rabbit hole
Of like
Random policy
And horrible stuff
And so
Like
We should have it right
Like absolutely
We should 100%
We should have two factor
We just don't
And it's all because of that
Like the tricky stuff
Around this
And like one day
I just have no doubt
We will implement this
But
Yeah
It's just
We just need to dig ourselves
Out of the hole
Of all the policy issues
Around support for this
That's the thing
And so
What I will say though
Is just as a thing
Is that you can
Effectively outsource
The two factor
On your account
By using Steam
If you want
Because they have two factor
And if Steam
Is the only
Login method
On your account
Then effectively
You're just relying
On their two factors
To be able to
To work
So you still have
That option at least
But yeah
We should add two factors
To the regular login system
And I want to add two factors
It's just a question
Of getting time
To sort through
All the problems with it
Speaking of
Regular login system
I can't remember
If this was already confirmed
But do we still have
Both the standalone client
And Steam?
Yep
Okay
Excellent
Another community question
So there is a limit
Of support gems
Right?
I can only use
Element control destruction
On one gem
I can't use it on two gems
Correct
Is that rule still the same
On my weapon swap?
Let's say that I have
A lightning ability
In one weapon swap
And a cold ability
In the other
But on both of these
Main gems
I want to use
Control destruction
So the
There's one per character
It doesn't relate
To weapon swap
Because the thing
That I just want to
Clarify around this
Is that like
It's not like
You've got slots
That are just like
One versus the other
Right?
Like when you look
At your skill screen
They're all just
On one screen
That you just get
To enable or disable
Certain skills
For being used
By a certain weapon swap
So there's no like
Like yeah
As far as the question goes
Like it is one
For the entire character
When we saw
Like videos
Somebody had a video
Going through the settings
And stuff like that
And I did not see
Lockstep or predictive
Being there
Is that still a thing?
Why wouldn't it have
Been there?
It should have been there
Okay so
Apparently it's only
In the menu screen
Oh yeah yeah yeah
Because you can't
Change it while you're
In game
But yeah
It should be there
As far as I know
One thing I will say
Is that predictive
With WSD
Sorry not
Predictive
Okay let me get this right
Okay so
There is a mode
Called hybrid
And I think
That with WSD
Predictive turns
Into hybrid
But I'm not sure
Whether or not
They've actually
Fiddled around
With the interface
Of this
Hybrid is the mode
That consoles use
But I don't think
It tells you about it
Because I don't think
There's a setting
For it in consoles
But effectively
What that is
It's somewhere in between
Predictive and lockstep
I guess I could
And effectively
What it is
Is that
This is kind of irrelevant
But
Effectively
With lockstep
When there's lag
Internet lag
The whole game freezes
And with predictive
When there's internet
Lag
The game does not
Freeze
Hybrid is a mode
Where we still
Use predictive
Networking
But we still
Freeze everything
When the server
Hasn't replied to you
And that's just
Because it keeps
Everything sync
A little bit better
But prevents
And prevents some
Of the issues
That you get in predictive
And that mode
Just works a bit better
When you're using
Direct control
WSD
And stuff
Without causing
Too many
Desync issues
So that's just
A random detail there
But yeah
As far as I know
They still work
And they should be
Fine
What I worry about
And this is just
Random speculation
On my part
Is that like
Pretty much everyone
In GGG plays in lockstep
Yeah
And so what that means
Is that like
I worry that there won't
Be as much testing
In predictive
And there could be like
Issues that happen
In predictive
That we're just not aware of
Because of the fact
That like everyone's
Just playing in lockstep
All the time
So it probably
Hasn't received
The same testing
As what lockstep gets
So I would suggest
To you
You play in lockstep
If you can
Obviously the issue
Is when your latency
Is high
But yeah
That's the sort of stuff
That I'm sure
We'll get more testing
As we go into early access
As well
But yeah
Just a random thing
A question I just thought of
Was in Peewee 1
A thing that can happen
Is
Assets loading
And being invisible
If they were already
Loading ones
Is that a fixed thing
In Peewee 2
Unfortunately
That's not fixed
And this is something
That really really
Bothers me
But look
It's something that
We're going to be
Like we
We do
We
I really want to fix that
I really
Really want to fix it
Like it's
It's the worst thing
To me
Is that
Is that occurring
So we'll get to the point
Where that can occur
It's actually been made
Harder in Peewee 2
Because of the fact
The assets are larger
In general
You know
Like higher resolution
Textures
And higher resolution
Like models
And stuff like that
So I don't think
It will necessarily
Be worse or anything
But yeah
It sucks
It really sucks to me
Whenever a thing
Doesn't load
And so
This is a thing
That we will be working on
And improving
Over time
I want to get to the point
Where it's just 100%
The case
That you never see
An asset pop
Like that
That would be ideal
Awesome
Yeah
But we'll work
Towards that
But we aren't there yet
Cool
A lot of people
Are asking about
Pre-download
Being
Especially for people
With slow connections
Being able to
Start downloading
The files
Before the 6th
So the concern
There
Is
Would be
What do you call it
Data mining
Yeah
That's the concern
With that
My question is
Pre-download
Slash data mining
Yeah
I'll
Like
We're
Definitely more
Vulnerable to data mining
For POE 2
Than we are in POE 1
Usually
Just because
You know
Like there's so much
More new stuff
Like just
The whole campaign
Being something
People haven't played
Yeah
You know
So like
It's
That
That would be the concern
I guess
I do understand
Why you'd want this though
So
I'll
I guess I'll just have to
Talk to
I guess I just have to talk
And see how we feel about it
Like yeah
The concern is data mining though
That would be the reason
Not to do it
So
Yeah
That would be
That
That's really the issue
Yeah
I'm a big fan of
Like that
That it hasn't been
Datamined yet
At least
I love that
Right
It will be interesting
To see how fast
The data mining occurs
Like
Obviously
When you've got a thing
Like this
Like a lot of people
Now
We do have some stuff
To improve
The
Like
Certain
Certain things
Will be harder to data mine
Than they were in the past
But on the other hand
There are some things
The client just has to have
And if the client has to have it
Then there's just no way
To prevent data mining of it
Because like
You know
It has to be on the client
For the client
To be able to see
A mod on the client
The client has to have
The text of the mod
Right
Yeah
So on some level
You've got to have that stuff
So yeah
Cool
Makes sense
Is rarity multiplicative
Or additive
With a map
Slash monster rarity
I
You mean
So player rarity
Yeah
Player rarity is multiplicative
With the map rarity
Yeah
So that's still the case
Right
Yeah
A question about
What like
What leagues are
Because obviously
We are still going to have
Leagues in PeeWee 2
What are they going to be
Based around
Right now
They're being inspired
By other games
Is that still going to be
The case
Oh I mean
That's always the case
Right
We're always looking
At other mechanics
I mean ultimately
It comes down to
What is cool
And so that means
That all we're really doing
When we're looking
At other games
Is like
Is there something
We can notice here
That could inspire us
To be cool
But like
It doesn't have to be
Another game
It could be a movie
Or like
Some random other thing
Like you never know
Where the inspiration
Is going to come from
But yeah
That stuff can definitely
Happen
Just you know
Can we come up
With a cool mechanic
That's all it comes down to
Yeah
Is there any game
Off the top of your head
That you're like
Oh
Do we really like
Want to find a way
To like get this in PeeWee
That like inspires you
I don't know
That I can name one
Right now
If we
Like it's like
Anything that would
Have happened like that
We probably already
Made a leak for it
Yeah
So it would have to
Be something recent
And we haven't been
Talking about leagues
In PeeWee 2 yet
So we haven't had
Like a brainstorming session
About that yet
Yeah
So yeah
I don't think
I can come up
With one at the moment
Awesome
And
That's pretty much
The final question here
I kind of tried
To avoid open-ended questions
But
Is there any
Particularly large
Engine changes
With PeeWee 2
That allows you
To do something
That you've always
Wanted to do in PeeWee 1
But you weren't able to
So most of the changes
Like engine wise
Have actually
Are actually on
PeeWee 1's engine
Because we wanted to
Merge them so that
We can make all the
Assets transfer
Yeah
Probably one of the
Largest changes
That is different
Between PeeWee 1 and 2
Is the global
Elimination system
And
What that kind of
Means is that
So like
Any
And this was
Like we had
G.I. in PeeWee 1 as well
But it kind of
Works differently
So like
Effectively
The nice thing
That you can do
With a really good G.I.
Is that you can
Light objects
Without having to
Actually place lights
In them
Like they just get lit
By the glowing parts
And so you just get
A really nice
Like soft form of
Lighting from certain
Things
And
Certain areas
Can actually be lit
Entirely with
The G.I. system
Which is just really nice
Like you get the ability
To do some lighting
That's just really
Quite different than
What PeeWee 1
Has been capable of
So yeah
Like that's pretty cool
I'm trying to think
If there's anything else
That like we didn't
Actually port over
But not really
Like because we've
Tried to get everything
As much as possible
To be the same
Just for asset portability
So
Oh there's quite a lot
Of stuff to do with
Like
One of the engine
Features we have
Is the ability to read
The
This is like real
Technical stuff
But
To read the material
That's on the ground
And use that
In the shader
Of a thing
That's sitting on top
Yeah
And that lets you
Do things like
For example
We use that in the
You know the bear
The bear slam
When the bear does a slam
Like the actual ground
That's under the bear
Like the chunks of rubble
That come up
Are like
Red from the ground
That's actually there
So that kind of like
Fits to the area
So that's kind of cool
That's very cool
And
There's a few
That's actually used
Quite a lot
Like in more subtle ways
The bear is like
Really obvious
Because it's like
Big chunks of terrain
That kind of
Come up
So that's like
Another one
What's another one
That's like
PoE2 only
I'm not sure
As I said
Most of the things
Get moved over
Like I mean look
One of the things
That's been
That's gone on generally
Is that all of the
Like
We've upgraded the
So we used to use
In PoE1
Originally a like
CPU based particle system
And then
For most of
PoE2's development
We've had this like
GPU based particle system
And that just means
That the particles
Can look way nicer
And like that is
Available in PoE1
But it's just like
All those assets
Were made like
A long time ago
Right
So they all use
The old system
So like just what
We're doing with
Particle systems now
Is just like way cooler
In my opinion
Like just like
A lot of the
There's stuff like
Like the particles
Will respond to like
Wind in the environment
So like
If you have like
Explosions
You can have like
Wind events on the
Explosions that will
Cause like other
Particles that are
Around to just get
Pushed away
And stuff like that
Like there's just
Like little cool
Things like that
Awesome
I don't know
There's just like
There's nice little
Touches
But as I said
All that stuff is
Theorically available
In PoE1
It would require us
Like redoing a bunch
Of effects to actually
Take advantage of it
So yeah
Probably some of the
Newer stuff in the
Leagues probably does
But yeah
Most of the stuff
Isn't that
Yeah
Hopefully that answers
Some of those questions
No that was great
Actually I thought of
Another thing
Guild tabs
Guilds are not
Transferring over to
PoE2
What about
Guild stash tabs
So because of the
Fact the guild isn't
It means the stash tabs
Aren't either
And that's kind of
Unfortunate because I
Would want that to
Happen
But in order to
The guilds just
Aren't integrated
Across both games
So therefore
Because one guild
Owns the tab
And that guild
Isn't across
Like therefore
The tabs are where
They are
And as I said
That's really not
A like policy decision
It's just a kind
Of technical decision
So I suppose
In order to fix that
We'd have to merge
The guilds of PoE1
And 2
And like I wouldn't
Even be against
That idea
It just requires
More work than
What we have time
To do unfortunately
So the answer is
Basically we will
Have to buy the
Stash tabs again right
You will for that
Yes unfortunately
But as I said
I just wish that
Wasn't the case
But it just is
Unfortunately just
Due to the way
That we couldn't
Get the kills managed
No that's fine
Sarah
Is PoE Mobile
Still being worked on?
It's not being worked on
Right now
Like we
Put it on hold
When we
Like as we realized
That we needed
The resources
And effectively
The people who
Were working on that
They then
Were the ones
Who then were
Taking over
The console
Interface
For PoE2
So what that meant
Was that we suddenly
Had a team
That could actually
Like you know
Work on all that stuff
And like you know
Do all the work
That we need to do
For console
So the intention
Would be that
When we get to the
Point of like
Feeling comfortable
With like PoE2
Is fine
Like all the
All the interface
Stuff is like
All resolved
Like you know
We're out of
Early access
We're kind of
Like everything's good
Then we'd be keen
To restart the
Console version
Sorry the mobile
Version again
But for the time
Being we're not
Working on it
And yeah
We'll just have to
Get to the point
Where like feel
Okay yeah
The console version
Of PoE2
Is like
Is good enough
That we can get
Some of the resources
And move them over again
Awesome
I don't know if
The last one's like
A question
I just want to
Throw my hat in the
Oh my god
Please let us mute
Other player sounds
I hate the goblin troops
I want to throw my hat
In that
Okay
So much
Understood
Yeah understood
I'll talk to you
I'll talk to them about it
Awesome
That was pretty much
All the questions I had
Like thank you so much
Like we are a few days
Out for launch
And you're taking time
To do this
We all
The community
Super appreciate it
Yeah
Thank you so much
And we're very excited
To play PoE2
When it comes out
Yeah
Awesome
Well thank you very much
For you know
Giving me a chance
To talk to you guys again
It's always fun
Awesome
Yeah
Thank you so much
And yeah
For everybody watching
Both YouTube and Twitch
All right
Try to die
See you later guys
Awesome
All right
Bye
Thank you so much
Thank you
Bye
No problem
All right
I've got someone to
I have to go
Shut off the stream myself
I guess
All right
No that's not good
Thank you
Bye
All right
Thank you
Bye
Awesome
There it is chat
There it is
That went pretty well
I hope I didn't cough too much
I'm still pretty sick
But my fever's mostly gone
Ah
I hate being sick
Oh
Man
It's so like
It's so split
Whenever I ask a question
There's like
Some people like
That's the dumbest
Fucking question
I've ever heard
And some people are like
That's amazing
And I'm like
I guess that means
They're good questions
If they're equally
Like representing
And not representing
People
I also feel like
A lot of people are like
Thinking like
All the questions
Are from me
But like
Most of these questions
Are from other people
I had like four
From me
Hopefully
Hopefully you like them
Ah
Your questions were
Ultra good
Thank you
Here are my goblin troops
Now fuck your goblin troops
Oh
That was great
Do you feel satisfied?
Yeah
I mean we've already had
A lot of
We've already had
A lot of good
Interviews
In my opinion
Every person's interview
Is good
Because you get
Such a different approach
I know I've seen
Like
Every person that does
The interview
Gets some form of backlash
But I love that
They do so many
Different interviews
Because you
You get so many
Insights in different
Parts of the community
So I love that
They do multiple
And not just one
I think it's
It's really good
And thank you so much
For all the subs and resubs
I super appreciate that
Super super appreciate that
He's doing so many interviews
Yeah
It's crazy good
No preload
Second message to DL
No
Oh that is such a big W
By the way
I'm biased
Because I don't have
A dog shit connection
But such a big W
In my opinion
Do pre-download
Like three hours ahead
Or six hours ahead
I hate
Data mining
But I'm biased
I mean we're all biased
Right we're all biased
To our situation
What's your opinion
On the leaked walkthrough
By Fextra Life
Oh I mean
I fucking hate
Fextra Life
I agree with Lily
Who posted a very
Based tweet
Saying there's
Scourge on gaming
As a whole
Or a blight
I think the blight
Was what she said
Um
It's like
If it was only
That they've done
Like five
Or six shady things
That's fine
But it's like
Ten plus
And it's like
At some point
People should stop
Giving them
Any opportunities
This is actually
Mad yeah
Just cause of the
Embed thing
No it's just so many things
The embed thing
Is definitely
A big part of it
Uh I think
Fextra Life
Gets a lot of hate
But I personally
Think they don't
Get enough
I agree
Salty Dane
Um
I've heard
So many
Slimy things
From them
From like
Actual companies
Too
So like
I just
I really
Dislike them
Fextra Life
If you're reading
This
Ignore the
Positive comments
Based
Hope you feel better
Yeah I'm
I'm a lot better now
That's a lot of people
That tuned in
Man some guy posted
During that on YouTube
Like he's ignoring
YouTube chat
It's like
Brother
Like what
Oh shit
So
So annoying
It's like
I'm ignoring
All of you equally
That's really cool though
Like 18,000
Or something on Twitch
And like 13
Or 14 on YouTube
Thanks for the amazing interview
Yeah I hope I did okay
Somebody was asking
Like why is he not prepared more
And I was like
I felt super prepared
I'm just sick
Like huh
I prepared so much
Like a big spreadsheet
I even prepared
Follow up questions
Uh
Five person
Called that person dumb
Yeah that's good
You did great
Thanks
Thanks for asking
About kilts
I wasn't going to
That was really far
Down the list
Um
I was
I had set aside
More time
To talk about
Ascendancies
Um
But it didn't feel
That useful
To talk about more
Other than you know
Express my discontent
When he hadn't really
Changed his mind
Or thought about it more
Um
Yeah he didn't
He didn't want to
Talk about it
It seemed like
So I
I didn't really want to
Push that
If that makes sense
Um
When he hadn't had time
To talk about it
Since last
Think about it
Since last time
Double your rarity
Question
Now is another thing
I wasn't going to ask
I mean
Most of the
10-15 things
At the end
Were things
I hadn't planned
On asking
Um
I praise you
For asking about goblins
I fucking hate goblins
Dude
Like the force and clip
Does anyone have
The force and clip
This is why
I asked about goblins
Someone link the force and clip
And I know
This is not everybody's experience
But I want to show off
The force and clip
Why is fuck
Getting censored
I love fuck
Ah
Perfect
I
I would probably just
Show this to Jonathan
As to why
I hate
The goblins
Oh my god
Uh
Was there one
I don't have the waypoint there
What
Is this important
For the quest
Oh I'm level 20
Ah
I'm level 20
Now
I
I do see the humor in this
I think it's funny
But I play this game
Too much
To want this
In my fucking game
Imagine sitting there
Trying to listen to lore
For the people
That care about that
Like fuck me dude
And I know
That this is a more
Extreme version
Because it is forcing
It is
But holy fuck dude
Who did that to you?
Oh
I play hardcore
I'm entirely
Unaffected by this
There is one other person
That plays hardcore
On the same server
That I do
Right
Cause it's spread out
With like Milan
Paris
London
So it's not a me problem
This is definitely
Something I'm asking
For the community
Right
No it is me and Steel
On the server we play on
It's just
A very cancerous
Dude
I love
How candid they are
In interviews
And again
Thank you so much
For all the subs
And resubs
I super appreciate it
The clip you watched
Is in hardcore SSF
By the way
Yes
But I would still argue
That it is more of a
Selfcore trade experience
Because those people
Are doing that
Because it is forcing
If that was any other player
That town would not
Look like that
So
Are you playing
Peewee to hardcore
From the beginning?
Yeah I mean
There's no reason not to
I'm going to start by
I'm absolutely like
Continuing on software
When I die
I'm continuing on software
I'm doing a key giveaway
On twitter by the way
We'll do some key giveaways
Honestly
Is Vyro still here?
Vyro can you do giveaways
For me?
If so
Should we give away
Some keys now?
We could give away
Some keys now
On twitch
There is a key
Giveaway on twitter
Honestly
I just saw that
That it's just too easy
To farm
Interactions
On twitter
By giving away
For a few keys
And I was like
Fuck that
I'm dumb not to do this
So
But we'll just give away
Some in twitch
Tattoo I think
Is Vyro here?
I was just like
I saw somebody
Got like 6,000 likes
For two keys
And I'm like
The fuck?
I'm gonna throw up
Five keys
Fuck all y'all
I was like
Huh?
That's fucking stupid
They said
Give me five minutes
Okay cool
We're gonna give away
Some keys here
Honestly
We're gonna give away
A bunch of keys
I think we have like
20 to give away
I don't know if we'll
Give them all away now
Who cares about likes?
I mean
I do
It's cringe
But like
Realistically
The more people
Interact with me
In any space
The better for me
As a content creator
It is sadly my job
To farm interactions
I generally try to do that
In a positive way
And not like a cringe way
This is definitely
More on the cringe side
I do realize that
But you know
It is what it is
As far as cringe goes
I think
It's pretty limited
Compared to like
Rage bait
And stuff like that
Now
We don't
Like
People always ask
Is he ignoring
YouTube chat?
No
But YouTube chat
Will definitely be
Fucked by giveaways
I realistically
Don't have a way
To include
YouTube giveaways
So you do actually
Get fucked here YouTube
I'm so sorry
You do actually
Get fucked here
But I do read you
We're trying to get
Like a good way
For this subathon
To work on YouTube
I've seen a lot
Of other content creators
That are just going to
Ignore YouTube
I don't really want
To ignore YouTube
Get fucked YouTube
Oh my god
Luality was giving me
Advice yesterday
So I'm doing
Baldur's Gate 3
Honor mode
And she was
Molding when she
Saw my gear
Because I'm level 10
And I had like
A medium breastplate
On my Gloomstalker
And she was like
What the actual fuck
She was having a full on
Meltdown
And she was like
Half your gear
Doesn't fucking do anything
It was like a Sunday roast
She was literally
Like molding
She
She like linked me
A gif
Of how she felt
Luality was like
This
This is my reaction
To your fucking gear
She was like
So bad
9,000 YouTube viewers
I know
I mean I do try to be
Pretty respectful
To my YouTube audience
It's just
Twitch ads are predatory
YouTube almost too
So the Twitch ads
At least for my channel
I don't disagree with you
By the way
It's why I use Turbo
But the Twitch ads
Are always entirely
Run by the streamer
Except for channels
That don't run ads
Then you'll get
First pre-rolls
But like when
Streamers are saying
Oh Twitch are going
Really hard on ads
They are lying
There is a streamer
Like anytime you get
An ad on Twitch
It's just me
Running the ad for you
It's just most people
Lie about it
So I run three minutes
An hour on Twitch
And I try to time
That really well
With like
I'll never do it
In the middle of a
Boss fight
Or anything like that
It's just completely
Out of my hands
I just really like money
So I try to be
Really careful
About how I run ads
Like for example
Before this podcast
I actually ran
Technically nine minutes
Of ads right before
The podcast started
And then we didn't
Have any ads
In the middle of the podcast
So at least for my channel
I very much curate
How I run ads
Like accidents do happen
Where I fuck you over
By accident
It is still me doing it
Except when I use
All five minute delays
And then forget
It's Twitch's fault
Then it's Twitch's fault
Yeah
I mean you do run out
Of delays
I can just like
Quickly show you
How it looks
From my end
So I have it
On an automatic timer
So this plays
Three minutes per hour
And then I see here
That in 37 minutes
Ads are gonna start
And click snooze
And then I have
Three snoozes
So basically this choice
To keep me right
For three minutes an hour
That's like the sweet spot
For making money
So ads are a pain
But like I like
Making money from what I do
So it is what it is
You can also like
Sub if you really hate it
That podcast was for
Drop frames
No drop frames
It was yesterday
It does disable pre-rolls
For narrowing
Send to a narrow relay
See if that works
Okay so we are going to
Try to do
A key giveaway
How many keys
Do we have to give away
How many do you want to do
How many do we have
We have 700
I'm just kidding
You didn't say that
I imagine though
Where's browser source
Key giveaway
How about 11,000
I wish I had that many
You know what
Fuck it
How about
We do a big one
We do like seven keys
Right now dude
Let's see
If this works
It might
Now this will not work
On YouTube sadly
So you will have to
Fuck over onto Twitch
Because it only reads
The Twitch chat
And obviously there will be
People not realizing that
And we'll spam whatever
The thing will be on YouTube
But we'll give away
Seven keys right now
There should be a key giveaway
That'll pop up
And again I'm so sorry