The End
Sir, just what are we facing here?
A relic of the old world.
Ready your men, Captain.
We will only get one chance.
And remember, when you hear the whispers, call for help.
Do not attack!
When you hear the whispers, what do you think he was on about?
It's Dorman, right?
Uh, yeah.
Then Dorman. Shut your damn mouth.
Why do I always get stuck with these rookies?
Hey, the kid's got a mean cleave. Give him a chance.
Quiet!
Come on.
Leave, eh, Captain?
A rookie can't even lift his own sword.
Captain Oren?
Captain?
It's here.
Rain! Send the signal!
What the fuck?
Rain!
On my back, we'll be laid off!
Come on, come on!
I'm ready!
It's a man!
No.
It's not!
Run!
Captain!
It is over!
Why are you here?
Captain!
It is over!
Why are you here?
What is this?
Stop!
Humanity isn't ready.
On your feet, lad.
Sir, the captain, I...
You'll be fine.
Here.
What is this?
Get the body.
Stop.
Murder.
It can still be contained.
You don't know what you have unleashed.
Your kind no longer control this world.
We cannot destroy your body, it's true.
But you will watch as we destroy everything you have built.
Bind him!
Feed.
Grow, my child.
I'll make sure you can eat your food.
Hi.
I'm Jonathan Rogers, game director on Path of Exile 2.
Now, Path of Exile 2 is going into early access in around two weeks on December the 6th.
But even though it's early access, this isn't just some small taste.
The game is huge.
In this live stream, we're going to be introducing everything you can expect.
So without further ado, let's roll the gameplay trailer.
Existence is a thing of beauty.
Precious, but impermanent.
Life and death are mortal enemies, and yet bound to one another.
The continuation of life must be protected at all costs.
Some have said, my methods are brutal.
To this I say, there can be no salvation without sacrifice.
To this I say, there's no salvation without sacrifice.
Back to death are principalTS andmen in the air.
We are faced with the end, and I will do what I must.
I must, but they're okay with my methods.
Those who obsess with death
Let them soon be acquainted with it.
Now as you just saw, even in Early Access, Path of Exile 2 is a big game.
It's actually been five years since we announced PoE 2, and over that time we've revealed a lot, but it's been in bits and pieces.
It's pretty hard to keep track of it all, so today we're going to do a full rundown of all the content that will be available at the start of Early Access.
Classes, character progression systems, and for the first time, a full overview of the end game.
This is going to be a big one, so get comfortable.
For 20 years, Rhaeclast has been free from any sources of corruption.
But the Count of Ogham, tempted by promises of power, intends to harness it once more.
The dead are rising, monsters are mutating, and madness is spreading.
Under the dark influence of corruption, the Count doles out sentences of death to any who would question him.
And this is where you find yourself at the start of PoE 2.
Explore the dark forests of Ogham, traverse the barren plains of the Vesteri Desert, and delve into the jungle ruins of Utsal, an ancient Vaal city.
There are challenging monsters, hidden runes, lost camps and treasures, roaming merchants, and of course, unique bosses.
No two areas are the same.
It falls to you to track down the seed of corruption, the source of all this devastation.
On the way, you'll face fearsome monsters, meet strange characters, forge unlikely bonds, and uncover lost civilizations.
But first, you'll need to pick a class.
Now, Early Access will initially have six classes available.
Let's have a look at them.
The Monk is a fast and furious melee fighter.
He dashes in and out of combat, and has mechanics that involve building up and keeping momentum.
Like all classes in PoE 2, you'll want to use a wide variety of skills to mix and match different combos.
To get new skills, you'll first need to find skill gems.
Using a skill gem will open the Gem Cutting menu, which shows all the active skills available in PoE 2.
You can choose an existing skill.
Although he the other behind-the-angle assassinants
With no carbon-aziscy of coyotables.
chauffeur christgons.com
With no carbon ovation of水 HeINDVELD
She wishes and supports all Hernándabgas.com
Who doubts.
With no gas Boys, nothin' рекорд purchasing the football moon.
Enjoy the rejoice.
Having boost the emocion Netz参 site of your sanctification may be beyond the handний- Rickuster cellars.
So to get along the nextinee of the picnic sets,
the Kil flip we plant throughout the picnic setting.
That was a lovely Muchas-Books-府avings.
Thank you very much.
가져 theきた Tch откґins
You can try or doctorateHmm
vorver and multiplication of Reno.
Are you having trouble
Thank you.
you're also blocking the whole time,
so you have full damage immunity from the front.
The Warrior also has access to Totems.
Some Totems have built-in abilities, like Shockwave Totem,
which can be placed to stun nearby enemies
and trigger aftershocks like those from the Earthquake.
But you can also get Ancestral Warrior Totems,
which allow you to use any slam skill in your repertoire.
This is a meta skill,
which means that it's a skill you can put other skills into.
I can take a slam like Sunder
and socket it into my Ancestral Warrior Totem.
Now when I summon him, he'll sit there
and slam the monsters from a distance.
There are 20 active skills for Maces,
so there's a lot more to try out.
But by endgame, you're going to be dropping Hammish from the sky,
leaping fearlessly into combat
and separating the very Earth you stand on.
Time for some ranged attacks.
The Ranger is primarily about the bow,
but we wanted to make sure that she feels agile as well.
In Pee-Wee 2, you can shoot while moving.
Combined with all the skills the Ranger has that allow you to jump around,
you'll have a lot of mobility in combat.
Bow skills have a variety of lightning, poison, ice and physical attacks.
Lightning attacks bounce around between targets.
You can also stick lightning arrows in the ground,
which explode when hit by the bouncers,
or electrocute enemies to take them out of combat.
Ice attacks allow you to slow and freeze enemies to keep them away from you.
Using poison, not only can you slowly damage your enemies from afar,
but also grow some interesting plants.
With 21 bow skills and all the mobility and combo tools the Ranger has,
you can take advantage of every situation.
By endgame, you'll be creating hundreds of arrows,
be they falling from the sky, bouncing around between enemies
or spraying out of tornadoes.
You might have noticed in the bottom left of the screen
that the flask slots look a little different.
In Pee-Wee 2, you have one dedicated life flask slot
and one mana flask slot.
Flasks gain charges as you kill enemies
and typically allow you to heal six or seven times if they're full.
But that's not the only thing you can use charges for.
Charms are a new item type
that will automatically defend you
from various debuffs or damage types.
Having trouble with getting frozen?
Equip a thawing charm.
When it's fully charged,
it will make you immune to freeze for three seconds
if you get frozen.
To recharge them, just kill more monsters.
You can use a thawing charm.
You can gain more slots for charms
by upgrading your belt.
The Mercenary wields a crossbow
that can be loaded with different ammo types
offering versatility, power and mobility.
All classes in Path of Exile 2
can be controlled with WASD
which makes this class play exactly like a shooter.
For the crossbow,
you will find skills that work like shotguns,
sniper rifles,
assault rifles
and even grenade launchers.
But not only that,
there are a wide variety of more interesting elemental ammos too.
It's very fast to switch between ammo types
so long as you already have them loaded
which makes the Mercenary able to combo abilities together
for devastating effect.
Use Glacial Bolt to create walls of ice to separate enemies
then switch to Fragmentation rounds
to explode the ice dealing massive AOE damage.
If I come across an armoured enemy,
I could use armour piercing rounds to break their armour
and then high velocity rounds to take them down.
Or perhaps I could fire a gas grenade to poison enemies
before detonating the cloud with an explosive shot
for massive damage.
If you want to call in some suppressing fire,
you can summon artillery ballisters.
These have a minimum range
so you'll want to prepare your position carefully
before moving in.
There are 22 active skills for crossbows.
By endgame,
you'll be calling destruction down from the sky
as you litter the battlefield with grenades
and pepper your enemies with your automatic shotgun.
If you're looking to take a backseat
and let your minions do the work,
then the witch should be your choice.
She can call forth hordes of undead monsters
to fight for her
casting powerful chaos spells
that debilitate her enemies.
Occult skills are some of the most varied in the game
with skeletons,
noxious spells,
specialty minions,
curses and sacrificial magic.
Before we talk about minions,
we'll have to talk about a new resource
in Path of Exile 2 called Spirit.
This is a spirit gem
which allows you to pick from a range of persistent skills.
All classes have a variety of these skills
which can add some very interesting effects
like Arctic armour
which does cold damage to enemies that hit you
or raging spirits
which summon fiery skulls
each time you cast a fire spell.
For the witch though,
we'll want to be using our spirit
to create permanent minions.
These minions will be revived
automatically when they die
so you don't have to worry
about resummoning them all the time.
Here I'm using the skill screen
to allocate which minions
I would like in my horde.
You can see the spirit cost of each one.
Skeletal Warriors are cheap but weak,
useful for tanking damage
and distracting enemies.
But I want more heavy hitters in my army
so I'm going to unsummon some warriors
and instead add skeletal arsonists.
Permanent minions
come with special active abilities
called command skills.
You can order these guys
to detonate your own minions
for even more damage
and air of effect.
If you want a bigger army
you'll need a scepter.
This new weapon type is imbued
with even more spirit
allowing you to summon
even more friends.
And if you want an even bigger
army than that
you can take advantage of corpses
to summon true hordes of minions.
But what can a witch do
while her army is at work?
Well, she has a range of
chaos spells
to spread disease
amongst your enemies
or bone skills to impale them.
Or, you know,
you could curse them
to make them weaker
so your horde can take them down.
There are 25 active occult skills.
By the endgame
you'll be the leader
of a fearsome army of the dead
consuming everything in its path.
The sorceress bends
the elements to her will
using them to unleash
devastation on her foes.
This classic spellcaster
weaves a flurry
of elemental magic
from afar.
The elemental skills
have everything
you might expect
and more.
Fireballs,
icy explosions,
lightning storms.
You get the ability
to use the ability
to use the power
of the enemy.
You can use the power
At times you get the idea.
Each spell is unique
and has many different ways
to build and combo
with others,
even between different elements.
For example,
Flamewall conjures
a burning line
that not only damages enemies,
but also empowers
all projectiles
that pass through it.
If you place a wall
and fire lightning sparks
through it,
they'll gain extra fire damage.
It's a good idea
to take advantage
of the ability
to automatically swap weapons
when you use certain skills.
Having a special staff
with bonuses
to fire skills
and another with bonuses
to lightning skills
can really power up
a combo like this.
The sorceress
can also take advantage
of powerful trigger jams.
For example,
you could grab the
cast and ignite gem
and use it with firestorm.
As you ignite enemies,
a counter will go up
in the top left corner.
When it's full,
a firestorm will automatically
be cast at the enemy
that was ignited.
There are 25 active
elemental skills.
By endgame,
you'll be firing off
projectiles left and right
as you rain down
elemental storms
on your foes.
the enemy's enemies
and the enemy's enemies
will be firing off.
Now,
those are the characters
that will be available
at the start of early access.
But we will be adding
six more character classes
with just as many skills
and options as these.
There's a lot more to come.
There's one more important thing
to mention about skills.
Even though we talk about them
as belong to each class,
in reality,
there are no restrictions.
You can use all these skills
on any class
so long as you have the attributes.
For example,
a poison ranger might want
to try out using occult curses
to increase her poison damage.
Or a monk might want
to trigger elemental ice walls
to use with his glacial cascade combo.
The possibilities for cross-class combos
are practically unlimited.
We're looking forward
to what kind of things
you guys might find.
Now,
Path of Exile is a game
known for build customization,
and we haven't even scratched
the surface of what is possible yet.
So let's talk about support gems.
Path of Exile 2 has a system of support gems
that can be combined
with your active skills
to dramatically change
the way they work.
If you find a support gem,
then right-clicking it
will open up this screen.
Here you will find a variety
of recommended support gems
for each of your skills
that you can pick between.
For example,
this is a multiple projectiles support gem
and can be used to add
multiple projectiles to any skill.
Normally,
when you fire a grenade,
it'll look like this.
But if you can use it,
you can use it.
You can use it.
But if we add multiple projectiles,
then you get three of them.
Once you have the gem,
you can also freely move it
between any of the skills
in your character.
If you want to have
a multi-shot sniper rifle instead,
then simply move the gem over
to your high-velocity round skill.
Generally speaking,
if it sounds like a support gem
should work with a skill,
then it will work.
So it's a good idea to experiment.
Note that you can only have
one of each support gem
on your character,
so you'll want to think carefully
about which supports
can be used best
with each skill
for maximum damage.
Now, if you want to stick
to the recommendations,
you should have
a perfectly good time.
But if you want to experiment
a bit more,
then uncheck that
recommended button
and you can see the full list
of supports that will work
with your skill.
There are hundreds of support gems
to choose from,
and even we don't know
the results of all the possible
ways these can interact.
Each skill can have up to
five supports socketed into it.
And if you're clever,
you can come up with
some pretty interesting ideas.
Now all of this is just
scratching the surface.
You can make frost vortexes,
break people's armor,
make minions explode,
make skills repeat,
make enemies set each other on fire,
cull enemies or pin them to the ground.
It supports that you drastically change
the behavior of your skills
and create your own unique build,
or at least follow someone's OP build guide.
So, speaking of builds,
let's talk about one of the most iconic
Path of Exile systems,
the passive skill tree.
Yes, it's huge.
There are over 1500 nodes on there.
Now a lot of people open the tree
and can get a little intimidated at first,
but try not to be scared.
There are lots of options,
but at its core,
it's pretty simple.
Each level you get one point
to put into the tree.
Each class starts at a different location,
but they all share the same tree.
Around your section of the tree,
you'll find relevant bonuses
for your character.
You should be safe in the knowledge
that there aren't many wrong choices here.
Almost all the starting nodes
will be useful for your character
in some way.
But if you do happen to make a choice
you regret,
you'll be able to respec
any nodes you've taken
by spending a little bit of gold.
Now, the tree is generally divided up
into clusters which have similar themes.
In each cluster,
you will find small nodes
that give simple bonuses
like increased damage,
but the real power comes from notables.
Notables normally have much more
interesting bonuses,
and they tend to care a lot more
about how your build works
and what skills you're using.
For example,
in the mercenary area of the tree,
this one gives a 25% chance
for crossbow skills
to not consume a bolt.
And here's one that gives grenades
a chance to blow up a second time.
This one gives a chance for projectiles
to rebound off terrain,
as well as giving you some pierce chance
to make that more likely.
Note that even though this is
in the mercenary section,
this would work with projectiles
from all classes,
so there are often reasons
to go to different areas of the tree.
In order to get between these clusters,
you will generally have to allocate nodes
in the attribute highways.
Attribute nodes allow you to pick
which attribute you would like to use,
so it's very easy to get points
for any attribute that your gear might need.
You can change which attribute
these nodes give you for half price
at the respec vendor.
In addition to notables,
you will also find even larger passives
called keystones.
Keystones have both an upside
and a downside,
and often require changing your entire build
to design around them.
A great example is Giant's Blood,
which allows you to wield two-hand weapons
in a single hand,
but doubles the attribute requirements off them.
You can use a two-hand mace with a shield,
or even dual-wield them.
Or how about Mind Over Matter,
which makes all damage go to your mana pool first
before your life pool,
but you lose 50% of your mana regen.
Skills like these can be tough to build around,
but if you're up for the challenge,
they can be very rewarding.
As we showed you earlier on the Sorceress,
you can swap between weapon sets on the fly
as you use certain skills.
One of the new features in Path of Exile 2's passive tree
is that you can choose to have your passive tree
to have your passive tree
and use your mana pool.
You can swap between weapon sets on the fly
as you use certain skills.
One of the new features in Path of Exile 2's passive tree
is that you can choose to have your passive tree
change as you switch between weapon sets
to take advantage of specific bonuses on the tree.
For the Sorceress,
you might want to change between
fire and lightning specialization.
Or you could switch between one-hand
and a two-hand setup
in order to be able to block boss attacks
while following up with heavy hits
from your bigger mace.
Or perhaps you could have a full curse setup
on your witch to debuff enemies
before switching to a chaos degen build
for maximum damage.
If you're able to block boss attacks
or you could have a full curse setup
on your witch to debuff enemies
before switching to a chaos degen build
for maximum damage.
If you want to stick with just one weapon set,
you can just use these specialization points
as bonus points to invest however you like.
But creative players will find plenty of opportunities
with this system.
You can get weapon specialization points
throughout the campaign
from optional bosses and quests.
For example,
if I manage to defeat the Crowbell,
I'll get a weapon specialization book.
There are lots of other permanent boosts
available from the campaign too.
On the map you can see icons that indicate
the many optional encounters you can find.
Some of them have permanent character boosts
and others have powerful items.
If you're having trouble getting past a boss,
it might be a good idea to explore
and see what you can find.
For example,
if you defeat Blackjaw the Remnant,
you'll gain a permanent increase to fire resistance.
One of the most important finds are spirit bonuses.
You can find the first one here in the canopy in Act 1.
Defeat the boss in this area
to acquire a permanent addition of spirit.
The permanent buffs you gain from spirit are very powerful,
and every class will find the use for them,
so make sure you hunt down these upgrades.
There's one in each act.
Now we haven't even talked about
the most important element of character progression, items.
That's why we're all here, right?
Items in Path of Exile can be broken down
into four rarity groups,
Normal, Magic, Rare and Unique.
One of the things you're going to want to do
as you play through the campaign
is upgrade the items you find,
and you can do that with currency items.
An Orb of Transmutation will allow you
to upgrade a normal item to a magic item with one mod.
You can then apply an Orb of Augmentation
to add a second mod,
then use a Regal Orb to add a third mod,
and upgrade it to a rare.
Finally, you can use some Exalted Orbs
to add more mods to your rare to a total of six mods.
One of the things we think is really important
is to make these options available to use as you play.
All the items that add mods are much more common
than they were in Path of Exile 1,
so that you can use them throughout your campaign playthrough.
We want you to find things on the ground
that can be crafted into upgrades much more frequently.
As well as making the drop rates on these items
much more common,
you can also get them by disenchanting unwanted gear
at the magic item vendor.
If you disenchant magic items,
you can build up to an Orb of Transmutation,
and by disenchanting rares,
you can build up to Regal Orbs.
Another important area of crafting items in PoE2 is sockets.
Some items you find will have sockets
that can have Ezimite runes placed in them
that add more mods to the item.
If I insert this glacial rune into my helmet,
it will give extra cold resistance.
This is a great way to solve problems
that you have with your build,
like resistances or damage.
If you find socketed items that you don't have a use for,
you can take them to the salvage bench in town
to work towards an artificer's orb.
This will allow you to add sockets to your existing items.
Body armours and two-hand weapons can have up to two sockets,
while the rest of your armour and one-hand weapons
can only have one socket.
You can also salvage items with quality
to create items like armour scraps or whetstones.
These will allow you to increase the quality of your items
for an up to 20% boost.
If you don't want to disenchant or salvage your items,
you can always sell them for gold.
Gold can be used to buy items from vendors,
and we've tried to do a lot to make sure
that the items they have for sale are actually useful.
Every time you level up, they get more stock,
so make sure to check back often.
Other vendors offer a gamble.
Pay a flat amount of gold,
and you'll get a random item of a specific type.
This could be a great way to improve your gear,
if you're lucky.
Gold is also used to respec your passive skills.
Take advantage of this system to experiment with your tree
and rework it as required.
The other thing you might want to use gold for
is the currency exchange.
This allows you to exchange currency items
with other players on an open market,
in exchange for a small gold fee.
Now, all items in Path of Exile are freely tradable.
We never bind anything to your character, except gold.
Now, most gear in Path of Exile 2 is randomly generated,
but there's another type that isn't.
Uniques.
They are especially rare,
each with a handcrafted set of unusual mods
which can dramatically change a character's build.
They're not just better rare items.
They can do much stranger things
that can fundamentally change your character.
Corpse Wade will make any corpses you run through
explode into clouds of poison.
The Sands of Silk is a body armour that changes your dodge roll
into a blink, morphing you into sand as you teleport past your foes.
And of course, some uniques are just pure hits of dopamine,
like Quill Rain, which just turns your bow attacks into full auto
by doubling your attack speed.
Each unique is something that you can build your character around.
We try to make sure that most unique items have a potential use at endgame,
even if you find them early on.
And as you can see, every single unique item comes with custom art to match.
The last character progression system that you can do during the campaign is Ascension.
Starting in Act 2, you will come across Ascension Trials,
tests that you must complete to unlock your Ascension class.
We'll explain these trials soon,
but first let's take a look at what Ascending can do for your character.
Each class has access to three Ascendancy classes,
but at the start of early access, only two per class will be available.
Ascendancy classes are unique to each character class,
so choose wisely.
They can drastically affect how you build your character.
As a Sorceress, you could become a Stormweaver,
a master of the elements.
Tempest Caller causes elemental storms to be summoned
each time you do a critical hit with a spell.
With Strike Twice, you can stack two copies of Shock for more damage,
and going deeper into the tree,
you can make all your damage-type supply Shock.
Make a Shock build from any skill.
Alternatively, you could become a Chronomancer and command time itself.
She literally has the ability to stop time with Time Freeze.
Not only that, but she has many other time manipulation abilities.
Using Temporal Rift, she can teleport back to a previous location,
resetting her life and mana back to what it was.
Or with Time Snap, she can reset all her cooldowns
and cast all her spells again.
On the Warrior, you can choose between the Warbringer or the Titan.
The Warbringer channels the might of his ancestors
to gain tremendous power.
Using Answered Call, you can summon ancestral spirits
linked to each of your totems.
With Jade Heritage, you can encase your body in a protective layer
that absorbs all damage until it breaks.
Warcaller's Bellow allows you to explode the corpses of your enemies.
And with Great Wolf's Howl, you can ignore the cooldowns of your Warcries.
Let all that anger out.
The Titan class is all about hitting big.
With Earthbreaker, every slam is a chance to create an Aftershock.
With Crushing Impacts, every hit becomes a Crushing Blow,
which will allow you to stun your enemies with ease.
With Surprising Strength, you can take advantage of stunned enemies
to deal 40% more damage.
As a Ranger, you might choose to be a Deadeye,
an expert markswoman who can take down foes with style.
With endless munitions, every attack gains an extra projectile.
With Gathering Winds, she gains a small increase to movement speed
with every attack.
But be careful, she loses them when getting hit.
With Eagle Eyes, she will never miss, allowing you to stop wasting all those passer points on accuracy.
Alternatively, you could become a Pathfinder, the master of flasks and poison.
She can choose from one of several throwable concoctions,
allowing her to spend her flask charges to throw explosive bottles
that deal various types of damage.
A Bleeding Concoction will make your enemies bleed,
while a fulminating one can shock your enemies, allowing you to do extra damage.
Contagious Contamination allows her to spread poisons between her foes,
while Overwhelming Toxicity doubles the number of stacks they can be infected by.
Running Assault allows her to move much more quickly while firing,
while Relentless Pursuit makes her totally immune to being slowed by enemies.
The Witch can ascend into the Infernalist or the Blood Mage.
As an Infernalist, she can summon a loyal Hellhound companion.
The Hellhound sets enemies on fire, as well as taking a percentage of the damage if the Infernalist gets hit.
With Pyromantic Pact, you can turn your mana into Infernal Flame.
As you cast more spells, the flame builds up, and if it overflows, you'll take damage.
Using Bringer of Flame, you'll want to make sure you keep the flames topped up.
While your Infernal Flame is above 30%, all damage from you and your minions will ignite enemies.
She can also transform into a literal demon.
While in demon form, she takes an increasing amount of damage,
but her cast speed and damage increase rapidly as well.
So if you're planning on transforming into a demon, make sure you stack a lot of life recovery.
She can also become a Blood Mage, a master of life and energy.
All Blood Mages must pay the price of making skills cost life as well as mana,
but in exchange, every monster they kill will drop life remnants,
which allow them to quickly gain back that life.
With Crimson Power, she can gain large amounts of extra life,
and with Vitality Syphon, she can use her spells to leech life back as well.
Once you've got a significant amount of life, you can use Gore Spike to make your critical hit steal
incredible amounts of damage.
A monk who is in tune with the elements might become an Invoker.
With Elemental Expression, the Invoker will create waves of elemental power each time he does a critical strike.
With Faith as a Choice, you gain the ability to meditate, allowing you to double your energy shield.
Choose between I am the Blizzard or I am the Thunder to specialize in Cold or Lightning.
And I Shall Rage will allay to turn into an unbound avatar.
Each time you apply a status ailment to an enemy, you gain unbound fury.
When you have enough, transform into an avatar to deal way more damage and inflict even more elemental ailments.
Some monks choose to reach into the darkness instead.
The Acolyte of Chayula can exchange their mastery of spirit for darkness,
a resource that can be utilized to both absorb and deal damage.
The Shroud of Darkness will protect you from all damage incoming, but if you take grasp of the Void, you will deal extra chaos damage from all the darkness you have.
Their Dark Pact offers greatly increased resistances to chaos damage and can allow their mana leech to not only happen instantly, but apply to their energy shield as well.
Another node you can take is Waking Dream, which allows you to see into the domain of the breach demons.
There you will see the Flames of Chayula that can be taken to gain life, mana and damage.
The Mercenary has a job to do, but which job suits you? You might choose to become a witch hunter.
Obsessive Rituals will give you a sorcery ward, allowing you to defend yourself against elemental hits in exchange for less defense against attacks.
With Zealous Inquisition, your enemies have a 10% chance to explode on death. The chances doubled against demons and undead.
With Judge, Jury and Executioner, your initial hit against enemies can deal up to 30% of their life in damage, if you're lucky.
This is great for hunting powerful bosses.
And with Witch Bane, you can break your enemies' concentration, preventing them from casting spells as often as they would usually do.
You could also choose to become a Gemling Legionnaire, enhancing your abilities by embedding gems directly in your flesh.
Integrated efficiency will give you extra skill slots.
Thermatological Infusion gives you extra maximum resistances as you sock up more and more support gems.
Adaptive Capability allows you to use any color of gem without worrying about attributes,
while Crystalline Potential adds extra quality bonuses to every gem socketed into your character.
So those are the Ascendancy classes for the start of Early Access.
But one thing we haven't talked about yet is how you ascend in the first place.
Ascension in Path of Exile 2 requires completion of one of the Great Trials, which you'll find as you progress through the campaign.
Each one is associated with one of the major cultures of Rhaeclast.
Located in the Vasteri Plains are the Marraketh, a culture of rich tales and brutal traditions, who must do whatever it takes to survive in the desert.
The highest position in Marraketh culture is a Sekima, and it is not a title given freely.
All aspirants must complete the Trial of the Sekimas, a gruelling gauntlet that will test their strength, will, cunning and patience.
To enter, a warrior of the Marraketh must prove their worth by trapping the soul of a Djinn in a coin, and you are no different.
Once you have earned your coin, it may be placed in the Relic Altar to begin the Trial.
In the Trial of the Sekimas, each room has its own challenges to overcome.
In this room, each rare monster you kill will send its blood to the chalice in the centre of the room.
Once the chalice is filled, you will be able to proceed.
While fighting monsters in the Trial, you will need to be very careful.
Each hit will not only hurt you, but will damage your honour.
The monsters are well telegraphed, so that you can avoid their attacks, but if you run out of honour, you will fail the Trial and need to find another coin in order to try again.
It is a good idea to make sure that you are well prepared before challenging the Trial of the Sekimas.
After each room, you will be rewarded.
In this case, you have been given a key that can be used to unlock chests later in the Trial.
Once you have claimed your reward, you will be shown a map of the rest of the floor, and may choose how you wish to proceed.
Which challenges would you like to face, and which rewards do you want to claim?
Some rooms are more dangerous, afflicting you with debuffs that will persist for the entire Trial.
For example, entering this room will afflict you with spiked shell that will cause all monsters in the rest of the Trial to have 50% increased life.
You will want to take care if you choose such a path.
There are many different challenges and rewards as you journey through the Trial.
Deadly traps, waves of monsters, and strange artefacts will test your honour.
As you progress, you will be able to gain boons from the Djinn, which will help you on your journey.
For example, the Sekimer's Cloak will revive you once if you die, giving you a second shot at a run.
One of the rewards you may find is Sacred Water, an extremely valuable and treasured resource to the Djinn and the Mariketh.
Trading it with the Djinn will allow you to receive many benefits.
You can recover honour, gain additional boons, or remove afflictions.
At the end of the floor, you will find a powerful boss which will truly test your limitations.
In order to ascend, you will need to defeat him.
Having defeated the boss, you've earned the right to ascend. But first, the loot.
The keys you have found may be used to open the various treasures in the vault at the end of the floor.
We only have a single bronze key, so we'll just have to open one of these small chests.
If you want to open the better ones, you'll need silver or gold keys.
Let's use the Altar of Ascendancy.
Your first ascension will allow you to pick your class and grant you two points to use in the tree.
Now there are more flaws and many more rewards that can be found within the Trial of the Sekimus, but we'll save that for the section on the end game.
For now, let's talk about the second ascendancy trial, the Trial of Chaos.
In Path of Exile 2, you can choose whichever trial you like to earn your ascension.
Each culture on Wraeclast had their own methods to ascend.
If the Trial of the Sekimus is not your kind of playstyle, or you're finding it too difficult, you could try another.
You can gain all your ascension points from just one, or mix and match them. It's up to you.
For early access, we will have two trials as options, with a third trial coming later for the full release.
While exploring the Vaal jungle, you'll discover the Temple of Chaos.
Before the Vaal embraced the science of corruption, their civilization worshipped Chaos.
This ancient trial was once used by the Vaal to test their High Priests.
A High Priest of the Vaal must show willingness to risk everything to gain power.
Entry to the trial requires a token from a strange entity known only as the Trial Master.
For those in which he sees potential, he shall inscribe an ultimatum.
Many have attempted these trials in search of greatness. Most have perished.
Will you be able to defy the odds?
Before you begin each chamber, the Trial Master will offer you a reward and a choice.
Choose one of three Tribulations to affect you through the rest of the trial.
These modifiers might beef up the monsters, curse the player, or add environmental hazards like turrets or trap runes.
In this case, we will be picking Shocking Turrets.
As you enter the room, the Trial Master will fill it with hazards to test your commitment.
In this case, you must destroy all the monsters that fill the room, while dealing with the lightning projectiles from the Shocking Turrets.
After each room you will need to make a choice.
Take the rewards you have earned once again, depending on the goal, sony will heal.
Once you enter the effectiveness, it'll turn into the next console related to the surveillance 카 won and distress stars,
or defeat the Gra frenteians.
Feel which makes sure you will choose a speed loopנו
and make your 600 pre-meanternals.
Take the rewards you have earned so far, or go double or nothing.
Increase your rewards, but take on more risk.
Each tribulation you add is minor on its own,
but they quickly stack on top of each other and can become overwhelming.
There are many types of chambers in the trial.
Each will test your resolve in different ways.
This one simply requires you survive for a certain amount of time.
Another requires you to escort the stone idol through the level
as elevators full of monsters descend to attack you.
Should you be able to get through the first three chambers,
you will face your first boss.
The order of the bosses is random,
and combined with the tribulations you have selected,
the fight will never feel the same.
After defeating the boss, you may claim your rewards.
Of course there are the items, but you also gain the right to ascend.
If you already did the trial of the Sekimers,
then you can claim two more points to add to your ascendancy class.
Now it's possible to go much deeper.
There are more bosses, rewards and risks to take.
But we'll talk more about that when we get to Endgame.
So how about we talk about that now?
So far we've only been showing you footage from the campaign,
but some people would argue that the Endgame is where the game truly begins.
Something that happens almost every time a new action RPG launches is people saying,
there isn't enough Endgame content.
Well, we want to make sure that in PoE 2 people don't feel that way,
and we actually only changed our development priority for this recently.
The first three acts of PoE 2 already take around 25 hours to complete if you're a new player.
This is already a pretty significant campaign.
On the other hand, people spend hundreds of hours in Endgame each league.
We realized that finishing the rest of the campaign for Early Access was actually a bad idea.
Instead of having acts 4 to 6 in Early Access, we could concentrate on Endgame and make that great.
For new players, a 25-hour campaign is already a huge game with lots of content.
But for existing action RPG players, what you mostly care about is all the Endgame challenges to overcome.
So several months ago, we switched the entire development team's focus over to making Endgame content.
At the start of Early Access, there will be 50 bosses and around 400 monster types.
But the great thing is that the rest of the game is like 80% there.
We'll be adding content to roughly double the size of the game during Early Access and into release.
Now, in order to make the Endgame happen at the same character level as what it would be after we added the rest of the acts,
we've added a second difficulty level called Cruel,
where you repeat the campaign with all the monsters and bosses leveled up, and of course new rewards.
You can kind of think of it as like a new game plus.
It's also a lot faster to get through the content the second time as your clear speed increases.
That will take you to around level 65, where the Endgame begins.
Once we add, the remaining three acts will be removing Cruel difficulty,
so you'll progress straight from the end of Act 6 to Endgame.
But what is the Endgame?
To explain that, I'll hand over to Mark. He can tell you all about it.
Hi, I'm Mark Roberts, Game Director on Path of Exile 2.
Well, one thing that Path of Exile is known for is having a lot of distinct Endgame content to choose between.
Each Endgame mechanic needs to have its own progression system, areas, bosses, rewards, and player power that can only be gained from that content.
We are going to be adding a lot more over time, but for Path of Exile 2 we decided to start with seven distinct systems you can progress through.
This is the Atlas, and it serves as the core of the Endgame for Path of Exile 2.
It's infinite and expands in all directions.
Now, we are not going to spoil the plot too much here, but corruption from the beast has blighted the land, and your objective is to help fight it.
In the center of the Atlas you will find the Ziggurat, a temple in which the Vaal research the fundamentals of space and time.
Here, we can open portals to nearby locations and begin cleansing corruption and finding resources.
In order to power the portal device, we will need Waystones.
Each waystone has a tier which will determine the level of the monsters that you will face.
To go to an area, simply click one that is adjacent to an area that you have already completed.
Insert the waystone and click Traverse.
Portals will open, allowing you and your party to travel to the area you have selected.
All the areas in the Endgame feel distinct from the locations in the campaign, and we have dialed the randomization up to 11.
The monster packs you will face in each map are totally random, and the combination of them can lead to some very interesting combat situations.
There are over 400 monster types in early access, and they have a lot of varied and interesting abilities.
Depending on which combinations you face, you might find some serious challenges.
In order to cleanse the corruption from the area, you will need to defeat all the powerful rare and unique enemies in it.
Once you have done that, the area will be marked as completed,
and you will be able to travel past it to progress deeper into the world.
If you die, then the map can no longer be run, and you will have to find another way around to get to the areas behind it.
There are also all kinds of other random encounters you might run into as you play maps.
One such encounter are Precursor Artifacts.
These are ancient, corrupting monuments that irradiate the monsters around them.
The monsters that feed off the corruption are drawn to their power.
If you defeat the monsters and cleanse the artifact, you will get a powerful temporary buff.
Some of the buffs make you faster, others rain lightning or fire around you, and some even give you increased experience or help you find better items.
You can also find Strong Boxes.
These enigmatic chests guard piles of treasure, but are always a trap.
Monsters lie in wait to attack you the moment you open it, and the boxes often have mechanisms to unleash powerful spells or dangerous debuffs.
There are different types of Strong Boxes containing different items, and you can even use your currency items to craft them on the fly, so you can optimize the content.
But be careful of opening one you can't handle.
Sometimes you'll discover monsters frozen in essences.
Solidified, crystalline corruption.
These dangerous monsters can be broken free.
If you defeat them, the essence they drop can be used to upgrade normal items to magic items with a guaranteed mod from a category.
For example, we could use this one on some boots to ensure a movement speed mod.
Rarely, essences will also drop that allow you to upgrade magics to rares, adding the guaranteed mod.
This is incredibly powerful since it allows you to get a second deterministic mod in your crafting projects.
Combining these with the currencies that are commonly found in Rayclass for modifying items, and we can get a very nice pair of boots indeed.
Waystones, like all items, can also be crafted using your currency items.
Adding prefix mods will improve the rewards, while suffix mods increase danger.
The more dangerous a map is, the more waystones will drop.
Adding mods to your waystones is key to progressing to higher tiers and sustaining them, but it will require you to take on larger challenges.
There are a variety of factors you have to consider when crafting your waystones.
Some maps will have higher density, some lower, some have more magic and rare chests, or monsters, some are more linear, and others more open.
Make sure you explore and think about what makes certain maps good if you want to maximise your returns.
As you cleanse corruption from higher and higher tiers of the Atlas, you will gain points that you can spend in the Atlas tree.
This tree allows you to juice the danger and rewards of all areas in the endgame.
You could increase the number of monsters, the number of rares, the number of precursor artifacts or strongboxes, even the quantity of item drops.
As you explore the endgame world map, you'll notice various different biomes, from snow-capped mountains to dense jungle valleys.
Most maps are restricted to certain biomes.
As you continue to explore deeper into the Atlas, there are all sorts of things to discover.
These cities are constructed by different peoples of Rhaeclast, and have specific items that can be found there.
These strange structures marked on the map don't appear to do anything for now.
Perhaps you'll work out how to use them later.
You might find unique maps like Untainted Paradise, an undisturbed island full of beasts that give an extreme amount of experience.
You may even find a lonely man just enjoying his retirement who will give you a unique item for free.
In addition, you can find special areas that would make a good spot to set up camp.
Clear these areas of their hostile inhabitants, and you'll be able to claim them as your own hideout.
You can decorate your hideout as you see fit, and invite various NPCs to join you there to create your own personal base of options.
Explorations.
A great tool for exploration are towers.
These mysterious precursor constructs are dotted around the Atlas.
Completing the tower will reveal a large area around it, allowing you to scout out your next challenge.
There are lots of things to find, so keep looking.
Some sections of your Atlas are influenced by corruption.
This adds extra modifiers to the maps in the region, increasing difficulty and rewards.
Here, slaying monsters in close proximity to each other will cause the vestiges of corruption within them to merge together, forming powerful and grotesque abominations.
You may have noticed while looking at the Atlas that some of the areas have these icons above them.
The icon indicates that the area contains some kind of special encounter.
This icon indicates that the area has a powerful boss.
Because only one in four maps contain a map boss, we are able to make them very powerful and very rewarding.
These bosses come from the campaign, but have had their difficulty increased with changes to AI and some of their abilities.
It's worth noting that because you can see where the bosses are, you can choose to take them on or avoid them.
If you do choose to hunt bosses though, then you will be rewarded with special points for the boss hunting section of the Atlas skill tree.
The points here will allow you to specialise in boss killing, giving you much greater rewards for defeating them.
For each different type of content in the endgame, we are adding specialised trees in order to make it so you don't feel the need to respec your points when you change between different types of content.
We will be showing you seven of these by the end of this presentation, so there is still a lot more to come.
Bosses are not the only icon you will see on the Atlas. Let's take a look at one of the endgame systems, Breach.
If you played PoE 1, you might be familiar with Breach. For PoE 2, we have created sequels to several PoE 1 leagues.
While the mechanic is familiar, the monsters, bosses, rewards and progression are all new.
A Breach is a tear in the fabric of reality. Opening it will allow you to see the demons and otherworldly monstrosities that lie in wait on this other plane of existence.
By engaging with a Breach, you'll create a bridge between their world and Rayquast.
In order to keep the Breach open, you will need to kill the demons that pour forth.
The faster you can kill the monsters, the more monsters you will fight and the more loot you will find.
You can also find clasped hands that will open and drop more items if you run over them.
These can be a good boost to the rewards of the Breach, so keep an eye on them.
One of the rewards that you may find while fighting monsters from Breach are Tablets.
Tablets are special items that can be used with Precursor Towers to add more encounters to the Atlas.
Breaches will drop Breach Tablets. Clicking on a completed tower will allow you to consume the tablet to add more breaches to areas within range of the tower.
This makes all the content in the Atlas self-sustaining. Want to do more Breaches? Find the tablets, add them to your towers, get more Breaches, getting more tablets.
Soon your Atlas will be covered in otherworldly domains.
In addition, like all items in PoE, you can craft them. Use your currency to add mods to your tablets, allowing you to upgrade all the Breaches in range.
Tablets can have up to two mods. These mods do things like adding extra rare monsters, extra clasped hands, or even mods to density of Breaches, allowing you to keep them open longer.
Often, you will find multiple towers near to each other with overlapping areas of effect. This can allow you to really juice the mechanic by stacking the mods from multiple tablets.
In your fight to hold the Breach Demons at bay, you may want to use the powers of their world against them.
Each endgame mechanic always has player power that can only be gained from that mechanic, and Breach is no different.
In Breach, you will find Catalysts, items that can increase the quality of rings and amulets by improving specific mods.
You can also find Breach Rings, a special base type that can have its quality improved by Catalysts up to 50%.
In this case, you could create a ring with around 170 life.
Breach Rings can become some of the strongest rings in the game, giving you some good motivation to face the Demon Horns.
In addition, each endgame mechanic needs to have a pinnacle endgame encounter.
While killing Breach monsters, you may find Breach Splinters.
Collect enough of these and you'll be able to create a Breach Stone.
Using a vile technology called the Realm Gate, you can use your Breach Stone to access their domain and bring the fight to them.
In this twisted domain, you will find nothing but a single massive Breach.
Triggering it will reveal hordes of Breach inhabitants.
And should you be fast enough, you will be able to fight their leader, Zest, We That Are One.
We that dreamed, We in nightmare, We that are one.
Fate relies truth.
Fawak'd sayendenki be a great hero of Bollywood, now we use Mine.
ALL we're numbered biết in the future are under hierarchies in the game.
of PoE too. We won't be showing the rest of them, so you will have to discover them for yourself.
But rest assured, this is some of the hardest content we have ever made.
All these encounters have specific uniques that can only be found from them.
But that's not all. We still have the progression system.
Defeating Zest will give you points to allocate into the Breach section of the Atlas tree.
Allocating these points will make Breaches and the Breach domain even harder,
but will give you more rewards.
The small nodes will increase the difficulty of the Twisted Domain,
while the large nodes have more specific bonuses.
For example, this node adds more Clasped Hands to your Breaches,
and adds a pack of Magic Monsters that can guard them.
Get some more points and you can allocate Waking Nightmare,
which will double the number of splinters you get from Clasped Hands,
and inflict you with a mysterious debunk.
In order to earn more points, you will need to defeat Zest at a higher difficulty,
and some rewards from Zest can only be found by increasing the difficulty of the Twisted Domain above certain thresholds.
Defeating Zest at difficulty 4 will be a challenge indeed,
but there are many more threats in Wraeclast.
Ritual Altars are sacrificial sites built by the mysterious King in the Mists.
If you encounter this symbol on the Atlas, then you know that the area contains Ritual Altars.
Ritual Altars demand tribute.
Every monster you slaughter in the Circle will feed the altar.
After the sacrifice, touch it to begin the ritual.
The monsters you just killed will be resurrected by the King of the Mists' dark magic,
and you must fight to survive.
The tribute you have offered to the altar can be spent to buy powerful items,
but they can be expensive.
To gain more tribute, you will want to find more altars.
Each successive ritual you do within an area will spawn the monsters revived by the previous ones,
in addition to the ones you sacrificed next to them.
By the end of an area, you will be fighting a truly imposing number of foes,
but will have a significant amount of tribute to spend.
One of the rewards you can buy with tribute are omens.
These are special items that allow for metacrafting.
Crafting items that affect other crafting items.
Have an item with good prefixes but bad suffixes?
This omen will help you to remove the mods you don't want, while keeping the ones you do.
There are a bunch more of these with different effects, but we will leave them for you to discover.
Now don't forget that Ritual will also drop tablets,
which can be used to specialize into getting more rituals.
If you want to get to the pinnacle boss of Ritual, then you will probably want to use them.
They can also be crafted to grant mods, making your rituals more rewarding.
The pinnacle encounter of Ritual is the King in the Mists.
Feared by the Asmiri people, he is said to have brought eternal darkness to the Wildwood.
We won't show the encounter, but just like Breach, there are a range of unique items you can get for defeating him,
and you will gain points in the Ritual section of the Atlas Tree.
Some maps have been touched by insanity.
A mysterious entity has taken a special interest in you.
Step through the looking glass and you will find your nightmares coming to life.
When you touch a mirror, the mists of Delirium will spread out across the area, infecting your mind.
You must stay within the mist to maintain the nightmare, which is as profitable as it is terrifying.
Everything you kill will increase the rewards that drop.
However, the deeper into the mist you travel, the stronger the monsters are.
Be careful not to overstay your welcome.
Rare and unique enemies will become vessels for terrifying demons, who will manifest out of them to unleash powerful attacks on you.
The mist also offers a strange crafting material.
Distilled Emotions.
By combining these Emotions, you are able to instill your amulet with a notable from the passive skill tree.
This is like gaining an extra passive point for free, attached to your gear.
They are also particularly great because you don't have to traverse the tree to get them,
allowing you to get off-class bonuses that would normally be much harder to get.
Distilled Emotions can also be used to instill your endgame maps,
applying Delirious to them and adding additional difficulty and rewards,
allowing you to further juice your endgame maps.
The tablets you can find from Delirium can be used to further improve it,
increase pack size, make the fog dissipate slower,
or improve your progress towards the pinnacle encounter of Delirium.
Speaking of which, every now and then you will find Simulacrum Splinters.
The mysterious entity will create strange encounters based on warped versions of your own memories.
Monsters and Simulacrums come in waves that get progressively more difficult.
You will receive loot at the end of each wave,
and you will have to make the decision to leave now or continue on,
facing up against even tougher foes from the mist.
The bosses you will face as you get deeper into a Simulacrum are truly terrifying.
If you can complete a Simulacrum, you will gain points for the Delirium section of the Atlas skill tree.
Next up we have Expedition.
Occasionally, while clearing Corruption, you will encounter these Kalgurin settlers.
The Kalgurins have discovered ancient burial sites with lost Varicium artifacts,
and they want you to help dig them up with explosives.
The Kalgurins have marked the locations where the relics can be found.
Place explosives as best you can to dig up as many as possible.
There is just one problem.
Corruption has brought the corpses of their ancestors to life,
so you might have to do a little clean up before you can reclaim the artifacts.
You can also find remnants, the destruction of which will further anger the restless dead.
Each one you blow up will make the subsequent monsters more powerful, but also more rewarding.
Danig, Rog, Tujan, and Gwennon will exchange the artifacts for useful items and runic magic.
You can also find tablets to increase the number of expeditions and the rewards.
This one increases the radius of explosives, while this one increases the number of remnants you will find.
Eventually, you might discover a logbook.
These are special maps full of buried treasure and relics.
Essentially one giant dig site.
Here you can create an extremely long chain of explosives and go through a very high number of remnants.
But be careful!
Many remnants have mods that can really break your build,
so you will probably want to avoid these ones.
If you add too many remnants, you could easily make the encounter harder than you can handle.
There are all sorts of interesting things buried under the ground in logbooks.
You might find dripping caves and hidden pirate caches.
But the most powerful encounter is Ulroth, the ancient undead commander of the Knights of the Sun.
Defeating him will grant you unique rewards,
as well as points to spend in the expedition section of the Atlas Tree.
So those are the endgame systems on the Atlas, but we are not done yet.
The trials we talked about earlier have much more content when you get to endgame too.
Just like the other endgame systems, they also have progression mechanics, unique rewards,
and player power that can only be gained from them.
As you get higher level coins for the trial of the Sekimers, you will unlock more floors to explore.
Each floor has its own challenging brooms and a floor boss that you will need to kill.
There are four floors in total, leading to another pinnacle boss at the end of the last floor,
which can only be accessed at endgame.
The trial of the Sekimers is where you'll find duels, which you can socket into your tree.
These are like passives that you can craft with your currency items.
They can be really powerful, as they allow you to stack modifiers that may not be easily accessible on the tree normally.
This duel gives lightning damage and shock chance, for example.
There are quite a few duel sockets on the tree, so it's possible to gain a lot of power here.
There are also other types of duels that don't provide any bonuses themselves, but affect other passives surrounding them.
This duel increases the effect of small nodes and radius by 25%.
With careful placement in the tree, you could get a significant amount of power from it.
There are also unique duels available with very interesting effects, but you will have to find those for yourself.
In order to push further into the trial and uncover the secrets of the Marakev, you will want to take advantage of its progression system, relics.
Relics are items that can be placed in the Relic Altar as you start the trial.
They give special bonuses that affect the trial, making it easier and increasing its rewards.
Of course, you can craft these with your currency items, making them even stronger.
If you can complete the entire trial overcoming all four flaws, the final boss will reward you with one of many unique relics.
These relics will be consumed when used on your next run, but can reward you with unique and powerful items.
For example, this is The Last Flame.
If you use it, you will have only one honour for the entire trial, so you will need to do a completely hitless run.
The Trial of Chaos also extends into the endgame.
As you gain inscribed ultimatums of higher and higher levels, the number of chambers that you can go through increases.
In true Vaal style, this allows you to take even more risks for even more rewards.
At endgame, you can progress through up to ten chambers with three bosses on a single run.
Stacking ten tribulations on top of each other will make this a significant challenge, but it's worth it.
The Trial Master will tempt you with items of the Vaal Empire, such as Vaal Orbs.
Vaal Orbs are powerful crafting items that corrupt your gear with random mysterious outcomes.
Corruption prevents an item from being modified further, so it has to be the last step of your craft, but it's also the most impactful one.
For example, if you use one on your body armour, it might add a new powerful enchantment, or it might reroll up to half of its modifiers.
Vaal Orbs also have the ability to add a socket, allowing you to bypass the normal restriction of how many sockets an item can have.
A body armour could get up to three sockets this way, allowing for a significant number of mods.
Vaal Orbs can even modify uniques.
Adding enchantments or sockets to uniques can make them incredibly powerful, but there is a good chance that you will break them as well.
The Trial Master will also occasionally offer you Soul Cores.
Originally formed by Chaos, the Vaal sought to replicate Soul Cores through human sacrifice rituals and blood magic to power their civilisation.
Soul Cores are powerful socketable items, with mods that cannot be obtained from regular runes.
Like all endgame content, there is of course a pinnacle boss.
The final chamber will drop keys to this mysterious door.
Some say this is where the Trial Master himself resides.
Perhaps you are willing to take the risk to find out.
Had enough yet?
Because there is still just one more thing.
The most difficult content in Path of Exile 2.
While mapping, you might come across this fortress that has emerged from underground, surrounded by an enormous maze riddled with danger.
Is the maze preventing something from getting in? Or something getting out?
This fortress is of ancient origin, and its construction has similarities to the towers and tablets that you have been using on your journey through the endgame.
It is clear from the entrance that there are three keys required to enter.
Local factions are vying for access to the fortress in order to seize the power they believe will be inside.
Each of the faction's leaders have managed to get their hands on one of the keys, so you will need to defeat them.
Each faction is led by an Uber Act boss.
You can see one of them inhabiting this city, but in order to fight him, you will first need to defeat their two lieutenants in the adjacent zones.
Be careful.
If you fail against either of the lieutenants, or to kill the leader, they will move on, and you will need to find them again.
Kill all the Uber bosses and you will gain access to the fortress.
We aren't going to spoil it, as we can't wait to see you guys attempt it for the first time.
But is there a tree you get points in after killing it?
Of course there is.
This is Path of Exile. There is always another tree.
So these are your challenges for PoE 2.
As you can see, this project is crazy huge.
Way bigger than even we expected when we started out.
But how do you gain access?
Well, during early access you'll need a key to get in.
To thank our existing PoE supporters who have spent more than $480 US dollars, we'll be giving you guys a key for the PC version for free.
Anyone else who wants one can get one by purchasing one of the new early access supporter packs that have just been released to the store.
If you just want early access to PoE 2, then you can get a key in the $30 US dollar early access pack.
The pack also comes with $30 of points to spend in the MTX store.
But we also have a variety of other supporter packs filled with exclusive microtransactions, points to spend in the store, and even physical items.
The cosmetics can be used right now in PoE 1 and in Path of Exile 2 when early access starts.
Most of this footage has been recorded in Path of Exile 1, since that's where you can use them immediately.
The Lord of Ogham supporter pack contains a cosmetic armour set befitting of the Count of Ogham himself.
There is also a matching back attachment which has an alternate variant depicting the influence of corruption.
Also in this pack you can find a portal formed of the rusted armour of the fallen soldiers in the Red Veil of Ogham.
And the offspring of a vicious crowbell boss found in the hunting grounds.
This one doesn't look so vicious though.
On top of that you'll receive the Iron Counts Zwei-Hander to apply to your one-handed or two-handed swords.
For those who are wanting to decorate your hideouts with fond memories and tales of Path of Exile's history,
you will also get a series of hideout statues.
This pack contains the statue of Hillock.
For Path of Exile 1's closed beta, each pack contained a true New Zealand icon, the Kiwi.
Following this tradition, all packs in this series will also contain a new themed Kiwi pet.
The pet will loyally follow you into battle, but run away at the first sign of trouble.
Become the ruler of the desert with the King of the Farad'n supporter pack.
Show your mastery of traversing the sands of the Vasteri plains.
The body armour will allow you to glide along the ground with ancient sand magic.
Now each armour set comes with body armour, boots, gloves and helmet.
But the boots are covered in sand.
If you'd prefer to show them off, you can turn the gliding off if you want.
The accompanying back attachment equips you with two powerful pillars that can control and manipulate lightning.
They will periodically release their energy in a powerful blast while in town,
and hover in a circle around you, arcing lightning between them forming a barrier of energy.
Replace the appearance of any bow with the Farad'n's Glory skin.
Or replace the appearance of a spear with the Tyranny's End spear skin.
This spear skin can be applied to staves and war staves in Path of Exile 1.
If you want to truly show your worth as a King of the Farad'n, then you definitely need your trusty, moving entire city fortress known as the Dreadnaught to travel across the Vasteri plains.
In Path of Exile you can decorate your hideout however you like, and it's no exception here.
It comes with a variety of thematic elements to use, or use decorations from elsewhere in the game.
Additionally, you will get the Deshret's Blessing level up effect.
The King of the Farad'n Kiwi pet.
And last but not least, a statue depicting the Vile Oversoul from Path of Exile 1.
For those who don't know how supporter packs work, each pack comes with all of the cosmetics from the previous tier, so you will get all the items from the Lord of Ogham supporter pack as well.
The Thaumaturge of the Vile supporter pack features an armour set and back attachment themed around the Vile and their pursuit of science and progress.
You can find the Soulcore weapon effect in this pack, which causes Thaumaturgic energy harnessed from Sacrifice to spill from your weapon.
This pack also contains Dooyani's Idol.
It replaces the default appearance of any foci to an ancient relic once used by Dooyani, and this can be applied to shields in Path of Exile 1.
That's not the only Vile weapon you'll find. It also contains the Wand of the Thaumaturge skin.
And the Royal Sacrifice dagger skin.
You wouldn't think to put sacrificial gems on a Kiwi, but the Vile did.
Thaumaturge of the Vile supporters will receive the Thaumaturge of the Vile Kiwi pet.
And the Statue of Dominus. This is also the first pack in the series with a physical item.
When purchasing this pack, you'll receive a Path of Exile 2 logo t-shirt.
But if you don't want one, you can opt out and return for additional points to spend in the store.
Becoming a Warlord of the Kaorui supporter will grant you an armor set and back attachment, adorned in jade carvings and iridescent feathers resembling power.
Enough to even impress the Ancestral Gods, specifically Tukuhama, the Kaorui God of War.
Overkill, you say? I think the Kaorui people would disagree.
Why not drop a gigantic totem on rare enemies you slay to crush them to a pulp?
Replace your crafting bench in your hideout with the Ancestral Canoe crafting bench,
where Ancestral Chief Mata will summon a giant canoe manned by Kaorui warriors to aid in your crafting desires.
We must all start somewhere.
You'll also get a pair of weapon skins.
Equip Akoya's Felling Axe skin to your one-hand or two-handed axes,
or Tukuhama's Crusher to your one-handed or two-handed maces.
A true Kaorui warlord is always accompanied by their trusty Kiwi.
Equipped with armor and harnessing Ancestral Magic, they make the perfect sidekick.
Once one of the most feared beings in Wraeclast, Malachi was slain by a powerful exile.
May the statue commemorate the virtue of exile's past, present and of the future.
Of course, it's not all about dressing up in game.
You'll want to look good in real life too.
By becoming a Warlord of the Kaorui supporter, you'll also get a Path of Exile 2 hoodie.
Our final tier of supporter pack in this series is the Liberator of Wraeclast supporter pack.
The Liberator of Wraeclast armor set and back attachment come made with the finest materials in Wraeclast,
and shattered glass mosaics suspended in divine power.
Set up your base of operations in the Beacon of Salvation hideout.
Why restrict yourself to just one island when you can liberate more?
The Beacon of Salvation hideout comes equipped with your own collection of small islands and personal operators of boats that you can use to row between them.
Just walk to the piers, click a boat to enter and navigate as you choose.
Decorate each island as you see fit to best represent your well-earned hideout.
Everyone in your hideout can use their own boat. Why not have some racers?
You can also get the Window to Twilight portal effect.
A beautiful mosaic piece of art that shatters and reveals a gateway to your desired destination as you approach it.
As you walk away, the glass magically reforms back to its original form.
Rule in style with the Throne of the Ruler map device.
Sure, this map device can create portals to endgame maps, but it also comes with a throne you can sit on to oversee your growing kingdom.
Look down on the plebeians running your maps.
Being the Liberator though is not just about sitting in your throne all day.
If you do decide to join the fight yourself, you can leave a High Priest in charge as your second in command.
Liberator of Rhaeclast supporters will also get a set of varied weapon skins.
The Light of Divinity Scepter skin.
The Deliverance Crossbow skin.
The Justice Flail skin.
And the Redemption Shield skin.
Once again, you'll have an Accompany in Kiwi, and of course a statue depicting one of the most iconic events in Rhaeclast's history.
The battle between a powerful exile and Kitava, the Insatiable.
With the help of two deities, Sin and Innocence, the exile was able to defeat him once and for all.
This supporter pack also contains the Path of Exile 2 art book.
This 215 page full colour art book includes a huge amount of amazing concept art and lore, produced during the long and exciting journey of Path of Exile 2's development.
And finally, Path of Exile has a tradition of letting the community participate in designing game features.
For Path of Exile 2 we'll be adding the Twilight Order foil reliquary.
By becoming a Liberator of Rhaeclast supporter, once Path of Exile 2 is released, you will be able to select any unique item you have found, and be able to drop it from the reliquary.
Once players have submitted their items, keys to the reliquary will start dropping, and other players will be able to find foil versions of uniques that you have submitted along with a message for the lucky player.
The more players submit the same unique, the more chances there will be for the reliquary to drop them, so choose wisely.
Now almost all of these items are available to use in PoE 1 right now.
There are a few exceptions where the item class clearly doesn't exist, such as crossbows or flails.
And there are also a few microtransactions on weapon types that are unavailable in PoE 2 at the start of Early Access.
Once classes that use those weapon types are added, those microtransactions will be available to use.
If you can't decide which supporter pack to choose yet, you can always start with the Early Access Supporter Pack, that just includes a key and some points to spend in the store.
Then you can upgrade to any of the following tiers at a later date.
These Supporter Packs will be available for purchase throughout Early Access.
We'd really like to thank you for your ongoing support. Without you guys, Path of Exile 2 could not have happened.
Now, I'm sure you guys have a lot of questions. Stick around, because coming up next, we have a live Q&A with Ziggy D.
We'll see you next time.
To the post-show discussion and Q&A. I hope you all enjoyed what you've seen so far.
It's been pretty exciting for us here as well, as you guys have been inspired already just watching things and already cooking a new ascendancy class.
Yeah, for sure.
You've got to do design whenever you can.
Absolutely.
There's been a few fun moments here already.
But I'm your host, Ziggy D, and I'm joined by Jonathan and Mark to talk about everything you've seen.
Honestly, it's so much.
I mean, we were really keen to make sure that when we went into Early Access that people didn't feel like it was just, you know, limping along and kind of, you know, just like a minimal amount of content.
We really wanted to kind of blow people away.
So hopefully people feel like, yeah, there is enough content.
Because, yeah, it was certainly a mission to get all that stuff in.
Yeah, I did come here expecting that there would be, you know, maybe a basic mapping placeholder endgame and your three acts and, you know, the half the classes.
But you've made a decision here, clearly, that's got to go to the core POE player community in mind.
Absolutely.
So, I mean, we have to make sure.
Like, I mean, look, Path of Exile's endgame is kind of known for the fact that you get to choose between different types of content and that, like, you know, some people enjoy one thing, some people enjoy another.
And I feel like that choice is like a huge part of what makes it good.
So if we didn't have that when we entered endgame, then I don't think that would be, you know, like, that wouldn't be a Path of Exile endgame.
So that's kind of what we have to make sure of.
So we kind of said, okay, well, like, what is the minimum number of, like, different endgame things you need to be able to have in order to be able to actually have a viable endgame that you feel like you get different choices?
And that's how we ended up with what we have here.
I definitely feel like a lot of games nowadays release, you know, and their campaigns intact real good.
You get to the endgame and it just falls real flat.
Yeah.
And it was certainly a very important moment for us when we were like, hold on, that's the wrong thing to do.
Like, let's not make the same mistake as everyone else.
Let's pivot.
And we actually did that.
And like, it made a world of difference and made the game all of a sudden, you know, a hundred times bigger with an infinite amount more content.
Right.
It was definitely hard, though, because like, okay, like, so we're, you know, we're progressing.
It's like we would have, we would have made it.
We would have gotten, you know, all these acts in if we hadn't have changed direction.
It's like to actually say, you know what, we're going to specifically not finish this content.
We'll be working on, you know, that we, that we, that we, you know, it's like pins down everyone.
We're stopping work on this.
We're going to move over to end games.
It's actually more important.
Like that was certainly a hard one.
That would have been some whiplash there.
I imagine.
I mean, it's like suddenly the whole, you know, like environment art team.
It's like, you know, they were just like, whatever you're working on, just scrap, you don't want to scrap, but you know, just stop it.
We're doing something else now.
So saving clothes.
Yeah.
And for a lot of the developers, cause you got to also think like a lot of our developers have just been working on this campaign for what is it now?
Six years.
I think it's even longer.
Yeah.
It's like, it's just this epic journey.
Whereas none of them, you know, a lot of these people haven't been working on path of Excel one this whole time where, so some of us are like, you know, we're just churning out in game with every league and doing all of that.
But for a lot of these people, a lot of these developers, yeah, it was quite jarring to swap over, but everyone embraced it.
You know, we talked about it.
Everyone was happy about it and stoked about it.
And it just ended up coming out real awesome.
So I think it's landed well.
And it definitely kind of blew me away when you, even before I saw anything, we were in the car on the drive here and you were just info dumping all of the end game.
You're like, Oh, we've got this feature.
We've got this feature.
I'm getting dopamine just from hearing about it.
I haven't even seen anything yet.
But do you guys feel like you're competing against yourselves a little bit here?
Because path of Exiles kind of set the bar.
The original game has set the bar for what is available to end game in a game like this.
And it makes it's not acceptable really to launch with just nothing in terms of end game now.
Absolutely.
I mean, yeah, I mean, like if you're not competing with yourself, then I don't think you're going to make good progress.
Right. So that's what you really have to do.
Yeah. But cracking that out for beta even.
Yep. Absolutely.
I just think it would not have landed nearly as well without that.
And I think it's important that our existing Path of Exile 1 community feels like they're also served.
Like, yeah, sure.
We're doing all this stuff for new players and that's really important and that'll expand the audience.
But, you know, if we launched and all the PeeWee 1 players are unhappy, that wouldn't be good.
Yeah.
So, you know, we have to make sure that they also feel like, you know, they've got a game for both them and for all the new players we hope to bring to the genre.
And you definitely want all those different axes as well.
Like just having two, right?
You'll get a lot of a lot of content can be immediately divisive.
Right.
Obviously, that's the nature of it.
That's how it goes.
Right.
And so you have all of these different avenues because there are different players who like different types of content.
Yeah.
And if there's your one end game system, well, immediately then there is a portion of players who are just like, I don't want this.
Right.
And so having all of these options is like ultra key.
And that is what Path of Exile 1 has taught us.
And again, it's like, I'd say lessons learned, you know, for the genre and it is expanding and other games and stuff.
But yeah, certainly, as you said, competing with ourselves.
Yes.
And it has like, you know, 40 axes, you know, and we've got seven really good ones here and obviously more to come.
But seven is a lot, mind you.
Especially when it's all like, you know, like people have to learn a lot of things again.
Yeah.
It's going to be very interesting to see how long it takes people to do the kind of difficulty for Pinnacle content.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's like we have to, you know, we have to, it's honestly like we actually don't even really know because like you never know what people are going to find in terms of builds and so on.
Like, I'm hoping that it will take people a while to be able to work it out.
But, you know, you never know.
Maybe end of day one, people just like, oh, yeah, easy.
No problem, mate.
You know, it could be what it's like.
A few people that are doing that sort of thing.
I saw like a solo cell phone level 100 in 24 hours or something.
Jeez.
Okay.
This is where we've got it now, is it?
So I imagine there'll be a little bit of a soft reset there for people.
Yeah, for sure.
A relearning period.
There's stuff to learn.
And I mean, PeeWee 2 has changed a lot over the years.
More than five years of development now.
And what was that initial pitch when PeeWee 2 was first put forward as to what it's going
to be?
Because it was much smaller in scope originally.
Yeah.
So when we started, it wasn't even a sequel.
It was just, we're just updating the character ricks.
And over time, it kind of feature creeped into a proper sequel.
But the thing that we were saying is whenever we were talking about it, and I guess this
is the main thing, is that we're like, okay, when we make an area here, it needs to be that
there's like a theme for it.
And whenever it feels unique from everything else, we're not going to just like have recycled
stuff like within the campaign that just feels like, oh, you know, we just took this area
and modified it slightly.
Each one's got to have its own stuff.
It's got to have monsters that were like carefully thought about that like, you know, fit in
with the world.
And it's got to have bosses that are actually like good tier quality.
You know, every area is going to have one.
And so those decisions has kind of been things that have meant that like they really raise
the quality bar to a level that took us way longer than we even really expected.
Like the, those things there just like they, it's huge, right?
Like, honestly, I feel like we underestimated significantly what it would take to deliver
that level of quality.
I remember really early on a battle I fought for.
And I mean, like way back was like, if you think back to say Diablo 2, which obviously
still holds a lot of, you know, power in terms of design motivations and philosophy and stuff
within the company, you get things like the super uniques and POE one did them.
And it's just like, here's a boss with one or two skills.
And I remember very, very, very early on in POE two, I'm like, I want every single boss
to be memorable and a thing.
I don't want a unique monster.
That's just like dies in two seconds and uses heavy strike and has a fancy name.
And I remember, I even got some push back at the time and thinking like, you know, I love
the bosses, my favorite part of everything.
And so I was just like, man, I really, I don't want this.
This is just terrible.
And, but of course that decision, me pushing for that, me wanting that turned into this
megalithic.
Now we have 50 aiming to be a hundred, honestly, probably later, several more hundred once
all the end games, everything start to evolve and more expansions comes out.
And I'm like, yep, we maybe just made, you know, a hundred times more work for ourselves,
but a hundred percent bloody worthwhile because I'd say those bosses are one of the main, you
know, attraction pieces of the game.
And anyone who plays it is just like, holy crap, those boss fights are amazing.
So like, you know, obviously some are bad and some are good to different people and all
that.
That's how it all goes.
That's part of all the fun.
But it is true that me pushing for that thing literally created thousands and thousands and
thousands of hours of work.
Now worthwhile work, but it is again, that exact thing of like, the scope was kind of
small on numerous axes.
And as we just raised it and raised the quality bar to what we thought was good.
Um, it certainly went from, you know, what was it initially just reskinning some character
classes and new rigs or whatever into this like mega scale entire campaign.
Yeah.
Everything, but full standalone, separate game.
One other anecdote since we went out of that territory, it was originally code named project
Chimera.
What?
I don't, I, I, that was, it was this pipe dream.
I've never been a fan of these code names.
It was just like, there were times way back in the original office.
It was all this, like, sometimes there'll be a feature you can't really do in P.O.E.
1.
And it was always like, ah, we'll do it in project Chimera.
That was like amongst the developers.
And people were like, what the heck is that?
Now, ironically, um, there is a boss, uh, in act three called, well, it's got a different
name, but it's called the Chimera internally.
It is a Chimera.
It's a multi-headed beast.
And you've seen in a few of the, um, marketing, you know, things here and here, different trailers,
little snippets of it.
Um, and I think it's just ironic that that, that was actually the first boss asset made
before everything, the first monster, because back in when we used to just make random monsters
and we'll find out how to use them.
And that was made for that game.
It was used in the original P.O.E. 2 trailer.
Right.
It is the only incomplete technically, but only from a balance.
Or was the last boss to finish in the entire path of Exile.
It sounds like there was like some sort of emotional demon that you had to battle there.
Like the legacy of the original idea.
And you had to finish it.
We had a moment with the monster game designers where we're like, oh my God, it's happening.
The Chimera is finally being finished.
Holy.
This is like, yeah, we were effectively like, we need to celebrate this boss finally being
done.
It was like at the origin.
And now it's at this, you know, point where we're about to deploy early access, you know,
not to say the end, because there is, the end is forever away.
Yeah.
It's still the beginning of a journey in many ways.
Yep.
But on that note of celebrating, like, how do you guys feel having now kind of, for the
first time, I feel really like laid bare kind of everything you have, you're putting
it out there and only being two weeks away from everyone playing it.
Well, it's always scary, you know, coming into a release.
And I think especially for, you know, there's like a bunch of people on the PeeWee 2 team
who have, you know, like they have, this is their first game that they're going to be
releasing.
And that experience is something that, you know, like, yeah, like it's tough.
And honestly, I think that even we were feeling a little bit cocky actually about the fact
because, you know, we release, you know, content for PeeWee 1 all the time.
And I feel like we kind of felt like we knew what it took to get a game released.
But honestly, like PeeWee 2 was just a whole entirely different demon as far as getting
things out, right?
Like, it's just way more difficult.
Like when you actually have to make everything, like the whole frickin' thing right from the
ground up again, it's like, wow, there's way more stuff there.
And like, there's even things like the passive tree where it's like, I feel like we underestimated
what it would take to get something like that to an actual releasable state.
Like, that was a huge amount of work.
Just like absolutely colossal to get it to, you know, to get that kind of stuff in shape.
Like, it's just been crazy.
So, yeah, like, obviously it's nerve wracking, you know, coming up to a release day.
But I think we do have something that players are going to really enjoy.
And, you know, like, it's always comforting when, you know, I mean, we had a live event
in LA recently, you know, people, you know, we got to the time limit and everyone's like,
oh man, we don't want to stop, you know.
So, like, I'm really, I think people are going to really enjoy it.
It's been a whole different experience for me here playing this time around as well.
Whereas before I was playing a very buggy kind of internal version of the game that was
very experimental.
Now playing, you know, almost what I'm going to be playing.
Well, I heard you still managed to blow the count up the elevator with some kind of knockback bugs.
I wasn't going to mention that.
Yeah, we have to say, we have to just go with that word.
I did send the Act 1 boss up an elevator with knockback.
It was good.
Intended mechanic.
I thought it was pretty funny.
He was in his like big wolf form and kind of trapped in there.
So just barking at me through the wood.
It's good.
So if you feel a lot, I'm sure there's a few things to work out over this next two weeks.
I hope the team can have a little bit of a rest for a day before they get back into it.
Yeah.
It's been a lot.
So you've done that pivot to the end game focus and got so much for us now to play around
with in the beta.
And it seems like originally I was thinking, you know, we might be playing for a few weeks
here and then, you know, maybe going back over to some part of Exile 1 stuff.
But it seems like you guys want us playing through Christmas.
That would certainly be good.
I mean, look, there's enough stuff there.
I think it will take people a long time to get through.
Yeah.
And I mean, obviously, it's also going to be the first time people playing through a completely
fresh campaign as well.
I think that will take people a fair amount of time.
So, yeah, there's.
And then, of course, the end game as well to explore.
I mean, yeah, it should be pretty significant.
I mean, we've always wanted it to be that Path of Exile 2 leagues, you know, are going
to be, you know, like how PvE 1 leagues are.
Where you play them and you play them for, like, you know, a reasonable amount of time.
Yeah.
And then, you know, sure, you get done with them eventually and then you've got the next
content that comes out.
So, yeah, in order to be able to realize that, you have to have enough of a base to make
that happen.
Yeah.
People are definitely wondering, like, how invested they can get in the beta.
So I definitely want to ask a few questions kind of around that idea.
So, firstly, is there going to be wipes and resets and will there be something before
launch as well?
So we are going to be having new, like, leagues effectively throughout the beta whenever we
launch something significant.
Because, you know, we want to make sure that all of the, you know, effectively that people
are able to play through.
But that stuff will be merged into an early access league.
And effectively, after we go into full release, that league will stick around.
Now, I can't promise that everything about your character will function exactly like how
it did in that thing.
Surely not.
I imagine it will be a glorious kind of snapshot of all of the broken stuff I have.
Yeah, here's all the broken stuff.
But effectively, we can contain all that stuff in the sort of early access league.
And then if you still want to play those characters, you know, like, then you can go right ahead
and do that.
But, you know, the action is always going to be in whatever the most recent league is.
And then, of course, after that point, there'll be a standard that everything goes into, which,
you know, all our economic sins will forever more be archived in standard.
So, yeah, that's, you know, no doubt what will happen.
It's nice that it's not going to be affecting what will be the standard league.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's the idea.
Also that people will be able to kind of get invested in their characters.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, there's even something kind of cool about the idea of making something that will
be like that little historical piece.
Absolutely.
A little collectible.
And I'm sure there'll be some handful of legacy things that only exist in early access
leagues.
So, you know, I guess we'll have to see what comes of the unique balance.
You talked about like the, you know, playing for a week or how long are we expecting?
Well, we sort of remember and a lot of the, you know, a lot of the P.O.E.1 players,
we've thinking very differently to people who are obviously going to experience this
as a new game, but it is a new game, right?
You don't have all these predefined, hyper refined builds to play to immediately, you
know, go through things.
You don't have people coming in with like fully detailed 7 million line, but with build
guides of exactly what to do with what items.
The discovery is going to be there.
The discovery takes time and the discovery is like honestly ultra fun for me.
I love it.
Yeah.
Now those things will emerge after time.
Of course they do completely fine.
But you should remember like there's a lot of game to play here to discover, to learn,
learn about the world, the new narratives, the new world building, the new unique items,
the ascendancy classes, the massive passive tree, which is bigger than P.O.E.1s.
The, like, you know, end game systems, the bosses, that like, it's, it's not going to be this
like, you know, even, you know, I personally, when I appear we won league comes out, for example,
I play for like a month, sometimes a bit longer, sometimes a bit less.
It ultimately also depends largely what's going on here and how much I need to invest here.
So, you know, and there are other people who play for more like three and whatnot, but there's
certainly going to be a much longer time period you can play this for while still discovering
new stuff and not feel like you're finished.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I mean, I don't know if you see that subjective, everyone can pick their own point when they
finish, but if you want to see everything and do everything, you're going to be investing
a lot more time, especially these first time rounds.
And then obviously with every league, there's more to discover, but you get faster at doing
all these parts over and over and over again.
You'll get more efficient over time.
That's how the game works.
So yeah, I would expect a lot of time to be sunk into this to fully explore it to start
with like a lot, you know, not a week, not two weeks.
You're going to be going far, far longer than that if you want to see everything.
You know, it's up to you.
Play at your own pace.
See how you want to go.
Learn at your own pace.
That's the beauty of a new game as well, which we haven't been able to experience with
Path of Exile 1, you know, or other games for so long is actually discovering the entire
world.
And yeah, there's some familiar mechanics at the end game and stuff like that, which is
awesome for people.
Yeah, I certainly want to really, I'm very excited to see people discovering the new
things and getting so excited about it.
I can tell you're amped for watching people go through that discovery process.
I'm maybe even diving at yourself a bit.
100%.
I mean, I love sitting there in Path of Building as many of us do, but I am very excited for
that.
That new discovery process for a while.
I think you were saying how much you were part spreadsheet.
I think I'm like, I think I was saying I'm like maybe 60% spreadsheet, 40% discovery
and there's my play archetype.
You know, so.
Coming up with our player profiles and teamy spikes and things like that.
We're both of exiled characters.
The discovery part of me is ultra excited.
And I, and I'll mind you, that's coming from someone who kind of knows all the content.
I'm still, because there's something different about making it versus actually playing it live
with the players, seeing them discover it, uniques being linked in chat and on Reddit
and all of that is just so, so, so cool.
So we're going to get a massive dose of that.
And it is like genuinely exciting to just see how people are going to think, you know,
what's worth one chaos or what's with 10 chaos, what's worth the high.
If chaos is even the metric.
Is chaos even the currency that people settle on already?
We were arguing about this earlier.
I'm pretty sure that one C spam in chat might turn into one E.
Cause like, you know, one exalt, given that exalt is now.
I think it'll be chaos.
People probably, I've removed will still be.
People don't appreciate by the way.
Like, so when we say we've increased them,
you're going to be getting multiple exalts in act one in, in Peewee 2.
Like we actually have increased that a lot.
It isn't just like an idle, you know, like thing.
I can say exalts becoming the new kind of like chaos.
Yeah.
And then chaos being the new device.
I actually agree.
Um, but we'll, yeah, we'll see.
That's my point.
It's the economy, right?
Like who even knows?
The market will have to.
But I like they were already arguing about this.
It's good fun.
Um, so, uh, do you have some kind of like beta release roadmap for updates and things
like that for people to look forward to with that?
I mean, we certainly did have one six months ago when we, but now that we're,
but now that we're, uh, you know, now that we're sort of getting to, to release,
it's like, Oh my God.
Like, you know, we have to look at it.
So, I mean, look, I, I, I, I don't think it'll be any less than six months.
And, um, I think it could any, could easily end up being more.
Um, I certainly don't want to, I mean, look 2025, I think really want to, uh, to, to
be, you know, full release in 2025.
I, I don't really want to be spending more than a year.
Um, that would be, um, that would be pretty crazy.
But I mean, honestly, like we have to get all the content finished, um, and all that
sort of stuff.
Um, you know, we always feel like we underestimate these things.
Uh, and of course we have to, um, learn what we need to learn.
We have to get the game to the point when it is, uh, really fun.
Um, you know, we have to, we have to, um, make sure that like all of the things that,
you know, we've got the difficulty right for all the players, we've got the economy right,
like all this stuff.
I mean, there's a lot of things that we're going to, you know, we have to sort out.
And so I kind of have a feeling that the first few weeks at least are going to just be a scramble
of like, you know, um, oh crap, someone like worked this crazy thing out and we found this thing.
And like, you know, the, the, that, that's always scary.
Um, you know, because it's just, uh, when we add content to POE1, it's like at least the kind of base of stuff
that we have is kind of, you know, well tested and people know kind of what's going on with it.
But, uh, here it's like just complete new world.
And we're the kind of game that has a lot of ability for players to do stuff that we wouldn't anticipate.
Um, you know, we have, um, the, the, you know, just the way support gems work and everything like that.
So I just, there's certainly a lot of worry that like, there's just going to be builds that are like completely ridiculous
that we just never anticipated combining certain things in different ways.
We don't expect, you know, with hundreds of support gems, it can be like that.
So, uh, you know, that's going to be an interesting one.
It will happen.
Yeah, for sure.
It is inevitable, right?
Like there's nothing we can even do about it because you, you, you need hundreds and thousands of hours of testing to be able to do that with what can only be done with hundreds of thousands of players.
Um, and, but that's also the magic of it all, which is awesome.
That's why I was asking you, like, are you literally really doing 12 classes in 36 sentences?
Like actually?
Yeah, absolutely.
We have, we have, we know what we want to do.
It's a bit unhinged.
It is a bit.
Um, but, uh, you know, uh, we, we like a challenge.
I mean, you know, the, the, the studio that produces a passive skill tree, like we do, uh, clearly, uh, has a bit of a glutton for punishment, uh, for the card to just like mixing.
You totally put it on six and then like, I don't know, added more later in an expansion or something.
Um, yeah, I mean, maybe we could have, I mean, look, this is the point.
This is the plan.
Um, you know, I mean like as you go through, as people go through early access, it's going to feel like there's just expansion content coming up pretty frequently.
Um, just because, you know, we have all the stuff that we kind of, you know, got some of the way, a lot of the way through.
So yeah, there's, there's stuff that come in.
Look, I'm pretty sure like I really want to get the Druid out.
Like we announced it, we've talked about it.
Um, it's a lot of fun.
Um, you know, I'm keen to get that out there as soon as we can.
Um, you know, the Huntress, we've talked a bunch about as well.
There's like, those kinds of things I think will be, you know, we'll be able to move, uh, towards those pretty quick.
Um, but, uh, you know, there's, yeah, obviously more to do.
The other thing you mentioned talking roadmap like things is, um, we've always been, you know, it's hard to predict because a lot of what will happen is, and what we leave space for is reacting to what the players want.
Mmhmm . . . and so if you plan everything for so
Yeah.
You're gonna have very, very, very slow reaction times to fixing, you know, or adding certain content with them.
You know, maybe the issues are other campaign needs more events or this class, needs more of this or something.
So if you're planning, then you're going to be delivering on what they want.
want solved like a year down the line or even longer and where we like to remain very very
dynamic and like you know you want to be able to fix that stuff like oh well this is the main
problem like sure obviously you need more than a week sometimes most of the time but we want it
generally to be that the next releases expansions updates whatever can alleviate as many of those
problems as possible so yeah the you try not to get too strict with the planning is generally
been our philosophy because especially when it comes to actually having the live service product
out because that is very very important otherwise you're you're never going to seem like you're doing
what people want and what are you doing if not that so that actually is good point like i was going to
ask what do you folks what does the team want out of the beta because obviously it's like a good way
to market the game but it's also you know key to shaping the game in the future like the actual
beta it's not just early access i think one of the most important things i think it's going to be
really good for the development team to get back into a live mindset and like get it back into the
idea of like everything we make is ship is shipping people are seeing this like get back into this you
know people are seeing you know like actually getting back on that and like yeah like and like being
able to sort of see directly like okay we make something that goes in the game people like it don't
like it like that kind of stuff like and that that really like that has been our studio for like
most of its lifetime obviously we know before we released pw1 it wasn't but after that point i mean we are a
company like we are a company that likes to think that we can do live service better than anyone else like
that is our goal um and so like getting back into that again you know for the entire for everyone
in the studio so that everyone's working on things that are going to be releasing within you know
certainly in less time than you know than three months away um is i think be really really good
for us again um i look forward to just being able to do that because these these long term like really
long term things like that span over years so you go so long without proper feedback like stuff kind
of gets made and then like yeah you know it's not really in a real game and so it doesn't probably lose
perspective and you absolutely lose perspective on this stuff so i think that um that's just going
to be a really great to get back to that again yeah i honestly as you said it is early access it is a
beta period and i'd say you know personally speaking the thing that and we we mentioned it briefly about
the character balance and the builds that are broken and all that that's obviously pretty useful to me
right yeah plus we have other systems in there like you know the checkpointing system right you
have to kill the boss in one life you know these are things we haven't mass tested and obviously other
games have and they work and that's awesome um there are other things like you know the end game system
is a little bit less forgiving and that if you die you fail the map right these things are things that
we obviously need to test and iterate on in the future by adjusting the difficulty and stuff like that
and you especially as you get towards this point of um you know the end game like okay act one has
been tested like crazy yeah right and you get less and less testing as it goes on because you get
less um people you know they've just been around for less time and so yeah it's going to be a huge
amount of iteration and feedback and from the players and us just you know re-evaluating all the stuff
and the thing is we're always dynamic about that stuff like we'll just change things if it's wrong
we'll redesign it we'll come up with a new way um jonathan's a firm believer of if a doesn't work
and b doesn't work then we'll find c we'll find option c we'll find option d and we'll keep changing
things and we'll make it work so yeah it's going to be a lot of that iteration on our design decisions
how forgiving because like the game is pretty hard you know it can be pretty hard and so when you're on
that fine line of like you know things are difficult um you know it's not too easy to know if you've
tilted one way or the other so you know finding what everyone agrees should be the common corrected
difficulty is something that i will obviously be paying very very very close attention to it's a
pretty hard thing to nail down when you are making the game um and so you've we've seen that a lot
where you folks have been pretty willing to change and then re-change and re-change again some of the
core features like flasks and the waypointing system and portals and keeping that kind of mindset
going into the beta then of course i mean look we're always willing to change stuff like that flask thing
like the most recent change to that was like ultra recent um yeah like uh i don't have we even had
like a a closed beta of that yet was that no i think i think we haven't yeah but i mean i think
it's way better than it was like it's uh the things things have improved a lot and honestly like that's
one of those things we've been wanting to do something to sort out flasks for ages yeah and it
really came about because um when actually looking at what new players were having trouble with when
they were playing flask piano was actually like even from the very beginning of the game actually ended up
being one of those things that like people just had probably just like just the manual dexterity
required to like hit all your different flask keys and then uh like no like you have to know when one
of your flasks has run out so you can move to the next one and like various things like that like all
that stuff actually was like just a weirdly a large amount of mechanical complexity right from the very
beginning um and then even at endgame i don't think it was really that satisfying either because you
ended up with like you know just like having to press all these buttons all the time and obviously it's
all utility flasks that people are using at endgame um and then we kind of tried to band-aid
this in poe one with the um you know some of the flask automation stuff that was added there
but there was still this idea that um uh that you're still more powerful if you uh don't automate
so therefore you know like it's like you know it's like there's that trade-off there so um you're just
more powerful if you get mage blood really sure i guess i guess i mean it's all automated and you're
very sure all right but um you know so the point is effectively that the charm stuff that we're doing
effectively means that you no longer the game is making that decision of like you know the that stuff will
be automated you no longer have to do that like crazy flask piano to get the best um you know the
best out of your character and i think that is definitely a step in the right direction um and
uh the other thing as well is it actually makes the the crafting uh more meaningful i think on the
flasks because when you've got like uh five slots then um like the individual mods and the individual
stuff like seems to tend to not matter as much i mean obviously you know people want instant
recovery and things like that but you know like the uh the but but like now it's like the actual
it's much more meaningful like on your life flask the choice between do i want instant or do i want way
more uh like life like that kind of stuff actually can be a lot more meaningful once you've only got
one um so yeah i think i think it is a lot better personally you have uh we'll we'll jump ahead to
flask since we're on the topic you have um uh locked in effectively the fact that there's a mana flask
there now so that there's always going to be a mana flask and how does that how does that tie into
your design for mana and are we always going to be using mana flask slot or um if we solve another way
what does it do you can absolutely solve another way and then you'll just have a flask slot that isn't doing
anything for sure um but i think it kind of has to work that way because we um really don't want
um yeah like once you sort of start getting into changing changing that around um i feel like it's
the system sort of starts to break with regard to like you know the the feeling of like i know where
mana is i know where my health is like that kind of stuff that being said you know we've always got
uniques and stuff like that um i believe there's already yeah there is a unique there's a unique
that allows you to equip two yeah but the thing is then that's a build choice that you're making
uh so it's a little bit different um and that's fine um but uh yeah i think the the system as it
works now just yeah it's a lot easier so it does sound like on the mana side of things then that
there are going to be multiple angles of solving mana of course we've got leech um edition number 475
uh is how it works uh and uh we've finally got it right this time um so you know um the the and
yeah i think it works i think it's good so i think that leech uh it'll be more common i'm not gonna have to
like crack out the leech diagram showing the different buckets and things like i was saying
i think i think that leech might be no i think i was gonna say leech is one of the topics in the
studio that has most of them wasted the most designer time of anything in the industry but i actually
don't think it's that i think the actual worst offender is what stats should decks give you i
think that that is like that one has wasted so there's so many arguments about that i feel like
that one's never come to the fore like we know we know about the leech one but no one is happy
about giving accuracy but no one has a better idea than what accuracy that it can give and like
everyone's gonna come up with like and chat a bit i bet they'll be like saying oh you know it can
give this or this whatever um but uh there's like yeah seriously there's been endless arguments about
that topic it's like it's outrageous uh yeah yeah yeah hmm you've got me thinking about it now yeah
i mean speed would be good but then i know it's probably too much
something like decks you should yeah deck stacking speed we can get all the designers down here right now
i know we'll just have it we'll just have it out again we'll just have it out again the longest q a
of all time yeah yeah it's already gonna be that sometimes you're just like just you start the day
you're like here are the problems we need to solve and then you're like what about the
accuracy on decks comes up again it's 3 p.m and we're still discussing dexterity yeah yeah
so just make it accuracy exactly exactly that is literally how it comes back to accuracy every time
this is okay yeah um rewinding a little bit um we can't forget our roots with path of exile one of
course so for the poe one enjoyers uh what is the plan for poe one during the course of this beta is
there going to be leagues launching uh is it on the back burner yeah um it absolutely will be leagues
launching now i can't i don't know the exact date but the plan is kind of late february but i mean look
it's it's we'll see what happens i will admit that unfortunately we did have to steal a few poe one
resources just towards the end here um which is uh the kind of a been a bit unfortunate i really
wish we didn't have to but uh yeah as i said we kind of underestimated some of the stuff but
um everyone is going to be going back to p we won again um for the uh february for the february league
um and uh you know we're going to make sure that we can we can do that like one of the things that
um was a big problem for our studio when we had a long-term project and a short-term project yeah
is that um you know you've always had that thing of like it's always you always want to work on the
short-term thing yeah so now that we've got two short-term things uh coming up actually it's going
to be a bit easier to prioritize in some respects because you know it's like it's all it's just like
it's all that stuff is then um you know it's like coming up soon so uh but we'll see we'll see how it
goes but uh yeah we need to get that p we won expansion out next yeah obviously you know i just
want to always make it clear that you know the reason why things can't be so planned out is again
we're just releasing this game yeah um obviously we pivoted to end game and then that needed more
resources and then of course combined with the fact that um you know things obviously change
there are unpredictable things in the environment we can't necessarily guarantee and then of course
you have um you know uh christmas coming up and all of that right there's so many variables to
consider and but we also don't know how much time is going to be invested necessarily or need to be
invested into live operations for post-release how many problems are going to go wrong how many
builds how many of the uniques are broken how many you know and where do all these resources go
there are like just millions of variables here to consider and so like it can get very very difficult
especially at this time but once you release you have a uh a bit of a grace period so to speak
where more like a period of extreme amounts of fire where we're putting out fires everywhere
but we have a we have a period where we're fixing everything you get everything stable and then we're
going to be like all right let's recalibrate figure everything out and what is our plans and then
establish all of that based also on the feedback we get from that you know period where everything's
on fire um not to make it sound like it's gonna be bad but that is the inevitability is that there's
always problems hopefully it appears good from a player perspective but there's always going to be
there's always going to be like oh my god people found this and you know like yeah we don't have to
see all the fires yeah like ideally ideally the best thing is when we're able to fix some kind of
exploit before people even hear about it yeah and when i say exploit i'm just talking about some broken
thing like if we like so we obviously normally have to worry about like the whole mid-league nerf
concept but it's like if you can if you can deal with something within like an hour or two of it
happening then it's like you're kind of okay because um you know that no one had a chance to kind of
like everyone everyone didn't swap their build over to it or whatever yeah um but uh yeah we're gonna be
really on the ball for pwee 2 just because there's so many things that are new well i mean look we
have several bosses with several elevators how many of them can be pushed up the elevator you know
what i mean well that's what i mean when i say a fire i'm talking about bosses getting pushed up
elevators like that's not okay yeah i am liking my mercenary flashbang knockback is very fun
right yeah you need to look into that by the way the whole flashbang uh i feel like you're gonna nerf my
build yeah yeah stay away from my grenada already yeah
no no these are the fun things discovering that stuff can be very fun for the players it's just
internally it's like oh no we have to what are we doing it can get a little bit panicky after release
you know and it you know there's lots of things going on you're like oh geez what do i solve first
but um obviously you know it's the same as pwee 1 we're good at it at this point um got some
experience yeah you uh aren't going to be torturing us with like releasing beta stuff at the same time as
pwee 2 league launch pwee 1 league launches yeah the plan is to uh keep them separated a bit
from each other so that uh you know you get a chance to play they make me choose
so uh we saw a cinematic to put it lightly it was pretty that was quite epic and uh i know it's
been cooking for quite some time and uh that was pretty exciting but we've also seen just a lot of
story stuff happening you know on a much higher level than previously now so yeah stepping up your
storytelling game here a bit yeah so we're really wanting to make sure that the storytelling in pwee 2
is much better than what it was in pwee 1 um like you know there's a lot more kind of um
i guess uh like that kind of like stuff with the like the introductions to boss fights and the outros
and things like that like all that stuff we've just got a lot more storytelling going in um all of
those um all those things um we do have the intro cutscene there's also um can kind of like light
like between the acts there's these kind of like more kind of uh motion graphic type uh cutscenes just
kind of established things and there might be some more surprises later on in the game as well
uh not in early access unfortunately uh later on that uh that we can uh that you can see as well
but ultimately we just want to make sure that um like i think a lot of people who got through the
pwee 1 story had no idea what was happening by the end um and so uh effectively want to make sure
that that is not the case this time around that people really are able to absorb things but guilty
one thing i will say though is that it's ultra important to us that we don't break the feeling
that like when you're playing a second time that like that it feels like we don't want it to feel
annoying the second time yeah we were talking about this this morning yeah yeah don't take the
control out of the player exactly so yeah i'm a personally a believer of the fact that if you
just change if when you change the camera position for a cutscene um immediately it feels way more
annoying like because there's this whole this whole thing of like like if you click on an npc and like
the camera changes position like sure when you're playing through the campaign the first time
um that kind of thing is like you know like that can be cool but um then the the if if you're um
uh like you're playing through the you know second third fourth fifth time you want to just be able to go to
the npc and click click click and just get past and without feeling like uh you've you've had to
sort of worry about anything so um yeah like effectively we want to make sure that it's still
um that we still have that you know because ultimately you know we're a game you expect
people to people to play through many times so ideally we can kind of deliver both the situation
where the first time you play through it it feels like an amazing story that you're getting that
you're taking seriously that you're understanding that you you know there's like all those sort of
touch points and um you know little little um you know things just all through while also
maintaining the fact that if you know what you're doing it's like you don't have to go talk to
some quest giver just to get a quest like you could just go do the thing you know without
having to talk to someone about it first um so uh you know that kind of stuff is really important
just to make the you know that that stuff work well when you when you know what you're doing
yeah you said something this morning that stuck with me where you said like part of exile is a
game where the player's meta knowledge is allowed and encouraged absolutely absolutely
you're allowed to cheat this quest effectively there's what the character knows and there's what
the player knows and in our game what the player knows is needs to be sufficient as far as like
being able to progress the storyline if you can you're not you don't want to have it so you just
talk to mbc just to find out something you already knew as a player um yeah like if you know you kill
this boss you get the next area's waypoint so you just like kill it log out log in
right i love doing that
yeah um so you explained to me the other day the um kind of the context for the beast and how that leads
into the cutscene in the beginning of uh pwee 2 from pwee 1 and that i think helped put it in a lot more
perspective for me and made me appreciate and understand what's going on yeah yeah so effectively
what you're seeing in the opening cutscene is effectively the um a new uh a new seed of a beast
um that um is going to be uh is growing now in pwee 1 um you know the beast uh the beast was killed
and then uh what happened in response to that is a bunch of all the gods in the world were able to
um uh you know were able to effectively rise again and you killed a bunch of them but um there are more
uh you know in the world uh and effectively um you know we don't want to spoil too much about the
storyline overall but effectively obviously someone here uh you know the count is wanting to uh harness
the power of the beast once again um and then we have the uh mysterious figure there who is saying
you know uh no don't do this this always turns out badly uh you know comment in chat that i loved
that was like stop opening eldritch boxes exactly exactly why do people keep doing this yeah yeah i
i would yeah if someone handed you a mysterious orb wouldn't you press the button i mean yeah
yeah exactly exactly exactly yeah yeah i mean i'm gonna try but who knows how many hours it's gonna
take me indeed indeed so um we had a fun moment earlier where you were watching it and you were
like oh we really need need to rename that passive because he's a karui and and it's a wolf it's called a
great wolf's hound the great wolf obviously being in it so he went out is a might history
started telling him i stomped out of the room and i was like we need to rename that notable he's karui
and then i was kindly reminded that actually he was an orphan who an orphan and was adopted by
a isomite and raised and so yes there is a mixture of karui and isomite background and i was like
it works you were wrong fair enough i walked back in here all sad and yeah whatever my bad
it's fine the name is good he looked so chastised when he came back in but that just like
points to the fact that i feel like you're doing a lot more with the characters here for sure you
even mentioned that ascendancy stuff is going to have an impact story-wise um like with that's
why we just think a lot about this kind of stuff so the uh the acolyte of and i always get this
name wrong the acolyte of is it chalula chayula i always say this wrong um so uh the acolyte of
chayula for example um so that we have this sort of storyline with the origins of the monks where
there's like an order of monks who uh worship a uh thing they call the dreamer and uh the dreamer
is actually uh uh chayula so um and they don't know this so they're effectively worshiping a
breach demon so uh the acolyte of chayula is effectively you embracing the fact that i'm
worshiping a breach demon i'm just going to go all the way just and uh you know i'm in too deep now
yeah exactly we're just gonna we're just gonna do it so uh yeah there's a lot of thinking like that
that goes into these things like you know what is the history of these uh people like you know
because i think a lot of that stuff inspires uh interesting mechanics as well so for example
on that one you've got that into the breach skill which kind of means you know you're always in a
breach all the time you can see the like you know things going on like that stuff is i think that
there's a lot of cool inspiration there so coming up with that storyline stuff um for for that stuff
just i think just yeah there's a couple other little little things that i think is cool as well and
hopefully people will notice and pay attention to so there's one of the bosses that was shown as uh
uses a lot of time or chronomancy and um interestingly if you are a uh sorceress and
you ascend to chronomancer and you then go to fight that boss um if you for example try to use time
freeze uh the boss is like yeah there are no that doesn't work on me and has a dialogue line and if
you cast temporal chains on them he's like you know just puts it back on you and it's like yeah and so
there's interesting things like that and it doesn't like change things on a grand scale right it doesn't
make a certain class not viable or anything like that but there's this interesting little quirks and
quips everywhere different bosses have different intro lines depending on what class you're playing
um they have different skill lines sometimes depending on what class you're playing yeah um
we've got different dialogue all through the campaign for different classes like the um the
sorceress i was obviously from the maraketh when she goes back to the maraketh there's kind of a
little backstory there about how she was banished originally um so you know she needs to find a way that
you know to be she needs to be accepted back into their culture again uh you know like we've got things like uh
you know the character we talked about earlier um so the warrior you know was an orphan um you know he
uh he was brought up by actually one of the npcs in act one town so obviously there's a whole
different dialogue there because he's effectively his adopted son you know we've got things like that
um there's there's a lot of thought that's gone into you know just trying to make it feel like all
these character classes have some level of involvement with the world you know they didn't just come into
existence the moment that you there's um other little things so like more on the narrative side
obviously we saw the world map you have the icons that show different things that are in
each act like all the things you want to explore find and yeah awesome but each of them also has a
little bit of a kind of a little bit of text on them as well and like for example the um there's one
in one of the first areas in the game that's just like a camp of iron count guards and um you know
we showed it in a trailer when the when the ranger class trailer we did um you know whenever it was
you saw the ranger shoot some of the kill some of them because they were trying to like hurt a child
you know and the child was just trying to get some food and the ranger just like snipes them with
arrows and kills them ruthlessly and so you read this thing and you're like you know you hear whispers
of an iron count you know uh scouting party that was slain by a rogue archer or something like that
so you get these little things where we like connecting a lot of little dots and even that you
absorb a little bit of interesting little information um you've got other things for example when you enter
an area it only not only says the name at the top now it has a almost a subtitle text that's giving you a
little bit a little bit of history these little things like somehow make the world building feel
so much better and when you approach certain landmark rooms and you walk into them you'll get a banner at
the top as well which says what it is and gives again a little bit of a thing and all these little
micro uh narrative delivery mechanisms like make you feel way more immersed in the world and way more
aware of what's going on and way more connected to your character way more connected to the bosses to
the npcs um it's yeah there's a lot we're doing now that we certainly never did before we didn't
even think of before um but yeah it's it's i like that a lot because like as an action rpg gamer i don't
really care too much about plot but i do want a really cool world to be blowing monsters up in
basically that's like i want the characters to be cool i want the baddies to be cool and i want like
the things happening around me that like in you know build out a bit of that story without me having to
stop healing stuff yeah and it sounds like there's more of that going on as well which is great
there's the baddies being cool i mean that's that's how we almost designed an ascendancy class in here
just before when we were watching that trailer earlier yes so what you were you were saying a
shadow you came up with a shadow ascendancy yeah yeah we were well internally we had some developers
watching the trailer yesterday getting excited about and then i was like i want to play that i want to
play that character i want to be that character yeah that's awesome that like kind of vile
thormaturge type character and so like cool all of a sudden it's like we should make that a class
and then we had another guy like suggest it should be a shadow and so now i'm like oh yeah we're
definitely come on we have to do a vile thormaturge like shadow ascendancy like that's gonna be cool
you can do awesome things now even i know it's hard to see because you hide it under all the armor but
you can do things like you know with our character classes just due to the upgrades and models we all of a
sudden now the character can have tattoos added to them and stuff like that is completely feasible in
the future and like i would i want to do a lot more of that stuff like for the um there's little
things like for the uh war bringer i think was the class name on the warrior when you take that
ancestral totem node all your totems now have like an extra blue glow to them kind of like they're
enhanced by this ancestral magic um and what we also want to do is has uh add tattoos as well that like
glow blue when you're using certain skills and all that so heaps of little things that again
connects all the culture and all that stuff together and make you feel like you know it's
believable as opposed and this is a character as opposed to this is just a mechanic and you know
makes picking an ascendancy more epic i know that there was a part in the trailer that was like not
fully finished where you were saying that it doesn't really do anything but i know you want it to be
like a cool moment where some power goes yeah absolutely we just hadn't finished the vfx yet
even the uh another one the blood mage when you like you know play the blood mage now you get an
additive surge on your character whenever you cast spells you're getting like almost blood
bending kind of vibe going on and like drawing it from their veins and sending out a fireball
it's cool yeah it's real cool yeah you can have like the tattoos get tattooed on them as they
as they ascend and things like that i mean that just makes taking ascendancy way more cool which
is already i think i almost feel like ascendancy is more important than the classes for
players kind of like feeling the vibe of what they want to do with their character for sure because
i mean the classes are pretty open you can play whatever skills whatever weapon sure you're on a
passive tree at a start point but you know by high level you kind of go wherever you want to go
using jewels especially getting off class stuff you can kind of be whatever you want with the base class
yeah so eventually yeah the ascendancy is what becomes more of that important identifying feature
because that's what you have actually chosen that makes you distinct um that another different class
wouldn't be able to actually have so yeah yeah so you want to make that super super cool
and on that note uh i know i was definitely confused i know people definitely confused and
a little worried about ascendancy and what's happening with that and people were like watching
the like um the second trial and being like oh what if i don't like this oh it's just another lab again
but i want you to like lay it out as like simply as possible like how how do you ascend yeah so
effectively um in the full game there's going to be three ascendancy trials for early access there's two
and effectively you can use any of those ascendancy trials to be able to do your ascension you choose
yeah you choose which one and effectively um if you uh as you get to higher level like higher level
keys for those trials um that will unlock uh more points like if you do it at certain level break
points uh that will allow you to get more points for those classes so if you want to just play the
entire just just only the trial of the chaos god um with um uh you know to get all your points uh then
you can just decide to do that just play at higher and higher levels and you get more points as you go
through um you know if you want to do a mix that's fine too
um personally i think people will want to try out all the different content i mean you might
think that you um but even even within the trials there's there's choices right like
um i know that there's always contention around traps but uh because in the um because in the uh
trial of the sekumers you can choose which rooms you want to go to if you don't want to deal with
traps you just don't pick those rooms right like yeah you don't go into the gauntlet rooms you can
just go other things do the combat ones and that's fine too so effectively it's like you always get to
choose like what you're doing there um like it's funny because like i know traps are so contentious
but um also there are other people who just enjoy that stuff so you know you want to have something
for all those people too there's these like path of exile divisive content but lots of choice and
you can choose what to do and what not to do and then we're embracing that here now and that i mean
you're clearly leaning into that now you have you have i mean such a competitive advantage in that you
have so much content and even with pwee 2 that's still going to be the case so you can lean into that
like making content that is spicier but divisive for sure and now you're like separating trees and having
these things be a little able to be focused on a lot more um and you're doing that with the trial
with the ascendancies so and you can like you can kind of do all of them and drip feed yourself
smaller and there's also stuff that you're going to be getting from those like specific rewards and
everything that might incentivize you to do that but of course on the other hand if you don't want
to do that content uh we have open full open trade right you can just trade for the rewards and
that's fine too so uh you know like that's always part of the yes like the rewards there for example
um like jewels drop throughout the world but if you want to get more jewels you go and run sanctum
now if you want to get the radius jewels you you do oh it's sanctum i can't it's trial of the
sycamore so just for anyone who um isn't a path of xl1 player um this is effectively a sequel to
sanctum league that we did in path of xl1 um so it's mechanically very similar yeah but um it's
obviously you know ameriketh uh you know like ameriketh trial now and you know we've changed a lot of
things about it have changed you know like the content is new but it is effectively the
same overall mechanic uh you know in terms of that sort of roguelike uh mechanic that we have
the same with the other one you have ultimatum and poe 1 being the theme and of course now it's
redesigned and it's evolved into a trial of chaos um so yeah a lot of people in chat would have been
spamming ultimatum and for those who haven't played would probably be like what i don't understand
effectively the trial of the chaos of chaos is a sequel to ultimatum um which is um and we just
have to get used to the new names which is very hard um but uh yeah anyway the point being like
of course and val orbs drop in the world as well and if you want a larger dose of val orbs and you
know you don't want to trade go feel free to run some ultimatums thing is because they're all item
generated keys as well it's not like you have to do it right then and there you can trade the keys
away um at any point you can also buy more keys if you want to farm more of that thing um and if you
just want to do it later just stockpile a bunch of them run them all at your at your leisure you
know what i mean it's like you have the freedom they are uh itemized tradable as is a lot in path
of exile tradition but well as as is everything right we do the only the only thing you can't
trade is gold so we're like the exact opposite of most games where it's like the gold is freely
tradable and the items get locked we're like the gold is the only thing you can't trade and every
other item is free and open yeah and that's because you've made gold be this like way to be like
you're playing the game so you have access to this and absolutely you don't want to trade that
away effectively yeah um so how uh on the ascendancies and the trials how hard do you foresee getting your
ascendancy to be while leveling do you expect people to fail out and attempt these things multiple times
and what does that look like if you do well i failed the first time it is important to know that
that first itemized key um is a quest key and we have special rules around it that if you do fail
you can just repeat it right you changed that recently because uh that was something that i
didn't actually realize you'd changed uh i guess it was a little bit too harsh to require to get
another one yeah you weren't the only one failing it yeah um but uh yeah so pretty much you get to
re-attempt it and um you know for something like ultimatum you know yeah you know just to immediately
start thinking of exploits i can just do three of the waves then intentionally fail and then repeat
them well we've thought of that don't worry you can't but um yeah the first ones are repeatable
you're not going to be like you know oh what the heck now i have to just play to the whims of random
generation to ascend like that yeah so it is it is pretty hard though like it will take you i
definitely don't think you'll do it on your first attempt um but i did not to brag i did i did pass
i was clenched though yeah okay yeah especially in that boss fight i was watching i was watching him
do the boss fight you came by right as i was doing the boss fight you had some like kind of powerful
boons there to be perfectly honest i got 60 move speed yeah that was part of my strategic choice i was
watching you from i'm like how is he so fast this isn't the peewee too we just lied what was dodge
rolls going across half the arena this game is supposed to be slow yeah it was good it was good
fun i quite liked it i'm i like mostly like sanctum i'm not i don't want to do it all the time but i did
quite like the trial of sekima but knowing that there's other choices so i can do ultimatum instead or
something like that it's fun 100 so you've got these you've got these like two roguelike dungeons
that are going into the beta that launch but they've done very differently one's got the honor
system which is like a separate health but it's based on and scaled by your health which i noted
is quite and your defenses now it can be fully mitigated and everything fully scaled by your
character you go in in a tanky character you'll be tanky in the dungeon which is really cool
so and then with ultimate and and just because people will ask in ultimatum there aren't any traps
yes so uh that's no traps in ultimatum and no honor system in ultimatum if you just want more of a
pure combat experience then that's your choice and then there's gonna be a third one as well
which it will eventually secret for now so once uh once act four goes in um then we'll uh then we'll
have a third trial so you know uh people sort of broadly know that the crew are in act four so it's
the question of how would the crew ascend is the question there yes and if there's any other things
that have been called trials associated with the crew at some point in the past and how likely that
is to be related i'm just thinking now we're just thinking of the vile formature class before and i'm
already thinking like oh it'd be so cool if you ascend and ultimatum we want the trial master to
say different lines to you because you're like choosing the way of the vile i'm just i'm you
can't i can't stop thinking about all this stuff i did hear a few of his lines and some of the
gameplay jonathan was showing me is quite good i love i love that he's back the uh trial master
yeah he's cool a little salty sometimes that you're taking this power it seems so uh we have uh we have
the unique rewards from each of them we got like the um like you said the jewels are global but
there are unique jewels and then there are um unique socketables from the other one yep and is it
there's something planned to be unique from the final third trial that will be added later of course
uh yes there is already i know what i'm not going to say it don't worry keep some secrets fine then
again again i value the discovery right i'm certainly if i gonna if i accidentally say it it is
certainly by mistake but yes don't and that that vile orbs from the ultimatum in particular um is
they seem like they're a lot more important a lot more powerful i mean i certainly think that like
some of the stuff is a lot better with how they work so um yeah so one of the things that we wanted
to change was that implicits on items are truly implicit like you can't get rid of them they stay
there and so that means that when you do a vile uh vile or the mod that you get there now is an
addition to whatever implicit already had um which is obviously good and then the next one being that yeah
you can get plus plus one socket above the normal limit um which is uh you know also kind of
powerful um so especially with the soul cores so that in um you know in the uh trial of the
trial of chaos you uh get uh soul cores that you can't get from anywhere else and those effectively are
uh mods that are typically a bit beyond what you would normally get um uh like in on regular items
um whereas runes which kind of drop everywhere those ones are just kind of normal everyday mods that
you would expect to find it it just resists and damage and that kind of stuff so
effectively the soul cores is um you know is kind of the more end gamey uh socketables that you might
want to be using and um yeah obviously being able to get um plus one sock i mean it's something that
everyone will want um but on the other hand there is that risk of uh you know just bricking your item
so uh you know that's a the deadly gamble you have as your final crafting step there
it's what they are vile orbs are more forgiving though they are yeah but like you know if you think about um
we we talked about enchantment yeah so some slots you might value the enchantment over a rune or a
socket slot right that probably especially towards end game i'd say that's probably going to tilt that
way because you know well maybe a soul core contests with it but you know the whole point is that
there's you know choice there involved um you know and then there so there's enchantment we just talked
about the socket um there's obviously always the case of doing nothing um which happens but you know
for um just say regular rare items uh it will re-roll like one to three modifiers that ran
effectively do a chaos orb on one to three modifiers not all six and as much as that can
often be a downside because if you're using on a very good item um obviously it's going to take away
the good ones interesting um but if you're using it on a mid item you can actually turn it very good
now i've had this happen like when i've been playing i've got like ah just you know life defense
defense double res and something else that i don't want and um i'm like i'll just start
valing everything because why not you know i've got my val orbs and i val it and it re-rolls that
bottom mod into a tri-res and now i've got a tri-res double defense life helmet and i was like
awesome so even that which is can often be perceived as a bad outcome now it isn't going to completely
break your item and so for example if you have a weapon you know you've got your three damage mods
um and you've got some bad suffixes it could even be an option you know like or hopefully
it doesn't just remove all three damage mods you know whereas before it's like if it bricked it
it often was almost always a brick right like that item is now dead so and then you told me about a
new unique uh yeah result which i don't know if you want to swallow about the 100 yeah yeah it's cool
it's so cool i'm surprised you even got that pass with that one pass rishi honestly
i mean he got it made okay great we discussed it i i agree yeah i agree i messaged it to him thinking
he'll be like no way this is unacceptable but now he was there was all for it didn't turn into a
dexterity chat and so um yeah um what it effectively does is it just takes the mod values and it multiple
it it goes up to uh i can't remember exactly the values but let's just say it's it um changes all
the values to between 0.8 and 1.2 of what they were multiplied but it doesn't care about the minimum
and maximums so for example if you had a thousand life calms heart you can use this to get again this
is me assuming it's 20 variance but because i can't remember what we balanced it to but you'll be
able to get a 1200 life calms heart for example now that's obviously giving up the enchantment and a
socket um just think about sockets on calms heart i can't remember what we did but whatever
um i think you can actually uh do that which is interesting but um uh ultimately it's like yeah
now i'm choosing am i do i want the enchantment do i want an extra you know 100 something 200 life
whatever that ends up being um or do i want the socket um so it's quite an interesting choice and
adds an extra access of corruption to unique items that is i think corrupted divining of uniques
yeah yeah effectively yeah it's divining them but with um higher maximums and lower
surely there's going to be some broken things like max razz or something like that
i mean we'll guess we'll find out cross that bridge when it comes to it yeah it's fine
so that was all just talking about the trials how you actually get your ascendancies but what about
the actual ascendancies themselves how are they uh how are they cooking
um well they're fun they're cool yeah um we certainly try to get what we've tried to do is for
the the class we've tried to have one that's a bit more out there yeah you know something that isn't just
you know like if you think even about in pwee one you've got the dualist you can go like champion
or slayer or um holy words i don't remember but you know the drill um and the gladiator and the
problem is like okay they're all just about like hitting stuff with weapons and they haven't there's
nothing really out there they sure that they all sound cool like don't get me wrong and they can be
cool and they do have differences but there's nothing that's like kind of crazy um so all of a sudden
now when you're like you know sorceress you're using all your elemental skills and now you can
just like go into this thing that can stop time you know it's a little bit more uh crazy and you've
got the the mercenary and you can turn into a gemling legionnaire and effectively fuse gems into your
flesh to like you know mutate yourself you know it's like not just talking about crossbows and
projectiles over and over and over and over again it's like doing kind of whack stuff so i really like
that that's awesome and we're gonna make sure every single class has one thing that is like
definitely out there um and then one thing that's you know more predictable more to the expectation
of the trope you know for example the dead eye to the ranger and um but yeah lots and lots of uh
cool interactions just cool and playing with different mechanics and we've tried to make them
like for example none of them call out a weapon right none of them so you we're trying to make sure
that they're broad enough to be that you might be a ranger going a dead eye but playing a caster
right playing spells like keeping all of that open that flexibility that kind of crazy you know
for the johnny players as we call it out there who want to just completely experiment and figure out
you know the most broken weird stuff you know and you get things with that when you're still like okay
okay i'm a ranger uh and i'm using a quill rain and one weapon set specced into a bunch of prod speed
attack speed and in my second weapon set i'm using a spellcaster staff with a bunch of projectile stuff and
i'm invested into more spell damage side and you've got a whack tree and all of a sudden now you're
this like dead eye archer spellcaster mage hybrid doing all kinds of wacky stuff or like even or let's
say the same build and experimenting with a bunch of triggers and so you're using your bow as a quill
rain as a higher attack speed delivery mechanism for you know laying down a bunch of either ccs or slows
or building up crowd controls and then you're using the caster stuff and like you get some pretty out
there things going on and the important thing is it's not like just like uh benefiting only arrows
or only bow attacks or anything like that it's broad and now you know opens up the world to what you can
do and same like the gemling legionnaire on the mercenary is entirely just about gem slots skills
support etc there's no you don't have to be anything you can be literally whatever build you want
um and yeah so that that's embracing that making sure people still even though we have all these
classes you we're embracing that path of exile you can do anything fantasy that we want people to be
able to do and yeah if you don't want to go with the trope perfectly fine yeah it'll still be powerful
it sounds like you're really trying to avoid that thing that we've had a couple times in poe one where
like a certain niche is relegated to on ascendancy like that's the only way to go for it for sure it
sounds like that's not going to be the case here well at least if we're doing our job right that
yeah and with so many of the ascendancies as well got a lot of choices um originally the plan was to
like have all of the poe one ascendancies available and it was some sort of weird split campaign stuff
and all that uh i don't really know at this point it's a bit confusing it's you mentioned dead eye
though so it sounds like some of them are coming forwards but is it all just being i think it's more
done at this point yeah at this point they'll just be different right like originally way back when
we were planning on just keeping the ascendancies as they were and yeah but at this point um that
wouldn't even be good enough because like it doesn't fit the kind of like path of xl2 way of
designing this thing so yeah i mean like we might have a class called the dead eye and it might have
the same themes but it'll be like different actual mechanics and different things yeah i mean yeah even
the dead eye you got tailwind works differently you've still got an additional projectile you know like
there are there are things that certainly carry over um but it's really easy and it's honestly been
fun just looking at them going like you know now we have all these system changes all these skills and
everything works like this just what would the perfect class be not like how can we retrofit and
band-aid appear we want class to work it's just way better to look at it and go here's here's all the
things we want yeah so well yeah like when you only have now the life and mana flask and stuff it could
obviously things don't work quite the same but then now you have the charm system and all of a
i actually do wonder if path one would be cool with that exactly like stacking charms so so it's
it's just here are you know 12 eventually 36 classes um it's not really like here's the pair we
won counterpart and they're identical kind of thing anymore for sure too many things changed for that
to even be possible anyway yeah all right that sounds very epic um we can skip over the flask and
trinkets as we did cover that uh very well so uh moving into um skills i realized i like had many
pages of questions here and then i was like wait we haven't even talked about like skills here
it's so much to so much to for us to discover over the course of this beta um how has the list of
skills been shaping up overall i mean it's certainly getting there i mean look there are even certain
skills that won't even make it even just within the classes we have like there are still going to be
more some more skills coming uh later on as well for the for these classes because um there there are more
skills that we got um just about there and um yeah but just didn't quite didn't quite make it um so
uh yeah and like getting a class finished in terms of the skills you need like um it sort of seems
very easy when you um okay we need like you know 22 23 24th you know number of skills something like
that and it seems like that's not so many and you kind of design them but when you actually come up
with all of the things you know the way they interact together um you know the number of prototypes
you have to do that kind of don't really work and you know like you end up not being fun
um and then of course the support gem stuff like you need to make sure that every skill
has enough viable supports so that you can actually even recommend to people to do
uh then you need things like the uh you know the passive tree support for all of them
you need to have um all of the uh the stuff with like buff uh the buff gems for each character class
as well um you know you need to be thinking about uniques for the for the type of uh you know for
the uh that can work with these things it's just like there's so many different elements to
actually make skills work and once again it's another area i think that um was underestimated
to some degree um uh before uh and you know like it does take a um you know to actually get that
finished it takes a lot um so uh yeah that's been um a total struggle and we we didn't think we would
have to have only six character classes initially uh at the start of early access we were thinking we
would have eight um to begin with but uh yeah when it actually came down to actually getting to
actually finish something uh you know like it just ended up being too much um so uh you know now
obviously we've got a bunch i mean we've got a bunch of work on more of the classes that we've
done you know there's things there but um it's that finishing work of like making sure that all
the systems in the game come together to support um you know the how that how that works um that
requires a lot doing all of that as we're still discovering how we want those systems to work
you know like the changes to support gems and all that as we're also making support gems as we're
making character classes just can cause things to slow down quite a bit and then we have to
recalibrate and also yeah like it is it was an extreme amount of work that we certainly
predicted poorly um but that was also because we are making all these cool systems to all these
changes to all these systems which are having like immense benefits as well so yeah i would say
it's pretty safe to expect that you know as much as you can't play them on day zero um a lot of some
of those other classes that we have shown in the past um and some of the skills and stuff there's
a lot there like just not to make it seem like it's shallow or anything but we will be adding those
classes in for sure yeah the thing that keeps like surprising me is um well when you click that
old gems tab when you're doing an uncut there's quite a lot of skills in there but you initially
kind of box yourself away where you think okay so i'm playing the mercenary so i'm just looking at
the crossbow skills and then i was like well what if i go look at the elemental skills and then i find
flame wall and i'm like oh i can shoot my projectiles through that okay cool i like that but that's like
surface level because you also have the weapon swap thing and you can actually viably do with the
automated weapon swapping it's not like toxic where you have to push the button a bunch of times and
you've got the trees that like customize whenever you do it automatically on the fly so that's like all
of a sudden i'm like oh well why can't i use a sword on the other hand yes you absolutely that's
actually a very cool mercenary vibe sword and crossbow so um yeah i mean that stuff is like is
crazy i mean like in the in the actually there was one in the the the community guys recorded where
they were using um a bell the the bell skill yeah quarterstaff with the um uh the rapid the rapid
shot uh mercenary skill and when i saw it's like oh man you know that's like it's like a whole other
thing um yeah like that i didn't even know about that about that particular combo uh until i saw it in
the uh some of the footage they recorded i saw yeah i started thinking about that too with like
multiplayer i was like sorry i was throwing my gas grenades oh yeah which you can blow up with your
explosive grenades but then i was throwing it at a boss that was doing burning ground and they were
blowing up instantly i'm like oh wait so it reacts to the environment well it's obviously going to
react to my friends doing oh yes oh yes oh yes and um more friend and this and this is the reason
like this conversation here is the reason why there's going to be crazy builds that we don't
anticipate because like like like like the the some of the stuff that can happen between classes i just
have no doubt we will not have discovered yeah like how much have you really been able to test i mean we
i mean like we we do test party play all the time like mark's mark mark's like
i'm the support character player yeah now i'm like freezing armor breaking putting down clouds slowly
you know i'm like holy there's just a lot going on all of a sudden i'm not just standing there like
i've got buffs coming out of me you know it's like uh you know you're like i'm actually doing all this
active support and like different conditions to synergize with the group and how can it's like okay
you're doing that skill okay what i'm going to do is i'm going to just do this and enhance my armor
breaking and go ballistic armor breaking and you just spam your thing that consumes it
you know so you get a lot of that stuff going on for sure where um all right but you know it
it's kind of honestly the terrifying part as well where it's like
you know what do we have we had the whole like vulnerability curse with with gas cloud ticks or
something and it was like literally applying armor break like every frame and so you have the monsters
going ting ting ting ting ting ting ting and then you have some other thing you have some other guy consuming
it and again oh my god quill rain just don't even how many bloody synergistic things with quill rain
you can do a lot with that all the lightning arrows on the ground and because they can you
know lightning things hit them and explode and all of a sudden now you're just everyone's running
around with core rain spamming lightning rods everywhere and yeah and frost wall somehow frost
wall we had about 15 abuse cases and i mean that's historically accurate yeah
kinetic blast frost walls and all that
it returns sounds like it's coming back it's it'll be fun yeah it's cool even finding all the
stuff so far has been really fun but yeah i generally play multiplayer most of the alpha i've done is
being in multiplayer play with other people um it's good to get a lot of that testing in there as well
because not a lot of others do it that's really good um and then yeah try and see what we can break
just for good fun um honestly the thing that's like hard is to then like because you get this thing which is
quite interesting where you have a staff is both the player and a developer and i'm of the like
don't you you better not keep that x that you know something that's i wouldn't say exploit but you
know something that's op a secret right you better bloody tell me because that reaction you had earlier
you were saying people weren't telling you about exactly like you get a situation someone doesn't
want to tell you about their build that's because they're like oh mark will nerf it then
you're supposed to be making games i legitimately had a monday meeting and you know whatever
i was like i was like i swear if i see any of you at the top of the ladder on day one we're going to
have a talk exactly exactly exactly no i did tell you about my flashbangs and how good but maybe it's
fine i just don't i just wanted them to check well that's the thing that is hard no one knows if their
thing is actually bro look there's a line that gets crossed yes yeah but sometimes you don't know is it just
i've found something cool and it's powerful or have i found something cool and it's broken
you know and and those things i mean we have to make those decisions of course and a lot of the
time what is reported is just fine and it's like yeah you've you got a good weapon and you got the
right you got this combo you you're strong if it's if it's supported by items then it's like fine to be
very powerful but if you're just like i just pick these skills and no matter what weapons i'm wearing
i'm just like completely ridiculous then that's a different situation because now it's just a thing that
anyone can do at a moment's notice rather than actually requiring like you know oh i have to find the big
you know this combo of items and things like that that so that's a much different story um
yeah but now we've had a lot of good testing a lot of good feedback a lot of good um people reporting
that stuff especially in the last like month it's like coming in a lot because there's the systems and
everything's kind of stabilizing you start to get a lot more of that when and people are understanding
what the uh difficulties meant to be and what the power of characters is meant to be as all of that came
and started to stabilize we got a lot more of this coming in and we are kind of getting more
understanding but again you'll never find them all but uh you know it's fun good fun journey
support gems have changed a lot however you found the changes to them being now no having no levels
and uh the restriction of having only one support gem on your character of a type but having a lot
more of them i really like how this works like i think that it adds so much more build diversity and
interest um to have to be making the decision of like you know where is this going to go and the
thing that's been important though with that system is it requires a lot more support gems to exist
because you need because you don't have one on your character you need you need tons of them and
like you need like you need a lot of different ways to increase damage and a lot of ways to
different support different mechanics it's like if you're going to have something like freeze like
you know if you're going to have a freezing skill you need to be able to support that and augment
that in like many different ways and there needs to be more options than what you can even like
there needs to be in order to have choice you can't just have five here's your five freeze things
and that's all you do right there has to be more than that in order to be able to have it so you
actually have some choices as well so uh that kind of stuff has meant that you just need a lot of things going on there
but i think that um the choices that you end up with as a player of like you know where do i put my
model projectiles where do i put my ps whatever like i think that leads to a lot more interesting
decisions um with how you build and um uh you know like uh yeah i think that that to me is where a lot
of the why it just works so much better and we were certainly hesitant about the whole um you know
you can only have one support per um character thing because it sounds bad if you just hear about it as
a player without actually playing it like your first reaction is you just hear that and you're like oh it's just a
restriction and it is arbitrary in some sense right there's no like
we can't justify it thematically really um it's just a it's just it just is what it is and so
that i really don't like that kind of thing usually because um i if i'm gonna i want the
theme to match the mechanic as much as possible but in this case it just made the gameplay so much
better that um like it just had to happen um so arguably if you if you need to like if you end up in a
situation where you like i have to put the support on every slot exactly that that is less
choice and that's the reason why the gameplay is less choice less interest and also you may as
well just bake that now into the skills and or 100 and so this is the thing it is actually much
worse to have that because it results in this outcome but like that's a kind of more subtle
argument that's like you have to kind of make to people if you want to kind of convince them this
is actually the right way um because when you tell people oh there's this restriction it doesn't
sound like what they're getting out of that is more choice it sounds like they're getting less
um but the reality is it is actually more choice because you no longer have like mandatory uh like here's the
here's the five mandatory things you have to put on the skill um it's like there's actually much more
going on i think it's much better helped realize my experience on the mercenary that you uh your
vision of uh having like all of these skills available to you and them actually being worth
using for sure because if you had all the same support gems i feel like you just pick the one that
does the most damage and you make it do the most damage and that's the only skill you use yeah and
i mean the great thing is is now it's completely reasonable to have a skill in your character that
you just use occasionally right like every five minutes you might have a situation where you need to use
that and that's actually fine and completely reasonable yeah so i'm playing a grenader and i
would be like okay i should only use this grenade normally is what i would be like in part of exile
because this is the best grenade or maybe this one that does like interacts with it in some way
the obvious combo but now i'm actually like well there's a reason i i could use those lightning
ones to apply a shock because i have all these shock support gems that i'm not using anywhere else
because i'm using the damage and the lmp on my big damage dealers i can use i can put the shock
things on there and i can actually have a shock setup i can incorporate that into my build i can
incorporate poison into my build to strip their armor and whatnot and that actually is something
and maybe you only use that occasionally when you face something that's got heavy armor you know yeah
but it's like you know it's like that that kind of stuff i really want to be viable and that
that situational stuff i think just makes the game way more interesting it's it's really feeding into
the flavor of the mercenaries like this like prepared kind of fighter who has all these tools at their
disposal as well like you're like i have this grenade for if i get into this situation this grenade for this one
it's so good yeah nice i love it um a couple questions here people definitely been asking
about like vile skills and transfigured gems and stuff and like that i feel like this sort of thing
doesn't make sense at launch exactly yeah because ultimately if we're going to add something like
that it would make sense to add it um just as another skill um so at this point there's no real
reason to do that like that kind of stuff comes in where we want to have a specific reward system
somewhere that wants to be able to do that and so we don't really need to do it right now but um
yeah look we might decide to bring that theme back and you know in a reward system
yeah i think for vile skills especially it's a it's a cool flavor yeah for sure um but i think
the transfigured thing is also interesting like uh you know if you're looking to be able to like
the reason why transfigured was nice is because it's like we got to sort of iterate on a bunch
of different themes around the same skill um which uh obviously at this point we don't need to do that
because we've got we're already still adding the skills you know what i mean so uh all the iterations
of it like less of a necessary thing but um yeah i mean i'm look i'm sure we'll be doing more stuff
like that in the future like we absolutely will be do you know how many skills roughly you have
such are going to um end up with some you know um i actually don't know the number off the top of
my head but what i will say is is that we initially i think when we announced like what the full game
would have we said 240 and i'm pretty sure we're actually nearing that i feel definitely it's going
to be way higher than yeah yeah because i think we're nearing that now when we've only added half the
classes so uh i think that that uh means that there's going to be like i know 100 of them or whatever
like some little utility skill or whatever but there's even if you discount for those it's yeah i know
no no that's a lot yeah you got what like because there's 20 there's 20 to 25 for each of those uh
for each class um so just with six of those i'm terrible at math in my head um but i feel like
that's 120 well let's let's say it's just a bit over um 110 or something like end up around there 120
something like that uh around yeah i think probably 120 um around there um like that but then you've also
got all the buff gems as well and like each character class has nine of those um so that then sort of
adds up so you've already reached uh probably 200 just by the time you've got to there um and then
uh and then it doesn't even count things that really are skills but like are not you don't get them via
a skill gem um so like we're talking about all the ascendancy little skills and there's like uniques
that have little skill things on them all all staffs wands and yeah exactly we're not even counting
that right like so the staffs wands and sceptors have skills built in yeah uh and then those are like
that's another how many of those are there's like 20 of those probably yeah i mean like if you add them all
up i don't know who remembers all these things i know but there's no one has counted recently
but uh there's a bunch countless um yeah yeah um ascendancy classes with skills yeah yeah yeah
and those skills those skills by the way ascendancy class skills are fully supportable yeah yeah
that's wild because i remember you did the thing with the fault attack where you can support that
now you can support the fault attack um and you can support any skill that comes from something
that one caught me by surprise i was like oh wow you can actually link those up yep it's uh yeah so
you're gonna end up with quite a lot uh going on there i was even surprised when i was like oh i
can add you know additional accuracy to herald of eyes and it like provides a buff to my character i can
like add buffs through support james well you know why that is though because uh those those things like
heralds are so hard to find like a good set of supports to recommend so we're like damn we have to come
up with like tons of these now they're like really difficult you can like create a custom aura yeah absolutely absolutely
so yeah it's um that that actually means it's actually nice because um part of the um it means
that you get the feeling of having more aura effects on your character without having to have the spam of
actual auras that um every many characters had in pwe1 like you get to kind of have all that stuff as
well um so uh that's that's been really nice thanks for the uh invisible or mtx well it does remind me
though um so with all this is very off topic but with all the uh very good teasers you've been doing for
like new 3d art for uniques and stuff like that have you had any thoughts about uh reworking um
the transfer skin transfer mtx in some way making it more permanent um honestly it's not an hour
thing about stuff we're thinking about you know like it'll work the same way it works for now at least
uh but obviously uh skin transfer and peewee 2 there's a lot more cool base art yeah that's
going to make people actually want to use it now i feel so yeah you'll probably be using that a lot more
so yeah it'd be cool to see something for that in the future potentially um so on to the end game which was
i feel like a big bulk of the announcement for sure yeah um so just as like an overview so we have
the end game versions just for beta launch by the way yeah because it's gonna be a lot more later
we have the we have the end game pinnacle versions of the two um trials yep so as like fully farmable
content they don't have trees though those ones they don't have trees but they do have a progression
system of some kind so you've got the relics in um in the sanctum uh sequel and then for the trial of
chaos you have um the uh the inscribed uh ultimatums have getting mods uh uh from from the end so when
you kill the um final um uh the the final boss of that uh which is you know alleged to be the trial master
um then uh you um alleged yeah then uh you know he'll drop uh uh items that can then have mods on them to make the trial itself harder
and there's also some pretty interesting ones on there that we actually were going to put in the video
but it was starting to get a bit long um which was that um you've got the thing which i i uh where
you've got the uh the bets that you can make of like you know uh put up uh you know 13 exalts and
then you might get double that back if you're able to complete the uh thing so those are some of the mods
that can spawn on there um and as well as mods that make the actual trial harder as well so um there's
things like that as well so yeah those two have those kind of like different outside the
outlustry because they're not really part of the atlas like you'll get keys for them while you're playing in game
but technically speaking they're kind of like they they go they scale to end game but they're not
like sort of part of the the whole atlas um yeah like play them there yeah so their own distinct
yeah exactly exactly so there'll be three roguelike dungeon things that will be sure sure sure like
um i wouldn't say three roguelike dungeons i will say there'll be three trials that have various
mechanics that you know can be different yeah but uh then then of course you've got the um uh four kind
of what i guess would say sort of um i don't we actually need a name for what what
what are we calling what are we calling the things that are icons on the on the on the
because they were called leagues but they're not really yeah it doesn't really make sense to call
it a league exactly that is what we call them internally we just refer to them as like there
are four leagues that you uh have that appear there doesn't really work um uh i don't have a good idea
right now yeah we probably have actually named it i just don't remember what it is right right
and then you've got uh the kind of boss hunting kind of element as well uh and then the kind of i guess
what you would say is the pinnacle of the kind of boss hunting thing is then you know you've got the cities
with the lieutenants and then the uber act bosses and then above that you have the pinnacle boss who
we don't want to spoil um although i did uh show you a little bit about it uh just in private uh
before um but uh yeah that's uh that one's gonna be that one's gonna be hard like uh i know you're
you're cooking up some pretty difficult uh mechanics there um yeah it's fun i asked that's the fun stuff
mm-hmm yeah because now you don't need to worry about if people can't progress through it's not a
progression blocker you can just kill them yeah it's a progression it's a progression blocker to
uh difficulty uh to the higher difficulties though because yeah once you once you kill that of course
then you get the increase of the difficulties and then it's like okay now try it again but way harder
and then you know like and then there's four there's four levels of difficulty for each of those um for
each end game system like that so yeah like apart from the trials the end game trials everything has
like its own distinct passive tree and progression through them is also by doing them yes exactly yeah so we
really wanted to prevent the situation where you feel like you um allocate points for a certain
piece of content and then you feel like you can't do the other content because you're kind of wasting
the points that you've got yeah the lock-in and uh we kind of uh band-aided that and here we won by
adding multiple atlas trees as a way but i think the solution is much better where effectively you can
progress all of them and you can either do like you know just all in one for a while or you can just
like you know do each of them as you come to them and you know just add them kind of piecemeal um
but either way however you want to do it um you know you can make progress progress on your character um well i
should say in your league uh uh for all for all of those um because uh the progress and all that
stuff is of course um you know for the whole league not just for a single character yeah and previously
we used the atlas tree i would say very much so to make sure that we were doing the type of content
that we wanted to do yeah so now it's not so much about finding the content because that's what the
tablets are for yeah now it's more about um improving your ability to um like uh uh sustain effectively
like you you're going to want to have those points to sort of get sustainability for the next level up and
we want to make sure that there is sustain if you're doing you know engaging with those mechanics
well yeah but effectively you do have to actually like to to get sustain at higher difficulties um
you will need to be able to you know be making smart choices in terms of allocating and like
using the tablets correctly and that kind of stuff um like it is part of that sort of story of all of
that um so um yeah that's the that's kind of the main thing with that yeah this idea of like
sustaining the content you want to do by doing it is a little different to how it's been in period one a
lot of time where it's like sure you had to fuel it by going back to maps right right right
yeah get your old juice i mean you're still doing maps ultimately yeah in terms of like
yeah but but effectively like so long as you're doing the content that you um uh that you that
you want to do you should and as well and making it harder um you know so your build has to be good
enough to be able to to be able to sustain it as well then then you will be able to sustain that stuff
and you know uh like if you want every single map to have a breach in it that's absolutely doable
um by uh by by by you know using the tablets correctly yeah so the um atlas passive trees and the
trees for each of the distinct types of content is about scaling the reward and
difficulty primarily yeah yeah yeah yeah absolutely um and what does i saw like on the breach nodes it
said like increased difficulty what does that mean um it's somewhat arbitrary and asymmetric but um it
will feel like for example some of the difficulties will actually change the boss's skills and how they
work um generally they'll increase like the level of the area right so you get the general uh monster and
life scaling um but arguably to a player that's arbitrary as well because they don't know how that scales
um uh and another context here might be more of certain monster types less of others and stuff like
that um it is generally uh that yeah so the small nodes will increase difficulty of the meta content
whereas the large the notables will increase the reward of the in-map content um but when i say difficulty
that is reward as well so an example of how this works is like um let's say the boss has six uniques
it could drop or five or six uniques um it can drop three at difficulty zero then at say um difficulty
one it can drop you know maybe has increased level or higher item level um some rarity um you know now
also that when i say rarity also do note rarity does increase the grade of items not just making
them yellow or orange it does make them better yellows or better or no not better oranges um
it does affect yeah it affects other things about items than just the rarity yes um and so yeah when
i talk about just getting rarity here i don't want people to and peewee one players in particular to
think ah they're just going to go from yellow to more yellow um so anyway and you know maybe the next
tier will add a unique to the pool like a more uh you know what we hope will be more valuable unique
and then the next one can do a bit more rarity something else maybe introduce a different unique
perhaps and then the last difficulty introduces something ideally you know without giving away
exact specifics of them more in the line of a um modular unique item say like megalomaniac or like
um forbidden flesh and flame from peewee one so a unique item that is like ideally very powerful very
chase um but uh has a lot of different combinations watchers eyes another good example right so a new
series of jewels um is a good example there are other uniques that are modular and stuff and that
comes in at the last tier and so you want to really be getting to that hardest difficulty so you can be
getting these like farming for these extremely good powerful unique items um but of course you have
the thing if you're never ready for it if you try it and you're like oh this is too hard you can
always just respect the nodes yeah you can unspec them away and uh then not you know like uh just
effectively decide like i've got these points but um i'm not yeah yeah i want to go back and do this
later and so that ability to effectively configure the difficulty like that i think so if you're maybe
target farming one of the base one of the uniques the difficulty zero drops you might want to just be
like i'll do that i'll do the difficulty stuff later and i'll just farm it at this difficulty so and i
think that's a much better way than the than some of the systems we've used to scale that in the past and
the nice thing is of course the difficulty is that we can effectively get what use whatever scaling
levers we want to make that more difficult without necessarily having like like because we could
have been like oh you know you increase difficulty it's like 200 life or something like that but by
effectively being a bit more vague about it we can actually like specifically tailor the difficulties
yeah different tiers like you know with more specific changes yeah this like multiple projectile
thingy shoots has more projectiles sure and that kind of thing so you know whatever we feel works
best for making this particular fight more difficult it seems like there's a lot more for players to
kind of discover experimentally there as they progress for sure in what way they're getting harder and that um
it's going to be different for different players too where like a different build is affected by a
difficulty change more so potentially and uh that that's an interesting question as well i think
where how much are you guys pitching these sorts of distinct end game pieces of content at being like
completable by the same build or by encouraging players to make a different build that's better at
so this is this is a very difficult one um and uh it's something that we've discussed a bit recently is like
like the harder you make the hardest content the less builds will be considered viable by the players
because um effectively like a build's only viable if it can defeat like you know the the pinnacle boss
at difficulty four like that will be kind of the general perception so we have to be really like i
actually don't know necessarily what the right answer here is um like we uh have the ability i mean maybe
you feel like you do but i don't think i i wouldn't say i'm 100 confident on it but like you know
i'll i'll i'll have a go at it look there's going to be iteration here because what we'll see is like
you know if we find that like um you know there's only like some particularly abusive like only the
most abusive stuff is possibly able to defeat the hardest content that we might have to dial it back
a bit yeah um but it's kind of going to be a bit of experimentation and it's very hard at this point
to be able to pitch that because we don't have the um crazy history you know pwee does not have the
history of pwee one to be able to you know to know kind of what like what is the right life value to have
on a difficulty four pinnacle boss like yeah how do we even know that at this point really without
that being said though like the bosses are a lot more skill based and tactical right like at the end
of the day uh the gear is to some degree necessary because no one can really make no mistake for some
amount of time you know so you do have that thing and you do need to mitigate certain things but like
a lot of these are like very dodge roll tactical um or using different certain skills or mitigation tactics
or whatever you do there's heaps of different things to bypass the things that make them hard
for sure but i would say it is very much a lot of skill is involved um especially when it comes to
some of these with dodge rolling like i'm trying to emphasize that quite a bit um or blocking you
know if you want to do a different way about it um not to say you must block but yes dodge roll is a
pretty key mechanic here and i'd say we're certainly upping the emphasis on using and using it well as you
get into these higher tiers but gear is always a way and combinations of uniques and passive tree
and build is always a way to go i'm not good at dodge rolling i'm going to gear around that skill
check and become strong enough to defeat the boss you know or another skill like a some sort of skill
that helps you block using skills in the mix is fine yeah but i would say pretty generally you can
take i'd say any decent character you get pretty damn you gear up all the way and as long as you're good
enough that is a way to defeat them i would say there's no real hard requirement on doing something
crazy niche or out there or complicated you're certainly not going the route of like oh this
boss is fire immune or something oh no no no no no thanks no no we've been through that already yeah
excellent um so this uh this very cute atlas this infinitely expanding civilization map-esque
atlas which i know you're particularly fond of jonathan yep um uh what's the uh what's kind of the
idea here like is the layout the same for everyone is it the same across the league um so it's the same
for all your characters in the league but the layout is different for everyone it is random okay so you're
gonna have to find stuff like it works like delve in this respect which is obviously a league that i
was particularly a fan of yeah um so um yeah i'm just a really i i what i really wanted is i wanted a
feeling of exploration um in the atlas and um it's something that we sort of tried to do with the atlas
and here we won with that feeling of kind of you know having the connected areas and exploring but it never
really it didn't feel like exploration quite in quite the same way that this does yeah um so um
that's the thing i loved and it's one of the reasons i love delve um and uh so that's you know kind of
kind of where this was coming from and uh at the same time um it's sort of solving various other
problems that we've always had where um like one of the things that's really cool to do um is to be
able to have things like okay like in this area you've got like this item drops and like that kind
of thing you know like i guess in p1 you had div cards but yet there was always a problem where
if you have differences between in-game areas in a system that works like p1 does then effectively
that's the only map people like like whatever the best map is that's the one everyone will run
like continuously forever um so effectively um we wanted to try and make sure that you actually
like had an experience that had more variety while still retaining the whole like i get to play the
content that i want um so ideally with the with um with the atlas we kind of get that we've got in
p2 we get to kind of have both of the best of both worlds we get to make sure that there is
some variety you know you feel like you're exploring but because once you've run a map
that's run and now you have to you know move on and do it and find another one um it's not just like
the you know like just just play one map again and again and again but yet the content you know can
be added to it um you can do things if you if you like the you know particular maps you know because
there are biomes and you can see them from far away you can be like okay i know there's a particular
desert map that's great so i'm going to go for deserts and that's fine you can do that kind of thing
um so you know like you've you've both got controllability but also um uh you know the ability for us to
kind of make more variants you get a lot more very high satisfying spikes yeah um well like for
example you get more variables where you just have okay there are like four towers really you've got a
good tower cluster and you've got really good maps in in that range so like you know there are maps
so in and perfect so one for example um you know the range is effectively say um how do i quantify this
like say 350 monsters up to 700 monsters yeah whereas the range here is like 300 monsters up to
like uh uh 1500 monsters you know much much much more drastic range now those numbers are arbitrary but
um it is approximately the representation of the range obviously you then modify it and add more to
it and all of that so you will have some maps that are like extremely good with delirium um and some
maps that are like way better with something more like breach yeah because delirium enhances the monsters of
the map whereas breach entirely adds the monsters and you will even have things where there are maps
that are like way more magic monsters way more rare monsters and so you probably want that with you know
pick your league of your choosing and whatnot you have all these variables that are at play and so you
all of a sudden find a really good set of towers with some really good maps and radius and then you'll
get really good tablet modifiers and then you'll get really good maps with really good prefixes and you
want to just combine all of this and to and you obviously instill them all and you corrupt them
all and there's the corruption influence and so then there's a corruption influence on them and it's
like yeah okay like it is possible for this on one map to be many many mechanics stacks to the point of
uh craziness so it sounds like the the juicing is definitely there well yeah i mean that's that's
important right i mean like that that's part of the kiwi experience yeah for 100 but uh
uh how um how much control do you have as a player though over min maxing your just exploration of
the atlas map so effectively um can you do better in some way um so effectively what you're going to
be want to do is the towers are where you go to like see areas around and then there's the the
structure of the connections is quite open so like you can beeline for things um pretty well like if you
like you can certainly see a lot more maps than what you play if you know what i mean yeah um so uh
because of that um like you know choosing what you want is is is is easy to do and you can kind
of see the towers in the fog yes you can see the towers in the fog from a distance which means that
um you know you don't like a lot of the time it's like you know go to a tower you'll see some maps you
want to play you go play those then it's like the next tower is just a few other maps away go to that
tower see then you see the next area and so on i'm guessing that's like a certain range out you can
see yeah yeah the fog kind of uh in 3d kind of the fog's actually a 3d thing and it like it like
rises slowly as you get away from where the thing is so that's how you kind of get the towers to
oh so you might see a cluster of towers off somewhere yeah absolutely you can see that
it sounds like this is like potentially an infinitely expanding map that is going to be by
the end of someone's league quite big yes um so we haven't we actually need to add a search feature
i don't know if they've done it yet uh for finding specific maps that haven't been run yet yeah we
have a few things there's a button you can press and it like goes to your last map round one that goes
back to a home base and one that goes to some of the special uh you know more iconic things you
find but um this we certainly need more um 100 so that is something we will be working on hopefully
it's there who knows and uh so waystones have a tier but they don't have specific maps on them anymore
which obviously shrinks that whole map pool thing down yes substantially um it'll make the maps dash tab
a little easier to manage yeah so uh yeah so uh have you thought about like what sort of i don't know
economic consequences that have for like how players progress through maps is it easier to
do when you don't have to collect all of these individual maps to get the completion bonuses
and stuff like we do currently like we have that whole you know hunting down over 100 maps to get
completion for i mean yeah now you're hunting you know you're hunting certain valuable maps you're
hunting towers you're hunting content you're hunting um you know the the warlord the faction leaders to
to get the pinnacle yeah you know you're hunting uh unique maps very different thing for sure
um as opposed to and then the item is all about i've just got a key i just want good modifiers you
know there's not really all that whole other variable to it so there's still a lot of a lot
of interesting choice and axes um but we've taken it from the item and put it on the actual world map
um but it's cool it also makes you just feel like you're traversing a world you know you're not
instantly like finishing the campaign very grounded and now i'm in space you know like public
i only literally just thought about that i was gonna ask about that so you know the mapping system was
always this like extra dimensional kind of unknown thing it's pretty interesting but it is a little
so we wanted to start with actually like at least i mean look i'm sure we'll get to the extra
dimensional beings eventually but um but at least to start with you know we wanted to have a bit more
grounded initially yes you're on the planet yeah right you're on the planet that's like a good thing
we have not we haven't gone to the moon yet yes well even then we were saying like can we at least at
least before we go to outer space go to the moon first like well actually well how many moons are
we don't we know there's there's a whole complicated thing we need to figure out there wow
i feel like there's a delve but up league coming
all right so we've got this uh one in four maps is boss maps and then the other that means the other
three are not boss maps yes what does a non-boss map look like how do you win it so effectively what you
need to do is um kill the uh kill the rares um in the map to just to remove the corruption and finish
it um once you get down below 50 monsters it will point out uh any rares that are remaining there's a
little marker just so you know uh but honestly i wouldn't expect that to even be necessary most of
the time because the layouts are kind of designed so that you know like you know if you generally
speaking you want to clear the maps to find the rares anyway because those are the one you know
those have good drops um and effectively um the the only reason that you would need that marker
thing is just occasionally you get some slightly weird degenerate layout where there's some side bit you didn't
notice or something like that and that's like that's where you have to go so generally speaking
you'll be able to make your way around and kill them all the goal of the player is you're cleansing
corruption from the world you're bringing water back um you know stuff like that so you even get
the thing on the map where you're like you know there's some corruption-y looking stuff around the
map when you complete the map that gets purged away um you know so you feel like you're reverse
painting the map a little bit we're cleaning up yeah it can actually be quite satisfying as you're like
changing all the nodes from one color to another and you're like yeah this is fun i'm like you know
but the ultimately what we wanted to do is um we wanted boss combat and poe 2 to matter when we
have it yeah and so in order like if you have a map uh boss every area then if we made it so the
boss combat mattered enough like in order to actually balance it that way stressful it's it's too much
like it actually is like you know you you spend too much of your time fighting bosses yeah um so
effectively if that's what you want to do now you can do it because there's bosses there you know
like when i say one of four maps is a map boss that doesn't mean that one for maps you play as one
um because you know obviously you can pick what content you're doing by exploring around
you're picking your path and your path exactly so effectively if you want to hunt the bosses then
that is the thing you can do um if you want to just like do some mindless grinding for a while
uh you can do that too and what it means is we can actually make the bosses way more rewarding
uh they can drop way more items than they were going to because of the fact that there's not one at the
end of every area right like and then and the fight is substantial you get a lot of drops um so uh
that actually is something and they get their own tree and they what oh yeah i don't know right you
mean the boss the boss killing tree yes there's a tree for boss hunting sorry i thought you meant every boss had
its own tree and i was like geez but did you do some design while i wasn't doing well i was looking
not yet not yet josh was like wait no wait stop it's too much that's like a year three feature
yeah okay okay we'll get that in mind um yeah yeah so there's actually like a i i do love that there's
a boss hunting because i'm super into that there's a boss hunting tree that you can fill out as well so
how do you get points on that like yeah so effectively i mean well you can um you get a lot of points for the
core tree there's a core tree that affects all mapping um that all the things like pack size
quantity rarity and you've got multiple keystones that um all work can work together and all can
do so i think there's three of them uh one plays on like corrupted maps one plays on like prefixes and
suffixes and i can't remember what the other ones other one does right in this very moment um but
you obviously get that core tree and then you have you know a boss tree and then obviously all the
different league and pinnacle content trees so you get those points by just completing maps it just
has a um you effectively get a quest um and effectively it's like you complete 10 maps you
get your first two points and then like complete x maps and one you know but of certain tiers like
yeah at least tier one at least tier two at least tier three climb effectively where it's like as you
get up the higher tiers and clear maps of certain tiers that's when you start getting points for the
at like may say the third one i um i can't remember the exact specifics it's like complete this and
defeat a boss or and then later it's defeat at least five bosses at something and you know so
killing bosses get generally it sounds way better for a start so i'm not having to like go and get
that estuary map that i missed or something yeah oh yeah for sure i'm just i'm just doing content
but it is kind of the analog of that in a way because like it's that feeling of like i've got a
system to progress through like i just need to i need to meet these objectives and definitely
got a lot of i'm getting and i'm getting from that you're getting the um you know the atlas uh
the atlas passive points and so on um so yeah that's kind of the idea yeah so you can really
like focus in on map blasting with the bossless maps and or you know or on bossing content if you want
to or on breaches or and you can always put a breach on a map with a boss right you can do both
yeah like they can have all they can have you can have you can have every type of content in one map
if you want yeah is like a boss map a kind of like a distinct thing from like a regular map in terms of
like the the layout or the thing you've done technically they are separate but generally
speaking um like they're like similar yeah they're basically the same they're pretty similar
they're pretty similar so they'll be like a boss history and a non-boss history yeah there are there
are some cases at the moment where there are some maps that can't have a boss um and because just we
haven't done the you know the the one that would go here is not in early access yet and that kind
of thing but effectively um you know it as i said generally speaking it'll be one and four that you'll find
um okay excellent um so i think i think that covers did i miss some things from you've got
like the all the smaller contents like the strong boxes and essences yeah yeah so initially we actually
had a design where everything um like even all the smaller content there was still going to be icons
for it on the tree as around the atlas yeah but we actually found that it meant that when you were
actually exploring it didn't kind of it felt like there was nothing random to find so we wanted to
make sure we also have kind of just completely random stuff that like doesn't have a progression
system that you just run into randomly because that's fun too and i will probably be adding more
stuff like that as well over time that's just like just the i randomly encountered this and that was
like not expected so that's all the stuff on the core atlas tree yeah so you can kind of like see
more of that if you want yeah yeah yep great and and often mods on the items as well on map
keep waystones yeah cool yep lots of different names maps waystone same thing
yes i've had to keep thinking kind of correcting myself about that i was like yeah i don't know
i mean internally we cut we definitely call them maps all the time uh the thing is is the
only reason why it doesn't make sense thematically is because a map does imply it's of a specific
location whereas a waste can take you to anywhere yeah so that's the reason why if the name change
had to happen but i think that probably even players will probably just call them maps i bet
just because you know if that's the period um so we've got we've got the breach delirium ritual
expedition those like leagues that maybe need a new name yeah um is there another one that you're just
both personally really keen to bring back in the future oh i mean you know like i've always wanted
to have uh delve again but i kind of got a bit of that wish with the system yeah it's also a very
uh like like content heavy league to make because you need to make tons of encounters and like
doing it properly is a huge thing but um i mean look i'm i i love incursion as well it's one of my
favorites like i'm keen for that i don't know if there's anything you other than that you're really
keen for there's a lot especially because there's a lot i can do with we can do with all this new
art new monsters new monsters right like for example if you just take legion legion had all
those five civilizations we've now got an entire new array of vile monsters vile bosses etc that we
can use as a baseline we've got way better consistent direction on what's going on there up you know heaps
of stuff new animation and the capacities are just like out of control but then you've got
okay incursion we've got you know awesome vile artwork we can use there and make that all awesome and
nice um new corruption mechanics that we can extrapolate on you don't want to have a roof
as the boss anymore no you're not just gonna have a floating roof the omnitex is just a small
floating roof oh you're keeping with the theme of vacuum cleaners
look standing and then the states were made now we have minimum like that's a world where you have
super uniques with one or two skills yeah yeah right i don't there's only so much you can do with a
floating roof so anyway and then um i don't know even like bestiary coming back with something
because we've got all these like awesome bosses way grander in scale and you can do these more grand
hunts for them as opposed to just like oh i'm like in a city and there's a rare spider you know
you can just get way way more epic and way more um you know involved and with all the new art
and so much stuff to like bestiary 2 that's like hunting big beasts and preparing for them and tracking them
that'd be pretty cool exactly i'd definitely take some mercenary action to that
good fit i feel all right well there's lots for us to look forward to there you have some kind of like
penned already for adding to the beta i mean we all plans can change but uh they're absolutely i mean
look that we've we've we've done things like commissioning art assets and so on like we've got
stuff coming along it's just question of like you know when we actually get there what's it going to
look like yep all right um let's talk about crafting a little bit because you've done a lot
there and it's uh pretty fundamental to the game i think um so what's the core of what you're trying
to do with crafting in part of exile 2 compared to part of exile 1 uh kind of noting that you've
really kind of stepped back from the idea of like reforging an item many times or scouring it
so um we really want to make it so that you're you're finding crafting items all the time you're using
those crafting items way more often than you were in pwe1 um that you know you like the the just the
the game of like picking something up like seeing what i could modify it to like then actually equipping
those items is just happening way more often and there's so many subtle changes around this like in
terms of um uh just like the way that the way that the base mods scale and items and the you know
like things like that like all the stuff to kind of make it so that um as you find new base types and
new things like you've got a reason to craft them you know part of that is making sure that um you know
you've got enough of that currency um you know it's it actually took us a long time to even get
comfortable with the idea of making something like an exalt drop that often because there's just this
thing in your cemented in your mind of like um you know oh this is this is rare right like it's an
exalt how can it possibly drop like you know multiple times in act one um you know like it just it
just seems crazy um but uh with the way like removing scouring affected so much of the way that we
can craft like i know that you noted earlier that um you can uh there's so many more things you're
allowed to craft now that you weren't allowed to before relics yes and the reason why that's
allowed is because without scouring um like those crafts become one time things which means that
it's actually okay to allow for that stuff and i think that's opened up a huge amount of um stuff
you know there's just yeah there's so many more types that can add so much more valuable value to
the dropped exactly exactly so um that stuff is just i think opened up a huge amount there and um it
also has and this wasn't necessarily an explicit goal right at the beginning but it's also meant that
the the the the the game of like i'm just going to click click click click click again and again
as my crafting session is no longer really the meta just spam rolling yeah exactly like everything
kind of is something that you want to be able to use um you are still reforging and metacrafting
things oh yeah yeah we've still got stuff like that right we've got a nulls and yes but that stuff
is higher up like that that's kind of more of a of a later game thing yeah exactly um because you
have to think about it after each time like will i improve this will i make it worse yeah um so uh yeah
yeah there's stuff to do there and like you know like the metacrafting that um omens can do
yeah um is also very interesting like there's some pretty powerful stuff there but once again we
introduce that stuff later on and so effectively we want to uh you know i guess for lack of better
democratize crafting at early levels like make sure that uh everyone's able to do that stuff um
while having the more advanced stuff be kind of a little bit later we certainly had a goal at one
point where i was like we're talking with rishi and i'm like if ever it's every single time we're
doing alpha wipes or getting the stuff to play i am like if i am not seeing and hearing about people using exalts
during act one then we have failed and we need to drop more of them and so we ended up like i
would say honestly in the last month we have like over like eight to ten times the amount of currency
dropping you know and you know there's the cool things about it as well which are the subtle things
like a boss is way more likely to drop the higher tier currencies and stuff because again rarity
affects that as well now so you're like way more incentivized to go and kill bosses to get them and
there's heaps of awesome stuff around there but we're actually now finding people are exalting gear
um during the campaign throwing it on weapons and building weapons from scratch that you find a
very good transmute org regal exalt exalt you know that process is like transmute um org regal exalt
is like a thing that you're doing often yeah and like enjoy and you know like you find good bases and
you do stuff with that i can speak to that experience so i've played probably six-ish hours
some most of the way through act two on my mercenary and i've found maybe six or seven exalts i took a ring
from like a one blue stat ring that had a nice roll maybe a nice life roll or something and
crafted it up to six property rare and i crafted a crossbow that i found with good sockets that had a
good damage roll on it and i took that to six properties with multiple damage mods i'm like
each time that power is going up and i was i was i was doing that it feels good i felt like the bottom
was regals which was actually kind of interesting because i don't know if that's intentional just luck
because i did really have to think about which blue items were good enough to take to a rare yep
so that i could then put my exalts on them so you get more of those by disenchanting rares
yeah they are farmable so they are farmable which is um completely intentional we want to make sure
that like if you don't have enough of those like so you get so generally speaking it's like you're
going to want to keep uh like i feel like once you get like more than like five or six transmutes
then you stop disenchanting blues and start selling them instead yeah and the same thing could be true
also for um for regals where it's like okay once you've got more than a certain amount then you're like okay
i can stop having to disenchant the stuff and kind of switch over but the nice thing is is like when you don't have
enough there is a way to get them um which i think is really important and the same is true with the
socket currency as well where it's like you know when you don't have enough you can start salvaging
i know you were telling me you were buying stuff from the vendor with sockets in order to surprise them
with my yeah yeah with my methods uh yeah yeah um so uh that stuff um you know it's just really nice
to have that for people to have the ability to um uh you know to to get that stuff when they need it
and so it's nice that like all that really basic stuff of just like getting items to better tiers
and it is now way easier to get and that solved a problem that we had um through quite a lot of
the betas where people were saying they didn't feel like they had enough control like they didn't
feel like they had a way to advance their character um when they needed to um to be able to solve
specific problems and i think the socket thing really has helped a lot with that now because
now we have a way finally to be like okay if i need a bunch of fire resist there is a way to get
that and i've got the tools to do it and i've got items i can use to do this stuff so um that um
has helped a huge amount i think of um solving those like uh you know you know issues that come
up with your character and this is to confirm how you've solved bench crafting exactly so we went
through so many iterations of bench uh stuff it was like a huge thing we implemented tons of ui like
there was tons of wasted time there uh implementing crafting things the problem that we had was that
the systems that we were making it's like we could balance them in the ways the players were happy with
and um then the designers were very unhappy or we could balance them the way the designers were happy with
and the players were unhappy and it's like when you've got a system where like you're fighting
the players for what how the balance should be yeah but you can tell that means you have a system
that is bad um but i think we were very like like i myself honestly was too slow to recognize the fact
that a complete overhaul was needed um and um then at some point we actually the socket stuff originally
came from um the var orb like it was designed there yeah and then at some point i don't know who came
up with it i think it might have just been you um who said like why don't we just no appreciate
rishi thought of that okay yeah so rishi thought of the idea of like hey what if we just put sockets
um you know in an early game what if you got them in act one what if you had rooms uh that would
like let you um get the uh the you know the baseball as the way of solving the remedial crafting problem
so then suddenly as soon as we do that it's like oh like i'm happy uh you know players are happy
everyone's happy um so that means we have a good system that uh is working and you know and gets those
good feelings so um that that i think was a real win um and uh you know yeah i'm i love how that system
is feeling at the moment yeah so the bench was achieving two things kind of in its way um which
was uh maybe even three gear customization for one like you take an item and you can do something
more to it firstly and then you've got the problem fixing of like oh i need a bit more fire resistance
and then the third thing was like the meta crafts um yeah yeah so you've handled those each in
different ways exactly you've got the runes which do the first two things the customization and the
problem fixing so early on but i think for the customization it's even it's it's the uh um
sorry what do you call them the soul cores like the runes are more about the kind of like i need to
fix resistances whereas the soul cores are more about like i want to customize my items in different
ways than what i would um otherwise normally be able to do um and then of course you've got the
omens to solve the meta crafting problem so we effectively move all that stuff around and
essences of course yes of course um yeah so um yeah essence is what they allow you to do is get two
deterministic mods yeah um so because you can upgrade to uh blue and the but you can also upgrade from
blue to um to to to rare um with an essence as well so that lets you kind of get some of that stuff
and then plus some of the omen things you can yeah there's stuff you can do there um that uh is i
think going to be pretty interesting so that's just at the start of release yeah because obviously
there's going to be more of course as we add more things you know so uh yeah um so i was like i was
worried that you know some of the changes you're making might move us away from some of the like deep
impactful crafting that we have but it sounds like you are still allowing like powerful
meta crafting for sure and the ability to make like a really good item for sure but you're also
making sure that like the physical item itself that you find matters more absolutely and i mean
like the more subtle that's what it's all about right there's so much more going on i think just
like just like clever things we've done with the um with the item system as well like one of the things
i love that we did is we've made it so that um so we've got blue and uh yellow chests you can find now
and we've changed the uh world generation so that if a dead end is generated um the chance that you
get a rare chest there is is way higher so effectively if a rare chest will spawn in the
area then it will choose dead ends first to go there you feel better about um yeah effectively so
like that means that we effectively mean that like when like it makes the world feel like you know as
far as item drops go that like oh like it feels intentional right like oh i went down this into this
dead end room but look there was a rare chest there so i feel happy about it you know like that kind
of thing is is is really cool um so uh there's things like that but there's also the way that um
yeah so we've alluded to a few times but the the way that rarity now works um where the mods get better
as rarity increases and um also things like the um you get better currency rather than just yeah
it means we don't have to have like the spam of items that's like crazy like you actually feel like
um the uh that you kill a boss and it drops good shit um as opposed to just lots of shit um so uh
you know that that's the uh that's that's that's i'm a big fan of how this feels i think it's a lot
better um but it does mean though of course if you're a pew we one player and you see a boss kill
like the number of like the the expectation of like because a pew one player sees like looks at the
amount of spam on the screen uh in some to some level as the way of like knowing uh how good the
drops were now of course you've got item filters and everything we have quantity brain right yeah yeah
exactly yeah um exactly that is a good way of putting it um so uh yeah it really is more about like is
the is are the items actually good like ideally you kill a boss and you pick every item it drops
up um you know like that is a uh that to me is a win and i think we've uh we we're we're basically
getting at that point yeah um i i quite like how um the uh exploration systems in that as well with
the chests down dead ends and things like that acts as a player leveler in some ways where like
the more you're struggling yep the more you explore the more stuff you'll find and that's true as
well for the um optional encounters around the place as well um if you're um if you're struggling
go fight some optional content there'll be stuff there that can um that can drop and you know um
that then and you will definitely find more things and lots of guaranteed rare rare items here and
there exactly like that so this little boss here will drop a caster a rare caster item and like heaps
of stuff and the funny thing about that is that stuff um like the came about a little bit from the fact
that um we actually had a problem where people were just uh face tanking bosses and dying over and over
again yeah they keep on respawning and they would never be like oh i'm gonna go away and uh actually
find some other stuff and so um i was thinking for a long time about like well why is it that in other
games um that people don't do that like if i'm playing elden ring and i die to a boss like you know
10 times i'm not just gonna like just just continue doing that i'm gonna be like oh maybe i'll go do
something else for a while so we realized that the map like the idea of just there's lots of stuff to
find like there's actually a really important part of that so in pwee 2 now one of the recent uh things
and it's taken a lot of work from uh from people to get this working but now all of that um uh there's
a you can see all the sort of weird side encounters that have specific drops on the map yeah and that
means that you know if you're if you're having trouble with the boss you're like oh you know
what i'm just gonna go do some other stuff um and uh then you'll come back and you will be powerful
enough to kill the boss much more easily because you do absolutely find the rewarding things yeah
there's a little chest on there or a little campsite yeah yeah like you know there's lots of little
hard-coded drops from specific bosses they only the hard-coded drops they only drop one time so you can't
just farm them endlessly yeah but effectively if you go do all that side content and you check it
all off you'll get um some very rewarding stuff yeah you got some pretty clever systems there and
i definitely noted that i was using the map thing a lot so i'd be like oh well to be completionist
about it a bit but also yeah just being aware of like oh cool there was some there's some good
stuff in this zone that i can come and find and uh i think we figured out that like that some of
that stuff reveals after you like find the waypoint in a zone i think that's how it works is that yeah it's
either there's a few things so it's like uh either because an npc told you about an area in which case
it just happens to be revealed uh or at the very least yes when you get there uh generally it's just
when you get there you see everything um but there's a few different conditions that will reveal
everything um it kind of depends like a lot of people just click through the dialogue so they'll never
know the npc told them but they maybe i was checking my map kind of like when i went into a zone and then
maybe afterwards to see if there was anything but like you never get to an area and and don't see some
unless they are like very obviously hidden intentional secrets that there's no one
everywhere they might be there they might not have found half of your key for your secret quest
oh yeah yeah don't worry about that
so uh pivoting into economy and trading um the exchange from path of exile's one experiment
recently we got a chance to actually try that live in the field and it seems from the players
perspective it was a smash hit like definitely for us as well yeah okay solved a lot i'm like we're 100 on
board with that um it's very good it was the least least stressful league i ever played
i mean what what normally caused almost all the anger and friction for me was was um
was yes especially bulk trading it was horrible and i was just like oh this is like a dream come true
myself and so many other players i feel like we're more engaged in endgame we were able to do the
thing we wanted to do more and we're just less aggravated on that moment to moment basis that's good so do you
take that then as like um as a big positive for it going into part of exile 2 100 and how do you
feel like it adapts to the game being quite different in the end because they are pretty
different games like the economy works a bit differently um i mean honestly i think it will
i think it will just work um i mean look we don't we have no idea what the trade values will settle on
and like how that'll end up but yeah like is it going to be chaos is going to be
yeah but uh ultimately i think that the trades like effectively settlers was a test of what the
trade of what the um economy will be like in poe 2 and to some extent because of the way that you
know we did the gold and everything yeah so um i'm pretty confident that that's going to be okay
but obviously you never know right like uh when lots of people hit the economy what can happen um
hopefully we don't cause like horrible hyperinflation or have some horrible issue like that but uh i guess
well you know i part of partly this is what a what an early access is to find out right like
whether there's any issues like that was there any economy testing was there any surprises with
that or with gold in terms of how things panned out um thankfully not honestly like uh we were
worried but thankfully none of the like horrible situations came to pass with that and uh it ended
up working just fine so um yeah like uh it went great who'd have thought 10 years later we'd be
back here saying you know what gold was a good idea exactly exactly because we're i remember 10
years ago we're like this game is brilliant it has no gold stupid gold but the funny thing is is
i don't think we would have arrived at the way gold is now if we had had it in the first place yeah
like the non-tradability of either using it as a sort of marker for how much play you've done i just
don't i don't think that we would have ever had that way if we hadn't arrived from here so yeah
i think that path dependency kind of did matter um so yeah the paths we weave um so uh
uh how likely then based on just how successful it is are you to want to expand the like exchanges
capabilities to like other things like maps or waystones or even gear um well i mean look i'm
interested in this but i don't think it's necessary right now so we're not going in early access at
least um we're not going to launch with any expanded stuff in that way um but i guess i i do want to
sort of see how it works and um i'm interested in potentially trying something like that in the
future i just don't like the currency exchange was like 90 of the problem yeah um and and so
fixing that like fixed a lot of the you know like it seemed like there would be we would need to do
more initially and then maybe now it's seeming like maybe we don't but i still i i still want
to experiment with it potentially so um you know i'm interested to see how it goes but um yeah the
currency exchange definitely helped um a vast amount those were the annoying yeah they were for sure
they would yeah yeah definitely great um so we've had some uh well uh so this is a tricky question
to answer especially if we could just scroll down yeah um so what are you aiming for in terms of path
of exile 2 is kind of like personal player economy and progression uh so how much resources you're
acquiring how you're uh using them but also how much are you getting from trade versus from yourself
i mean this is a tricky question but i mean i think that really the feeling of like being able to trade
is super important so being able to get that stuff i think um is good like now not everyone wants to do
that you need to be able to progress through the game well without having to do much trade but um i do
think that like you know look it's definitely going to be the case that if you're playing in a trade
league you're going to have um the ability to to accelerate you very significantly and that's
that's that's the case and it will continue to be the case and yeah like we are a game that embraces
trade yeah like i think the dna of path of exile one is very much that like it is a game about
economy and trade and for some people getting rich is their main motivator 100 so effectively yeah so
i mean that that that will absolutely affect it and look like i think that the feeling of that will
probably end up feeling quite similar to pwee one in that regard yeah um and um i think that's what
you know that's the type of game we're making yeah do you think it's uh that said though do you
think it is in some ways better for a for a solar cell found sort of experience um i mean i simply
do simply because again as we talked about we're dropping a lot more currency that we expect you
to use on right as opposed to save to end game for one and then by end game like we don't have um
kerak mods costing you know that kind of stuff that all costs chaos and you don't have like the
meta mods costing divines and all that right they're all different items you know i want meta mod crafting
there's a ritual you know where to get them as well right so you're not just like having to
i'm blocked behind this thing because i need so many divines and i can't get that because i'm
solar self-found and farming divines is not exactly you know beyond trivial so you know there's a number
of ways there where i'd say it is honestly a much better solar self-found experience um but you know
each to their own that to be seen and you know and there'll be a separate solar self-found mode
presumably even potentially beta launch or in the future uh it is our intention to have
hardcore and solar self-found cool yeah i wouldn't play hardcore for your first round honestly because
uh you're likely to die like once you learn the boss mechanics it should be fine but someone's gonna
first time you know it's gonna be tricky couch co-op hardcore and you get to see your friend die right
next to you that's the true dream actually actually hang on wait in couch co-op hardcore do we still
lock the camera so you can't walk away from your friend uh no we we put you back to you back to
back to back to okay great that's good good to know it's like you have a morning period of about
30 seconds right right right but you're just like all right you can go home now i'm like yeah yeah
see you what do you do yeah that is uh that's a devastating moment um so uh
uh i did lose my place there um yeah i think we mentioned the co-op support and everything and
we'll scroll down and take some of the additional questions here excellent thanks um so uh will there
be a penalty for individual party member dying when grouping up for bosses on that note then
uh it seems weird that the boss straight up resets when playing solo but when playing in a group
nothing happens if a party member dies so tell us about the rules yeah because i know you've changed
them recently uh yeah so well bosses are obviously harder for having more people yeah um less crowd
controls um things like um obviously more life and i'm not just saying double life more than double
life right it does get more than twice as hard or more than in players as hard um
so yes you could argue okay we have reviving as an advantage well yes it does it does take time to
revive and if your friend dies early and you're unable to revive them because you're constantly being
interrupted well if i'm not sorry it's pretty hard you're not having a fun time get a big stun or
something um another change that we made recently is of course for each revived between each set of
checkpoints every time you have to revive them the revive takes longer subsequent times so that's
important because it just means that um if you're like you can't revive spam anymore because it's
going to take longer and longer each time um but then when you go to a checkpoint that resets so um
like you're back to normal now in end game maps you cannot revive each other death is a consequence
yeah um i was gonna ask actually about like end game maps and um what is the rule for dying
anything about is it one portal deal now not six portals well you still have six portals so you
have your party members but there's all right and you can leave and come back as long as you don't
die so you can take items out but a death will end that map for you ah yeah and to remind people the uh
if you like log out or server crashes or something like that's gonna happen then uh
the game pauses so when you log when you boot the game back up and log back in you'll be still in
your map right and also um even that we've also now have it so that when you if you just like if you just
order for the game at a random time um you'll actually even if you come back like you know
like the next day um you know because for example you might have rage quit you you you will appear
back at the checkpoint you were at so if you um are like fighting a boss you die a bunch of times
you're like ah crap uh older four um you come back you're going to be right there at the boss checkpoint
again that part is campaign specific because there are no checkpoints in maps yeah non maps but in um
for the for the campaign though um and that honestly um this has helped a lot like uh there were so many i
i think it's actually i think it i think it really did cause new players to have problems in pb1
where um they felt like they just lost track of where the hell they even were when they came back
after a session if like they might have not got waypoints for certain times or things like that
like you now can't have the situation where you log back in and you're like oh i'm like i forgot
like three waypoints in a row and now i'm like freaking miles away from where i was
um which i think happened to new players fairly frequently i'm glad in a world where everyone's
becoming a souls like that you guys didn't do the running back to the boss
right right right right right right right right right and you just kind of jump back in
yeah yeah i have another crack um so uh yeah so effectively like that that's nice to just have
the save checkpoints um to your to your character um which i think is a nice one um were there any
other mechanics around there reviving well obviously in hardcore you're dead you're dead
that's the drill so your maps almost embraces a kind of semi-hardcore mentality there where there is
actual cost like we went through so many iterations here where it's like okay like the moment that you
have to spend something of economic value to do the attempt yeah hence a map a map item and
especially if it's got breaches and all this content that's coming from precursor tablets all of the
stuff is worth stuff so you all of a sudden have heaps of stuff on the line and then you don't want to
be in a position where you're like uh no i i need to bring in some people to do this because i'm not
going to risk that value um so that's why we just were like in maps no reviving it's just like yeah sure
you still can always bring in any context someone way more powerful than you to carry things right
that's the benefit of multiplayer um but feeling like you have to do this thing because then they
can just keep reviving you so you can get all the rewards like we're trying to get away from all of
that otherwise you get this weird thing where like you you're often always too scared to do the thing
now now you're scared but everyone's scared and it's fine and you don't feel like you you're like okay i
you have to go in with a sense of confidence to like i can definitely do this thing um and so it's
just a little bit less fear when it comes to all of a sudden doing that that's much better in the
context of the fact that you can pause the game if your cat's on fire or if uh the server crashes
or something that you just paused and you can jump back in as well you're failing because of your own
faults yep now it's worth noting in multiplayer we do have a thing of course we've respawn at checkpoints
as an option so if a player dies and you don't want to like you don't want to die you
you don't want to finish the fight out you can both choose to respawn at checkpoint and then it
will just create a new instance you don't you don't have to die to do it um and you don't have to log
out and do any shenanigans like that you can just press escape hit respawn at checkpoint it'll ask
other players to confirm and then it moves you all to the new area cool excellent um i didn't want to
go super on it because we've definitely talked about it before but click to move versus wsd it's
definitely been asked about a bit um so there's been plenty of reports about wsd being amazing
personally i've been using it a ton and really enjoying it i know a lot of you've said a lot of
people around the office have like given it a try and adapted to that but it has raised the point for
people that feel like they're still uh very much against that for whatever reason or maybe that they
literally only have one hand and and want to use click to move still um how does it stack up how does
click to move still stack up now i think i think honestly it's fine like it's not been a problem i i
there was a time where every time i'd go to sit down at a developer's computer that'd be in wsd and just
because it's a little bit easier to move around again or whatever um but lately i'd say now it's
back to almost every designer's computer i sit back down at to go play they're back and click to move
interesting yeah it's gone full tilt the other way um and i'm always like ah change it back
um but um even watching octavian play on click to move he's a click to move player yeah yeah he's 100
click to move he is very proficient with that yeah with it that'll be reassuring for i think some of
the people that are worried about being forced into wsd even though it is obviously playing so
well by many by all accounts um that's very good then yeah and octavian's often doing the
demonstrations for your live things too so you'll be able to see that even i have to force them to
play wsd sometimes because i'm like oh i think the mercenary looks so much better with wsd just
visually yeah um so uh you know it does feel very good on the mercenary yeah they're kind of like
stalking through especially with that kind of like preparational yeah yeah play style yeah yeah
that's good loving loving it so far um we did already talk about the skin transfers could we
scroll down to any additional questions that we have i feel like i don't even know how long we've
been going for but i i mean it's a while we're getting creeping at this yeah exactly we've been going
we've been rolling yeah yeah um people asking if there's going to be anything like challenges or
challenge rewards in the early not at first no we will do it later though did i ask about races
events and private leagues uh i think not initially um but we will do it later for sure
um i think the i'm not sure what happened because i think i think the issue was that the private
league interface was like on the poe one site and we had to do some work and something like that
it wouldn't be far away though like it won't take us that long before we get to it like you know
i can't exactly remember either but yeah it wouldn't be private leagues in particular wouldn't be far
away yeah yeah um yeah so i mean we'll have them just not like right initially potentially
and uh i think i did miss this actually so cluster jewels are a thing or not a thing are they they've
been kind of replaced by those yeah we replace them with that almost like rollable timeless jewel kind
of thing yeah um at least for now there's like so much passive tree there and the jewels accomplish
the kind of off build thing anyway you hardly need to add the extra passive trees on your passive trees
yes yes we don't yeah we that's after launch we made the passive tree implicitly bigger so
the cost of jewels are in the tree already that's again i talk about like year three features that's
that's around like year three to year five feature as well so yeah we got another decade of what we
had with path of exile one to look forward to for path of exile two hopefully before we
start uh worrying about path of exile three maybe geez you go just just to start thinking just
start thinking about it we uh so i guess to just finish this off for today then do you guys have
a recommendation or of what is the best class to play in the beta uh i mean that's a very hard one um
honestly like so so many choices there are so let me well okay if we're going by the numbers oh yeah
if we go by player satisfaction reports on uh per class uh we break it down yeah i mean this is good
uh then uh then that means the monk is very interesting because the monk is the class that
dies the most often but it's also the class that when people play it they have the highest satisfaction
level by a very very tiny margin that compares the others that's fascinating yeah i mean it is like
glass cannon you know like it's very fast but you have to you have to retreat and move in and out
i fell in love with the monk playing it looks like it's got a little better yeah yeah that's interesting
but um i think if you're a new player um then the mercenary if you're like used to shooters and stuff i
think playing the mercenary could be a good win like i i i really love that class
um i don't know like i've been loving the mercenary um but uh to me it feels like a you need to really
be considering each engagement a lot more it's a bit more a bit more tactical
i don't know like i like it i i really like correct if you but um honestly like i mean i i go through
favorite classes all the time whenever i change to play a different class that becomes my favorite
so you know yes it's whatever whatever i'm playing tends to be the thing so uh yeah right now i'm doing a
mercenary playthrough so that's probably why i'm uh into that but uh yeah that's uh i'm not sure if
you've got a similar you're talking about the numbers as well it was interesting that monk and
then warrior had the highest satisfaction by the way technically if you're looking for that's pretty
good that's uh two melee classes exactly that's a win yeah that's something going on i mean they were
dying a lot more at the time but yeah it's such a change from like especially early part of exile
one like it's got a little better in one days but still i mean i i just have a like real desire
to freeze time so i just want to just go i don't know what it's good to get some sorceress love i
feel like she's not getting enough attention i don't know what i don't know what skills i'll play
but i definitely just want to be able to freeze time so yeah it just feels cool all right so you
could be playing you could be playing crossbow building yeah i might be a crossbow time freezer i don't
know we'll see what's going on yeah all right i i noted i liked that i noted that our mercenaries were
very different as well i was playing full grenade or you were i was doing the freeze uh free shotgun
yeah very cool yeah yeah some sort of monk trigger build obviously it's always just going to be fun
to yeah they have so many of those like stacking effects the wind and the ice coming off it and
the ascendancy showed some more as well just see how far that can be pushed and how many spells can i
get to trigger per second yeah like they'll seem good for that all righty well thank you very much for
your time both of you for i don't even know how long that was a mammoth session i think we're
coming up to one o'clock here so there's still lots to talk about but i think we just need some
time to digest for sure for sure um so uh well thankfully we didn't have everyone saying patch
notes when uh this time so good so that means we actually have a conversation there's no pressure
on this to like wrap it up yeah yeah exactly um so uh you know that's good fantastic all right thank
you very much for watching everybody i hope you enjoyed the q a that's a good eat oh they want patch
notes now oh thank you exactly exactly where's the launch notes yeah yeah all right all right
all right yeah and thank you very much thanks heaps appreciate it it's been an epic journey it's
kind of surreal and uh it's only the start of another journey really so that's it yeah can't wait to play
it's cool i mean i'm gonna go play more now but yeah that's true sorry yeah i gotta go fix bosses going
up elevators and sorry yeah i'm just pre-bug testing all right i assume we've faded out and cut hopefully
you never know