Hello.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Let's do my legs.
All right.
There we go.
Audio test.
I'm going to turn you up to 120.
Let's test again.
Okay.
Does that sound good?
Hello.
This is Mark.
Let's see.
Still louder.
Okay.
I'll turn you up to 160.
Try talking.
How's it sound now?
Does that sound all right?
And how does this sound?
This is Mark again.
We might be able to get it turned up on our end.
Well, I think now is good.
I'm going to try to get a...
Okay.
But I have echo when I speak, I think.
Yeah.
I can hear myself.
Okay.
All right.
We'll just get our audio guy to fix that.
Yeah.
All right.
Can you try again now?
Hello.
Testing.
One, two, three.
Okay.
I don't think I have echo anymore.
How...
What's...
I'm still louder than them.
Yeah.
Maybe turn yourselves up a little bit.
Okay.
Hey, Jenna.
You able to get the...
Sweet.
All right.
Apparently it's cranked up a bit now.
Is that better?
How's that chat?
Is that okay?
Test, test.
How is this chat?
How is this?
A bit more.
I mean, I can turn them up a little bit more.
I can put them up to 170.
Okay.
All right.
Try now.
Testing.
One, two, three.
Is that okay?
Hopefully that's all right.
Okay.
Everybody's saying good.
And my comparative audio to them is good?
All right.
Okay.
Cool.
Everyone's saying good.
I just hope my OBS doesn't crash during this.
Like, I've had some, like, OBS issues lately.
Okay.
So, hopefully not.
But, yeah.
I'm ready to start.
I'll do just, like, a quick intro, and then we go.
So, but, yeah.
Thank you so much for joining me here for our podcast after the launch of Point2.
This is Jonathan and Neon, for those that don't know, directors of GDD.
And, yeah, we're here to talk about the launch.
Yeah.
I mean, well, you know, it's always good to have a chat.
You know, obviously it's a bit of a contentious launch in some ways this time.
So, I'm sure there's going to be a lot of questions about that.
But, you know, it's always good to have a chat.
Yeah.
No, I do have a lot of questions.
So, I think we'll just get right into it.
Sure.
A lot of people are pretty unhappy with the current state of the game, especially, like, our relative power to the monsters earlier on.
And, obviously, we are finding some builds that are feeling okay and that are stronger.
But I'm asking, are the slower and more challenging builds the intended pace of the game?
Well, I don't know that, once again, I mean, we get this question a lot, right, of just the, like, what is the pace of the game supposed to be?
And I honestly find it hard to answer that because of the way that, like, there isn't really a, like, an obvious way to, like, to even quantify that, given that players have so many different abilities.
What I will make, like, all I can say is, is that if people are unhappy, then we will keep on improving things until they're not unhappy anymore.
Because, ultimately, we want to get the smooth progression where, you know, you start the game, you feel weak, you get stronger, you get stronger, you get stronger, you keep on feeling stronger and stronger.
And, like, you have to have that, like, progression where, you know, you're feeling more and more powerful as you're going through.
So, if you're not feeling that, then that means there's something that we have to improve and get better.
Like, and so, like, it really comes down to, like, okay, if you're talking about a weaker build, like, well, what build is it?
And, you know, like, then we'll be looking into that and seeing what we can do to improve it.
Like, we just have to go through these things one at a time.
So, I think right now the problem is that it's almost every build this week for a lot of archetypes and that it's more like, it's definitely in the minority that people are like, oh, I found something that works.
So, it's, like, almost like the reverse there.
And I guess I'm curious, like, what amount of time are you expecting people to take going through the entire campaign or on your own test realm?
Or, like, when you're doing test runs, how long do you take on a first campaign run?
You know, I actually haven't measured that on the current, like, version.
And it doesn't necessarily always work that way.
Like, the number of times I play through the full, and when I say campaign here, I'm talking about six acts, not just three.
Yeah.
Like, if you're talking about the amount of time, like, doing that, like, I might only do that, like, that full run, like, two or three times in total as we're developing a class.
Like, much more often I'm, like, either testing this part or I'm testing that part or whatever.
And I honestly am not sure exactly what amount of time that that's taking.
But, like, as I said, I don't know that, like, the time – like, the thing is, the presupposition with this question is that, like, you know, that we have a goal in mind for the amount of time for the campaign.
And the implication of that is that the campaign itself is not fun.
But it's, like, if that's the implication, then we just want to make that fun, right?
You know, it's, like, the campaign should be fun to play.
The amount of time it takes, to me, is not nearly as relevant as just make it fun, right?
If you aren't having fun, we want to make sure that it is.
So, like, that's why, you know, when we're, like, okay, people are saying, like, we don't like the Act 3 areas, make those shorter.
It's, like, well, what amount of – like, I don't think that quantifying that in an amount of time is the right way to look at it.
It's, like, here are some areas that are unfun.
I'll make those areas fun.
And then whatever the duration of time that that takes will not be bothering you.
And that may result in the areas becoming shorter.
But making it shorter is not, like,
like, it isn't a time metric that we are looking at to determine whether or not the game is good.
It's, is the game good fun to play?
So, like, that, I guess, is kind of the way that I would look at things.
And that's, I think, what puts us a little bit, like, when it comes to communication with the community,
like, people will have their opinion about what they think is the reason that the game isn't fun.
And they might be right or they might not be right or whatever.
But at the end of the day, what we're looking at is just, like, okay, you're obviously having a bad time.
We want to fix that.
So we're going to look at, like, here – like, so what we'll do is we'll be, like, okay,
so you're saying Act 3 isn't good.
We'll look at Act 3.
We'll look at the reasons why it might be bad.
We'll fix those reasons.
And then that may or may not reduce the time.
In this case, it definitely will.
Like, it's shortened it by a lot.
But, you know, and then – but to me, it's, like, the frustrating thing is when you go down a dead end
and you're, like, okay, you know, like, this is, you know, this is bad or – and then, like, you have to respawn or in the area doesn't – you know, like, the area despawns and you're, like, you have to do things again.
That kind of stuff, right?
That's the stuff that people don't like to do.
And so that's what we sort of look at.
And so then when it comes – coming back to builds again, once again, it's, like, okay, if you're not having fun with your build, then that is a problem.
We'll fix that.
But it's not like there's a correct pace for the game to be played at as such.
We just need to make sure that you're enjoying yourself.
Well, I guess a follow-up to that was I, among with many others, were not expecting a nerf to just how the campaign felt in general, right?
In the last interview I heard, it really sounded like the intention was to target things at the top end.
But there were so many things that nerfed us during the campaign here.
And a lot of –
Well, the first – the thing I would say about that –
I would like to finish.
Sure, sure.
A lot of people are really wondering about the long-term direction for the game with that in mind because they were also not expecting that.
So a lot of people are wondering –
Well, we weren't attending to the campaign, to be clear.
That was going to be my question.
That was not our intention.
So we should be more powerful than we currently are during the campaign then.
Well, that one I will have to look at specific cases, right?
Because, like, that comes down to –
Okay, so, like, we already did something about that, right, where we, like, nerfed Monster Life.
And it's possible that we would have to nerf Monster Life again if that's still a problem.
Like, that's the kind of thing that we can do.
But the thing is, is that, like, the – as I said, like, the first thing we heard when everyone was saying this, the first thing we thought was, like, what the hell?
We didn't even nerf the campaign.
Like, literally, that's what all developers were saying.
We didn't nerf this.
Why is everyone saying we nerfed it?
And so, like, then it's like, well, we found a few things.
But, like, we're still looking for what those things are.
Like, it's not always necessarily obvious with all the changes that you make and things.
Because I can absolutely tell you that our goal here was nerf the endgame, right?
Like, nerf the – like, well, no.
It wasn't even nerf the endgame.
What it was was nerf the things that were trivializing the endgame before you've even managed to get the – you know, like, your items and stuff like that.
Like, just the really trivial, easy shit.
Like, that was our intention.
I mean, there were some blatant fuck-ups.
Yeah, yeah.
Speaking bluntly, right?
Like, the minion change was just bad.
And when you say the minion change, are you referring to the rare minions or are you referring to the player minions?
Because those are both –
Well, both of those were incredibly terrible.
Both were just fuck-ups.
Yes.
Those were just fuck-ups.
And the thing is, it's so easy for shit like that to slip through.
Well, we have a bit of a – and a lot of it is just because there's a little bit of – it's early access, so we're allowed.
But we are firing from the hip a lot here.
And stuff like that, like, let's get it in there.
Let's try it out.
See how people think.
And if it's bad, we'll just undo it, right?
Like, we do regress on a decent number of things in the first few days of a release.
And so, yeah, there are some pretty blatant fuck-ups.
So, yeah, that's exactly what happened with the rare minion life.
It was like, what the – why are now – I don't know why it felt this way, but 100% it was the case that the minions was – for some reasons, the rare minions were surviving longer than the rare often.
And it's like, well, it doesn't – they don't have anywhere near as much life as the rare.
And then, again, once people got enough AoE and all of that, it solved it.
But it was just a bad experience.
There was just nothing good about that.
Right.
I think there was definitely a compounding of a few factors that were, like, on their own relatively small.
But the thing is, is that if – and this is the question that I have is, is that, like, if people are still having a bad time during the campaign, if they're starting fresh now –
because bear in mind as well that people will have an experience and then will change the balance behind them and then they still remember that the experience was bad and they're not playing it again to know that it got better.
So the thing is, if you're playing it again and still having a bad experience in the campaign, then that would be a thing where it's like, okay, well, where are the –
the campaign nerfs, actually?
Like, we have to find where they are because I don't – like, I don't know that there's anything intentionally done there that we're sort of aware of left.
And I think, like, that one just means that, yeah, like –
I can give examples.
There might still be issues.
Yeah.
Sure, sure.
We'll go for it.
What is it?
So the number one, especially to me, most oppressive thing, is the relative speed of monsters compared to our abilities to set things up.
Like, whenever you're talking –
Hang on, hang on.
But that's not a thing that changed, though.
No, but that's been continuously bad.
It doesn't matter if it's changed or not.
Okay, sure, sure, sure.
But what I'm saying is that – okay, but this is an example –
Well, I think that has changed.
But that's just an example of something that's bad.
So what I'm saying is that's not a thing that changed.
So, like, if you're talking about, like, is it your intention of the campaign?
But we are weaker now, right?
A lot of skills –
But if you're saying that's bad, I mean, that's a different question, right?
A lot of skills are weaker now, right?
They were tuned down on a lot of things, and things that people are starting with weren't necessarily strong.
So that relative speed of the monsters feels extra bad.
Like, you want us to set up these combos and stuff, right?
Where we're throwing down, like, a cyclone and trying to do, like, a combo move.
But the monsters are way too fast.
They're rushing us.
It's not even, like, the bosses are the main problem, right?
Like, if you're seeing, like, clips –
Yeah, so let's talk about the monster speed thing.
So one of the issues that we have is that if monsters are slower than the player, then combat is optional.
Like, it's just 100% the case.
Like, you cannot – if the monsters are slow – like, any time the monsters are slow in the player, then you can just run past them and they serve no –
Like, they don't – like, effectively you can just choose whether or not to engage or not.
And, like, I don't think that that kind of gameplay is good.
Now, there will probably be some areas –
Like, and the thing is, a lot of the time when people talk about stuff like this, it's like there'll be a few areas that are bad.
Like, I know there are definitely a few areas where, like, too many of the monsters are fast.
So the Faradon are a good example of that, where, like – like, when you go to the, like, the last areas of Acts 2, like, the Faradon are just really, really fast.
And there's kind of nothing slow in the area.
And so that's an example where, like, we probably want to make some tuning in.
I mean, to get more specific, like, I'm actually – I have someone right now literally going through the areas –
all areas in the campaign and listing all the areas that have a disproportionately high number of monsters that are too swarmy or too fast.
They're doing it literally as we speak up.
And my intention after this is to go through – and so, like –
I mean, a good example is, like, the canopy, right?
The canopy.
The monsters are real fast.
And then not only that, you're in a ritual with them in a tight, confined space.
And it just – you end up in this kind of moving around with packs.
So if you're not fast enough to kill everything, yeah, you just get absolutely swarmed.
And, yeah.
I guess I'm a little –
But the thing – just to follow – just to continue with that, though.
I just – because I just want to mention that, like, one of the issues we run into is, like, people will say, oh, you know, like, things should never be faster than the player and that kind of stuff.
And it's like, well, if we did that, then the game would feel pretty lame.
So it really is a question of, like, targeted changes, like finding where the worst things are and then solving that issue.
I really disagree with that.
So you were saying, like, if the monsters are slower than the player, then combat is optional.
But, like, it's an ARPG.
We want to kill the monsters.
That's where all the loot is.
That's where our XP is.
Like, sure, you'll have some speedrun scenarios where people are running past them.
But usually what ends up happening is that we're running past them, bunching them up in a large bunch and killing a bunch of them.
And that just feels really good.
That's a core part of ARPGs for a lot of people.
So I don't think that being faster than the monster is as bad as you think it is.
Like, we actively want to kill monsters.
That is the entire premise.
Well, I don't necessarily disagree with you that gathering and killing is fun, right?
And you should still be able to do that.
But I would, as I said, I don't think anything about the fact that some monsters are faster than the player prevents that.
I don't think you can have areas where everything is slower than the player.
Like, it really isn't that great.
In PeeWee 1, in the distant past, we had that problem.
And it just meant that running past monsters was the thing you did all the time.
And then there were some changes.
Like, I don't know how many years ago it was.
Like, what was it?
Four years or something like that?
When was the act one?
Like, we made changes where we made a lot of monsters faster than the player.
And that wasn't negatively perceived at the time.
It just made the monsters feel better that we had there.
So, like, you absolutely can have monsters faster than the player.
And I do think it's important to have those kinds of situations.
Like, it just shouldn't be that it's...
Like, it's just that, like, you need to make sure you're getting the balance right.
And I think that it's, like, a running theme with PeeWee 2 in general is that the target to hit is smaller.
Like, because if we want the combat to be more engaging,
then that means there's a smaller target that, like...
Like, it puts more pressure on the balance to be right.
And so I think that's the main issue that we're running into is just that, like...
Like, it's okay if, like, if everything...
If...
Okay, so this is sort of a larger topic, right?
But effectively, it's like...
In PeeWee 1, there are so many tools that the knowledge ceiling is absolutely astronomical.
And so you have a situation where a good player can completely dominate everything to, like, the absolute nth degree, right?
Now, what that means is that you've got a scenario where...
The game seems like an impenetrable mountain to a new player.
Because, like, if you don't know what you're doing, the game is just, like, impossible to understand.
And it's like, there's all these tools that you can use to improve yourself.
But the existence of everything like that and, like, having such a huge skill ceiling means that you can just trivialize the game right at the start.
And so, like, what that means...
What that also means, though, is that, like, if we get balance numbers wrong...
Like, if a monster has, like, double life by accident in PeeWee 1, it, like, doesn't even really matter.
Whereas if a monster has double life in PeeWee 2, it matters a lot.
And so what I'm saying is that the threshold for what is right is, like, way tighter in PeeWee 2.
And so that means it will just take longer to balance and get it all correct.
But it really is the case, I think, that it's getting all those numbers right that kind of makes it, like, that will make the combat ultimately fun at the end of the day.
And, like, if we're doing our job correctly, then we'll still have this situation where a good player feels like they dominate and a bad player feels like they have a good time.
But we won't have a situation where, if you're a good player, the combat is so trivialized that you literally never have a moment where you're in any danger or have any kind of, like, level of, like, sort of interest going on.
And I think that's the worry that we have when we're looking at things is, like, if we get to the point where, like, a good player never has to face a single challenge ever, then I don't think that that's going to be a game that will ultimately be fun in the long term.
And so that's kind of, like, that is, to me, the reason, like, what I fear happening if we just, like, say, okay, we're just going to, like, lower everything and make it easy.
And that, once again, that isn't to say that we shouldn't necessarily, like, maybe Monster Life does have to come down.
Like, if we're in the wrong band, we just need to lower it and that's fine.
Like, we will get to the point where that is fun.
But we'll do that by making, while still making sure that we have a good experience for, you know, like, ideally for everyone, right?
Like, it should be the case that it is balanceable to that way.
It's just a lot harder in PoE2 context.
Well, I think a large portion want, like, bosses to be what is the challenging content, whereas right now it's almost the reverse, where there's so many clips of, like, people, like, dodge rolling away from, like, packs, right?
And they're getting chased down, maybe not having a counterplay.
And they're like, oh, my God, I'm, like, I'm just being chased down.
So, and also I sort of disagree on the Act 1 changes in PoE1 not being negatively received.
I do remember there was quite a lot of people that really didn't like that because of what you mentioned with, like, the faster monsters is generally a bad thing.
So, I definitely do disagree with that.
Just because I like to have things to actually go and start to address.
Like, can I get a gauge on what you think is, like, where in the game it starts to become a problem?
Or do you think it's, like, just straight out of the gate?
Straight out of the gate.
Like, even the second zone, like, the first zone might be okay, but the second zone with the wolves, it's, like, pretty, like, instant, where I don't feel like I'm getting that, like, ARPG play style.
But won't we be hurting more players than we're helping with that?
By making monsters slower?
Like, won't that immediately make it?
Yeah.
Won't we that immediately mean that, like, a ton of players who actually enjoy the game because the combat is engaging immediately, like, what, doesn't it kill the game for them?
Like, what I'm saying is, like, it's easy to say, like, oh, you make the game easier and everyone's happy, but it isn't the case.
Like, a lot of people prefer the game to, like, actually have some challenge in it.
Like, for example, right?
Okay, so here's the thing, right?
So, every night I go home and I play, and I, like, do test runs of everything, right?
And it's, like, if we made it so that there wasn't any challenge for me in Act 1, I wouldn't play the game anymore.
And that isn't helping anyone, right?
Like, I need to keep playing the game every night to actually enjoy myself.
It's, like, if I'm not enjoying myself, then it's, like, how can I even develop the game correctly?
So, on some level, it's, like, it has to be fun for me.
And I know that if you, like, if you get to the point of having, like, everything just be trivial, it's, like, well, okay, like, why am I even playing this anymore?
So, there has to be, like, there has to be some level of challenge.
Now, there's just a lot.
There's a, I just think, again, thinking more on this specific, there's a big spectrum here.
Like, for example, I know I have seen the feedback of Act 1 minus Canopy and Mana.
Feel generally good on the pacing, the speed of monsters.
You feel like you can almost do no-hit runs, is, like, kind of what people have said.
And then you get to Act 2, and it's not too bad at the very start, and then you get to the, like, Helani gates, and it's like, okay, now everything's gone off the reservation.
The Faradon have a problem.
And then you get, and so, I've seen a decent spectrum like that, and I 100% want to fix that.
Like, so, that's why I was asking you, for example, because I, there's just a lot of people on the different spectrums here that want different things, and so I'm trying to understand what, you know, how much we would need to change things for the discussion with you as opposed to with other players.
Right.
So, that's all I was asking there.
Because I do intend on slowing down those extreme zones, and I think there are, like, 10 of them.
Mm-hmm.
And I think that is at least something hopefully a lot of viewers are going to be happy to hear, which is, like, okay, cool.
They are going to address those.
So, the Dreadnought.
Right.
Utzal.
You've got Canopy.
We're going to start.
Those are the most egregious I'm listing.
I'm not saying those are the only problematic ones.
Yeah.
And then you've got areas like Titan Valley, which is just, like, riddled with annoying monsters that are just, like, out of control.
And you've got heaps of this.
We start there, and we keep working backwards until we catch as much as we can.
And it's going to be a lot of different changes.
So, one could be, okay, like, why is it that there are six different varieties of which all are just, as you've, you know, heard people mentioning.
I think I saw something that you had to think, which is they're playing POE 1, I think.
Yeah.
Which I thought was a funny comparison.
Which I'm like, okay, fair enough.
They need to, not every monster needs to slow down.
But, like, for example, some of them can be fast.
And maybe the answer is, okay, they should be weaker.
So, sure, they engage you, but they die quick.
Or maybe the answer is, like, there's too many of them.
And then in a lot of the cases, it's going to be, like, okay, here's six different types of packs.
Well, six of them are fast.
Well, that's a problem.
Five is a fast.
That's a problem.
Four are fast.
Three are fast.
That's probably still a problem.
But two are fast.
That's probably more acceptable.
So, you get two really slow, maybe two fast, two kind of in the middle.
And you get some big slow monsters, some small monsters.
And that distribution isn't quite right in a lot of zones.
And so, this is why, again, why I asked.
Because I would say some zones have a nice, here are the slow monsters and here are the fast monsters.
And it's kind of cool.
You get this, like, up and down pacing.
And it can feel kind of fun where sometimes you're on edge and sometimes you're just obliterating things.
And then you get the ones where you're like, holy, I've just been three zones in a row
where I'm just on edge, getting swarmed, like, absolutely.
And that creates this extreme negative feeling of, like, I can't do the things that my skills want me to do.
And that is bad.
And I definitely want to fix that.
And I want to fix that imminently.
Like, I'm going to immediately get on to doing that.
So, there is a huge range of spectrum of players that want different things here.
And I want to at least address that thing because I know that's just bad.
Like, I think that's bad for everyone.
I don't think that's bad for some people.
I think that's bad for, oh, I mean, everyone.
It's for a huge majority.
So, we can start there for sure.
But to be clear, though, like, we still do need to have some monsters that are faster than the player.
It can't be that none are.
And, like, things like the wolves in the second area, like, if we didn't have that,
then I think that you wouldn't even, like, once again, you wouldn't get the feeling of, like,
you would immediately out of the gate have the game as just trivial.
And, like, I think that that really would hurt the game a lot.
Like, I think that that would be a big problem.
So, it's really just a question of, like, if there are parts that are frustrating, we'll address them.
But, like, it isn't the case that just everything needs to be slower.
It really, really would hurt.
So, I think that...
There's another thing you...
I was just going to say, I think there's almost, like, two different player bases where there are a lot of people that just want to blast and maybe have challenging bosses.
And then there are people that want, like, the entire gameplay, every second to second moment to be, like, very engaging.
So, it's...
I don't know that I agree with that either because I don't think it's so binary, as you say.
Like, there is a middle ground that will work.
Like, I'm almost certain that there is.
And the way that you get there is by just looking at the individual cases and just fixing every one of them until, like, the rough edges are all sord off, you know, sanded off.
And then, you know, and then it kind of works.
And, like, you'll get to a point where, like, you just don't get frustrating experiences anymore because we've managed to sort of fix all of those cases.
And that point won't be in a situation where just everything is slow.
Like, we really will still have a level of engagement there.
I guess the problem with everything being so fast and part of why I pointed out, like, everything almost is because it's such a heavy focus on combo gameplay right now.
But it feels like the speed of the monsters are heavily incentivizing, like, one button builds.
Like, as soon as I could, I was like, the less I can do, the better everything will feel just because I don't have time to set up combos.
We're getting completely overwhelmed.
That's why I pointed out everything is a bit of an issue.
Well, it isn't necessarily the case that you have to use a combo on every monster.
Like, if you've got stuff that's fast, you don't use combos on that because it's disrupting you.
But then also, it is also important that monsters do disrupt your combos because otherwise your gameplay just degenerates into doing, like, 1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3.
Like, the monsters have to be able – like, there has to be situations where your plans are disrupted in order to, like, have a situation where you can respond to things.
Like, you actually get some counterplay on stuff like that.
And so the monster designs have to reflect that on some level.
But, like, it's always an amount, right?
Like, there's an amount of that you need.
And there's probably too much of that going on.
But you still need an amount of that or, you know, it just becomes all flat.
Like, we've – I mean, we've been talking about, like – look, the last few days we've been talking about some, like, pretty extreme considerations and things.
And, like, you know, talking about – the monster life is the main thing, which you could argue is player damage, right?
Obviously –
Well, monster life is the easiest way.
If everything is too weak, then monster life is the way to solve it.
Oh, yeah.
If there's a few outliers of builds that find the tricks to do good, then, yes.
It is – bring all players up or bring all monsters down.
They're the same thing.
And, like, we have been talking about a lot of this and, like, actually going, like, what are we – what would we be willing to do here?
How would we be willing to change it?
What are we willing to test?
What are we willing to try?
And, like, there's heaps of things on the cards here.
Like, kind of honestly, everything's kind of been on the cards as long as we don't feel, like, at the end of the day that we've taken the teeth out of the game in terms of difficulty.
Like, that is what's important to us is making the game still have a feeling of heart being difficult.
And I would say out more than just bosses.
Like, it shouldn't just be that the bosses are the only thing that's difficult.
Sure.
And we certainly don't want it to devolve into what I would argue is, you know – I know this is, like, way further away.
But, like, you know, again, we're talking about changing – it could be changing anything here.
And the one thing I also worry about is getting to the thing where – I would argue a lot of the difficulty in P.O.E. 1 outside of a lot of the boss fights is just, like, you occasionally just instantaneously die to something.
And you're like, I don't even know what I died to.
And a lot of that is where you get, like – it isn't necessarily from monsters being too hard.
And it is often from just, like, spam and too much stuff going on combined with, like, daemons and volatiles and all of that.
So making sure we avoid that as well.
But it does mean the sense that then you kind of get that, like, okay, you have to have it be that you're engaging with the monsters for it to be difficult.
Which kind of means monsters do need to actually pose a threat, and you need to be able to see what they're doing and react to what they're doing.
Now, I wouldn't say that's universally perfect, but that's an argument for, like, you know, not wanting to get it to the point where it's too much of that just, like – well, I guess that's an argument for de-swarming things, as you said.
Which I agree with, by the way. It is, like, an important thing because it is kind of getting towards that, and that contributes towards where things are slow and stuff.
But I wouldn't personally argue that every zone feels swarmy.
I think there's a swarmy argument. I 100% want to focus on solving first.
And then there's, like, a certain things are fast and certain things are slow, and maybe there's that.
So, yeah, I'm not entirely sure where I was going with that, but I just want to – I guess it's more just giving my sense of where I want to make sure we don't end up is in that place,
just to make sure, and we want to be real careful about not getting to that point.
So, I would actually say we're probably a bit too far there in a lot of the areas, but I don't think it is a universal problem right now.
I think also, especially – even though Warrior is – or Mace skills are particularly strong now due to being able to use a shield,
but it can feel very bad that, like, every damage node, like, has a downside, whereas it isn't really the case for the other builds,
where, like, with Maces, it's like, yeah, you get 40% increased damage, but 5% reduced attack speed.
And reduced attack speed, especially with all these combos, can feel particularly bad compared to others.
I would say, like, Maces are kind of good right now, but a lot of that is the shield.
I actually do think there is a bit too much of the – I actually like a little bit of, like, here may be a cluster or two having the kind of upside-downside,
but it's honestly something we've – you know, obviously Keystones have upside-downside, but yes, it's true that probably there's kind of too many passives,
especially in the Warrior section, that are a little bit too giving downsides, where it was something, honestly, that's a bit experimental to Peewee too.
Like, we didn't have that in Peewee 1, and we were like, let's give it a go, and maybe we went a little bit overboard with it in that part of the tree.
But I don't hate it as a concept. I think it's just that it's a little bit too saturated there.
I will agree with you there 100%.
I would say, as people hopefully would know, we're going to iterate on that passive tree a million times, so it'll find its sweet spot for sure, and it's definitely not there yet.
I do think it's important, though, that, like, Keystones can be felt, and so –
Well, we're not talking Keystones.
Sorry, I didn't mean to say Keystones. I just said Notables can be felt.
And so part of the reason for the upside-downside thing is that, like, it lets you do a larger damage bonus because it's got the downside,
and therefore you're going to really feel that damage bonus.
No, they are good. I think it's the frequency of them in that part of the tree.
But I'm saying that you can find another way maybe to do that, but it's like – I do think that, like, having that feeling of, like,
I really felt that node is something that we – like, that that is a thing that you do get, and that, you know –
That is important in our passive tree philosophy, yes, is that you – the before and after of taking a notable,
especially the first – obviously, nodes become less valuable as you get higher level because they're just saturating into a bunch of diminishing returns –
well, not diminishing returns, but more like, you know, the 500% to 520% increase is going to matter less than the 0% to 20% and whatnot.
But especially for the first chunk of the game, we want it to be that every notable is felt.
Like, you're like, I definitely now can feel the difference.
And I would say, yeah, a lot don't hit that mark.
Some do, some don't.
But, yeah, we've been trying new things there, so.
Yep.
Bit of a pivot.
Yeah.
So, the next question, I want to talk a little bit about the fact that you have only done, like, the crazy large changes between seasons,
and you talked a little bit about that you felt forced to treat the game like it was released.
Are you still happy with doing only large balance changes between patches,
or is that something you would maybe revisit with something like every two weeks,
especially with, like, a warning period, like, changes are coming in four days?
It's hard.
I don't think that you can just nerf people in the middle of a league no matter what.
Like, we get highly punished for that.
And, look, I mean, people are going to be unhappy about nerfs whenever we do them, as, you know, like, as we can see.
But, like, it is actually strictly worse if you get nerfed while you're playing the game.
Now, we're in a position now where, because things, like, are probably possibly under-tuned,
that we can just do mid-league buffs.
And so that means you'll see way more patch changes happening now,
because, like, it's okay to do major buffs during the middle of a league.
Which we're doing.
Yeah, which we're doing now.
I generated a relatively large list yesterday.
Which, I know we have that whole, you know, philosophical discussion earlier about player power.
Well, like, there are many builds, many skills that are underneath,
because obviously otherwise I wouldn't be, yesterday, have spent a good chunk of the day going through
and assessing what needs to be increased, right?
So, like, I don't want it to take as, like, a...
I don't want people to take away from that as being, like, a no, we're happy with the current balance.
Like, obviously not.
We're still going to make changes.
We're still going through everything.
And we'll get to that sweet spot for sure.
But, like...
I mean, it's going to end up feeling like a season of buffs this time.
And the reason why it'll feel that way is because, like, the medicine has gone down now.
Now we can start on all of the actual, like, you know, like, all of the positive buff parts.
And so it's like the...
Like, last season we just weren't even in a, like, in a situation where we could even do that, right?
Because it's like you already had...
We genuinely tried to.
We had this plan of, like, bring all the top-end outliers down and then make sure everything is feeling good in the middle.
And we started with the bringing outliers down.
And then all of a sudden, and this is why the patch notes were so late, we were like, oh, no.
Like, we're, like, running out of time here.
Like, we thought we could get through more of the balance and start bringing more things up.
We didn't get to do all that we had hoped to do.
But, like, by that point, it's kind of too late.
And so, like, we're going in and then now our idea here is, like, we thought we were.
Like, literally up until the last minute, we were like, okay, we're going to keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going.
Right, let's start buffing.
Let's look at weak things.
And, like, it just ended up being too time-consuming.
And so the answer here is now, though, it's like, well, let's just keep going.
And so obviously the first few days is really, like, looking at all the player feedback and going, what are the biggest problems, right?
And this is where you get the Act 3 changes.
You get the minion builds.
You get the big things.
And we are trying to address all of that.
And I understand just game-wide balance is a big thing.
But now it's just going to be like, all right, this skill, this skill, this skill, this skill, this skill, this skill.
Like, let's go.
What are we changing?
Going through literally every single one on every single skill tree and every single reservation.
And then we're going to go, okay, well, you've still got Blood Mage and Acolyder Chiola sitting there at 0%, 0.1% played.
Okay, well, clearly not doing well enough.
Let's target that and just go on and just keep iterating through until we can get as far as we can.
And maybe we catch everything.
Maybe we don't.
But, like, the intention is to not stop just because the release day happened.
Like, we had a goal.
We didn't achieve that goal.
And so we just need to keep going.
And do you have, like, a rough idea?
Like, you were saying you were working on a lot of things to be buffed.
Do you have a rough idea on how early we could be seeing those already?
Well, we'll be seeing them continuously.
Like, okay, so this was a...
Two days?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, perfect.
This was a funny thing.
That's what I wanted to do.
Okay, so, like, one of the things I think that was majorly misinterpreted, that things we're working on post, was, like, this was the things we were working on that day.
Like, literally, that was that day's worth of work that we were talking about.
And then the next day, it's like, well, now we're doing this Act 3 stuff.
And, like, today we'll be doing a bunch of other stuff.
And, like, you know what I'm saying?
It's like every day we're going to be, like, continuing to iterate and do stuff.
It's like, so the idea that someone's like, oh, they're not even acknowledging this thing.
It's like, well, come on.
We've literally had, like, that was one work day.
You know, like, we've got, there's more stuff coming, right?
Which we need to be more clear about.
Sure, sure.
We'll try to be more specific about that, but yes.
I mean, the one that I found the most funny with that is it's like, I'm like, okay, we're
going to look into all this Act 3 stuff, but in the meantime, we'll just add some checkpoints.
And it's like, the reason I put that in there is because, like, that's literally a thing
we already noticed was bad.
And it's like, it's not like hurting anyone to add some more.
So it's like the idea that we're like, oh, we're just going to solve the whole thing
by adding checkpoints was, like, ridiculous.
Like, obviously that wasn't the case.
It was just like, here's just the thing that I can just tell someone, hey, go do this while
I'm looking at this.
You know, and like, and so they did that.
And so then that'll go in the next version.
But, you know, like, it's like, then it's like the next, like, four hours after that,
I'm like sitting there going through areas and trying to work out what's, you know, like
what needs to improve about them.
Yeah.
So checkpoints is kind of something I want to talk about with the large zones and stuff.
And you posted, you made a post yesterday talking about that several Act 3 zones would
be reduced in size.
But as a core idea, is Path of Exile 2 being aimed more at, like, doing one long playthrough
and finishing up one character rather than do, like, five to ten characters and the people
that are playing thousands of hours per year?
I mean, I don't, that's, once again, it's not like I'm not targeting one or the other.
Like, the, your second, I mean, like, if you're doing multiple playthroughs, the game is a lot
faster just due to the, like, items and stuff that you have.
Like, that is definitely the case.
You know, like.
Well, a big thing that's missing.
Making multiple characters in a league is certainly something that I expect and want you to be able
to do.
Well, a big thing that's missing comparatively to POE 1 is our, our ability to speed ourselves
up, right, on our second characters.
In POE 1, you have things like 7 League Step and stuff like that.
And at least so far, we don't have that many alternatives for that.
And our movement abilities are completely different.
No Quicksilver.
So even though, like, we can, we can kill the bosses faster, but since the zones are so large,
we can't get, like, the same amount of speed on our second and third character onwards
that we would be expecting POE 1.
Well, is the zone largeness issue, like, like, I mean, Act 3 was the one I would say that
was, like, pretty obvious as far as, like, things like that go.
But if it comes to other zones, it's just a question of what are those zones and which
are the issues.
And, like, also the other thing is, is that, like, generally speaking, like, once you know
how the zone works, there are ways then to, like, to, to, to, to, to know what you're
looking for and sort of how to go places and what to do.
So to the extent that that isn't the case, that's why, like, when we're looking at, like,
that's why when we're looking at Act 3, it's not just make this zone smaller.
It's like, what's actually the reason why a player who is experienced is not able to
find the thing that they're looking for, right?
And that's where we come to, like, oh, there's this whole area over here that you could just
walk down and you have no idea whether or not that's important or not.
And so then you end up doing that and it just wastes a bunch of your time.
But, like, the intention is to make it so that, like, if you know what you're doing, then you
know where to go and, like, you don't have a problem with that.
So, like, that's, that, that's why a lot of the changes in Act 3 are just like, okay,
yeah, like, you get this, you randomly get bad luck and then the Chimera Wetland has the
stupid Y fork thing in it and, like, takes ages to go one way or the other.
It's like, you get rid of all of that stuff and then the zones won't feel so large because,
like, you'll know where you're going and you'll know how to get, you know, it kind of
works out that way.
But I do know the layouts, though, and they are very large even with knowing the layouts,
just because our movement speed is, like, relatively slow.
Like, even, like, Matlin Waterways, before they're getting reworked, hopefully the rework
makes them a lot slower.
But I know exactly where I'm going.
I'm not, like, backtracking into the wrong area making it longer.
It is just a lot of these zones are very long.
That area in particular, like, I understand that area is a challenging one and it's hard
for us to actually fix, like, trivially because just the way that the level generation works
there, there's not an easy, like, it's not, like, okay, like, we, other areas we can
change the layouts very easily because, like, of the way that our generation works.
But that area has a very fixed type of layout.
And so it's going to take more effort, which is why it was on the list, because I didn't
have an immediate, like, thing I could do that day to sort that one out.
But, like, I understand that that's an area of concern for people.
But, like, once again, it's like, that's a specific area and I wouldn't say that, like,
that the issues that that area has would apply to the whole game.
You know, like, that's just an area, a specific problem for that particular area.
So is speeding the player up an option?
Like, is that something you'd be willing to consider?
Well, it sort of depends on how it was done.
Like, we've discussed some things in that area, like, before.
I'm not necessarily against that, but it would have to be done in a way that didn't compromise
the combat and compromise, like, the, the, the, um, like, it shouldn't be the case that
you'd, I mean, because, okay, because, because this is the issue with this, right, is that
speeding up the player is, um, if you speed up the player to the point where they're once
again faster, then always faster than the monsters, then you get back to the, like, combat
doesn't work anymore, like, you'd combat an optional kind of, like, situation again.
Um, so, like, we have to, we would have to find a way to do that that wasn't going to,
like, break that as well.
So there might be something we can do there, and we've kind of been discussing that.
Um, because I'm not, like, I'm not exactly wanting to subject people to, like, you know,
running when they're not doing anything, right?
But, um, the, the, it's the, it's just a question of finding a way to do that that's
not going to.
It's hard to say anything specific because, like, there's a little bit of, like, the moment
we say a specific solution.
Yeah.
People might hold us accountable to that in a degree.
And, like, we haven't tried it yet, so we can't, like, have been talking about it.
We do have some options we want to try.
I, we just don't want to talk about them before we try them.
Right.
Um, but, like, yes, I agree.
Now, you mentioned one other thing there, just because I don't want to gloss over things
too much, which is, you mentioned the Twink unique problem.
Yeah.
Uh, which is seven league steps.
There are many, many, many, many, many more items in POE1 that you can use to streamline
the efficiency on re-roll.
That is still very deficient, yes.
It will come in time, I assure you.
It's just a matter of, we did higher level uniques this time.
Obviously, they're not going to have low level item requirements.
Um, maybe next time there's a more even split.
I don't know.
We just need to keep going with the uniques and we'll eventually get there.
We do have some designs that, um, achieve specifically the low level high movement speed
boots.
We do have that as a thing that I, I definitely already have designed to just, I think it's
just waiting on the art and then it's going to go in.
Um, but yeah, we just, there's going to be a lot more of those coming over time as well.
Like that will solve itself in due time for sure.
And is that like the question I was, okay, so is for damage, the twinking situation is
not bad right now, right?
It's not as bad.
Again, you can kill stuff fast.
It's the movement speed specifically that we're talking about.
And the fact that we don't have movement abilities, like in the same way, like there's only so
much speed you get with shield charge.
Like if I'm doing like a third or fourth character, I can definitely get enough damage, right?
It's rough on my first character.
But you don't have to use movement abilities as the solution to this.
And I would prefer that that wasn't the solution because, um, then you end up with a kind
of like pretty lame sort of gameplay thing going on there.
Like there's going to be a better way to improve that without using, having a movement
build, build, build a solution.
We have some things on the cards.
We just need to test them out and try them and be able to actually have a good argument
as to why they work, why they are good.
And we convince ourselves, damn, we should have done this before or they're bad.
And we're like, here's why they're bad.
And we can explain what we tried and why it's bad.
But yeah, again, it's, it's, we're always a bit on, uh, discussing our, what those will
be because, uh, yes, again, they're being held accountable.
People get their hopes up for it and then we have to say it doesn't work.
So like, it's a little bit of like, let us just try these things and then we'll see
what we come up with and we will, we'll tell people the moment that we have it.
But again, it's not a piece of, um, it certainly is something that's come up and it will come
up every single repeat of the league.
And so it's not like off our radar by any means.
Okay.
That's good.
Um, so obviously a bit of a different question, but, uh, on console debuffs have the option
to be at the bottom of the screen.
Could that be a toggleable option for PC?
Um, just, um, can be rough today.
I'll look into that.
It wasn't, it wasn't on my radar.
We might be able to do something.
We have a, um, a full buff UI rework going on at some point soon.
Um, it was planned for earlier where like, you know, so this can be part of the consideration,
I guess.
But yeah, the, um, our UX guy's currently working on, has it on top five of his list kind
of thing of things that we're going to just do to improve the system.
That wasn't to do with moving them, but we can add that to the list of things that we
might want to do.
I mean, it's the hope they can go behind the boss's life bars and you know, all that problem.
And, um, hopefully if it's good enough as well, we can port that to Peewee 1 because
it's a more egregious problem there for sure.
Yeah.
Um, the next question is about, uh, in Peewee 1, we have a lot of player agency over how
we solve early problems.
Like the skill tree has a lot of temporary fixes, uh, for a build early on where if your
gear isn't up to scratch, you can get 30 to like strength decks int, you can get, uh,
leech, you can get resists, even like specific ones like fire, cold, lightning, et cetera.
You can get very easy access to fixing mana and stuff like that.
Um, and a lot of things that are like temporary fixes that you later on fix with gear.
Um, and the crafting bench also helps a lot more with that in Peewee 1.
And I know runes are meant to be the solution here.
Um, but we don't really get enough sockets early on.
We don't get enough gear early on.
And we then don't have any way at all to really fix this.
Um, so why, why, why is it that you're not getting enough sockets early on?
Well, that they're just not dropping.
Even if you're checking the vendor, like I'm checking the vendor every time I level up,
I'm, uh, disenchanting everything.
I still don't get enough because the game is very difficult right now.
So you try to keep getting gear upgrades.
There is not enough loot.
There is a lot of people complaining about not enough drops.
I don't get the, I don't get the same experience of not getting enough socket walls personally.
Like I would say that probably 80% of the gear I'd be wearing pretty much through the whole campaign would have sockets like in there.
Um, so like if that's the case, then like there must be something I'm not understanding about like why that people feeling that way.
Cause that's just like a totally different experience than what I see.
Um, when I'm playing myself.
Yeah.
I mean, I would love the intention.
Sorry.
The intention is that you use socket like socketables to fix those problems.
And that is fundamentally identical to the crafting bench as far as the resultant, um, like, like ability to fix issues on your character.
Um, like there's nothing about the crafting bench that really changes anything that way other than it's being less intuitive to use for new players.
Well, it is a lot stronger.
Well, there's the power.
Yeah, there is the power.
Well, okay.
So sure there's the power, but like, I mean, that's a different question again, right?
Like if you're talking about fixing problems, um, then, um, that, that just comes down to the values on the mods.
Um, and like what, what, what those should be, which aren't necessarily right.
Right.
But the thing is, is that it's, it's, it's supposed to be that you're getting enough sockets to be able to do that.
And I mean, I don't even, I don't buy stuff from the vendors.
It just, as a qualifying thing that I don't buy socketables from the vendors and do that thing.
I know people do that.
That's not a thing that I'm doing.
I mean, I might do it.
Like if I've got like, not like a stack of nine shards and I'm like, okay, I want to socket right now.
I might like do that.
But, um, generally speaking, that's not what I'm doing.
So like there's some clearly some disconnect here.
Um, as far as like what the, um, the, the, the,
the amount of loot that you're getting versus what I'm seeing, I suppose.
Um, so like, I guess I just need to understand why, um, like, why does it feel so different?
It might be quite, it might have a relatively high swinginess or something that we need to find a way, like more adding more.
Um, like I know something that was suggested was adding more artifices orbs, uh, to fixed quest rewards through the game to minimize the RNG outcome.
Right.
Cause we added those quite late.
We didn't end up putting them in any.
So that's something that we could definitely do, which would mean you just get more of them during campaign.
And I'd be totally open to that.
Like that's totally reasonable.
A second thing I'd like to do soon is explore.
I know.
I mean, sort of unrelated, but, um, is that, well, casters don't have their weapon crafting bench.
And we do need to, we do need to, we do need to fix.
We have to add sockets to caster weapons.
That needs to come as well.
Um, now there is one slight concern that I have seen echoed in a decent bit of feedback, which is that the runes are, um, which is mitigated with more artifices orbs for sure.
But the runes are creating a bit of a sense of, um, making it like the P.
We, the thing that the P.
We one sockets created, which is like replacing items becoming slightly harder.
Yep.
Um, so there's a little bit of just making sure we're careful about that as well.
Um, but being able to have more artifices orbs and thus socket more gear will mitigate that so that when you get your upgrade, you're able to add a socket to it.
Um.
But I would say that it's definitely the hard coded drops that would be the thing that, because if it's, if it's not happening to everyone, then it is a thing that, yeah, that we're better off solving that way.
But yeah, the caster, caster weapons, getting rune sockets and rune, obviously runes for them and, um, uh, adding more art of deterministic artifices orbs to the campaign is certainly two things on my immediate radar to help at least mitigate some of this.
Um, I might do a quick review on the power pass of the runes as well.
Um, I don't, I just don't want them to be too much about giving damage, but it might be a lot of the more utility and defensive ones are just on the weak side.
And, um, those can certainly come up immediately.
Um.
Well, the problem that you have once again is that, like, so I sort of mentioned this earlier, but if the tools that you have are too powerful, then you, the people who know to use them are benefited to a larger degree compared to people who don't.
And what you're doing there is, um, then you end up in a situation where content, um, will, you know, be like, it's just a new player goes into this and it's like, well, I didn't know about this.
And then, like, you get screwed over.
And so, like, things like, um, even, even nodes on the passive tree can be this way where it's like, okay, well, you had to know to pick this.
And if you didn't know to do that, then you're screwed.
Right.
Like, that's the kind of thing that's like a bit of a problem.
Um, and so the, the, the, that we, we just have to be really careful about that.
And, like, that's actually one of the reasons, by the way, um, why lesser runes exist.
Because if, in, before, if you knew to put, um, a lightning damage rune in your weapon, um, then you would just, like, completely, like, ridiculous compared to anyone, to compare to anyone who didn't know that.
And so it's like, you've got, like, it shouldn't be that just a single, like, there's a tool like that, which you just, just, just with knowledge alone, it's like, you're completely, like, uh, you're, you're completely overpowered compared to other people.
So you just have to be, like, we just have to be really careful with that stuff.
Well, it's important.
It's just important to make sure that the solutions are ultra, very front facing.
Because that passive tree stuff, uh, you know, in Peewee 1, sure, I agreed.
And it's, it seems obvious to a bunch of people.
But then also, there's two problems going on there in the Peewee 1, which is, A, it adds to a sense of complexity.
Because it's like, here are the things you must know before you start playing to have a good time.
And I know that's one small piece of that puzzle, or that problem.
Um, and the second thing is, uh, looking at Peewee 1 from that crafting bench, is that the crafting bench is in your hideout and not in any town, which I agree is a downside.
Ideally, it would be more in your face.
Um, and so, like, a lot of people just forget to use it and forget that it exists.
Um, and that is a thing where, like, again, if you know, you know, and you have a good time.
And if you don't know, you don't know.
And you, you, like, um, suffering.
So whatever the solutions end up being, we definitely need to make sure are, like, very front facing in your face.
And are, like, here's clearly the very intuitive way to solve these problems.
Um, so that's just an important piece of, like, philosophy we need to make sure we maintain.
A lot of that can be sold by, through Quest, though, right?
You can have an NPC early giving one of those, like, runes and even telling you, like, hey, chuck this in your weapon for more damage if you're using a bow.
Um.
Well, how do, it would, I mean, surely, if the runes are there to solve problems, then ideally we're not telling you exactly which one to use, right?
Because it should be dependent on what your problem is.
Um, but we do need to make sure that people have got enough artifices or to make sure they can do that.
Yeah.
That's the main thing that I would say.
But you were talking about the problem that you're rewarded for knowledge, which I don't think necessarily is a bad thing.
I think that is a good thing.
No, no.
You 100% should be rewarded for knowledge.
The question is, what is the degree of the reward?
Mm-hmm.
There's a fine line there, for sure.
But, um, yeah.
There's some improvements around here to be made, and there's some good takeaways from that anyway, right?
Like, the determinism, for sure.
And I think it's also a matter of, like, okay, I think there is a guaranteed rune from Ogham Village.
Maybe that's too late.
We should be doing that, like, earlier or having more of them.
You know, again, more of that deterministic outcomes.
But also maybe knowing that you're going to get that in advance would be helpful.
I don't think we quite have that displayed.
So it's like you, you know, some of those, like, the world map icons where you go and get a specific reward aren't, it's not necessarily explaining to the user what they're going to get.
And so they might just be like, ah, it's just another one of those.
I don't need another tier 4 skill gem.
But they don't, that's because maybe they think it's that.
So, yeah.
Bit of information improvements and a bit of just, like, some power adjustments, some more determinism.
Especially with Artifice's orbs, I actually 100% agree with that.
I think if we hadn't have added that system so late into the development, we would have actually put that more throughout 100% anyway.
So we should just do it now.
But, yeah.
Well, 100% some improvements there.
Another thing I'm curious about then, I asked about the skill tree.
Do you feel like the skill tree gives a good or does a good enough job of doing temporary solutions right now that you can later out gear?
Or, like, is that something you'd be open to looking at?
Well, our core philosophy there was that the gear should give you base stat and the tree should multiply them.
Which makes the tree implicitly worse at then solving the problem.
So the intention there is that, now, whether or not, I would say we haven't really re-discussed it since then.
I still believe that's a great thing to have.
There aren't some...
The other thing, just as a side note, is that there aren't runes that give you attributes, right?
Mm-hmm.
Right.
And so that means that you can't solve attribute requirements with runes.
Which is something that I brought up a bit ago, but, like, we didn't have time to look at what the implications of that were.
My sole fear with that is that it means that it is even harder now to replace an item with another item.
That is the concern.
Yeah, it is.
That's why, like, something like 30 dex, 30 strength, etc. was obviously very nice in Peewee 1.
And it does feel a little bit like, oof, I wish I didn't have to take that.
But that gives you, like, incentive to fix that through a gear later.
And obviously, we have so much resist on the skill tree in Peewee 1, too.
I remember, like, because the first time I played Peewee 2, we didn't know anything about the skill tree and stuff like that.
And I remember thinking, I was in, like, Act 2 somewhere, and I hadn't pre-planned my day.
I hadn't, like, looked at the data mines or anything like that.
So I was like, okay, let's go look at the skill tree where, like, where the resists are.
Because I'm, like, 10%, 15% on the different res.
So I'll pick up 15 on the skill tree.
And there was just, like, that one in, like, Warrior left start.
And I was very surprised for that.
So, like, what's the reason for not having that much resist on the tree?
Because, once again, as Mark said, the tree is, the theory of it is that the tree enhances what your items are doing in order to make the items.
But, I mean, look, there's something to think about again.
Like, there might be something to that that we should be reconsidering.
Yeah.
Like, we'll 100% go have a discussion about this afterwards, for sure.
I certainly have a whole bunch of thoughts on this real quick.
And I just, I definitely want to go over it and just re-evaluate this.
Because, like, we did make a lot of these philosophical decisions, right?
Where, like, tree should multiply, obviously, aside from attributes.
And gear should give the base.
And, like, you know, because an alternate solution might just be that the resistances given by the runes are, like, way too low as well.
Right?
Like, that certainly...
Because if you look at, think of, like, the tree for one on, obviously, Peewee 1.
And you combine that with the crafting bench on Peewee 1.
Like, the amount of resistances you're getting there, even from the lowest tier crafts and the tree, is enough to certainly be able to solve any problem.
So, there's a little bit of just, like, making sure we don't want to make it too trivial.
So...
Well, the other thing as well is that the monsters are balanced, assuming a different amount of resistance than they were in Peewee 1.
So, that, like, changes things a little bit as well.
You know, like, the expectation is not that you have, like, high resistances through the game necessarily.
Like, the expectation is that...
Okay, well, the expectation is that you should be able to get through...
From merely overcoming the negative resistances you get from going through the acts.
Like, if you're at 0%, you should be...
Like, it should be...
That should be enough.
And then any improvement you have over that is supposed to be just, like, something that's making your character better.
So, like...
But if the monster life or monster damage is not calibrated correctly, then it won't feel that way to the player.
But, like, that was kind of...
Like, balancing around 0% was, like, another idea that we had to try and make it so that you always knew the amount of resistances you were supposed to have.
Like, being that, like, if the number is red, you need more.
And if the number is not red, then you have enough.
Like, that was kind of the theory in order to make it more obvious.
Like, to...
Like, what people are supposed to do there.
The other thing about the tree that can be a bit tricky here is that when you have that problem...
Like, you probably have that problem immediately where you're like, oh, I'm dying to all this fire damage.
I don't...
This boss, I don't have enough fire resistance.
The answer can't be, like, okay, I need to look at my tree and get some fire resist.
Because that's too late, right?
Like, you need to solve this problem more immediately.
Exactly.
Right.
So having a more immediate solution is ideally what it would be.
So ideally there you'd be like, okay, I'm going to swap this item for this item and or maybe put this rune in.
And now I might have another go and have a good time.
Where if the answer is like, okay, there's resistance nodes over here.
I just need to get six more levels so I can get them to then go and fight the boss.
Like, I understand there's a level of, like, obviously they're good at forward-thinking problem-solving.
But, like, when you're, like, in the moment and you're like, damn, I'm struggling right now.
What am I going to do right now?
It needs to be a more immediate solution.
And that's why a rune can be better.
The passive tree solves it in one regard but doesn't solve it in another regard.
And it's important that, yes, the runes are there to solve that problem and certain items are there.
And, sure, it's easy.
It is not necessarily incorrect to say that that hasn't...
Those tools aren't as readily available as they should be.
Yeah.
Yeah, I also think part of it is that we're definitely not dropping enough gear.
Like, the state of my gear, it's quite rough.
Like, a lot of the things I've found throughout the campaign ends up being one or two stat items.
If that...
But isn't that just...
But, like, this is the thing I would say about that is, like, okay, when you're saying your gear isn't good enough, you're also just saying the monsters are too powerful.
Like, it can just be the monsters.
Like, I don't think that it needs...
Like...
There's an element here of, like, you might just be conditioned to wearing rares in every slot all the time, which doesn't have to be the case.
Like, the gear power is entirely relative to monster power.
So, if you're saying your gear isn't good enough, it doesn't have to be the gear needs to get better.
It can't just be that the monsters are too hard.
Sure.
If you're talking about also, like, damage and, like I said, speed.
But, okay, can you give me an idea then?
That's important, though, because one of the things that PeeWee 2 has gotten us is that
you're not just saturating on rares, like, halfway through Act 1 anymore.
Like, you actually do...
And what that actually means is that you have situations where you change from a rare to a magic.
In some cases, you're, like, changing around your gear through the campaign.
And it results in way more, like, gear upgrades as you go through the campaign.
Like, there's way more often because, you know, you'll downgrade to a blue, but then you'll find a...
You know, but then you'll find a regal and you'll upgrade it and then you'll add some more mods and so on.
And, like, just the amount of gear changes that are happening through the campaign is very, very high.
And so if we just dropped more gear, then we would lose out on that.
And whereas if we lower monster power, then you're improving the...
Like, you don't need...
Like, you don't...
We wouldn't need to do that.
Once again, that doesn't necessarily say that the gear isn't exactly the right place.
But what I am saying is that, like, it isn't just buff items.
Like, it is a question of player power relative to monster power.
But the thing is, like, we aren't switching up gear a lot, though.
I think a lot of us feel like we're, like, finally finding, let's say, like, a glove with 60 life and 15 fire us.
And then we end up keeping that all the way until maps because we aren't really finding anything else.
We have very little currency to craft with and stuff.
And a lot of people also reported finding, like, a large chunk of the majority of their currency in Act 1.
Where maybe people find as much as, like, 3 to 10 exalts in Act 1.
And then find 0 in Act 2 and 3.
So it seems, like, very, very early heavy.
I can't really explain why that would happen.
Because, like, the way that loot drops doesn't change.
The only thing that changes is the number of magic and rare monsters that exist.
And so over time, the amount of loot you get increases through the game just because the number of rare and magic monsters increases.
And due to the way the currency drops work in PoE 2, the more of those you get, the more rare currency you'll get.
Which means that, like, it just feels like you get more currency.
So, like, that isn't a phenomenon that I understand for sure.
Like, you should be getting more currency as you go through the acts for sure.
Like, that is as far as I understand.
Several times I've been joking about making new characters to farm currency.
And a lot of people, like, said they agreed.
Thankfully.
We can relatively easily, if we need to, pretty much after this, add some logging for that and go and see what's actually happening.
But that is unusual.
Like, I can't explain why that would be the case.
I concur.
There is, there isn't, it shouldn't work that way.
It shouldn't be that way.
So if that is the case, which isn't necessarily true, but it could be, we should never, we're never going to rule out any bug or unintended thing where we can get some logging for that relatively fast and just get the check, the data and actually see what's happening.
But I also do want to understand why some people feel like they get a lot of currency and others don't.
Like, I don't, once again, I just don't understand what can be the responsible for that.
Um, because like, you know, it's like, um, I wouldn't say that, I wouldn't say that every time I want six mods, I can get them, but I would say that I'm using exalts, like all through the campaign.
I'm using regals all through the campaign.
I'm like rolling, like from, up from whites to rares, like pretty continuously as you're going through.
So like there's something odd about that that I need to understand.
Yeah.
I mean, even like, I would say myself, I got very like few regals and stuff to use.
Like definitely was, uh, not on the rich end during the campaign.
Well, how many is a few?
Um, I'd say through the campaign, I dropped probably four regals.
Well, hang on, but we're not talking about dropping only.
We're talking about disenchanting too, right?
So, um, because of crafting being so RNG, I will generally have opted in.
I've, I've tried both obviously, uh, between like disenchanting, but I find that I benefit more from gambling than from actually trying to crafting.
My experience with crafting is picking up every blue, looking for one stat regaling, and then that missing and the item not being usable.
Um, so.
If you're not disenchanting rares, then you certainly won't get a lot of regals.
Sure, but I've tried both.
Right.
Well, I can't say much as to that, but, um, like that is the reason you don't have regals if you're, if, if, if, if, if, you know, like that is where like the, the primary source of regals through the campaign would be disenchanting.
Um, like that isn't to say that gambling isn't better.
Maybe it is, but, um, you know, like that, that it does explain that particular, particular one currency item at least.
It's also quite a few alchemies and stuff as well.
Yeah.
Alchemies are kind of not really intended to be that common anymore because the intentioned way to go through to rare is more via, um, more via regaling.
Um, so like alchemies are like relative, like the, the alchemies are the kind of like, oh, awesome.
I got an alchemy.
That's like a kind of, that's, that's the uncommon thing that you do occasionally, not the like kind of common work a day crafting that you're doing all the time.
Um, so like, yeah, there should be that the regals are the, the, the primary source of, of, of crafted rares.
Yeah.
And that would go.
Well, the good benefit here is we have so many players right now that we can just, uh, get some data and get some analytics very, very quickly about what this actually is.
Yeah.
And you might find that it's, um, just very, uh, sensitive to, you know, there's always just going to be a portion of unlucky players and a portion of lucky players.
Like I definitely know that there's a, a lot of swinginess of course, and that can happen.
And again, that it might just be that.
And I know you've probably played more than most, so arguably you should have the, uh, you should have the least, the most amount of data from a purely anecdotal perspective.
So, um, you know, you probably have the, uh, the best average going on, uh, the most accurate average, I should say.
But that being said, like we have the capacity to look into this very quickly and we can do so probably even today and figure out.
What's going on and whether or not it meets our expectations.
So, so, um, the next thing I want to ask you about is, uh, the ailment thresholds.
You have like how easy it is for the player to be stunned, uh, player to be frozen and stuff.
Uh, and I'd say that feels a little bit overly punishing when we don't have as many solutions or tools, right?
Because we have one charm slot and it is quite difficult to get a second or third.
Um, and that's competing for freeze immune, stun immune, poison immune, ignite immune, and chaos immune.
Um, sorry, chaos resist, uh, and bleed.
Now I would say poison, ignite, and bleed from the monsters don't actually do that much right now.
But if it did, like this would be a very, very heavily competed for, like singular solution to, uh, to doing anything with that.
Um, so, and as an addendum to the question, I wonder, would you consider letting belts get more implicit charm slots based on item level?
So like maybe at like 50 plus they have two and at 81 they get three.
Um, it's, I mean, we probably will increase the number of charm slots.
Like that is something that we like kind of were intending to do and never got to yet.
Um, but I don't think that the ailment threshold was in the right place before.
Like the effectively ailments didn't exist before we changed that.
Um, so like we need, like we needed a, we needed something that was going to actually cause them to happen.
Like, you know, during the campaign before you got frozen like three times, the whole campaign, it kind of was a bit, it was a bit silly.
Do you know what we didn't actually universally double the stunning?
This, I know you mentioned that just to clear that up.
It was only, it was ailments that were changed, not stunning.
They stun you more as things get higher level.
The expected amount of stun threshold you should have goes up.
Um, so it's not, but it's pretty minimal throughout the entire campaign.
But what we also increased is the, um, uh, you, you gain a bunch of stun threshold when you get light stun.
So you have way, way, way lower probability of getting stunned locked.
Um, but then I would also point out like some of those charms just suck because it doesn't even mitigate the stun that stunned you.
And that is just something that we were like, we initially did.
And then we're like, oh, we need to change this.
And then it just got lost in the weeds.
So like the other thing is changing those, um, and I know the resistance ones work this way as well.
Like those just need to also cancel out the thing that caused it, um, or mitigate the thing that caused it.
And those where some do and some don't.
So that needs to change a hundred percent.
And then, yes, we need more slots.
I think we're actually going to support up to six slots.
That isn't to say that everyone will trivially have six, but there is UI for it.
Six is only, six is a thing you might be able to do with uniques and stuff like that.
It's not something that you get, um, but it was certainly our expectation or intention, I should say, uh, that we give out more slots so that people are running more.
Like one is not what you should be running.
Uh, like two, certainly at high end minimum and like probably three and like sometimes four wouldn't be unreasonable.
Okay.
But it's interesting that even the ailment threshold change we made has not really affected most of the ailments that you just said.
Like you just were saying that like, you know, that bleed poison and stuff were not really doing much yet.
And it's like, yeah, like that, that wasn't even like even halving that number.
It apparently wasn't enough to make those be a thing that you need to care about.
Like only frozen is the one that really kind of changed.
I think.
And like, for the most part that you actually noticed the stun thing is separate.
It's not part of the ailment threshold.
Yeah.
I mean, but if they did do a lot of damage, that'd be very overwhelming right now.
And things we can deal with.
Well, but I mean, yeah, like it's not like we want it to be overwhelming.
It's a bit of a different game.
Right.
Like when you get the mod and modifiers and map mods and everything involved.
Sure.
Um, but you know, it needs to, it does need to happen sometimes in order to actually be something that's worth mitigating.
Um, so now we just need to look at the actual, yeah, the charm stuff as well.
Yeah.
And, and do you think the implicit will be tied to item level at all?
So it'll be something that you don't necessarily have to do a crazy investment or a path on the tree?
I don't know what the answer to that is.
I have to think about what, how we want to introduce that.
Um, like that is a one way.
I mean, there, but there might be other ways.
I just have to look at that.
The other thing is like charm.
There's a, there's a level of like reviewing charms in general is just how, you know, aside from how many you have and not just their implicit, like their, their base value.
There's also just like, I'd say a lot of the modifiers on them are just absolutely like nonsense.
Like, oh, recover four mana when it procs.
It's like, okay, thanks.
That's not a useful thing to happen.
So there's, um, a bunch of ethics is there.
We just need to make better as well.
And we'll may as well probably do that at the same time, unless of course it makes it take longer in which, uh, we'd rather just get out the number of charms first.
So, yeah.
Yeah.
Um, in PeeWee 1, we have masteries.
I am a huge fan of those, especially for temporary solutions.
Um, is that something you're open to bringing back in PeeWee 2?
Yeah.
I'm not a huge fan of them because they ended up devaluing the notables a lot.
Like the notables became really bland, um, when masteries were introduced.
And it's like, and it also means that like the way you are on the tree didn't matter as much either.
Um, which like kind of wasn't amazing.
So I think that we like prefer to have it be a situation where the notables are more interesting.
And I do think that in PeeWee 2, the notables are very interesting.
Like it's something that like, I think that is notably good.
Um, so more work to do there.
But there is more work to do, but I just, I don't love the way that the masteries kind of, yeah.
Like bland defied the, the notables.
And so, yeah, I think we can, that's probably, I think I prefer it.
Um, just yeah.
Putting the power in the notables rather than the masteries.
But I don't feel like they're directly competing at each other, right?
You can still have like really interesting masteries and notables.
Like those notables can still be super interesting.
I mean, there's only so many stats that, that, that, that can exist.
But, uh, like, um, I mean, look, fundamentally everything competes with every other thing
because of the way that like, you know, due to mod dilution.
So like you have to, you know, you, you, you, you have to budget that in some level.
Um, otherwise you just get a situation where you've got so many effects on your character
that like everything, like nothing, no one thing matters at all.
Um, so like that's, you know, just.
I'm a bit more torn about this one personally, because I do agree there are downsides, but
on the other hand, it's the one that added it to Peewee 1.
So like, I'm a little bit like.
Well, I don't think it was, I don't think it was obvious at the time.
Yeah.
What, what downside that would have.
I mean, that was certainly not something that I would be against.
There's also just like the passive tree is like overwhelmingly complicated to people.
Right.
And so having this extra layer on it was probably my biggest thing of like, oh no, we made the
thing that scares people the most more scary.
Right.
Um, because there's this extra layer that they have to, an extra keyword they have to know
about.
And that was my main thing of like, maybe we should just simplify the thing that is like
the scariest thing.
Um, like that was a big argument to me, which, but there are, you know, there's intermediary
grounds there as well, but yeah, there's like downsides to it for sure.
Like I agree.
Um, there's also maybe a way to make them have work.
I don't know.
But I mean, what's the goal of it, right?
Like if the goal is to give you temporary solutions, then, um, we don't necessarily have
to solve it there.
We could just solve it in a different place and then it wouldn't be necessarily something
that's going to give you temporary solutions.
Like the, the downsides that we see that those ones having.
And it's also the same as a, as a player, it is just very fun.
Like I, I absolutely enjoy it.
And it definitely ain't telling you, it does not make me feel like notables are devalued.
I was the, yeah, even more exciting.
Cause you get it when you get the notable.
Well, it's hard to identify that in the, it's hard to identify that in the moment because
like, you don't like, you don't notice the lack of something like, you don't notice
the lack of something of what something could have been in the same way that you notice,
you know, like the thing that's in front of you that you're enjoying.
You know what I mean?
Like it's harder to appreciate the fact that the notables are less cool in POE one.
Sure.
Because you're not thinking about that.
You're thinking, I want the, I want the, the, the, um, I mean, you can at least rest
assure that we're going to think about why they were important and, uh, what we could
do to solve them, whether it be that means or another, like, yeah.
The good thing about these is all of the things you are, almost everything you bring
up is going to result in some sort of multi-hour discussion between us over the next week.
So, um, well, which is the huge benefit of these things for sure.
Yeah.
And again, thank you for doing it.
But, um, the next one's something I care a lot about, especially as a hardcore player,
um, defenses seem very undertuned compared to offense.
And just like anecdotally, um, if the, if the two options, right, if we look at it in
a bit of hyperbole where, um, I get to watch like tankiness be out of hand or offense be
out of hand.
So like literally somebody walking up to a boss and one-shotting it, uh, or looking at
somebody standing there being mortal.
Right.
I always think like if one should be out of hand, it's more interesting when the defensive
one is out of hand, you still get to see the boss abilities and stuff like that.
Um, it, it seems so much easier always.
And I think most patches have been like this where it's always easier to scale offense rather
than defense.
And I wonder a little bit how you feel about that.
Well, you're not wrong that often the best defense is stacking all of the damage.
Yeah.
Um, I mean, we've suffered from this for a long while.
Um, it is ultimately a consequence of just having the game be like, again, talking about
the hip firing and things be a bit unregulated with respect to the levels of uniques and
builds and stuff going everywhere and hard to think of it all.
And like, but it is generally true that we have more offensive, I guess people find damage
in general to be more fun as an investment avenue.
That is the real thing is that most people would prefer to invest in offense generally.
Uh, I agree with that.
That is mostly the case.
But then shouldn't be, shouldn't defense be even more encouraged than for the people that
want to?
Because even as a hardcore player, I almost feel like it's the opposite.
Like anecdotally, for example, um, for, for 0.1 and, and full disclosure, I have not been
able to get to Arbiter yet, right?
We're very early in the league.
So I don't know if you made them do less damage.
Um, but in 0.1, uh, other people were doing some testing and I asked soft core players to
try a little bit.
And there were people that were getting one shot by Arbiter moves with 15 K life.
Uh, some that are like kind of hard.
Um, so as a hardcore player, what I felt like then I was like, well, and since I can't really
tank, like there are multiple moves here that I can't tank, not just like one big telegraph
one shot, but there are multiple here that I can't tank.
So what I did to over prepare instead was I went in with so much damage that I just one
shot the boss.
Um, which, which is a little bit deflating for me.
I would say Arbiter was one of the least fun bosses, whereas I would way rather go in
and be so tanky that I can make a few mistakes.
Um, and then end up leaving.
It's quite hard to split the difference between being tanky and being immortal.
Like surprisingly hard to get that right.
And when I say that it's because, um, you can regenerate life very quickly.
And so if you don't die, like, okay.
And, and the other thing as well is that possibilities that do those big hits take a long time.
Right.
And like the bosses often can't hit you again immediately afterwards.
It's like, they'll do their big ability and it's not like it's going to just immediately
follow up with something that's going to chip you down either.
So like if you fail tank them, no, but what I'm getting towards is that if the, if, if,
if you don't have.
Something that's going to do a lot of damage at the, um, for, for those big hits.
Um, like we just have to be very careful because like, if, if, if you, if, if, like,
let's say that one of those big hits did only like, you know, a third of your life, you know,
something like that.
Um, I don't think that then the boss would ever be able to kill you ever because it would
have to effectively be able to do three of those, like of those, of those things before
you can regenerate them.
So what you're really asking for, and this is something we discussed a lot in the past,
by the way, what you're asking for is for a more attrition based gameplay style, like
a more MMO style thing.
So, yeah.
What you're really saying then is, is that you want flasks to do way less regeneration
and you want regeneration to be controlled way more in general and then have a more attrition
based gameplay style.
And that kind of just isn't a POE way of doing things.
Now, like, I mean, that could be a thing we've, we could change to, like that would be an option
that we would have, but it would be like, it would be a, the balance change of the universe
to do something like that.
Like it would be a complete redesign of all the damage and like bosses and like the whole
way everything works.
Like, like change, change a more attrition style would just be like a, you know, an apocalyptic
level of balance change compared to what we have for sure.
I mean, I'm not a hundred percent sure I agree with that.
And I was going to ask, do you think the goal of a difficult boss should be to kill the player
or to deny the player the loot?
I don't understand what that means.
So when you're leaning more towards attrition based gameplay, right?
You're recognizing as a player that you've entered a fight that you're maybe not fully
ready for.
You're maybe getting the boss to 30%.
You're not able to finish it.
And you're like, I have to leave.
I have to leave this fight.
I'm not strong enough.
As opposed to punching the player with death, you're already just taking away the loot anyway.
There's not an XP loss anyway at the moment.
Um, I mean, that's, I guess we're not thinking in those terms at all.
Like we're just like, but, but okay, sure.
You're talking.
Okay.
Like, so, okay.
So, so that question I would say only makes sense in an attrition based gameplay context,
which is not what we have.
So like, it kind of means that like, that like the boss doing abilities to be able to
like, to the boss trying to win is, or like, and trying to kill you versus denying you
the loot isn't a different circumstance unless there, unless there's attrition, which we
don't have.
So like, you know, it's so, so, so, so what I'm saying is, so, so what, what are you not
agreeing with then?
Well, well, I think, I think you do have attrition based combat on a lot of bosses, right?
Because there are many of the like campaign bosses that don't necessarily have one shots.
Um, but even just on like, as a Viper, as an example, right?
Um, I was having a like quite long fight because I wasn't particularly powerful at Viper.
So I think I had to reset seven times without it killing me.
Uh, but seven times before I was able to actually kill Viper on my build, because I was running
out of flasks.
Uh, and I, you don't have a good way to read them during the fight.
So I'm not, I'm not, when I'm talking about attrition gameplay, I'm not talking about
that.
I'm talking about attrition in the sense that your life pool is.
Is something that goes down over long periods of time, rather than something that moves
around.
Well, well, at the fact of the S through the flask, right?
Well, yes.
I was no longer able to recover.
So yes, the, to the, to the extent that we have attrition based gameplay, the attrition
is through the flask.
You are correct.
Like attrition via flask is what we have.
Um, so, uh, what I'm, what I, what I am saying though there.
Yeah.
Well, okay, sure.
Fair enough.
Like, yeah, the, the flasks do give you the attrition.
And so therefore.
The campaign is quite attritioned.
In, in, in, in that, in, in that way.
The, the, the, the kind of cap comes off, so to speak at the end game where like, it can
be very, um, it's certainly the case with a concept like leech that the moment that a
boss can't one shot you at all, which.
Well, okay.
Like if you removed all sources of flask charge gain out, like, uh, that you could do in a
boss fight, then you could probably reduce the size of the, um, big monster hits.
Well, uh, just to check real quick as well, just cause specifically talking about Arbiter.
Um, there's kind of a few things going on.
Like it is the intention that the skills and what just happens in the game and PeeWee 1 as
well, and like some people might argue it's some sort of bad design or not.
I kind of like it.
Um, there are other skills that are more like your, your personal agility or dexterity based
and you have to avoid them.
And that's like, you know, stand in the elder donuts and the, you know, the dancers and the
like move into the lanes and the, you know, bullet hells esque things where it's like, that's
not really your character as much.
Like, are you thinking those are fine or whether or not they're exactly tuned in this context,
like in terms of timing, but are you okay with the idea that those kill you and you don't
get to make like whether or not they could be more lenient as a different question, but
like, would you, are you okay with those killing you and kind of your defenses don't really
matter?
Like, are those the problem is what I'm just trying to understand exactly what skills are
a problem.
Yeah.
So for the arbiter, I feel like there are multiple, right?
You have the, the corridor move.
Uh, that was pretty much always a one shot.
Right.
And sometimes obviously like you were saying, that wasn't like the main topic, but they can
spawn almost too far away.
I remember seeing a clip of like Quinn running slightly in the wrong direction.
And then he sees the corridors the other way.
And he's like, Oh, it's, it's over for me.
Um, you have the arbiter move where he does like the fake out meteor where he starts like
firing the beam into it and stuff.
Um, I guess the way like as a player, I would want defense to be is the more I invest into
defense, the, the larger my room for error should be, uh, which is where I'm feeling.
There's a big disjoint now, right.
Where it just isn't.
And then I'm entirely incentivized to go full offense because I'm still having enough defense
that those, like those mid range hits and small hits, there's still not one shotting me.
Um, so all I need to be able to do is tank them.
And then, yeah, I just don't have an option for a huge one shots at all.
Okay.
So yeah, I understand the, the, the point from a point of view from that one.
Um, the main thing is just, we're going to have to be really careful with the balance
to make sure that it isn't now just like, you know, 20% of investment of the way there.
Now you don't get one shot by them.
So you just hold down, you know, whatever button on the boss or whatever.
And now you're leeching permanently and you're fine.
Um, that's the concern.
So like, if it is a like universal, okay.
Like for example, would it be okay that, I mean, look, the corridor, let's use that as
the example.
So the corridor obviously has some like, okay, it's too hard to get, we need to probably
improve the, uh, the way the lane spawn such that you don't get into that situation where
like, this is literally impossible for me to run there unless I have X or Y.
Um, there is the thing where like, okay, for example, if like life regen wasn't regulated,
like, do you really think any player in the game, like this is fine, I'm not saying this
is wrong or right, should just be able to AFK in that?
Um, I'm just curious.
Yeah.
So definitely.
I prefer that over watching people, one shot bosses a hundred percent with enough investment.
Well, no, I, we won't disagree, but just like, yeah.
Do I'm just curious.
Do we, do you actually think it should be okay or able to?
Um, yeah, I'm not entirely against something just being a straight up one shot, like failing
the memory game, for example, in Pee Wee 1.
Like I'm not inherently against that.
Um, but I do think the, the current ones are a little bit like too fast to be those ones.
Yeah.
I, I, I, I agree.
I just think there's, there is two problems here, which I'm interested in.
One is, uh, mechanics feeling fear, which there are things here that are unfair and that is
bad and they need changing.
Um, and I will get that adjusted today and then, and I'll get that on live as soon as
I can, which might even also be today.
Um, the other thing would be that there are the, the bigger thing, which is that investing
in defense is not allowing you to mitigate it.
It's like, so it's a different from the corridor skill.
There's just like whether or not investing in defense enough, it gives you enough defense
against things in general, against the bosses, which maybe isn't the case.
It might be that it might be that.
Yes.
You investing in defense needs to be more advantageous right now, for sure.
And like, don't get me wrong.
There's nothing more.
And I've spoken about this before in the past.
There's nothing more demoralizing than putting, you know, hundreds of hours into a boss.
And then it's just like, bro, deleted.
And it's like, Oh, great.
That was also demoralizing to just watch someone sit there and face tank it and just attack it
with no, like having to, not even having to move.
Like that's also.
Especially without, especially without the gear.
Like it's kind of, it's, it's, it's almost a bit ridiculous to discuss like which, which
of these two horrible outcomes is better.
Like, you know, like surely the actual answer is like neither of them should be happening.
No, no.
I agree.
It's just that it's pretty rare that we've seen defense be the really OP one.
That's all right.
Like we very often see.
Yeah.
Maybe it is, but like, I think that that's probably also a lot around the fact that people
like building glass cannons.
Like that is a thing people just like doing.
And so like the amount of incentivization.
And so then there's the issue of like, like, well, let me put it this way.
Even if right now, and I don't know whether this is the case or not, like it probably isn't,
but even if defense was over-tuned compared to damage, I think that the, I think that you're
still not going to incentivize people to do that until you get to the point where they're
immortal.
Like, I don't think getting 80% of the way to immortality is actually enough even for
people to still not want to build glass cannons.
And so you've kind of got like that issue of like, it's just really, really hard to get
that balance right.
So the, like, that isn't to say that we won't try, but I'm just saying that like it, it,
it is people, there just tends to be an erring on the side of offense for that reason.
And, um, I don't think either immortality or insta-killing bosses is right.
So like, you know, the people probably concentrate on the damage more.
Yeah, especially, I mean, we have a bigger problem, especially with just in general,
just thinking about it, like damage also now resulting in crowd control amplifies the
problem even further.
Yeah.
Um, because that having the boss be heavy stunned and or frozen or whatever, like majority
of the fight is just even more of a reason to just go ballistic on damage.
Um, yeah, there's a lot, there are problems here a hundred percent.
I have, I'm just thinking of random other things that.
Well, yeah, I have other questions about defense as well.
Um, so armor break, uh, I would say like effectively disables armor, right.
As a defense for hardcore, it's sort of like when it comes around, it kind of like shuts
down your main form of defense.
You're feeling like very tanky if you do invest into armor.
Um, well, ideally I do still armor needs a buff.
Um, but I guess the problem I have with armor break and fizz overwhelm in Peewee one is that
it's just so crazy to me to have something effectively shut down your defense from time to time.
Um, so yeah, I, I, are you happy with armor break and fizz overwhelm being in the game?
Um, well, in Peewee two context, I am not happy with, uh, the current state of monster armor
break.
No, that is also on my change today list.
Um, so I need to, there's a few things.
It was meant to be that they're breaking flat amounts of armor and that isn't.
So if the more you stack, the less significant the armor break becomes from the enemy.
I suspect there might be some percent, some sources of percentage based in there, which are
just like.
It disincentivizes.
I mean, it just means that the more you have, the more pun, the more you're relying on armor,
the more punished it's going to be.
So I just need to do a quick audit.
There's not that many sources, thankfully, so it won't take long.
And I just need to make sure that it's working.
And then there are possibly cases where it is just doing too much.
And yeah, it's just like, it acts as an insane weakness, but yeah, I don't know.
A hundred percent agreed.
It is not in the right spot.
And, um, also on the today list, I need to make sure that, uh, uh, uh, we go back, get,
get, get the community team to go back through this afterwards and make sure I don't forget
about all these things.
But, um, no, that one I already have.
There's that and the speed and a bunch of these other, and arbiter and there's a whole bunch
of stuff.
Yeah.
We've gone over a lot already.
Um, do you think in the short term we could see just like a straight up number buff to
armor while you're trying to work out a long-term solution?
Oh no, but I'm not talking about a long-term solution for the armor break thing.
I'm talking about it.
It'll be solved.
No, no, I know.
But like, that's what I mean for armor too.
Oh, I see what you're saying.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Misunderstood.
Yeah, sure.
Um, I can't be able to immediately say that.
In order to change armor, we'd need to be able to understand why it's bad.
And I don't think just changing the number right now is right for that.
Okay.
That's fair.
Like, I don't think we've fully understood the issue there.
We did a few things.
Like, we, um, there was some overwhelm on some bosses and we removed it.
And there was, um, there were too many skills converting too much into element.
Um, and we, I think we, and we pushed back a lot of that.
So like, it obviously makes the armor more effective against those abilities.
And like, there's a lot more of that.
We probably need to reevaluate as well, just across the board.
Yeah.
Um, uh, but that stuff's really fast to change as for just a global number shift.
But that's an example right there of why just changing the number wouldn't have even helped,
right?
Like if the problem is elemental damage, then making armor stronger wouldn't have done anything
for that.
So like, it's so important to understand the reason before we just make changes.
Obviously the danger there by moving more fizz is it then makes it worse for, um, non-armor
builds as well, but that increases the power of armor differential to the others.
And so there's, you know, it's got to be careful with that, but, um, well, maybe, cause I, uh,
maybe, maybe there's something we can do more imminently.
Anecdotally, I would definitely love more access to different forms of defense.
And I know that is definitely an AEA problem where just not everything is in yet, but just
to like, anecdotally running through my experience, I am a Smith of Catawba.
So I have like the, the shared res and the, uh, shared max res.
So I'm like, I'm 89, 90, 90.
Uh, and for a long time I was like 85, 86, 87.
So very high alley res.
Um, and on top of that, I was wearing a cloak of...
Which means yes, currently moving more into fizz is probably going to be to your, uh, detriment.
Yeah, sure.
But, uh, even with that and a cloak of flames, and I can't remember the name hollow something,
but there's the, uh, the unique helmet with like 15% fizz reduction, even with all of that
mitigation, I was like at the start of today's dream, I was, I was very rough until I got
my fourth lab that I was able to like improve it a little bit, but it felt a little bit
weird to me as a player that I've like my entire ascendancy was defense based.
I picked up every defense I could on the tree and I was trying so hard to get really good
gear or two and it was, it was very rough on defense.
I mean, what I immediately probably will do after is I'm just going to grab your character,
put it locally, and then just kind of just have a look at that.
It's just so I can get a better exact understanding, but like, sure.
I can give you a snapshot before I, um, cause now with region, it has been, we don't, we can,
we have, we have it all.
Don't worry.
Perfect.
We can take anyone's character from live and just play with it.
It's not a.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Uh, the region did make a big difference.
But I'm still seeing, um, a lot of issues there.
Uh, another thing that, uh, has been brought up a lot and I thought was really good point
was we see chaos damage very early in Peewee 2.
In Peewee 1, it was like generally something we'd see a lot later.
Um, would you be open to considering something like the, uh, chaos soul core being a rune instead,
something that we can like get early?
Um, it's definitely a big part of what makes Viper so scary is it's, it's almost impossible
to get chaos rise early on.
Um, yeah.
Hmm.
Sounds like a sort of more of a hardcore related concern because in standard you wouldn't,
like, it, it, it, it, it's just balanced to be okay.
But in hardcore where you're wanting to definitely not die, it's like a different concern.
And I don't think we would have thought about it in that way previously.
It is sort of a medium core concern.
Cause like, if you can't get past the boss, you're just stuck there.
Oh, sure.
But like, I mean the damage, like, like it's balanced assuming zero chaos resist, right?
So like, well, Viper's hard.
It is hard.
It is a hard fight.
That's just a side note that's separate.
But like, in terms of just the fact, like the fact that it's chaos damage, I don't think
is as relevant in standard play because like the, that we, we're balanced assuming you
have no chaos resistance.
And so what does she do?
That's chaos.
Obviously the big purple meteor storm that I want to make some changes to, cause it just
creates too much mess on the ground.
It's a little bit lacking clarity or that fairness.
And then the spare things, right?
I'm assuming.
Um, so the way it works is aside from poison itself dealing chaos damage, uh, the only other
things that are chaos damage are anything that is purple.
Yeah.
Right.
So, so all of your green stabs and slashes, none of that is chaos and none of it should
be chaos.
It's physical hits.
And then the poison, if it poisons you, then it is chaos damage.
But because you, because the poison damage is based on the hit, your armor effectively
mitigates the, um, your armor mitigates the chaos damage because it reduced the hit size.
Right.
Yeah.
Um, so yeah.
So yeah, the, the meteor thing is a problem, but it's like more of a fairness problem because
ideally you should be able to dodge that pretty reliably every time.
Right now, a bit of a mess.
It is hard to dodge that.
Yes.
But aside from that, it would only be the poison of which, yes, you're, you're, you're,
other defenses would, I mean, armor in particular innovation would mitigate.
Right.
Um, but yes, I do.
It is the case by the way that if a thing like the, any snake spitter that's spitting
at you with some green poison thing that aside from the poison debuff, which I believe you
said kind of wasn't that dangerous earlier in general.
And maybe there are certain cases where it is.
It's definitely dangerous if you're playing an evasion character.
Like that poison feels lethal.
And that's once again, cause the armor didn't.
The hit is never chaos damage.
Just to be clear.
Which in P.O.E.
One it is.
It's like half chaos, half fizz.
Yeah.
No, I, I did not know that.
I fully thought the spears from the side, which a lot of people say is the most dangerous
attack.
I thought that was chaos.
Cause it's very heavy.
Just fizz.
Right.
Okay.
Yep.
This is pro, so that's probably just more of a viper is too hard problem.
Right.
Makes sense.
Um, I wanted to ask you a little bit about, she's for her.
Uh, I wanted to ask you a little bit about pushing, um, as a player, I experienced that
sometimes like, as like, it's almost seems like decent to me, if I'm being frank.
Um, is there an option to have more source of push resistance?
Something, for example, like the, the more strength the character has or wearing heavy
armor.
It does seem a little silly to a lot of people that like people maybe have 300, 500 strength
or are they wearing like full plate, but like, yeah, a lot of monsters are just pushing
you around variously.
Hmm.
It does currently exist as a concept of mitigating it, um, because it was meant to be more of
a physical thing of, well, there's two things.
There's like monsters pushing you because you literally cannot occupy the same space as
them.
Um.
So here we're, are we talking right now about monster charge abilities or are we talking
about like a sword, like a sword swing?
The, uh, the number one thing that has been noticeable for me is that like little, I think
it's from an ant line maybe or something.
It's like the little like yellow beast that like rolls on you.
Uh, that still does take you for a ride.
Sure.
Uh, in that case, that's probably just a matter of fixing that particular thing.
Like I suspect that the answer to this one is not, we need to mitigation really.
It's more just like, we just need to look at places that are like just monsters that
are bad and just fix them individually.
There are certain things I wanted to do.
Like I wanted it to be, and there was, there were technical limitations here that we need
to revaluate, but I want it to be when you were blocking or parrying and you got hit,
you had, you got knocked less back because you technically did deflect them.
Right.
Uh, in the parry case in particular.
And like some cases there's just push direction, like maybe the ant lines.
Yeah.
And then some, that thing, the charges and things taking your ride has been like honestly
the bane of my year.
That's just a, that's more of a just specific setup of specific monsters and stuff like that.
Like is, is, um, did we fix, uh, what's his name?
Um, the lumberjack guy in theory, but it seems to regress.
It still happens sometimes.
It seems to just break everything.
I don't think, I don't think this is a like balance question.
I think it's just a technical, like, we just need to fix some places.
Yeah.
I just wonder.
There is also some desync we need to fix.
Yeah, sure.
There's also that annoying.
Yeah.
Is pushing something you would consider temporarily removing until you have fixed the issue?
Not at all.
No, no.
It will make the game feel like dog shit if we do that.
Like there's just lots of things that you need to have.
You need to have some pushing in order to make work.
Like, I think it's more just specific monsters.
Right.
Okay.
I, I, yeah.
I'm not 100% sure I agree with that, but, uh, we'll, we'll move on.
Uh, you, you, that's because you haven't seen it without it.
Like it's, yeah.
That's fair.
That's true.
If we turn up all sources of pushing, it would just be, it would, it would, it would be,
it would be a disaster.
Right.
Um, yeah.
Okay.
Um, so during early access, we've talked about like, uh, re-space and lowering re-spec costs
and stuff.
And I wanted to bring up the point that a lot of players are using a large amount of
their gold on gambling.
Um, cause we are, a lot of people are falling behind or feeling behind on gear.
Uh, so I wonder if, if you would consider further lowering costs, uh, and even like reopen
the conversation on ascendancy re-spec during early access, especially since you've been
talking about, um, that you are going to be buffing things.
So let's say somebody is like, oh, wow.
Flame blast looks really cool.
Uh, I would love to be able to try that, but the, maybe redoing the entire campaign again,
which can be over 20 hours for a lot of people feels very, uh, prohibitive.
I do find it to be, maybe not.
I do find it to be very fucking cheap right now is the thing.
Exactly.
Hmm.
I can't say personally I've run into that as a problem.
Like I'll respect my character all the time.
I don't even think twice about it.
Like it's not been a concern really.
I guess it depends how much you gamble or not.
It probably does.
Well, at that point, yeah.
But even like, I'm saying even if you're just like early, so I don't think it takes that
long to actually do a pretty substantial risk.
I have to admit that I haven't been gambling in my playthroughs really.
Hmm.
Like I was like probably about six months ago, I was doing that all the time and I just haven't
really been doing it recently.
When we did the like gold model and respect costs, we made, we had assumptions of like,
here's how much people will spend on vendors and here's how much.
And there's probably it.
Look, those assumptions assume a perfect world of that person exactly doing that thing.
And so, yes, if anyone was to stray from that assumption, they're now not going to be able
to afford one thing over the other.
What I'm actually hearing right now, by the way, from this and an earlier conversation
we had is that I need to not be disenchant.
I need to do some disenchantless runs because apparently I'm not testing something that players
are actually doing.
Like my runs are entirely like I disenchant every rare on my runs generally.
And so if that's a different behavior, then I need to test that and see what the experience
is like.
Because like the whole like there's not enough currency thing, there's not, you know, like
stuff like that.
And like saying, and if you're telling me that you're like selling your res and buying
gambling all the time, and then you're also saying, you know, I've got to respect.
It's like, well, this is just like a materially different play style that I'm not currently
testing myself.
Right.
So like, I think that that's what I need to do to see what's going on with that.
And with the last point I made, would you, especially with the fact that there are going
to be buffs coming during this, would you be?
I don't think that anything changes between early access and not early access regard,
by the way.
Like, I think that if the argument is that it should, like, I think the argument is the
same regardless of whether it's early access.
Like, I don't think the early access is a part of this decision regardless.
It's just what is the price supposed to be?
We should get it correctly.
Well, sure.
But I'm talking about ascendancy respect was what I wanted to.
Yeah.
Otherwise it depends a little bit on the severity of the change.
But like.
It depends how, it depends partly also on just how much we change.
Without knowing the, you know, how big those changes are, because I needed to get in there
and actually do them first and then make that decision, really.
Yeah.
Like, there are certainly options there.
It is important to me to make sure that I understand exactly where I sit on the ascendancy
class respect thing, because the moment that's turned on, it ain't going back.
Um, so that is blocked by me and I will take whatever is necessary on that one.
I understand it.
Um, well, it is more.
Can I ask you a question about it then?
Sure.
Um, do you feel like that?
Do you feel like it is absolutely necessary to have those both be permanent choices?
Because you already do have the character class itself be a permanent choice, right?
Oh, no, no.
And I'm like, I do understand.
Do, do be clear.
I am on the fence about this.
Like, I can't say that.
Like I play, I'm like, oh, I can't believe POE one has ascendancy class respecting.
Like I'm all for that as well.
It's just, I'm all so off.
I'm also for the more permanent decision.
I'm just like, I need to find the variable that makes me be able to, or the articulation
to be able to go one way or the other.
And it's very easy to just fold on that.
Like very easy.
It'd be very easy to just be like, ah, we're going to change it right now.
Um, but it's not when you have the things that you can't come back from, like you definitely
want to be certain to some degree.
Um, there are some other staff that share the same sentiment as me.
And I, I might just go and have a bigger discussion and actually figure that out.
And like, it is true.
It's not really fair to make people have to wait for that decision on my behalf.
I kind of was like, look, by release post early access, I will, you will have that decision
one way or the other.
And that must be the way it is.
Um, but yeah, fair enough.
If the argument is like, if it's going to come up every single time, which is fair, people
care about it.
Then I probably need to press the decision sooner than later.
So, um, I'll just get that answered sooner and, and, and not, um, not have people wait
so long.
Uh, hopefully, uh, for everyone's sake, it's the answer you want, but if it isn't, well,
you might just have to deal with it.
That's fair.
Um, I think I was curious about like, so you went with the decision to keep that, um, and
it's shield does not get bled.
Um, which is sort of like giving monsters a form to be immune, right?
Like it feels very similar to like, I don't, I don't think, I don't think that we've actually
come to a decision on this really.
Like there, there, there wasn't like a, we, I think after the last time this was discussed,
we never actually went back and talked about it.
So I wouldn't say we've decided that it's more just that it just went in like that because
we didn't get another chance to talk about it.
So I don't know that we have a real answer as to what we want to do with that yet.
Okay.
Like we should probably will revisit that.
I personally am just all for changing it, to be honest.
Okay.
Well, sure.
Then I mean, I have no objection to that.
Yeah.
We made the decision a while back.
Like, I don't see why it can't.
Yeah.
Um, I did want to bring up, if you do make it like that on players too, remember to put,
uh, bleed immune on CI.
Yeah.
Uh, we will definitely change CI, but it is a thing that the players,
are now going to have to deal with who aren't CI just as a light, you know, a note as a
thing that will happen.
Yeah.
But I wouldn't say that bleed is exactly breaking the bank right now.
Is it all?
It was for a while.
There was a period there where like bleed was just brutal.
Like what, what changed to make that not the case?
Like I'm talking pre-release.
Uh, it.
Like, do you remember when the fricking like prowlers and G1-4 bleed you?
We had bleed on a lot more.
Yes.
And then there was some crazy damage multipliers on it.
Some that I can't remember why they were, but I mean, again, pre-release numbers, things.
Cool.
Um.
Which was also unfun, by the way.
Yeah, I'm just saying like, I don't remember what happened.
Yeah.
Um, I have a question about ignite prolif, uh, specifically with the monsters needing
to stand still for, or like needing to be near the source for two seconds, um, to be
able to proliferate.
It needs, probably needs to be on the, it's on the today list.
It was actually on my yesterday list and I didn't quite get to it.
So it sucks.
Um, I know we've had a lot of heavy questions, but I have a, a bit of a lighter question, uh,
for myself, like, uh, how are you feeling about the current, like, blessed orb and diviner
being bundled together?
I don't have a problem with it.
I mean, is there anything?
I would say I don't have a feeling one way or the other, really.
It's just, how do you feel about it?
Uh, I definitely, like, I don't know if this is just a PoE1 player thing, but I definitely
feel like it's missing.
Um, because, like, I, I would never divine an item, like, cause the divine is, it's a
big investment, right?
Like, we use it a lot on, like, uniques or, like, when a, a main weapon is, like, in need
of it, but, um.
Like, are you saying that, are you saying that you believe that, um, this is reducing the
desire to actually use divines?
It's just that I, I would never use it for just an implicit on an item.
So it just makes an item feel, like, pretty much permanently worse than what it should
be, I guess, is, like, my personal anecdotal feeling as a player.
Hmm.
I mean, that's, hmm, is that partly also just because the ranges and or power of an implicit
is just too weak as well?
Yeah, potentially.
They're not, they're not exactly impactful in most regards.
Some are good.
Some are very good.
I can't say this is something we've really thought about.
Yeah.
So that's just.
It's just a thing that kind of happened and then, like, yeah, we honestly just went under
the radar the whole time.
So.
Yeah.
If there are more opinions on that, I'd be, like, really happy to hear them.
Mm-hmm.
Yep.
Uh, it was just something I was curious about, so I'm afraid I'll bring it up.
Um.
The next thing is about movement speed.
Uh.
In Pee Wee 1, we have a lot more things like Whirling Blades, Frost Blink, et cetera.
And in Pee Wee 1, I feel like it's a bit more viable to completely forego movement speed
on boots and go for, like, triple energy shield.
Uh.
But obviously, movement abilities aren't in the same spot in Pee Wee 2.
Is there ever a world where you either, like, think about, like, removing the hidden movement
reductions on shield and armor?
Um.
Give, like, a implicit movement speed to boots or something like that, so they scale a little
bit with, like, the higher bases?
Well, I mean, you're just, are you, are you just saying here just make movement speed on
the player faster?
Uh.
So, for example, like, one idea that I saw was, um, if you, let's say that some bases
have 5, 10, and 15 movement speed, so, like, that the higher bases are slightly better,
and maybe even, like, scale less, right?
So that some of your movement speed is guaranteed, or make it, like, a lot easier to roll movement
speed, like, increase the weight, uh, that it can roll.
Well, I don't necessarily think it's bad to have a base type that, where you've got a
mod that, you know, that's somewhat mandatory.
Like, that's okay.
Um.
But it sounds, like, because, but if you're.
Well, as a player, it just.
Like, like, like, if, if, if, honestly, because I mean, the thing is, in Pee Wee 1, are there
really people going around?
Like, surely it isn't common that people don't have movement speed on their boots in Pee Wee
1.
I don't know quite a lot.
I guess it's technically viable if you just, you reckon?
Yeah, quite a lot of, like, triple energy shield boots and stuff.
Right.
Or, especially different in Pee Wee 1, because we have the, um.
It's specialized.
Influenced things.
Right, right, right.
Again, you've got seasoned, seasoned players, not like.
Right, right.
Yeah, not new players, sure.
Random.
But, but it is an option, and it isn't really in Pee Wee 2.
Like, movement speed is a lot more mandatory.
I mean.
I don't know.
I, to me, to me, like, I mean, sure, I do not disagree with the fact that there can
be scenarios in Pee Wee 1 where that's not the case, but I would still say it's basically
mandatory there for them, like, for most of your Pee Wee playing career, I would say that
you're going to be wanting to get movement speed on your boots, you know?
I would even argue, like, the single best boot in Pee Wee 1, which is the Ralec Kish
Impatience, they don't have movement speed on them.
And, like, they're still considered, like, pretty much the best boot.
Right.
But, I mean, isn't that fundamentally, then, just the back to, like, back to the question
of, like, you want to move faster?
Yeah, for sure.
It is.
Sure.
So, I mean, I guess that would be the...
So, really, it's kind of like that.
Move faster implicitly and less dependency on the mod, right?
Yeah.
But, I mean, whether or not it's implicit or based on the mod or anything, it's just,
I want to move faster, right?
Like, it feels like that's really the core of it.
Which comes back to the, we need to have those discussions.
Right, right, right.
Yeah.
It's similar.
A difference in PoE 2 is that the implicits of uniques, especially things like life sprig,
will scale into the endgame, where, like, if I find a life sprig on my level 80 character
now, it's never going to be usable early game.
But the explicits on life sprig, sorry, and a lot of other caster uniques and things like
that, they don't scale either.
So, have you explored the idea of the actual explicit scaling or the implicit not scaling
so that you can find these, like, twink leveling uniques?
Like, what are your thoughts around the uniques there?
I don't think we would want uniques to have the explicit scale like that.
That's kind of not what uniques are about.
Yeah, yeah.
So, I just not, that is not a particular solution.
The bigger question is about whether or not the implicit, the skill should or shouldn't
level up with the item.
Well, I mean, it apparently does, right?
It does.
But something that could be interesting is that if you find a life sprig on a level
80 character, it can scale up to that level.
So, it would scale with your character.
That would make you feel really good as a leveling item, for example, that you can use it at level
one, you hit level three.
I really don't like that kind of thing, the whole, like, item that just scales with your
character.
Like, I don't think that we want to move in a direction where you'll have less, like,
have less times when you put items on your character as you level up.
That doesn't feel like the right direction to me.
But there's also more whether, and there's a second part to that, which is whether or
not life sprig should even have high level requirement ever.
Which is a more, I think that's come up a bit more.
That's a separate question.
That, yeah, it's come up.
I'm kind of not quite sure about that one at the moment.
That's fair.
Yeah.
There'll be more discussions.
I mean, so actually, so one thing that was proposed, and as a central solution to this,
is that just the, like, I feel like maybe you didn't like this.
I can't remember who didn't like this.
Someone didn't like this.
Because I proposed that we make it so that the implicit skill on Unix has, like, a cap
level.
But then that does level up as you go through the game.
Like, not, so it does not, sorry.
It's not that it levels up.
It's that, like, it is capped to the level of where you are.
Yeah.
So that way, even if you get a level 80 life sprig, you can still equip it at low levels
and then, you know, and then that will go with you effectively.
And somehow I see that as different from, like, your items changing as you level up.
That, to me, that's not, like, quite the same thing.
So, like, that would potentially be an option.
I don't remember why we didn't.
There was some reason why we didn't do that.
But, like, it might still be on the cards.
That's fair.
Wait, so you're saying if you find it at level 80...
I'm saying if you find it at level 80, it's a level 16 skill, but you can still equip
it.
It doesn't change the level requirement.
But then the skill gets down leveled to the maximum that it can be for the...
Oh, sure.
I thought that's what he proposed just a second ago, but...
No, no.
He's talking about the explicit skill.
No, no, no.
There's a second thing there.
The second one was that.
Yeah.
Okay, sorry.
Maybe I misunderstood then.
Okay, right.
Sorry.
In that case, then, sure.
Like...
I mean, I would personally prefer to just be like, you can drop a
low-level life sprig, and that's you using a low-level life sprig.
Yeah, but I don't love that either, honestly.
But I don't hate that.
Yeah.
I don't hate it.
There's a part of me that also kind of liked the idea that there were some uniques that
were more valuable to find at lower levels, which I thought was kind of interesting.
But I don't know whether players actually like that or not, so that's just kind of like
a random other thing.
That's fair.
But...
I don't hate that.
Yeah.
I was just curious, because we do find them a lot.
Another question is about the minion resurrect timer.
Um...
It keeps resetting, like, the entire timer every time a monster dies.
And, uh...
That can feel very frustrating.
So I wondered...
Yeah, just how do you feel about that?
That the entire timer resets?
Well, if you don't have that, it feels a lot more frustrating, let me tell you.
Like, that was how it was until we changed it.
And, like, it was so bad.
Because what happens is that, like, the monsters...
Your minions just die one at a time, and then they can never really accomplish anything.
And it's just like...
Like, trust me, that was a buff, that change.
Like, that was a massive improvement.
So, yeah, like, until you experience it the other way, like, yeah, like, you will understand
if you play it the other way.
There might be an intermediary there.
I want to explore some options.
For example, like, instead of resetting the entire timer, it adds to the timer based on,
like, the cost of the minion or something like that.
We might do something like that.
But I don't know.
But that's not going to fix the fundamental issue, which is that minions work best when there's
lots of minions.
And so the issue that we had was is that you just get into a situation where they just
trickle in and die one at a time.
No matter what, they have to revive all at the same time.
That has to happen, yes.
I'm just saying it could be that, like, okay, let's say everyone's dead but one.
Oh, I see what you're saying.
Right, right, right, right.
So it increases a bit, but not as much.
And so instead of, like, oh, all about to revive except for one, oh, he died.
And now it's six seconds.
That actually is viable.
And that maybe is a change we could make.
And, like, would you ever be open to adding a keystone that changes the behavior?
I was actually thinking about that earlier today.
And I mostly, as, like, the troll in me was like, we should do this just so the players
can see how bad it is.
Yeah.
But, yeah, that was probably a negative thought I shouldn't be having.
No, that's fair.
I think a lot of people would like to see it.
Sure, sure.
But, yeah, no, I think the thing Mark just said is much more reasonable.
Yeah.
And so we should probably do something more like that.
Convocation.
Is that something on the table?
It's, like, maybe a spirit skill or something?
I don't love it.
That's fair.
I'm kind of like, I could see a world where a reservation cooldown or you have to earn
it or something like that.
To go in, it would have to be different enough that players probably wouldn't see it as Convocation
anymore.
Like, I suspect that's kind of the reality.
Like, as Mark said, you'd have to have some kind of conditions or you'd have to do something.
And it's like, at that point, it's not even doing the thing the players want it for.
Anyway, so it's like, you know, like that being said, it might still just be better and there
might be some room for it.
I don't love it.
Yeah.
Well, yeah.
I don't love it.
I know.
Like, I would much rather find a better solution to that issue.
Okay.
When it comes to map completion, obviously there's been some changes this patch.
But one thing that easily feels the worst is when there is one monster just like really
far away.
And the checkpoint system doesn't really cut it there.
Would you consider making the completion of a map be like 90% of the rares instead of 100?
Because the bad feeling is very often tied to just one monster, the other side of the
map.
And I have to like do so much backtracking.
Well, I want to solve this problem.
I don't know that that's the answer, but I understand the issue.
Like, there's been a few different questions.
We straight up discussed last night that like just having the mini-map icons on always is
probably...
There was a discussion of doing the mini-map icons on all the time, right?
Because you're not going to miss the monsters if you see them.
The main reason for that is like the current way it works is it's like when 200 remaining
they appear.
And on some maps, that's like you kill three packs and they appear.
And other maps, it's like you've got to clear 80% of it before they appear.
And honestly, that's kind of weird and bad anyway.
It's just that we kind of want to...
Like, the main thing we're worried about with that change is the whole you just play on
the mini-map.
Like, you're not even looking into the game.
But I think that fear...
I'm very in favor of that.
I love playing off the mini-map.
Do we just turn off...
Yeah.
Literally just showing from the start.
Like, I love that initially, for sure.
At least for me.
Ah, okay.
Sorry.
I thought you said you love the idea of not looking at the game and only playing off the
mini-map.
I kind of do that anyway.
One of the...
Like, when we were trying to find that in Video Crash...
Yeah.
One of our developers tried playing with just the graphics turned off.
Like, they just had the mini-map and they played literally to the end of Act 2 with just
no graphics.
And they're like...
And the funny thing was, I was like, what the hell?
How did you even manage to get through two acts like that?
And he's like, oh, Huntress OP.
I was like, okay.
Like, this is...
So it is actually possible to play entirely with the mini-map.
No graphics at all, apparently.
Yeah.
That was fun.
I would love that.
I want to change that imminently.
The thing with the 90% thing you're suggesting, by the way, there is like, let's say the map
only has three rares.
Is it just two out of three?
Sure.
Is it round down?
Does it round up?
If there's only two rares, is it literally just one?
It would just enable seeing the rares on the map.
I agree.
It's probably better just to do that.
I like that.
Another quick question about Delirium.
It seems very fast.
Obviously, we're a bit slower now.
Any thoughts on Delirium speed?
I very specifically made a number of builds and tested them just before this O2O release.
And I was actually surprised how well I was doing.
And I was like, okay, I thought this was a big problem.
And I was like, I'll just actually go and actually test it myself.
So it could be...
Okay, here's...
I'd like to know a bit more here, I guess.
Which is like, is it certain maps over others?
Yeah.
100%.
Like...
Because it's still expensive to donut, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Which we do.
And we do kind of have to balance it around probably the bottom...
Maybe it's...
Yeah, sure.
There's probably a point where it's balanced around an assumption of being more acceptable maps
instead of the worst ones.
And so I just need to shift that assumption and then change it.
But yeah, I did specifically personally test this on a number of characters pre-O2O.
And I was actually surprised...
I was like, I expected it to be way worse than it was.
That being said, I wasn't using like a massive range of maps for testing that.
I was like, you know, probably five or six different things on many different characters.
So...
Yeah, sure.
I will look at that as well.
I will add it to the today list.
Yeah.
It's going to be a big day.
Well, I appreciate you guys doing this.
So, obviously, P.O.E., you're not necessarily tied to like the warrior being melee, right?
Like right now I'm playing artillery ballista.
Would it be possible to implement some sort of favored system that I can just tick like artillery ballista with a little heart on it?
So then when I go to like level up those gems, I don't have to in the bottom left search artillery ballista and I'm ticked the...
I would suggest just having a tab for equipped gems would be the way to do that.
Yeah.
Like you just have a tab that just shows you the equipped gems.
You just click on...
Perfect.
And you level up that way.
Yeah.
All the classes, then my gems, and then all gems is probably what it should be.
Another question.
The Smith's Hammer ability.
I was watching...
I have not used it myself, but I saw Queen69 using it and it looked pretty painful with like a little like tink, tink, and then going out and hitting twice.
Any improvements to that?
So there were meant to be some changes that were made to this that I even specifically spoke about, I think, with maybe Darth and Gazzy or whatever when we had that last one.
Yeah.
And those changes didn't occur.
They have occurred locally.
They should be in a imminent patch coming out.
But that's...
It somehow got missed, I think.
Or I don't know.
I actually don't know what happened there, but that was a sheer mistake.
Straight up.
All good.
Whenever...
So there are multiple skills that can use chargers.
A few players have reported that they might want to use chargers on a specific skill.
Would there be a way to deactivate that a skill uses chargers, but you still want to use that skill, but you don't want it to be empowered?
This was something that came up probably about three or four days before we shipped, actually.
I mean, the obvious case is barrage on the huntress, right?
Yeah.
Like, whether or not you want to do that.
So I think...
I'd have to look into whether or not this is going to be okay, but we could have a support gem that does that.
Like, give some other power boost that says it can't consume chargers or something.
And then that way you could use that with barrage if you wanted to disable it for that.
Something like that.
So I think that'd probably be the way.
But I have to think about exactly what that should be.
But something along those lines would be the way I'd do that.
It should work.
Yeah.
I have a little, like, just interesting question about how do you feel like class identity revolves more around weapons, right?
Because, like, I'm a warrior build, but a lot of people inherently think, like, warrior is maces.
But, yeah, like, the class identity is more around the weapons themselves.
I was curious how you feel about that.
Well, we explicitly moved to having 12 classes partly because of that, like, to make that the case.
Like, we want that.
And this is actually was driven partly...
I mean, so when we were talking about, like, adding weapon types and so on, there was this thing where we were like, okay, if you're...
You know what it actually was?
Okay, so we had the spear base type.
And we're like, okay.
Because this is, like, way back, like, a long time ago.
We're like, okay, what is going to make a person who selects a ranger ever switch to spears and do that?
That's just incredibly unlikely to actually happen.
It's like, ultimately, the purpose of the classes at the start are kind of to give you a stereotype to, like, to go to.
Now, you don't have to follow that, obviously.
Like, everything's open.
But giving players, like, a thing where they're like, okay, like, I know what I'm going to do.
Like, I'm going to do this thing.
It's, like, it's kind of important for new players to have that happen.
So I think it is overall very positive and kind of, like, why we did that in the first place.
And, I mean, like, an evidence of that in POE 1 is, like, yeah, players who select ranger, like, even though there's all this whole thing about being able to become a melee ranger,
like, a new...
It takes a long time before someone would even experiment with that if they're a new player.
Like, they just wouldn't even cross their mind to, like, change weapon type like that once they've already started.
So, effectively, just due to that, we needed to have some way to make it so that, you know, from the very beginning, you kind of know...
Like, you've got some idea in your head about what kind of thing you want to play.
Yeah.
The next question is about corrupted items.
And you added, in my opinion, a very fun, new, unique strongbox.
Actually, whoever made the Venter strongbox.
Chapskis.
Love that thing.
Please put it in POE 1 as well.
Coolest thing ever.
But I find corrupted items a little frustrating, too, due to quality and sockets.
I don't know if the answer is just, like, that they always have quality and sockets.
But, obviously, it's items that we can't recombinate anyway.
And I just want to hear your thoughts on a balance pass from that.
It's very frustrating to get a really cool unique that is...
Or rare that it's effectively useless.
Yeah.
Something needs to change there.
Like, it isn't right.
We actually removed some corrupted drops before O2O went out.
And then...
Because we were like, wait, hold on.
Getting corrupted items just sucks.
Like, this isn't a good thing you want.
So, like, corrupting an item of your choice is great.
Yeah.
So, we just straight up...
We're like, we need to just start removing the corrupted drops and find a different way
or a different item mechanic or do something with them.
Yeah.
Cool.
100% just, like, what is this random white corrupted item on the ground?
Like, that is never going to be of use to anyone.
Right.
Yeah.
We just need to fix that, for sure.
Cool.
Is there a possibility of the runes being added to the currency stash tab?
I believe we would...
So, what was it?
We're adding a socketables affinity.
Yeah.
We're adding a bunch of affinities.
I think it's, like, socketables, fragments, which will include tablets.
Yeah.
And, obviously, fragments.
Breach and or catalysts.
Cool.
Expedition and also logbooks and the currency.
You know, we're adding a whole bunch of them.
I think there's five, six, seven, maybe different affinities that we're meant to be adding
within, like, you know...
I would expect to see that within a week, probably, is my, like, guess.
We're not going to add...
This is, like...
Currently, it has the whole, you have to have the stash tab in order to have the affinity.
And we're, like, having to divorce that a little bit so that we can just have the affinities
because the tabs take longer to make.
And so, we're doing that work currently.
And I would expect to have all of that.
So, you can use your premium quads, whatever, you know, to stash all of those.
Cool.
I actually almost threw with all of my questions here.
So, this isn't something, sadly, that I've been able to interact too much with.
But I wanted to talk a little bit about recombinators anyway and just see if you guys have looked
into it, looked into the data a little bit.
Obviously, I've seen a clip of, for example, Karin having, like, the 0.91 chance to recombinate.
And, yeah, just...
What do you guys think of recombinator use this early, basically?
I don't think we've even had enough real experience.
Yeah, yeah.
That's fair.
Waiting for more info and data there, for sure.
I did worry that there'd be an...
That people would start seeing those very low values because they're using extremely rare item modifiers.
Yeah.
Or numbers of mods.
And getting, like, oh my god, it says less than 1% or less than 2.
This whole system sucks.
There was a real, like...
It's interesting because, like, with recombinators, I feel like every time we've ever even looked at them,
they've always got this thing of, like, this tension between, like...
Like, they're so OP and yet also they look so underpowered.
Like, when you...
Yeah.
They've got this, like, horrible tension like that.
However, what I do think that this system is, compared to the previous one, is so much better
is that if you're using them for the, like, low number of mod cases,
then, like, you can get relatively, like, relatively good weights.
But we do have the ability to do more specific balance here if we want to.
So, like, we'll just adjust it.
Like, honestly, I have to admit, like, I haven't even recombinated anything on live myself yet.
So, like, you know, like, it's just not...
It's not...
I can't really say anything about...
Yeah, that's fair.
It's something I haven't...
Like, I just don't know how it feels enough, you know?
There were two major item systems that I was, like, expecting to get a bunch of feedback on
and then would calibrate.
One was recombinating.
And the other, which I am very thoroughly looking for,
and maybe you have some opinions on it,
is how the new map drop progression works.
And I know there is two...
There's one thing I changed last night,
which is to make it a bit easier to get guaranteed maps from the fixed last rear and last final boss.
But the other thing is there is currently a bug, which I saw,
which is sometimes the boss's drop isn't plus one level.
What?
Yeah, I don't know how that happens.
But I saw that bug.
But assuming those are fixed,
I am very curious to know and kind of just get people's, you know, feeling on that.
I've seen some people get through the tears very, very quickly,
which is fine because they have proven that they can and that's fine.
And they weren't at the whims of the RNG as much.
But I'm looking for a lot of feedback on that
and I'm hoping to start getting a bit more of that as people get into endgame.
I have anecdotally heard people telling me that they're happier with how endgame is now
than how it was in 0.1.
I have also heard that, but again, very anecdotally.
Especially when it comes to sustain, I'm the wrong person to ask
because I was shocked at one of the previous podcasts
when people were saying they were struggling with sustain.
So I thought it was funny when you basically said skill issues.
Well, that was also the case for us, which is why we did this.
So that's why we just were like, let's fully redo this.
So I'm the wrong person to ask for about sustain
and obviously there's no issues for me with sustain now.
I've talked to my community a little about this
and it was pretty split with the new like how you unlock Atlas points.
A lot of people didn't like it.
I personally like it a lot more.
I had a strong dislike for the do 10 tier one maps, do 10 tier two maps.
So I love the new way, but a lot of people in my community didn't.
So you're definitely going to have to get more feedback there.
I'm just not 100% sure.
I think the issue that people in my chat were saying
was that they were struggling to see the corruption.
So maybe even like some sort of indicator of like,
like not an arrow, but like more.
When you say C, do you mean,
when you say C, do you mean like out of the fog of war
or in the fog of war?
Both, I guess.
Like, just like, do you know the way we have the beams
towards the pillars right now?
Yeah, that's why I'm asking.
Are you saying just like physically you don't see them
when they're revealed?
Just before the patch went out, we were like,
we actually did go,
do we want these to be visible in fog of war or not?
Yeah.
And they were, by the way.
And then we were like,
I think maybe actually we don't
because you're going to spend too much of your playtime
just looking in fog of war.
And I wouldn't be looking in the revealed section more.
And so that's why I did change it.
So that some things are in fog of war,
but it's like not that many.
So towers and citadels being that.
And then you could have like a very short distance,
maybe.
Yeah.
So we don't currently have a distance in fog of war.
You can see it's just either it is or it isn't.
And so maybe we can mess with that and have it be like,
yeah, you can see, you know,
some depth in or something like that
just to make it a bit better.
But yeah.
But it's good feedback.
It's good to know.
Yeah.
So that's about the Atlas points.
If you do get any more,
and of course,
if you happen to get a collective
from your community in particular as well.
And of course, people are going to post it.
You have my discord as well.
Just tell me,
because I'm very,
very curious about the map drops
and how people feel about now
that it's like way more deterministic
for both sustaining and going up the tiers.
Yeah.
Now, obviously not a huge amount of people
collectively as in the end game,
but like it's enough to start getting stuff.
So yeah.
Yeah.
I'd really, really,
really like to make sure we got that right.
So if any of that comes up,
just give me a yell.
I have one last question about P.E.W. 2.
And then I have a few quick fire questions
about P.E.W. 1.
and then we're done.
How do you feel about the removal of clear speed
things like Herald of Ice,
but then sort of adding it back in
with effectively a few players
were telling me the Lightning Strike
and a Roa effectively just swaps it
from Herald of Ice to the Roa
and the Lightning Strike.
Well, I don't know whether or not
the balance of those is correct,
quite frankly.
It's not quite like,
there's probably misbalance here,
100%,
but it's not quite the same
as what the Heralds were doing.
Yeah.
But it is still a balance anomaly for sure.
Like I certainly have people playing,
I know people who are playing
Lightning Archers right now
and they're like,
why am I suffering like this?
I'm going to swap to Lightning Spear.
Which I assume is what you meant.
Yeah.
Roa 2 made me promise to ask that.
So it's pretty clear.
It is their number one play build right now
is Lightning Spear Amazon
and for good reason, right?
Like it wasn't the intention to be like,
we removed this thing and added this thing.
That isn't intentional
that it ends up playing that strongly
and that powerfully.
And it's like a clear,
like, I mean,
just use it in the whole screen and plugs, right?
But the trouble we have now is,
like, you know,
this is people,
what people are doing now.
Yeah.
And we nerf that.
Like, you know.
No, that's fair.
The answer is usually that we can't very easily.
That's fair.
So, you know.
Yep.
So, a few POE1 questions
and then nothing.
Do we have a rough estimate at all for 326?
I mean, are we telling people?
Have we said anything about that?
I think last we said was
around that territory,
at least towards the later half of May.
You cut out.
Oh, no.
Sorry.
I said nothing.
No!
I was just pretending.
No, towards the end of May
was what we last said
and the intention is still
that that is currently on track.
Obviously, all these things
are kind of like, you know,
up to within a two-week kind of band
because, you know, things happen.
That being said,
if you're not hearing about things
by the end of May,
then I'd be very, very surprised.
You should be, for sure.
Cool.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Any chance of WSC and POE1?
Have you thought more about it?
It's not really a question
of thinking about it.
It's a question of, like,
I mean, I would put it in tomorrow
if we could.
Yeah.
The problem is that the character rigs
are just not set up for it.
And so I will just mention, like,
kind of like the long-term plan here.
So once every microtransaction
from POE1 works in POE2,
at that point,
it will mean that we could then port
the character rigs from POE2
back to POE1
and rig the old character models
and items onto them.
And that would then mean
that we would have access
to the animation library
and everything that we have
in POE2 in POE1,
which would then mean
that we could put WASD in, basically.
Okay.
So what I'm saying is that, like,
in the, like,
but this will take a while, right?
But, like, in the long term,
this can happen.
But, like, it would effectively, like,
like, yeah,
we always sort of imagined
that we would take the POE2
character rigs
and port them back to POE1
once the microtransaction
had all been ported over.
Yeah.
But it requires 100%.
Obviously, we can't turn
a microtransaction off
in POE1 you already bought.
So, like, therefore,
we have to wait
until we've got full compatibility
before we can do that.
Another thing is, like,
we can't incentivize
to make a change.
Yeah, yeah.
And the reason for that is...
That we have to rig everything
to all the stupid
POE1 character models.
We currently have to...
Yeah.
So the moment that we can
finally get rid of those
POE1 character models,
like, character rigs,
that means that it just
reduces our workload
a crap ton.
So, yeah.
And then at that point,
we could add WASD.
We've got a pretty large
rigging department right now,
and they are spending
probably the majority
of their life
all rigging microtransactions
to POE2 characters
right now.
That is what they're doing.
So, I mean,
eventually it will get
to the point
where that is the case.
Cool.
I have the same question,
but with pausing.
So for POE1.
That one,
I think that
they even tried
to do that.
It was almost there.
It was almost there,
and then there was,
like, a couple of things.
So, like,
it is our intention
to get that in.
Awesome.
Another thing
that I really love
in POE2,
the highlight effect.
Like, when I right click
a transmute,
and it shows, like,
what items this works on.
It's really nice
quality of life.
Oh, right.
Well, I've been,
there shouldn't be any reason
we can't do that right.
Should be fine.
I mean,
I don't know why
that would be a problem.
Yeah.
Yeah,
should be fine.
we can probably do that.
100%.
Either we're just not
going to,
or it just won't.
Yeah.
It won't just happen.
Cool.
Final question is,
Valorbs in POE2
can change the magnitude
of unique items.
Is that something
we could ever see
in POE1?
Well,
the amount of work
that it would take,
so here's the thing,
right,
like,
that for every unique,
we, you know,
have manual work to do
to work out
what to do there.
Yeah.
And obviously in POE2,
given that there weren't
all uniques made already,
like, you know,
we were able to do that.
So, like,
I'm not going to say
never in POE1,
but just the amount
of work it would take
to, like,
look at the balance
of every single unique
and do that work
would be quite large.
Most would take
only, like,
two seconds
and would just be fine.
Sure, sure.
But there's, like,
implications for a lot of money.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
There's just a lot
of uniques in POE1,
right?
Like, a lot.
Awesome.
That was,
that was all the questions
I had.
Thank you so much
for taking time to do this.
I know this was super
welcomed by me
and the community.
We really appreciate it.
I know it was a bit
combative today,
but I promise it's
from love for the game.
Well, actually,
so I,
at the beginning,
I obviously got out of bed
on the wrong side
of the bed this morning
because I was feeling
a little bit angus,
probably more than
I should have done,
and I apologize for that
because that was
probably not great.
But, yeah,
I don't know,
for whatever reason,
I just kind of,
yeah,
as I said,
wasn't,
I was just feeling
a bit ugh.
No, I appreciate it.
I actually,
you know,
compared to most,
I think we came out
of this one with,
like,
here's, like,
actually,
like,
15 changes we're
just going to go make,
like,
immediately,
which is awesome.
And some we knew about,
some we didn't,
and some,
and a whole bunch of discussion.
So, like,
I actually,
the value coming out of this,
I feel very,
very good about,
honestly.
And I'm hoping we can get
all those,
a lot of those changes
and I'm hoping it,
obviously,
it'll help,
but, like,
it is,
it is good
because,
I mean,
at the end of the day,
it's just creating
that collaborative environment
between developer
and player base
that,
and using users
as the intermediary,
and I'm sure
a lot of these opinions
and yourself,
you're part of that,
but it is very important
that we keep doing this
because it,
it will create greatness.
Yeah,
no,
I really appreciate
you guys coming here.
I'm actually,
like,
as a rule
from my podcast,
I actually took something
Jonathan said to heart
really,
really hard
that I really liked
and you said that
you really like
when the interviewer,
like,
when it's their questions
and not just on behalf
of others
because they're able
to do better follow-ups
and stuff.
So,
I've tried hard
to focus on that as well,
that it's things
that I am able
to do follow-ups.
So,
but yeah,
thank you guys
so much for your time.
Yeah,
thank you,
and thank you everyone
for watching
and playing.
We appreciate it.
Bye.
Whew.
Try to die
less than I do.
Okay.
I don't know
how I did
because I have not
had chat open,
so I don't know
if you guys
hate me now.
but I can promise you
that I did my best.
That was my best,
at least.
I thought you were
a GDD shill
and I was wrong.
Thank you.
Oh,
thank you.
That means a lot.
I don't know
if you're joking or not,
but I really appreciate that
because I saw,
like,
a lot of questions
at the start
and on Reddit
where people were like,
this entire thing
is, like,
pre-prepared
and Ziz is just
going to ask the questions
he's allowed to,
and I was like,
these are all
my questions,
man.
I made these.
So,
I promise you
I did my very,
very best.
Jesus.
Thank you so much
for all the subs.
I really appreciate it.
I actually collect money.
Oh,
I got some more.
Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
Oh,
thank you.
Thank you.
I really do appreciate it.
I hope you guys think
I did a good job.
That,
I,
I'm not saying
it was the best
anyone could ever do,
but that was my best.
That was,
that was my best.
That was my very best.
Um,
it is hard to do,
like,
follow-ups
and,
and stuff
in the moment,
but I,
uh,
I tried really hard.
You know,
not reading,
chatting,
a podcast is so nice.
I was able to,
like,
really focus on the questions
and,
uh,
try to do follow-ups,
but at least,
hopefully,
a few of the people
that are really negative
on Reddit
or in general
before that,
hopefully,
they're,
uh,
happy with,
how it went
and maybe happy
they were wrong
if they were wrong.
Um,
thank you guys
so much for the horse
with the 50.
Jesus Christ.
No Huntress questions.
Uh,
yes,
I'm fully aware of that.
I haven't played Huntress
and I do agree
with Jonathan.
It is,
makes for a lot
better interview
when the person
interviewing
is fully aware
of the problem.
So,
yeah,
I'm sorry
that I didn't have
more Huntress questions.
I didn't play it
and,
yeah,
I really agree with that.
Um,
and I,
I think it's why,
at least I,
I'm happy with how
I,
I did it.
Um,
but yeah.
It's gonna be
curious reading comments
about,
um,
how I did.
But that was my best.
I even,
like,
prepared beforehand
with having Ventura,
um,
uh,
make me mock questions.
That was a tough one.
Oh.
Was that too combative?
I was a bit worried.
Like,
I,
I wanted to,
like,
make sure that I,
follow up really hard
on everything
and talk about the things
that I did disagree with,
but I was
a bit worried
about being too combative.
Ugh.
Huh.
I'm,
I'm tired.
I just,
I had a lot of things
I really wanted to ask.
Wait,
do you think people
are gonna call me
a shill more
or less after this interview?
She.
Less?
More?
Both?
She.
Oh, no,
I'm,
I'm happy.
Nenevi,
thanks so much
for the 10 gifted.
And the eyes,
thank you so much
for all the subs
and resubs.
I have alerts off
at the moment.
Um,
I really need to pee.
You never pulled out
your dick,
to real.
Stank's just resubscribed
for three months.
Great job.
Thank you.
Thank you,
thank you all.
Thanks so much
for the subs and resubs.
Maybe I should have them off.
Um,
I super appreciate
all the money.
I really,
I collect it,
so thanks.
Um,
right.
I'm gonna put
another music.
I think I did
very well.
I found some cases
I need to play
a bit of hardcore stets
essentially as an option.
Sure,
but like hardcore
is a challenge mode.
I am cognizant
of the fact
that I,
uh,
take that on.
Um,
you did well.
Started a bit too harsh,
but it got diffused
and it was a good interviewer.
Well,
yeah,
Ventura did so well
at pretending to be Jonathan.
That was really useful,
actually.
Okay,
I need to pee.
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna throw some ads
on you guys.
For those that don't know
how I run ads,
I run ads when I go AFK
so that people that
don't have ad blocker
can't afford to sub,
don't get ads.
Well,
they do,
but there's no content
you're missing.
Anyway,
I'll be right back.
Thank you so much
all for tuning in,
by the way.
I hope I,
I hope I made you proud.
Thank you.