Hi, I'm Jonathan Rogers, Game Director on Path of Exile 2.
Welcome to GGG Live.
Well, it's been a little over three months since we launched Early Access,
so it's about time for our first major content update.
Today we're going to show you an exclusive reveal of Path of Exile 2, Dawn of the Hunt,
which launches on April 4th.
Twitch drops are enabled on today's livestream,
so make sure you follow the instructions below
in order to claim your Executioner's Guillotine Finisher effect.
Now in today's stream, we're going to take you on a deep dive into the new Dawn of the Hunt update.
We'll cover a new class, five new Ascendancy classes,
and huge expansions on character systems like unique items and support gems.
After that, it's on to the endgame improvements,
including changes to systems, a bunch of new encounters, and lots of other content.
We're going to finish up today with a live Q&A session
where Ziggy D will ask Path of Exile 2's Game Directors, myself and Mark,
your questions from Twitch chat.
Now we have a lot to cover today, so let's get started with a trailer for Path of Exile 2, Dawn of the Hunt.
We as Mary are guided by the Spirit.
It provides prey, shelter, even love.
But for me, one day, all that were changed.
The Spirit, it showed me something.
Something forbidden.
And to defend all I want, I used it.
I lost everything that day.
But fate won't finish with me yet.
I'll right the wrongs I've done.
I'll do what I must.
No matter the cost.
I will hear the Spirit once more.
you later.
I know that...
... Mutual marksmanship.
Tell us more.
Soon, you'regriffin on if cells may raise.
There are ways of setting Jay in fakears.
Make me feel more.
Fail.
How fast?
A huge choice?
Fail.
Who doesn't come?
For now, we've fixed the ability.
Uh-oh, we're able to allow ourselves消 our cannons.
They didn't want us to help transactions life,
and we'll have obstfloor them emotionalikat'sнем然后 el Reynolds to candy.
Don't make me kill you!
I shall make you your plan.
Now as you can see, in Dawn of the Hunt we're introducing the first new class since early access to Peewee 2, the Huntress.
The Huntress is a spear wielding as merry warrior. Born into a society with strict traditions, she was exiled from her homeland after using the power of a skill gem to defend her village.
As a dexterous spear user, she specializes in both melee and ranged combat, dashing into and out of battle.
Spears have extended range and a short dash, but unlike other melee weapons, you can also throw them.
In order to make a hybrid ranged and melee character work, we have to do a lot of thinking about ways to make it fun to both enter and exit melee range.
The first skill you will get as a Huntress is Whirling Slash.
As well as striking in a circle around you, this skill creates a whirlwind that blinds your enemies.
Leaving the whirlwind will make it explode.
The more Whirling Slash is used, the bigger the whirlwind and the bigger the explosion.
Once you're out of there, you'll want to follow up with something ranged.
Whip your spear around to shoot twisters towards your foes.
These twisters bounce off walls and can hit enemies multiple times.
You can also throw twisters inside a whirlwind to shoot out extra tornadoes that do way more damage.
In her offhand, the Huntress will usually want to hold a Buckler, which allows you to do a new skill, Parry.
While holding down Parry, your character will counterattack any incoming attack from monsters near you, stunning them.
In addition, the monsters will take extra attack damage from your follow up strike.
Some specific skills are designed to be used after a parry and have extra effects.
Disengage is a skill that does a quick jump back, damaging enemies in front of you, and it can be used to interrupt other actions, like Dodgeroll.
If you use it against a parried enemy though, it causes an explosion and gives you a frenzy charge.
Just be careful. If you parry too much, you're going to get stunned and possibly killed.
You can combine this combo with Whirling Slash.
Slash, Parry, Disengage, and you'll get an explosion on the Disengage and the Whirling Slash.
The Huntress also has a variety of elemental spear throw attacks.
You could use Lightning Spear to bounce lightning between your foes.
Or you could throw Explosive Spears into the ground.
These spears take a while to detonate, but when they do, they'll incinerate anyone caught in the blast.
All spear throws on the Huntress can also be empowered by frenzy charges.
For example, Explosive Spears will do an even larger explosion and leave fire on the ground.
And these empowered versions can activate even more combos.
Using Whirling Slash over Ground Fire will suck it into the Whirlwind, adding fire to the explosion.
Using Twisters inside a Fire Whirlwind will shoot out fire tornadoes as well.
And you can do similar combos with Ice and Lightning too.
Now a key aspect of hunting is exhausting your foes by causing blood loss.
This skill is Rake, which dashes towards your target and unleashes a deadly slash, opening up wounds on your enemies.
Follow up with Disengage and watch them bleed out as they run towards you.
On the health bar of monsters you can see how much blood loss the enemy has experienced.
And the Huntress has skills to take advantage of this.
For example, using Blood Hunt will thrust forward and cause a bloody explosion.
The more blood loss, the bigger the explosion.
If you want to cause bigger bleeds, try out Rapid Assault.
The final hit of this multi-hit combo will stick a spear into your enemy for a big bleed.
Now Explosive Spear and Rapid Assault both result in leaving spears behind, either in the ground or in enemies.
But there are other skills that leave spears around too, like Storm Lance,
that leaves an electrical spear that arcs towards enemies.
But what can you do with all these spears?
Dedonate them of course.
Thunder Asleep will allow you to jump onto and explode any spears either in the ground or in your enemies.
Now as well as hunting animals, the Huntress also has the ability to work with them.
While fighting any beast you have the ability to tame it and use it as a companion.
You can only have one companion at a time, but it will keep the mods that were on it.
Try to find a rare beast with good mods to take full advantage of your ability to tame them.
Now this is just the beginning of the Huntress.
We've really tried to make the hybrid ranged and melee gameplay work for this class
by having a huge amount of synergy between ranged and melee options.
There are 22 new skills available for the Huntress.
By endgame you'll be slinging hundreds of insanely powerful spears, sending forth spirit animals and summoning the might of Solaris from the sky.
But we still haven't talked about Ascendancy classes yet.
What can the Huntress ascend into?
Well, the first Ascension class you could choose is the Ritualist.
The Ritualist has embraced the darker side of his merry traditions by harnessing the power of animal sacrifice and plague.
The Corrupted Lifeforce skill causes all enemies around you to grow volatile blood boils on their skin.
When those enemies are slain the boils will burst, spreading corrupted blood to all enemies around them.
The Ritualist also excels in taking advantage of magical trinkets.
The Unfurled Finger skill allows you to equip an additional ring on a finger around your neck.
Taking Mystic Attunement increases the bonuses of all the rings and amulets you have equipped.
Now this is one of my favourites.
As the Whispers Ask grants you a new skill, Ritual Sacrifice.
Use the skill on the corpses of slain rare monsters to absorb the power in their blood to give you one of their modifiers for a short time.
Specialise further into Ritualistic Sacrifice with As the Whispers Demand.
Which allows you to perform that skill on yourself instead of a corpse.
Cut your own hand, sacrificing some of your own blood to empower yourself.
The Amazon Ascension is for those looking to hunt more than just beasts.
Trained as an elite guard to the most important as merry elders,
the Amazon will use more traditional fighting techniques mastered to perfection.
The Predatory Instinct skill will cause you to reveal weaknesses in the defences of rare and unique enemies, causing you to deal more damage.
You can see those weak spots represented on their life bars.
While using Elemental Infusion, any charges you consume will infuse your weapon with elemental power, causing any projectile attacks to explode on impact.
The Critical Strike skill is as simple as it sounds.
It takes your excess accuracy and gives it to you as critical strike chance.
Additionally, you have skills like Mystic Harvest, which allows your elemental damage to leech life.
And as Merry Brew, to be able to use either flask to restore both life and mana.
So those are the two new ascendancies for the Huntress.
But those are not the only ascendancies in Dawn of the Hunt.
We've added a new Ascension class for three of the other, existing classes too.
First up for our warriors out there, we have the Smith of Catawba.
The warrior is a blacksmith in origin, taught by his father, Renly.
With this ascension, you can take your smithing skills to new heights by embracing power from the insatiable one himself, Kitawa.
Smiths of Catawba are master blacksmiths and have the ability to forge their weapon, quite literally.
Using the Against the Anvil notable skill, you can enhance your weapon with fiery destruction before any battle.
After doing so, your attacks will release explosions on hit for maximum devastation.
You can also use the power of Kitawa to summon an animated copy of your weapon to fight alongside you.
A great blacksmith can do more than just forging their weapon though.
Their armour can be enhanced too.
Now you might think this ascendancy class tree looks a little… abnormal.
And you're right.
There's a lot of notable skills all disconnected at the bottom there.
By taking this point here, which is free to assign, your character is unable to equip body armours with mods of any kind.
So your body armour must be normal.
Sounds like a downside, right?
Except now in true blacksmith fashion, you get to craft your own body armour by taking those disconnected notables with your points.
If you want your body armour to grant life, take this notable.
If you want resistances, take this one.
There are so many choices.
Think of it like you're crafting your own body armour, just in a more literal sense.
Now, let's move on to those who prefer the reassuring feel of a crossbow in their hands, the Mercenary.
Alongside the existing ascension classes, the Gemling Legionnaire and the Witch Hunter, you can now play as the Tactician.
The Tactician is a former Blackguard elite.
Free from the duties of a Blackguard, he is able to use his training to decimate the monsters of Wraeclast and earn a healthy income doing so.
This training comes in the form of various skills, like Suppressing Fire, which causes all projectiles to pin enemies.
When combined with the Right Where We Want Them notable, your pin not only stops your enemies from moving, but stops them from performing actions too, similar to Freeze.
With a soldier's training, the Tactician also works well cooperatively.
Using the Whoever Pays Best notable, you can place multiple banners at once.
The Watch How We Do It skill gives a portion of your weapons damage to your allies as well.
But if that isn't enough, you can also command your army of off-screen archers to unleash hell and carpet an entire area with Arabs.
Finally, Witch players will be able to join their legions by becoming undead themselves.
In Dawn of the Hunt, we're introducing the Lich Ascension class.
The Lich is a master of chaos and curses and could sacrifice her life to enhance her energy shield.
The Crystalline Phylactery skill allows you to nominate a jewel in which to contain part of your soul, massively increasing its power.
There's just one downside to splitting your soul this way though.
If you have no energy shield, your mana costs will shoot up.
The Necromantic Conduit skill causes you and allies in your presence to have unholy might, granting extra damage as chaos damage.
Rupture the Soul makes enemies you curse explode with chaos damage when slain.
Rupture the Soul makes a curse.
Dominion over Flesh allows you to apply an additional curse.
It's safe to say you'll be the true master of the Occult by choosing the Lich class.
So Dawn of the Hunt has the Huntress and five new Ascension classes, but it doesn't end there.
Let's take a look at some of the new skills we've added.
Now you may remember what previously talked about the Raise Spectre skill.
It's finally complete and will be made available in the upcoming expansion.
It can be found in the Occult skills on the Skill Gem Crafting panel.
Raise Spectre is a skill that allows you to trap the soul of almost any monster in the game,
which you can then summon in the Skill Panel.
Spectres cost Spirit and will revive automatically if they die, but the Spirit cost varies based on the power of the monster.
You could summon an army of weaker monsters, or a few of the more powerful monsters.
You can combine them with their existing skeleton minions, or summon exclusively Spectres.
It's all up to you and how you want to customise your army of the undead.
Given that there are hundreds upon hundreds of monster variants in Path of Exile 2,
it's safe to say you'll be experimenting with this one for a while.
We look forward to seeing which monsters serve you best.
Now let's move on to our next skill.
Since we've been talking about summoning undead so much,
let's have a change of pace and summon something a little more alive.
In Dawn of the Hunt we're adding the Summon Rower skill.
Summon your friendly rower to aid you in combat as a minion.
You can also mount your rower in combat at any time,
allowing you to move at full speed even while shooting arrows or throwing spears.
Be wary though, if you take too much damage while riding your mount,
you can be knocked off and get overwhelmed.
It's worth keeping an eye on your stagger bar,
as falling off the mount can mean almost certain death.
On the topic of new ways to enhance your character, let's talk about support gems.
Support gems are used to modify your skill gems in meaningful and interesting ways.
Currently we feel that a lot of builds have insufficient options here.
To alleviate this, we're adding over 100 new support gems.
Hema Crystals will enable a new kind of bleed build,
turning the damage over time you would have done into explosive vile crystals.
Alignment is a support gem for bow attacks, which can reward skilled players with good positional skills.
Cal-trops will allow you to litter the battlefield with hazards,
slowing your foes as you fling spears through their ranks.
But there's plenty more for every playstyle, such as...
Enormity.
Unsteady tempo.
Profanity.
Retaliate.
Syzygy.
Profanity
Retaliate
Syzygy
Yep, that's a real word
And many more
Now we've talked about a new class
New ascendancy classes
New skills
And new support gems
But let's not forget about the core of a true action RPG
The items
To start with, let's talk about uniques
We're adding over 100 new unique items
This time we've made sure to add uniques
With a focus on mid and endgame tiers
To make sure there are more exciting items to find
For higher level characters
Let's look at some examples
Embrace your inner devil with Chernobog's pillar
It grants you a large amount of fire damage
Based on your block chance
The coming calamity allows you to become a true master of the elements
Granting you all three elemental herald skills
Without costing any spirit
At the same time it penalises enemy resistances
Wastegate is a belt useful for builds
Using a single resource like blood magic
Or archmage builds
With this belt you can use two life flasks
Or two mana flasks
It's up to you
Now we could go through these all day
But we'll leave most of them for you to discover
Suffice to say though
We want there to be way more cool things to find
Over time our goal is to add a unique to every single base item type at a minimum
So that you can chance any base in the game
Now, given that we have the Huntress
We have a set of unique spears from early game all the way through the end game as well
One example is Scyther's Spear
Which combines bleed and fire in a powerful way
It allows your ignites to be aggravated dealing substantially more damage
We're also introducing a suite of unique bucklers
With some interesting parry mechanics
Calgyra's Arc for example
Allows you to parry projectiles from any distance
And we're also adding our first unique charms
Bayra's Anguish will not only protect you from ignite
We'll also emit a devastating fire nova whenever you do get ignited
In sum, there's just a ton of new uniques to find
We can't wait to see the weird and broken builds that come out of it
Now we also want to talk about crafting options
And each major update during early access
Will be continuing to add and improve the options here
We have various new crafting tools that have been added as rewards
To many of the different types of new content that we're adding
But for now, I just want to mention the changes to runes
Runes add commonly available mods
But since they only have one tier
Flat damage mods tend to get outclassed by endgame
So we've changed runes to have multiple tiers
Allowing you to get higher tier mods than before
Our plan is to significantly expand the number of more specialised mods
For crafting using socketables as we add new content over time
And the first new set of those comes from what we're talking about next
In Dawn of the Hunt we're adding Asmerian Wisps
Which can be found throughout both the campaign and the endgame
The Asmeri spirit has made itself present in Wraeclast
And it appears to be trying to warn or maybe prepare us for the coming darkness
You will first encounter a manifestation of it in the Grellwood in Act 1
Where you'll meet Delwyn and Asmeri Hunter who is trying to find out what exactly is causing the spirit to behave this way
As you approach the wisp it will flee leading you past monsters
Any monsters it comes into contact with are infused by it making them more powerful
Each spirit is associated with a specific revered animal within Asmeri culture
This one is a wisp of the great bear and grants enemies extra life and stun
The wisp moves faster the closer you are and as you move away they slow down to wait for you
But if you get too far away for too long they'll dissipate and return to the woods
As you continue to chase the wisp it will find and possess a rare or unique monster
Granting it a new powerful ability
Because this was a wisp of the great bear this monster now also has increased life and stun
But on top of that it will periodically summon a large spectral bear that slams with wild fury
If you are able to defeat this foe you will be rewarded
For each monster that was infused and killed along the way the rewards will be increased
Each wisp has its own mechanics
The wisp of the winter owl is a primal wisp that causes enemies to deal extra cold damage
Gain energy shield and release wind vortices on death
When infusing a monster they will call down large tornadoes to protect their host
The wisp of the wild cat is a vivid wisp that causes affected monsters to deal more critical strikes
And become more evasive
When it infuses a monster it will summon a barrage of feline spirits that will attempt to tear you limb from limb
If you're lucky you may even find sacred wisps that can do some pretty crazy things to the monsters they influence
Like the wisp of the cunning fox which turns normal monsters into magics
Magic monsters into rares
And rare monsters into actual bosses
Asmerian wisps can drop a new set of socketable items that allow you to craft a wide range of interesting new mods onto your items
Each one may only be used on a specific item slot
As mentioned the Asmerian wisps can be encountered throughout the game
But there's also a new endgame map called the Asmeri Rangers
A mountain village where the Asmeri once lived now overrun with corrupt monsters
This map always has multiple Asmerian wisps in it and familiar yet not quite the same boss fight
Asmerian wisps can also be further modified by the endgame atlas tree as well
And by tablets
But I'm not going to be the one talking about those things
In order to cover all the new content in endgame I'm going to hand things over to Mark
Hi, I'm Mark Roberts, Game Director on Path of Exile 2
There's a ton to talk about with the endgame today
So let's dig right in
Path of Exile 2's early access began with a brand new endgame
And it was clear that it needed a lot of work
After absorbing your feedback
We're ready to make some epic changes
The first thing is
We just need a lot more content
In Dawn of the Hunt
We have made sure to focus on increasing the sheer number of interesting
And different encounters you will randomly stumble into
As you explore the endgame
And the second goal is to smoothen the progression through maps
And reduce the amount of annoying busywork
To start with
Let's talk about the new interesting stuff to find
Well, the most obvious thing to add are new maps
As well as the Asmeri ranges that Jonathan mentioned earlier
Dawn of the Hunt also contains seven other new maps
All with their own custom encounters
Let's start with this one
The Feral Megalith's map
Starts off in the wild Azamite forests
As you progress through the forest
You will find mysterious rune carved stones
That when touched surge with energy
After activating all the stones
You can find a Grand Henge
Where all the energy is coalescing
You can then start an encounter
The area darkens
A storm moves in
And a concentration of energy summons a dangerous boss
You must fight and defeat the boss to get its rewards
Once you have defeated it
Summon another
And another
You have ten total waves of boss fights
Which get incrementally more difficult
If you manage to defeat them
You get full boss rewards
But also opportunities to get new runes
These can only be obtained from this map
The Fractured Lake contains a surreal waterscape
With fractured mirror-like objects
As you move around the map
The terrain itself elevates from below
Creating the ground you walk on
In this unique map
All the rare monsters are mirrored
So you're always fighting two of the same rare
At the same time
Which can prove quite difficult
If you manage to overcome that challenge
And make it to the end of the map
You'll be presented with a broken mirror
A powerful altar-like object
That contains an item within it
The item contained within is a new base type
Either an amulet or a ring
That can be crafted to have additional prefixes
Or suffixes at the cost of the other
The last unique map we'll show today
Is one based around the essence mechanic
You enter a crystalline cavern
And you will find a powerful map boss
Imprisoned in the centre
It is surrounded by many rare monsters
Also imprisoned in essences
By freeing and defeating the rare monsters
The essence they held will be upgraded
To a greater essence
And be added to the imprisoned map boss
How brave are you?
How many essences will you add to the boss?
Overdo it and you might lose everything
Underdo it and you might regret it
It's your choice
Speaking of essences
Alongside visual improvements
You're now able to apply varlorbs
To corrupt the essences
With a range of unpredictable outcomes
It could increase the number of essences
Reroll all the essences to the same type
Or even upgrade the essences to greater essences
What if they're already greater essences?
Well, it can upgrade those too
We have four new corrupted essences
Essences of hysteria, delirium, horror and insanity
Each corrupted essence has its own interesting combat mechanics
For example, the essence of insanity causes you to question even your own mind
As monsters split into shadowy clones
And you must locate the real one
Before a devastating icy explosion freezes everything around it
Each of these has their own crafting outcomes
The essence of insanity can be applied to a belt
It adds a mod that will ensure the next varlorb used on the belt
Will guarantee adding two enchantments
It's worth noting all the essences in the unique map can also be corrupted too
If you're willing to risk it
It's worth noting we have also added ten extra atlas passive points
You can earn by completing five different unique maps
Now, new maps are just the beginning
We had a goal where we wanted to make sure
You were constantly finding exciting new content
And that it could be lurking around any corner
So, we have added a bunch of new things that you could stumble into
In any map you run
On your travels you will sometimes encounter rogue exiles
Others like you who have been exiled and are openly hostile
Some are malicious, some are mad
While others are simply fiends for loot
They will challenge you, a fight to the death
They use the same skills available to players
And even the same items
They aren't just dressed up in those items
They're actually using them
It's going to feel like a true player versus player situation
Of course, if you are able to slay these exiles
Those items will all drop on the ground
So, if you encounter an exile using a powerful or valuable unique item
Which you can see displayed under their life bar
You want to be damn sure you kill them
Because if they kill you and your party
They'll portal out taking their items with them
Every fight will feel completely different
Depending on the items they come equipped with
These exiles are much smarter than your regular monster
They have capabilities to dodge roll
Avoid your abilities with smart pathfinding
Smart targeting
And much more action-packed gameplay
Fortunately, they're like you
And they're not super durable
Unless, of course, they're wearing uniques like Kalm's Heart
In which case, expect a longer battle
There are 12 different rogue exiles you can find
Each with their own skills and personalities
Some may insult you
While others may admire your honour in combat
Another encounter you might stumble onto
In Dawn of the Hunt
Are one of four new unique strongboxes
Strongboxes are chests with modifiers
When you try to open them
They activate traps
And spawn waves of monsters that you must defeat
To access the loot
Let's take a look at two of the new unique boxes
That are harder to find
And behave just a little bit differently
The Ogam's Legacy strongbox has a corpse splayed out
In front of the rune-carved stone
Upon interacting with the stone
You activate Forbidden Ezimite Magic
Which revives the monster as a powerful red
The strongbox comes with a modifier
Which determines how many times it will revive that red
Each time you defeat the monstrosity
The strongbox revives it again
Adding an extra modifier to the monster
With each resurrection
It becomes more difficult
But also more rewarding
This strongbox is infused with Thaumaturgy
From ancient Fale technology
E-Shell's Torment has a powerful artifact inside
And is guarded by Chaos itself
Defeating the monsters will grant you a unique item
With a specific corrupted outcome
You'll have to find the other two for yourself
To see what they do
Now, let's talk about the introduction to the endgame
Upon starting the endgame
Doriani tasks you with cleansing corruption
To help restore the land
However, in practice
The quest objective just sent you on a grind
To clear 15 maps
We wanted to make the quest to unlock your atlas passives
Much more interesting
Now, Doriani is tasking you with a more specific objective
On the atlas you will find areas of corruption caused by the beast
In the centre of each one you will find a corrupted nexus
The source of the affliction
In the areas leading up to the nexus
You will notice that corruption spills out from slain enemies
And amalgamates into powerful monsters
Corrupted maps existed on the atlas before
But we've done significant work on improving these monsters
We've also done a full pass on the modifiers on these maps
To make them more interesting and more rewarding
Once you reach the nexus you will have a new task
Cleanse the source of corruption
When you defeat the last rare in those maps
They will spawn one of three terrifying bosses
Amalgamations of corruption itself
After defeating that boss
Doriani will come and cleanse the corruption for good
As the remains of the boss are purged of corruption
It coalesces into raw crystallized power
Which you can use to gain points for your atlas passive skill tree
The upgrade system that allows you to add and enhance content in your maps
We didn't stop there though
When you complete a corrupted nexus
All of the remaining surrounding corrupted maps will become cleansed maps
Cleansed maps also have new monsters
A new boss
And their own set of modifiers and rewards
Including finding fracturing orbs by slaying cleansed enemies
These orbs can be used in crafting on a rare item
To cause one of its modifiers to become fractured
A fractured modifier is one that cannot be modified by any means
You are able to freely modify the item
Ensuring the fractured modifier will never change
If you get the right item
With the right mod
It can prove to be a very powerful crafting base indeed
You must now choose
Do you complete all the corrupted maps and then the nexus?
Or maybe you beeline to the nexus
Complete it
And do all the remaining maps cleansed
Both have rewards to entice you
And challenges to assess
Now
Let's have a talk about towers
One thing we've had a lot of feedback on
Is the busy work around running towers
And managing your tablets
The first change we've made here
Is that we have reduced the number of towers drastically
So there are now one third as many as before
But we've made them much more powerful
To start with
Tablets now inherently add twice as many mechanics
But that's not all
Running higher tier maps and towers
Now increases the number of mechanics applied by tablets
By tier 15 the bonus is double
Allowing a single tablet to now add four times as many mechanics as before
So
We're running far fewer towers
Dealing with fewer tablets
And affecting even more maps than before
But
Because there were fewer towers overlapping with each other
You won't get as many opportunities to stack different tablets
In order to solve this
We've made it so that each tower can consume up to three tablets at once
You always get one slot on completing the tower
But if you can complete a tower with more mods on the waystone
You can unlock a second or third slot
Overall
This allows for even more juicing from towers
While drastically reducing the amount of busy work you have to do
On top of that
Towers are much more interesting maps
Because they can now spawn with all mechanics
Including bosses
Each tower map has a new boss
Let's take a look at a couple here
The boss fight of the Alpine Ridge map
Has two powerful witches contesting for territory
One witch has an affinity for ice
The other fire
Who will win?
Hopefully neither
The boss of the sinking spire map
Is a remnant of the Vaal
That has been charged with lightning
It uses a full suite of lightning abilities
But be careful
If any of them hit the surrounding constructs
They will power up
Another thing that we've seen a lot of feedback about
Is sustaining waystones
As we looked into it
We realized that the people who couldn't sustain waystones
Were dying a lot
A lot more than we had expected
And that made us realize something
During the campaign
The expectation is that you can die multiple times
In order to learn how to overcome challenges
You are able to learn how the monsters behave
Adapt to their skills
And eventually overcome them
But as soon as you get to the endgame
You are effectively no longer allowed to die
If you want to sustain waystones
By the time you are getting towards the end of endgame
We want you to have to be careful not to die
But it certainly shouldn't be that we have such a sudden shift
As you run your first maps
The first change we're making is you can now respawn
And return to a map if you die
Continuing from where you left off
When you start the endgame
You get up to six total attempts per map
As you add more modifiers to a waystone
The number of respawns goes down
This means that as you get to the point that you are running every waystone as a re—
You will have to be more careful
In parties, everyone gets to respawn that number of times.
But we still think it's important that you can kill a boss in one go.
In order to allow that to happen, we've made a change so that once you start the boss fight,
it changes over to the same respawning system we use for Pinnacle bosses.
This means that the map owner can choose to respawn everyone at the same time.
Another complaint we've seen a lot of is players not wanting to do the Pinnacle content
because of the experience penalty from dying.
A change we've made here is that all Pinnacle content now no longer grants experience,
but also no longer removes experience on death either.
Dawn of the Hunt also brings the first batch of Twilight Order Reliquary keys
from the Early Access Supporter Packs.
These keys contain items selected by our supporters.
They can contain any unique item found in Path of Exile too.
If the selected item is a Pinnacle boss drop, then only special keys dropped by this content
will be able to provide these items.
For example, Hand of Wisdom in Action can only come from a key dropped by Zest.
We're also making a change that allows Pinnacle boss uniques to drop at any difficulty.
Rarer uniques will be rarer at lower difficulties, but still possible to find.
This applies to the drop charges for the Reliquary keys from this content as well.
We spoke about towers and tablets earlier, but we have also added a suite of unique tablets.
Each of these adds crazy interactions to the maps influenced by it.
For example, this unique tablet allows you to run any map in a tower's radius without requiring connections,
which can be quite useful for jumping gaps and traveling around your atlas.
And this tablet causes all runic monsters spawned during expedition encounters to be duplicated,
and weakens all expedition monsters that emerge from the ground.
The Atlas tree has also been expanded, and you can find many of the new mechanics there.
And improvements to existing ones too.
Now through this livestream we have mentioned quite a few new crafting options that we've added.
New runes, corrupted essences, fractured mods, and jewelry crafting bases.
But we did have just one more crafting system to talk about. Recombination.
Expedition was the only in-game mechanic that was lacking a crafting system, so that needed to change.
Recombination is a mechanic that might be familiar to some players.
It allows you to merge two items together, hoping to get the best elements of each on a single new item.
This new crafting bench will be unlocked as you complete your first expedition,
and requires artifacts found during expeditions to fuel it.
The rarer the mods on the item you are combining, the more expensive the cost.
That wraps up all the major end-game changes we're talking about today.
With all the system changes and new content, we can't wait to get in there, start blasting maps, and obliterating monsters.
There is one more thing we wanted to clarify before we move on, which is that all the content we've talked about today
will be made available in the existing Early Access Leagues, so you can play your existing characters.
However, there will be new leagues made for those who wish to start in a fresh economy.
It is recommended to start over and get the full new experience in the Dawn of the Hunt Leagues.
For all our existing Early Access players, we're really looking forward to joining you playing in this new update.
For those who don't already have access, and are interested in playing Path of Exile 2 Dawn of the Hunt,
you are able to at any time purchase an Early Access Supporter Pack at www.pathofexile2.com.
Additionally, the Paladin and Penance Supporter Packs are now available to purchase in Path of Exile 2,
and contain 6 microtransactions each, and the full pack's face value in points.
All the microtransactions contained within these packs are purely cosmetic,
and do not affect your character's power or progression in any way.
Thank you so much for your ongoing support.
We're just about to start the Q&A with ZiggyD.
With release at the end of next week, our community team will be posting crucial information you'll need for the release.
Keep an eye on the news.
On release weekend, we expect to launch the new Mystery Box and many new microtransactions,
including Path of Exile 2's first alternate skill effects.
Thanks for joining us today and checking out our latest developments.
We're looking forward to playing the Huntress, trying new builds, and exploring the new endgame next week.
We'll begin the Q&A shortly, so please get your questions ready.
Good morning, Exiles, and welcome to the Q&A portion of today, after a very exciting reveal, with lots of new people,
and the folks are going to be talking about the future.
Great.
Good morning, Exiles, and welcome to the Q&A portion of today.
Good morning, exiles, and welcome to the Q&A portion of today after a very exciting reveal
with lots and lots in it, exceeding my expectations, particularly in crafting.
But on that note, we're joined here by Jonathan and Mark to talk about all that we've seen today
and more in the future of Path of Exile 2.
And you had an update about the recombination.
Yes, that's right, that's right.
Yeah, so we actually last night had a bit of a design session
and realized that we weren't actually fully happy with the way the recombination worked.
So we actually made quite a big change to it, which wasn't reflected in that video, obviously,
which is basically that we sort of wanted to give a bit more control to the player
over how recombination works.
And we also kind of weren't really happy about the fact that recombination is something
that kind of matters a lot for really, really ultra-endgame players,
but it wasn't something that was really mattering a lot for people who effectively got access
to the feature at the start.
So we've actually changed it now so that the way it works is that you pick which mods you want
on each item, from each item.
And then it gives you a percentage chance of success based on the number you picked.
So if you pick just like one from one and one from the other,
then the chance is much, much higher.
But if you pick six mods, it'll become practically impossible.
So effectively, you know, like the more you're wanting to design the item,
the less of a chance of actually having success.
So it means that if you just want to get like a mod, if you want to get an item with like,
okay, these two mods that I've found off the ground, that's, you know, relatively easy.
If you want to get an item which has, you know, all of them then are very hard.
So we think that's a much better design because it means you can kind of use the,
the recombinators actually become something that you can use even from a relatively,
from the first point you get them.
But there's still this kind of endgame, like, you know, like for perfect, perfect stuff,
you might still be able to do it with more.
It is kind of balanced though, so that like, like if you pick literally all six,
then it's going to be like incredibly low to the point of like, don't even try that.
But, you know, like four mods might be a good thing to sort of be striving for,
that kind of thing, and then exalt the other two, that kind of stuff.
So yeah, that's kind of the new design of that.
So hopefully that'll be in by the time Zero Two comes out.
We're going to, we've kind of got a plan for doing that.
But yeah, like I think it's a much better design than what we had before for recombinators.
If it's not there for Zero Two, it'll be as soon as it can afterwards.
But yeah, you know, spur of the moment, night before the live stream design sessions.
But increased player agency and visibility into the success result is just a win.
And honestly, took way too long to, you know, get to the point of us actually going,
this is just straight up better to have observability into that and the freedom of choice.
Sure, sure.
Yeah, that's the thing.
Recombination definitely felt like something that was both really high end in terms of the crafting that it was intended for,
but also just even understanding it.
This seems much more intuitive.
Yes.
You just pick what you want.
Selecting the mods you want.
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
So it does sound like it's a little bit of a nerf for the very high end of crafting though.
It might end up being, but I'm not like, it sort of depends on how the numbers come out.
Like because we only just designed this, we need to still work out like exactly how the numbers end up looking.
But I mean, look, we have to make sure, obviously whenever we're designing any crafting system,
we have to be really sure that we're not like screwing over finding stuff on the ground.
So, you know, you have to, you have to sort of have that balance.
And that's, you know, so that kind of informs everything we do with crafting usually.
One difference here though, of course, is if the success chance fails, both items are destroyed as opposed to always keeping one.
Yeah, yeah.
So, okay.
So it's basically a percent chance for success.
And if it fails, item's gone.
So, yeah.
Roughly, what do you think you'd try to pitch just choosing two mods at?
It depends on what mods you're selecting.
But I'm kind of thinking kind of like 35%-ish kind of thing for like two normal mods, that kind of thing.
For both to go over?
Yeah, for them both.
If you pick two.
Yeah.
And then, you know, but we'll see.
It kind of depends.
We'll see how the way to do some math.
Higher team mods are rarer.
Yeah, exactly.
So it's sort of an exception.
And also, the other thing is it's going to now have a fixed cost.
So it's not going to, you know.
And the idea is like doing a single expedition should be enough to do a recombination.
So, you know, you're going to be doing them like relatively often as you're doing expeditions.
So is the part of expedition where you get to craft with the NPCs still a thing then?
Now that you're adding this?
Yeah, I mean, you've still got that whole mechanic.
So effectively, it's competing for the artifacts.
Yeah.
Between recombination versus buying things from that other way.
So is there some buffs intended for that then to make it more competitive?
Not yet.
It definitely needs some love in the future, but not at this time.
Yeah.
It seems like the systems can kind of go hand in hand where one is giving you items that you can then potentially recombinate.
That is also true.
You can use the ingredients of one in the other.
Yeah.
Or the outcome of one as an ingredient in another.
Cool.
We'll talk more about crafting a little bit later on for sure because there was a lot announced there, which I'm quite excited about.
Definitely exceeded my predictions for what you'd be adding in terms of crafting.
But firstly, though, just a quick clarification on the league.
So there's not going to be a wipe for the new players joining us.
If you were playing on a character, you can still keep playing on a character.
But a lot of long-term Path of Exile players know the importance of playing on a fresh start.
And it's also really important for you guys as well.
For sure.
Yeah.
I mean, basically, if we don't have any character that's come from before, you're just not going to – because the balance is so different and because so many things have changed, there's no point in even listening to feedback for someone who's playing in the old league.
It really has to be that you're doing the fresh start and we're sort of seeing how things go in the new economy.
So we were really sort of – it was kind of an interesting decision about whether or not we should make it so that all the content is exclusive.
Or rather, what amount of content would be exclusive to the league versus not.
And the issue that we had was that – so, I mean, a league means something in Path of Exile.
In order for something to be – to rise to the level of a league, it needs a certain amount of features.
And the original thing we were thinking about doing that way would be the Asmere and Wisps.
But there wasn't quite, like, the kind of, like, meta mechanics and, you know, stuff with that.
So, like, we didn't quite rise to the level of feeling like it deserved to be a challenge league.
And at the same time, we've also got a lot of new players playing Path of Exile too.
Never played Path of Exile before.
So we were a little bit – like, we kind of were deciding, like, should we – yeah, should we make them exclusive or not?
We sort of decided, you know what?
For this one, we're not going to.
And then what we'll probably try and do is for the next – for the next league that we do, we'll actually make it a proper challenge league with, like, its own exclusive mechanic and so on.
But, yeah, it's a little bit funny because, like, in early access, there's a bit of a different situation.
You know, like – and so, yeah, we'll sort of see how this goes anyway.
But certainly I would encourage everyone just, like, start again on a new character.
And I think, you know, you'll have a much better time because, you know, obviously if you're – there's structural changes to the passive tree.
It's like if you log in with your character, you're going to have, like – you know, your tree's going to get reset.
You have to do stuff.
You know, like, there's things like that that are going to happen that mean that – and, you know, also just balance changes, right?
Like, huge numbers of them.
So you're going to have a better time playing from the start.
That's it.
And speaking of the Huntress then, so we saw our initial Huntress quite some time ago now and had some hands-on time with it and things.
But I certainly, having played that before and played it now recently, the Huntress has changed quite a lot.
Yeah, yeah.
So what was the – how hard was it to get it ready for release?
What was kind of the key there?
I mean, it's funny because class design is one of those things where every time you add something, it can make you re-evaluate everything else,
which is why it's so hard to predict, like, how long a class will take.
So, like, it changed a lot since the last time we had – like, we were showing Huntress.
And honestly, like, you know, it's – like, while there are some skills that you will still see, like, it just plays completely different.
And, I mean, whenever we're looking at, like, how we're going to design something like this, it really comes down to, like, what is – it's special about the character class.
Like, how can we double down on that to make sure it feels different?
So with the Huntress, you've obviously got Spears as a base type.
Like, the key difference between a Spear and any other weapon type is that you can both use them at melee and you can also use them at range.
You can throw them.
And so because of that, you know, we really were just really trying to incentivize everything possible so that you use both of those things.
And, you know, Action RPG players, they – you know, generally speaking, you know, the balance can often be such that you only really want to do one thing and do that one thing well.
So trying to incentivize the kind of ranged and melee is, you know, quite a thing.
And, I mean, the way we do it effectively is try to make sure that, like, there are combo chains where, you know, a ranged thing can combo with something that's melee and a melee thing can combo with something that's ranged.
And then also give you good abilities to move between the two states.
And so that kind of means that you end up with a very, like, agile character.
Like, you're constantly moving, like, backwards and forwards and kind of moving around.
And I would say that, like, given that it's the dex character, that it's good that it feels that way, that it feels the most agile of all of the melee character classes.
So, you know, that's been a really good one.
But, you know, I mean, look, there are – in terms of changes, I mean, look, there are just changes all the time.
Like, the frenzy charge thing was, like, relatively late in development.
Like, there's, like, quite a lot of things going on that just meant that, you know, the feel kept on evolving.
And another big one, of course, was parry, which I honestly was very skeptical of working.
And Mark, like, Mark was the one who saved it, honestly.
Like, I was like, you know what?
There was, like, three times, I think, where I was like, you know what?
I don't think it's going to work.
And then you were like, okay, I think, you know, we're going to save this.
I was like, give me a week.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
And it works completely differently than most games.
Because in most games, obviously, with parrying, the way that works is that, you know, you have to time the – like, to push the block button at exactly the right time.
But that's just something that just wouldn't work in our combat system because, you know, you're often in packs of monsters.
It's just like you don't really have the ability to read combat in that way in our game.
And at the same time, we need to make something where there's going to be, like, you know, if a single monster in a pack hits you, you need to be able to respond to that with something that's going to –
you know, you need to be able to respond in a way where you don't just then immediately get hit by a bunch of other stuff.
Yes.
So having it so that the parry – like, it always parries, but it's then taking advantage of what the parry does to the monster by following up with something that's going to give you, like, you know, an explosion or something like that to kind of deal with the pack.
That's something that sort of allows that counter gameplay to work in our game.
So you've kind of got two primary parry follow-ups.
You've got the frenzy charge one, which dashes back, which means that, you know, you don't have to worry about the monsters hitting you.
And then you've also got the one that – there's another one, which I don't believe we showed there, which, you know, called Fangs of Frost, which does a counter where you attack with ice, which freezes the pack.
So it's another way to kind of – so in both cases, you've kind of got something that's kind of dealing with the fact that you've got all these monsters around you.
And that was kind of the biggest challenge, I think, that we had with that kind of – yeah.
Yeah, I'll also make note of there was a support gem I found that you can attach to any attack that allows you to follow up parry to generate a frenzy charge too.
So it doesn't even have to be the backflip.
Yeah, yeah, in that case.
Yeah, I mean, there's other –
Create your own parry follow-ups.
And then, of course, there's always Sniper's Mark, you know, and there's, like – there is a skill that does give you a guaranteed crit, so that's a potential option as well.
Like, you've got a few different ways to generate them.
Because parry guarantees a light stun.
Yeah.
You always get that small window to actually engage or do a thing before they – before you're under danger again.
And I'll tell you this, like, I am one of those players who never parry, right, in any game ever because I can never do it.
It's always just so frustrating.
So I was very skeptical of that.
But it feels really good.
You've both managed to make it something that's easy to do because you can just hold the button down and parry at any time.
There's no skill involved in that.
But at the same time, you've incentivized making it so that you do want to still try and time it as best you can personally by – well, how have you done that?
How have you made it so that, like, you actually still want to kind of play it skillfully?
Well, I mean, ultimately, you know, any time you're holding down the parry button is when you're not attacking, right?
So you still want to kind of minimize the window.
But at the same time, like, the timing is just not, like, you know, not as bad.
But the nice thing as well is that, like, once you do successfully parry, it's very obvious.
You get the sound.
You get, like, the token on the monster.
It's very chunky.
So, you know, it means it's very obvious when you're supposed to counterattack.
So, yeah, I'm very happy with that.
I think that it came out really well.
And honestly, one of the funny things about it is that it immediately made me realize, like, how bad shields are in comparison,
which is why we're also trying to ninja in a change to how shields work at the last minute,
which we'll see if it makes it into 020.
I was playing around with it last night.
Yeah, this was 8 p.m. last night.
Yeah, 8 p.m. last night, exactly.
Messing with this.
Yeah, messing around with it.
And so, you know, I won't talk too much about how that's going to work.
But effectively, we want to make the shields better as well and kind of build something into those to make them more interesting.
So, yeah, that's the plan there.
We'll see if it makes it for 020.
Yeah, following that kind of similar design space idea of being able to do a bit more with it.
Yeah.
And then that feed into other skills and things like that as well.
There's a lot of room there to play with.
Yeah.
So we talked about Huntress being very combo heavy, and she has the deepest combo chains out of anyone so far,
even exceeding, like, things you can do with Monk.
You've got three, four different skills deep of things you can start to synergize together.
So how do you balance, how do you make that fun, firstly, like, rather than, like, onerous, for example?
Well, I mean, you just, I guess there's a few things.
Like, one of them is it just has to be very readable and understandable when, like, you know, like, what you can do and when you can do it.
And I think the other thing that's really to our advantage here is reusing skills in multiple ways so you don't need, so you can make a deeper combo chain without requiring you to be using as many skills in order to do it.
So the way that Whirling Slash and Tornadoes interact with ground effects and kind of, like, all that stuff sort of means that, you know, you're using Whirling Slash multiple times as part of the same combo chain.
And that's an idea, I think, that I'd like to try and explore more because I think that it is a cool way to kind of extend the combo chain, yeah, as I said, without sort of getting too many things involved.
And that makes it a lot cooler.
So, yeah, I'll think a bit more about, you know, how we can apply that to other classes and other skills.
But, yeah, it's worked out really well here.
Yeah, it's a bit of, like, a loose create-your-own combo system in a way.
Like, obviously there's intended combos, but because it's interacting with something that's fundamental, like ground effects, you're able to combo with anything that creates a ground effect.
And there's a lot of different ways you can do that.
Like, I added Shocked Ground to the backflip skill, or I got a companion pet that had a Shocked Ground aura.
Nice, nice, nice.
So that was just there, and that was available all the time.
I mean, it's funny as well because it also works on just enemy ground effects.
And so sometimes you can just get a damage boost because the rare just happened to be dropping ground fire or something.
So that's kind of fun.
Yeah, yeah.
But it's been a, it's just a lot of fun to play.
You know, the first time I ran into that was actually in the graveyard where there's these, like, chests that, like, pop open with fire.
And, like, I was using tornadoes, and then one of them just randomly turned into a fire tornado.
And I'm like, oh, what happened there?
Oh, yeah, sweet.
It was just, like, a really cool moment where you're just sort of interacting with the environment, which was really fun.
I, yeah, it always feels like you're getting a little bit of something extra for free when you're taking advantage of the enemy effects or a boss fight that just has burning ground everywhere.
I was like, sweet.
So how do you go about balancing, though, when you have a class that has deeper combos and kind of somewhat requires you to do a bit more versus a class or a skill or a build that is just bonk?
I mean, you have to ultimately make the combos matter, right?
And I think, actually, that's one of those things that we're trying to really focus on with the balance changes we're doing in Dawn of the Hunt more generally is making sure that even, like, I think it's the case where some of the combo gameplay kind of degenerates a little bit by endgame in a way that, like, I want to make sure it still feels rewarded.
And so we were sort of doing various checks, you know, like, recently about, you know, like, as a random example, right?
Like, so on the Mercenary, we found that doing, you know, but when you get to endgame, doing armor break, sorry, what's it called?
The armor piercing that causes armor break followed with high velocity rounds is just worse than just using high velocity rounds.
And that's, like, really bad, right?
Like, we have to make sure that we're improving that stuff.
So it's, like, sometimes you just get these things where, like, the balance by endgame kind of degenerates in a way that doesn't support the combo anymore.
And so we have to make sure that when we're looking at buffing things that we're, like, making sure that when we're doing it, it's to support the fact that using more things is actually a good thing.
So, yeah, we're really trying to make sure that we're bringing some of that, you know, improving some of that stuff as well as we're doing the balance changes.
So do you have, like, a baseline there of where, like, the really simplest build should be, the build that just bonks?
I mean, you mean in terms of damage or in terms of, like, what it does?
You know, I mean, we always want you to be able to build that way.
I guess the players have to do a combo.
I mean, no, ultimately you never have to, right?
But it sort of means, what it means is that, you know, you are sacrificing something.
And, look, the ideal situation is that, like, you don't feel like you have to do combos.
You feel like you want to do combos, right?
Because you feel rewarded for them.
It's like, it should feel like a fun, like, oh, I can add this, you know?
Like, it's the feeling you should be getting.
Yeah.
I think the Huntress is doing that very well.
It must have been, like, extremely hard because I don't think I've ever seen this, like, ranged melee combo done well before.
Well, I mean, it does require a lot of discipline.
And it means that a lot of skills, like, end up on the cutting room floor because you try them out and then you realize, well, if this is in the game, then that's the only thing I'm ever going to do.
So you've got to be really careful about that stuff.
Certainly playing the Huntress now makes me go back and look at the other classes and be like, we need to up that, the level there.
And we miss the mark a little bit now because this is better.
And who's to say the next class won't even be better and make us question even this?
But, you know.
But that's the way it is with class design.
That's what he says to me.
Like, literally, when you make a new class, you question everything.
He's not understating the level of questioning everything.
Yeah.
Do you see, like, going back to the Monk at some point and looking for more, like, opportunities to link skills together?
I mean, we haven't got to the full skill set for any class yet already.
And we need to add more pieces for a lot.
I think there's at least four skills that were designed and then aren't in the Monk currently.
Yep.
Ranger the same.
There was extra poison skills.
There was intended to be more chaos darts.
All kinds of stuff.
We have to, obviously, at some point, fill all of that in.
Hard to say when, but we're going to try and incrementally get it.
Like, much like how Ray Spector and, I mean, the mount works with the Huntress,
but we were like, let's give something for the Ranger this time.
Let's give something for the summoners out there this time.
And so we're just going to keep filling in those gaps over time.
And it feels like you're getting better at class and skill design as you go to.
So I imagine the last class you're going to release is going to be, like, amazing.
You'll look back at the first ones and be like, ooh.
Possibly.
That is the worry.
But whatever.
But look, that just means we've got another round of going through everything and improving stuff again, right?
And that will never end.
That's it.
But so with the parry came the kind of looking at the player getting stunned.
In particular, the player heavy stun.
So it's always hard to tell players, like, hey, we're going to do something to you, and it's going to be a bad thing.
You're not going to like this.
Well, the funny thing.
Let's talk about why.
There's a few things like that, actually.
Because, I mean, for a start, we needed the downside of parry to be, you know, like, yeah, you get stunned out of it.
But then when we're looking at how long, like, we're like, okay, right now, even, and it's true with shield block as well, by the way.
It's like, if you get stunned out of that, the amount of time that you get stunned out for is actually not even enough time for most bosses to do a follow-up attack on you.
And it's like, well, where's the downside if it doesn't even have enough time?
So we did have to extend that out a little bit.
And it makes you a little bit more careful.
But just to warn people, right, there's a few other things.
Like, we lowered, what's it called?
The, I can't remember the name of that thing now.
The thing that makes you more easy to be elemental statuses apply to you.
Element threshold.
That's right.
Yeah.
So we lowered element threshold to actually make it so the player has those mechanics happen more to them, right?
Because, like, right now through campaign, like, you barely get frozen or burning or shocked, really, to be honest.
So there's stuff like that that we've had to do to kind of make sure that, you know, that.
Because if you don't have that stuff actually happen to you, then there's no point in mitigating it.
And it's like, you know, things like charms were, like, not very useful because, you know, those mechanics weren't happening to you.
There's stuff like that, right?
The downsides do actually matter in order to make it so that, you know, that you then, you know, there's other things you can do to sort of bypass those downsides.
So, yeah, that's kind of one of those things that, you know, we just have to make sure is there.
I did always find it a little bit strange that, like, I was able to count the number of times I was frozen in the campaign on one finger.
For sure.
But as always by those vile ghosts.
Yes, yes, yes.
So expect a little bit more, like, a little bit more danger from the stun.
I definitely died a couple of times to getting heavy stun.
Yeah, yeah.
It can happen.
So that's mostly occurring if you're, like, doing bad blocking or parrying.
But can it also occur just from, like, taking a really big hit or something?
Nope.
At least we've discussed that.
We've gone through a whole bunch of different, like, should certain boss abilities heavy stun you?
And if you speak into enough stun threshold, it, like, demotes it to a light stun.
And if that, you know, there's all kinds of mere multi-hour discussions we've had.
And we haven't really come to anything conclusive there.
But it's only from mount, raise shield, and parry.
And of which, you know, at least for all of them, you can see your stagger bar filling up.
It's worth noting things like evasion apply to...
So when you're parrying, we turn off your evasion from taking damage because the block does.
Right?
And otherwise you'd be like, I'm going to parry it.
Oh, I evaded it.
It didn't parry.
But you can evade the stagger buildup.
So you don't take the damage anyway.
Just before anyone misunderstands that.
The evasion still works.
Yeah.
So high evasion will mean you can parry for longer.
There's a bunch of parry stuff on the tree.
Including damage affecting the debuff.
The duration of the debuff.
So you get to benefit for it longer.
Reducing stagger is all over the place for both mount and...
So in the deck section of the tree.
So yeah, you can mitigate...
I mean, my expectation is probably you'll get some endgame builds that are just like,
I can parry forever.
There's no real consequence.
Not every skill can be parried, of course.
Yeah, it otherwise follows the slam rules.
If it's a slam from above or below, you can't parry it.
Much to your frustration for something.
I mean, there are a few things where I've got disagreements about what looks like it's parryable, but...
My helpful there was when it's contentious, people would bring it up and we'd change it, right?
Sure, sure.
So like, if it's on the line, it's meant to be blockable.
If it isn't clear.
And there was no way with hundreds of monsters and many dozens of bosses that we weren't going to miss some things.
So you mentioned this a little bit earlier, but action RPGs kind of naturally pull you towards one damage type, one skill, one specific thing and optimizing as much as possible.
Because otherwise you're just making a bad build a lot of the time.
But I noticed Huntress has a bit of everything.
She's got bleed.
She's got all the elements.
She's got physical.
The only thing she doesn't have is like chaos, but there's kind of poison on the tree right there.
So how do you like promote this, like all of this different stuff together?
Are you supposed to only kind of be relegated to using two or three skills or are these supposed to come together?
And how do you manage that?
Well, there's a few things.
So one of them is that we provide a lot of combos with the expectation that, you know, you'll probably be focusing around like a few specific things rather than necessarily using the whole tree.
So like there's that.
The other thing as well is just making sure that in the passive tree there's sort of options that go across both.
So the Huntress's passive tree has quite a lot of things like, you know, extra melee damage if you've done a ranged attack recently.
And then it's got things like bonuses against blinded enemies because while you're in a whirling slash there's, you know, sort of stuff like that.
We're trying to carefully think like, well, how can we come up with something that's interesting and buffs everything that you might want to be doing, you know, that kind of synergizes with the stuff that Huntress can do.
But it is honestly hard because, yeah, like many categories of things only matter for, you know, one thing, part of a combo.
So it's just like trying to come up with categories that can somehow span all of them in different ways.
And, you know, ideally, you know, we can achieve that.
But yeah, it is pretty hard.
Generally, you're going to become more niche or more selective because, again,
even mixing elemental and bleed is just probably often going to result in something.
You probably wouldn't do both elemental and bleed.
You'd probably choose one or the other.
But that's why we kind of try to make sure that, like, so you've got sort of linkages between them though, right?
Because it's like, for example, the Thunderous Leap detonates the spears that you do from the bleed thing.
So it's kind of like the idea there is to, like, it changes how that skill then has a use in the combo with the other one.
So even if that skill itself isn't doing a lot of damage, it's triggering something that's taking advantage of all the damage bonuses you got for your bleed stuff.
So that's kind of like the idea is just to link all that stuff in a bit so that you can use the non, like, directly, you know, synergistic things in a kind of more synergistic way.
Yeah, that's, if you didn't see that from the earlier trailer, you spear them with a bunch of spears and then jump on them and it explodes them.
So it's really amazing.
But, yeah, that's using an elemental skill, like, in another way as a detonator.
But, and even more, you've got weapon swaps as well.
Yeah, of course, of course, of course.
I mean, there's all those systems we already added about all that kind of stuff.
So, you know, I mean, like, what will be interesting is whether or not we miss something cross-class, right?
That's always a concern is someone will come up with some way to abuse something, you know, between something that's going on in the spear skills with some other class that we've failed to consider.
Yeah, I mean, so that's it.
When we look at a new class, we typically, like, call it, like, oh, Huntress is spears.
But kind of not really.
It's a signature weapon.
Absolutely.
But nothing in the ascendancies prescribes spears.
Exactly.
So, effectively, we take great pains to make sure that the ascendancies never mention weapon types, that there's, like, that they're always generalized.
So, for example, the, like, infusion mechanic in the Amazon, it just says projectiles.
It doesn't say spears.
And the reason it does that is so that you could make an Amazon who is a, you know, a bow user.
And that's all fine.
So, yeah, like, it's effectively, like.
Open-ended.
It's open-ended.
And honestly, like, I know that Mark, like, does, like, it makes the constraints a lot harder for how to design an ascendancy class.
You have to think about it that way, for sure.
Oh, it'd be much, much easier to just put a bunch of cool spear stuff in there.
Right.
Now, only really.
I mean, it was similar to the original Peewee 1 Saboteur.
It called out traps and mines.
And so, yeah, if you're a trap and mine character, what are you doing?
Well, that.
You could do something else, but no one else is playing that thing, you know?
It isn't.
It is easier to design.
It is certainly less flexible and open as to what people can play in the different combinations and all that.
So, yeah.
How much do you have to consider the different weapons and the skills and how they interact together when you're originally designing them?
Or is there just literally so many possible combinations you're just like, the players will take care of that for us?
I mean, I think it is relatively impossible to come up with everything.
But certainly we have to consider, like, you know, is this going to be broken with anything else in particular?
And there just has to be certain rules for things about, like, you know, how easy is it to apply this debuff?
How easy it is to consume this debuff?
And even then, it's like, you know, we often make mistakes and have issues.
So, you know, I mean.
When he says relatively impossible, it is actually impossible.
Actually, yes.
But, you know, I mean, yeah.
That's relative.
But even just looking at the balance pass we're doing at the moment, right?
I mean, there's hundreds and, like, there's hundreds of things, like, that, you know, that we still.
I mean, there's things that we could never honestly understand all of the different broken things that could possibly exist.
And so it's like, it really does depend a lot on the, you know, like, on seeing reports on what people are doing on some level, right?
But then I think that what will happen over time is obviously, like, you know, the game is still relatively new.
We're still making relatively big changes.
Over time, the balance, I think, will get to the point where we no longer have these, like, crazy outliers to the same extent.
And it should mean that we get to some sort of relative class parity.
By parity, what I mean is, like, you know, people playing all the different classes rather than focusing only on a few as we get towards full release.
Because, you know, right now it's obviously very skewed because, you know, there's certain broken things.
So, you know, yeah, we just, the balance over time, we'll get there.
It's one of the main goals and benefits of the early access is just, like, let's get the balance of characters right.
And, yeah, this patch release was always going to have a thousand problems, or probably 10,000 problems, you know?
The next one will have half that, the next one half that, and probably eventually it's going to be down to, like, here's only a few things going, you know, out of whack.
There's always going to be something because we add too much content for it to even be controlled.
Like, again, there are too many uniques, too many supports, too many skills, and too many other changes for any amount of people.
Like, you're talking about a matter of you'd have to put in, like, thousands and thousands of hours internally to find it where, and then you give it to the players.
There's so many people it's going to take literally five minutes.
So it is, it's very beneficial.
We're lucky in that regard that we get that level of testing and feedback on such a mass level, and especially, you know, with things like Ninja and all of that, and other people being able to see it and discuss it more openly, we're just going to be able to iterate on it even faster.
But, yeah, every single patch, you're going to see a pretty substantial change in what's going to happen here.
Thanks for making the broken builds.
Well, 100%.
100%.
I mean, you mentioned support gems.
It's, like, over 100 support gems added just this patch.
Mm-hmm.
It's already, like, so many, and with you doing a different weapon for each of the, what, 16 classes?
Yeah, there's going to be a lot with the time we're done.
But there kind of has to be, right?
Because, you know...
That's what, you made it, you made this system that you need so many supports to support.
You do.
Because otherwise it's not going to work.
Yeah, yeah.
Especially with this one support system.
It's like, what have you guys done?
Well, I mean, look, this is why we have recommendations, and hopefully we can improve those as well and continue to...
...to get that better.
You know, like...
There's certainly room for the complexity to get a little bit out of control here.
So the recommenders are going to become more and more important.
Right.
So we need to make sure those are very much right.
Mm-hmm.
For sure.
You must be looking to players, even, to find some of those recommendations down the line as well.
In some cases.
Yeah.
What stuff is popularly getting used for some...
So the thing with the recommendations, though, is that they can't really take into account what you've already got on the gem.
Yeah.
So the recommendations have to be just sort of generally good, but not really taken into account combos.
And, you know, that kind of means they're a bit more simple.
Like, the recommendations are going to be more simple than what you'd otherwise be doing if you're not following.
Feels like at some point you're going to need some sort of nested recommendation system.
It's like, well, I'm kind of doing bleed stuff.
So you go into the submenu for feed recommendations.
Yeah, I'm less certain about that, because I kind of don't want to get into the thing of actually telling you what your build should be.
So, yeah, that's a little different there.
Maybe, like, more sorting methods for the show me all the gems.
Oh!
Because there's a lot that are only in there that I never recommended, right, at this point.
There are, yes.
There are.
It's going to be an interesting challenge you guys have set yourselves to make enough supports there.
So another thing that you managed to challenge that you set yourselves, and I always wonder, like,
why did you do this to yourselves with Spectres?
So originally those were planned to be in for launch, but obviously Spectres are a whole can of worms.
It's, hey, let's just give players access to every monster.
Also, we've made so many new monsters.
Yeah.
We're talking about all the broken.
There's going to be some broken in there, I promise you.
And there's going to be some stuff we have to change.
I mean, you know, they've done, but I mean, effectively, what the time between early access and this was,
was like, okay, let's actually attempt, at least, to do a balance pass of this,
and, like, see if there's anything that's going to be a problem, and then adjust up the support.
Yeah, but now you've got to count all those support gems on all those monsters.
Yes.
Well, this is an interesting thing, isn't it?
The support gems work on them.
And, you know, like, what the hell is that going to do?
Yeah, like, it's impossible to completely know.
But, yeah, look, I mean, there's probably definitely some dark secrets lying in what kind of specter mix with support gems are going to do.
And monsters have skills now.
It's not like P.O.E. 1, where it's, like, just a bunch of zombies just doing default attack.
It's, like, everything pretty much has a skill now at this point.
But, you know, the great thing about it is we got to leverage all that work again for the beast taming as well.
So, and, of course, the difference there is that you also get the mods from the thing that you tamed.
So, you know, that's going to be...
Auras, ground effects.
Yeah, exactly.
Expon-death explosions.
You've got a whole other ruckus of potential interactions.
So, you know, we'll see what happens there.
We've done nice specific player versions of those things, specifically when you tame the beast so that they're not sitting there spamming skills in your hideout and all of that.
Good.
Yes.
But also, like, there actually are player versions of the mods that Rez can get, like, so that we can balance them if we need to.
Yeah.
Because some of that stuff was actually would be ridiculous if you had it yourself.
So, you know, basically, we still have it sort of work.
It mostly works the same way, but there will just be numbers tweaked to the player versions.
And the same works as well for the, what do you call it, the virtual sacrifice...
Headhunter.
Headhunter and headhunter and stuff like that.
So, yeah.
It's player versions of the monster mods for that.
Yeah.
This new attention to these things is going to benefit, like, the pre-existing stuff like Headhunter and that as well.
That's insane.
There's a new...
Probably should have let people discover it.
There's a new unique charm that possesses you with a random Asmiri spirit as well.
And so you get the daemons and the stats.
And those technically also have player versions too.
But actually, not to necessarily make things worse, to make things better.
Because monsters are balanced to fight player.
Player life and monster life not in the same universe.
So, actually, what we've done is all the things you steal that are monsters and monster skills,
like the explosions and the summoning beers and all that,
we've actually specifically balanced them way up to be more effective against monster.
So, when you steal them, they're much more powerful, actually.
Just so they're not just tickling monsters and doing 1% of their life kind of thing.
It was mentioned in chat, actually, the whole, like, Asmiri modifiers and things on stuff.
That wouldn't go...
That wouldn't transfer over with the companion system, surely?
No.
No, no, no.
That would be a little bit too far, perhaps, to get unhinged.
We actually had to, because this is certainly a benefit.
But once you have tamed the beast, it is not tradable.
And people might immediately be like, oh, that's sad.
Well, the issue is, and as much as you might want some of that,
I'm sure you don't want to be carrying around a whole bunch of tame beasts in your inventory all the time.
So that every single time you find a good rare, all of a sudden you have to go and...
Because it would mean that finding a rare would become a thing.
Yes, exactly.
It's actually, like, this annoying...
In order to make the most money, I have to be constantly thinking about and carrying around tame beasts.
But then we also made it so that as soon as you activate a beast,
then no one who comes into the instance after that is allowed to tame it.
You can't do any, like...
So you can't TFT the, you know, the...
It's like a whole...
There's a lot of thinking about that stuff in order to make it so that, you know...
It's a sad thing to have lost, but it is like, yeah, no, I'm not signing up for that.
I didn't even think about that.
Yeah, yeah.
The, like, needing for cheat sheets and dives and stuff.
Yeah, exactly right.
And so you have to be really careful.
You have to be so careful.
And the thing is, it's like we design this thing and then think,
oh, trading beasts is going to be fun.
But then you realise that the horrific reality...
Actually.
...of what it will turn into.
It's like, yeah, okay, well...
But yeah, at least we're thinking about that kind of thing,
like, with more experience that we have now early so that we don't...
We've been on that row before.
Exactly, exactly.
Yes, we have.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm glad we've learned from past issues with that sort of trading.
Yeah, yeah.
Fantastic.
So, talking about some of the other new skills, we had the addition of the Rower,
which was a teased quite some time ago, I think.
But you've got it in and working now.
Yes.
It looks like it's moving around pretty good.
Yes, yes.
It's obviously...
You've got, like, a big downside.
If you get knocked off at a heavy stun and stuff, you can't use melee from it,
so it's for ranged attacks.
Yeah, yeah.
But it does seem like one of those things that it's going to be like,
everyone's going to use or no one's going to use because it's a clear speed machine.
It is a concern.
I mean, look, my ideal situation is that you're using it sometimes
and not using it other times.
Like, if you're using it, like, during clear, I think it will, you know,
like, you will definitely want to.
But it's...
We want to just make sure that we've got, like, you know,
sort of fun things like that.
Like, it's just a cool fantasy.
Like, there's stuff like that that I just want to get in.
And it's like, you know, look, if it doesn't work later,
if we have to nerf it, I mean, sure, I suppose.
But, you know, like, I just...
I want something like that to exist.
So, you know, we believe...
I believe that it is balanced as much as we can do.
As much as we can...
You sound very convinced.
Yeah, yeah, it's balanced, it's balanced, it's balanced.
As I said earlier, you can probably get builds
that get to the point of parrying indefinitely.
So, you can...
That means, there, you can probably get to the point of
riding a row indefinitely.
Sure, sure, sure.
Again, enough evasion and enough...
Stagger speaking into and all of that.
Yeah, yeah.
Fundamental question, actually.
Like, what's its move speed based on?
Its own move speed?
The move speed is just your move speed.
Like, you...
Yeah, but it's...
But what you don't get is the penalty
for when you attack.
Yeah.
So, yeah, that's the thing.
But it's funny.
It's funny, though, because, like,
even though it doesn't have a move speed bonus,
it feels like you're motoring when you're using it
just because of the fact you don't get that downside anymore.
Like, you feel like you're the fastest thing on the planet.
It is.
When you're doing it.
There are other, like, more mechanical benefits,
like, it's considered a companion,
which is a kind of subclass of minion that we've added
where you can only have one of each minion.
One companion base is a keystone for another,
but you can only have one of each type.
So, like, you can have a tame beast and a rower
with the keystone.
Oh, right, yeah.
But inherently, you can only have one companion.
Right, so you can't use a tame beast
if you're using the rower.
And then there are heaps of passives for, like,
if you have a companion,
like, companions while they're in your presence
and all that kind of stuff,
heaps of that stuff around the bottom of the tree.
Yeah, I saw you guys remade the minion damage,
this player damage node on the tree.
It's your companion damage nodes become player damage nodes.
And I was like, oh, that looks like I'm going to take that.
Well, yeah, so that's the, like, companion
where it's, like, more the mercenary over to ranger Huntress
is more like, yeah, you want your one powerful minion
and benefiting that benefits you and you benefit it
and there's that, like, you know, synergy between you
and your companions.
So, since it is a companion,
I like the idea of, like, balance-wise,
maybe it ends up being that you're, like,
map clearing on back, on rower back.
And then you get to the boss and you dismount,
like, you know, old-school mountain knights
who would charge in battle and then dismount and fight.
Yep, yep.
So, if it ends up like that,
that seems like that would be a pretty cool balance for it.
I think that should be the best way to use it, I believe.
Yeah, because then you gain access to your dodge roll
for the boss fight where you need it.
And does the rower then kind of do a bit
when you're not on it?
It can attack, but, I mean,
it's not exactly a huge damage source or anything.
It's certainly better to stay at range.
It's not the most durable of birds.
But it acts as a distraction, maybe it's a support gem.
Yeah, yeah, I mean, it's a minion, right?
Like, it attacks things and does stuff.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, and you can support it
with minion supports to make it more durable
and all of that, so, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, there's the one that's, like,
the minion takes 10% of the damage before you do,
so, sacrificial bird.
Yeah, yeah, true.
Poor little guy.
So that sounds, I'm looking forward
to playing around with that one then.
Speaking of 100 new uniques this time,
so how many are you aiming for, kind of, in general?
Is this about really, like, filling that roster out?
Well, we want to have every base type have a unique
for the purposes of chance.
Outside of boss uniques.
But we want every base type to have a unique
that you can chance.
Yes.
And so that was the eventual goal.
One of the things, of course, that we had
that was sort of a problem in early access
is that because of the way, like,
because when we were designing uniques,
we kind of designed them, like, in order
from base type up, just literally,
because that's the way the, like,
spreadsheets are arranged.
It's like, we ended up with all the low-level uniques
first, kind of before the either one.
And it was kind of, it's like,
we didn't see that mistake coming.
Like, it was kind of stupid because, like,
We thought we'd get through way more.
Yeah, we thought we'd get through them all, right?
We were like, okay, we'll get all the uniques.
And so we designed them all.
It's like, okay, we'll start working on the art.
Just go down the list.
So then we're like, oh, crap.
You know, now we don't have any,
don't have very many in-game uniques.
So, yeah, this time we're like, okay,
we really need to make sure
that in-game uniques are a thing.
There's way more of them.
So the focus really is on getting,
making sure there's lots of cool stuff to find.
You know, lots of really chase things
that you can get.
You know, it's not...
You discovered the sort order changing
in the spreadsheet.
Yeah, yeah, it does help.
But the, so yeah, effectively,
yeah, like, you should,
it should be a lot better.
And like, there's lots of cool stuff there.
And we're just going to keep going with that,
by the way.
Yeah, yeah, of course.
100 now, 100 later, 100 next.
Just keep going.
Until, well, kind of, honestly,
we never really stopped making uniques.
Like, especially anyone familiar
with Path of Exile 1's history
is every single expansion
since the dawn of time
has had new uniques added to it.
So, you know, there's, you know,
a lot there and there's going to be
a lot here eventually as well.
So, yeah.
So then let's talk about the idea
of like players seeing a unique
and be like, ah, 1x, you know,
that's not very good.
Where do you guys,
what do you guys want uniques
to be in Path of Exile 2?
Like, how powerful should they be?
What should they be aiming to do?
And how should they affect
the rares in that slot?
I mean, it's always a tension
because we want rares to still matter.
Like, we don't want just you,
your character to be just
only full of uniques.
So it really is like the role can,
like, can evolve.
So at the start of the game,
they're really supposed to be
more about that.
Like, so the earlier game uniques
are supposed to do two things.
One of them is when you find them,
they should be powerful
for a little while.
But then also they have a,
some kind of combo thing
that you might be able to do
with them at endgame.
But we don't always know exactly
what that might be.
Like, I mean,
we've got sort of ideas, obviously,
but it's like,
we don't necessarily design them
to say, okay,
this unique definitely has,
like, an endgame build
that's going to be, like,
that's going to be actually strong
to do with it.
And that's because you're kind of
putting in things where,
you know, later on,
some other mechanic might come along
or something might happen
and then people find
an interesting interaction
and that's when the unique
kind of comes into its own.
And I mean,
that's the same as, like,
magic card design philosophy,
that kind of stuff.
You just put in, like,
kind of weird stuff
and sort of, you know,
maybe you find something.
But obviously it can mean
that, like, you know,
when people see a new unique,
they dismiss it.
But then one day
they might also be paying
vast amounts for it
if it becomes a meta build.
So, you know,
but I feel like a game
has to have that stuff in it
in order to feel like
there's lots of interesting ways
to experiment
because, like, you know,
it's like the feeling
of being the first person
to discover some new interaction
is an amazing thing
and then when people see something
that, like, feels smart
and it's like, you know,
if we don't have uniques
that just take chances
and do weird shit,
we'll never have
that kind of stuff happen.
So, you know.
When we're designing a unique,
we don't think about,
oh, what's the value going to be.
Yeah.
We're not even coming out of it
going, like,
this is going to be really expensive
or this is going to be really cheap.
Well, in some cases, you know.
You knew what you were doing
with that Herald unique.
No, I don't remember.
It was more of the charm.
But that's the thing.
Are you aiming for the...
Honestly,
someone said the other day
they were like,
a successful unique
is one that should be divisive.
And I was like,
I agree for the most part,
but not every unique
should fill that role.
Some should just be clearly,
this is powerful,
I want it for sure.
It is going to be on my build.
And others are like,
what can I do with this now?
And then others are just like,
we don't know
if anyone's going to do anything
with this,
throw it in.
And sometimes it doesn't get
anything happen with it
for three years.
But we don't know that necessarily.
It's like,
let's just take an experiment
and throw it in there
and let the players
figure that out.
Yeah,
I feel like with a lot
of these uniques,
you're designing a question.
You're just like,
I'm going to put something
that's a little weird.
Maybe someone will figure that out.
Well,
I think as Rishi called it,
it's a puzzle piece,
right?
Yeah.
It's just a piece in the puzzle.
You put it there
and maybe someone
will complete the puzzle
or half of it.
Maybe not.
And then others
where it's just like,
yeah,
this is powerful.
I mean,
there are definitely
some Chase uniques
in this.
Yeah,
100%.
Oh,
definitely.
So on Chase uniques,
then we've obviously
had some pretty crazy
ones so far.
Where do they want to be
in terms of how hard
they are to get
for players?
Because at that point,
you do need to consider
how expensive they end up being.
It's really tricky.
So whenever we're looking,
so if there's a unique
that's broken,
I guess there's two responses,
right?
One of them is
make it rare enough
that you only get
the brokenness
after the point
when you're,
at the point
where you're supposed
to get that,
which is to say
post-pinnacle boss type
level of character development,
right?
And then the other response
would be nerf the actual unique.
And it honestly
is a case-by-case.
So I think that
Temporalus,
for example,
actually got nerfed
in both ways.
The actual unique
was nerfed a little bit,
I believe,
although I don't believe
it's maybe as much
as what players might expect.
But then also,
okay,
whatever.
But also,
we have made that one rarer.
It's still pretty crazy.
Oh, it's still crazy.
For sure, for sure, for sure.
But the thing is,
you want to chase stuff,
right?
So therefore,
you don't want to just go
nerfing everything
into the ground
the moment that it's good.
So therefore,
that one becoming rarer,
I think,
was the right answer there
because it was way too common.
We had also the issues
with like,
I mean,
there were three real issues.
One is darkness
at one point
bypassed on a loss.
So all of a sudden,
a no-hit run.
It wasn't a no-hit run.
You had guard bypass
on a loss.
So once again,
a no-hit run is not a no-hit run.
And then there was just like,
well,
how can anything hit you
if you can kill literally
everything on your screen
in one frame, right?
So those three problems.
And so as the like,
the balance issue
of not everything surviving,
things surviving
for more than one frame
due to a subset of builds
and those other two things go away,
it becomes a lot rarer in itself.
Yeah.
I mean,
it is much harder to acquire,
require like very specific
and ideally high-skill gameplay.
And then there was just like,
well,
it also was just too common,
the Relic that yielded it.
I mean,
the expectation was that,
oh,
because this is a hard challenge,
most of the time
when people try,
they will fail.
The reality is
once you get the ability to do it,
you just trade for that thing
and get it every time.
So that's kind of meant
that the rarity
kind of didn't work
like we thought.
And yeah,
now that should be better
in both ways.
Like again,
for the POE 1 player,
it's comparison,
like it was far more common
than Original Sin,
which was the same role
in POE 1's version of the Sanctum,
just to give us
some sort of comparison.
It's just much easier
to actually reliably do it.
And it shouldn't have been
that much more common.
Right, right.
Yeah,
gotcha.
So crafting really surprised me.
You guys announced,
I thought we'd maybe get
like one little thing,
maybe you'd do something
with essences or something,
but we've got essences
coming out a lot more,
it looks like.
You've got,
because you're violent,
you can integrate it now.
So greater essences
are much more,
going to be much easier to get.
One thing we didn't mention
in the video
is that like omens
are way more common
because I believe
you made a chance
that there's an omen
in every...
Two and a half times
more common,
I think.
Yeah,
than every thing.
So like you've got
stuff like that.
Like we certainly knew
that we needed to do more
with what crafting stuff.
And so we're kind of like,
well,
let's just make sure
we're at least adding,
you know,
three or four things,
like new things.
Every ritual
will now have one,
at least one omen
in the window.
Amazing.
So you can know
upon finishing a ritual,
you're like,
what is the omen I'm going to get
and hope it's a good one
and maybe most often
it's not,
but you know.
But yeah,
the greater essences,
obviously,
yeah,
the Varlorb thing
makes it much more common.
You know,
there's more sources of them
with the map
and everything like that.
So that'll be happening more.
And then of course,
there's the improvements
to things like the runes.
We've got higher level mods
that you can get from them.
There's like a ton more runes.
There's like,
you know,
yeah,
like we just wanted
to expand the set
and having the kind of like,
you know,
the,
yeah,
the nicher mods
that you can get
and craft on things
like you just,
yeah,
just,
it just needed more options.
And yeah,
it's sort of interesting
because like some people say,
oh,
you don't have crafting
in,
you know,
in Peewee 2
because we don't have
a crafting bench.
But it's like,
we actually have a huge number
of crafting options
and the crafting being good
kind of comes down
to like how many
of these kind of weird systems
are there
and how they can interact.
But we just have to be
really careful
because,
you know,
like you don't want
to get to the point
where ground items
no longer matter.
Like you,
and I think Peewee 1
kind of basically
did get to that point
for various reasons
where like people
aren't caring
about what's on the ground
nearly as much.
So we still want
to make sure
with every change
we're making
that,
you know,
they still use
the ground stuff,
that you're still excited
for things on the ground.
And so that's like
a really careful balancing act
because they do directly
contravene each other.
Like the more,
the better stuff you can craft,
the less important
the ground stuff is.
So you kind of,
it's a really sort of
subtle balancing act.
But yeah,
I think that the stuff
we've added here
will definitely push things
in a way where you feel
like there's more smart things
that you can do
to kind of improve your stuff.
Yeah,
well I think done right
and what you're doing
is making sure
that the ground items
do matter with each
of these crafting systems.
So you have
that fundamental change
where you can't just
turn an item back
into a wide item.
Exactly.
And that's very important.
One of the biggest ones I think.
And that kind of then
unlocks the ability
to do more.
And so the great thing
about the socketables
as a crafting system
is that they don't
compromise the ground at all
because they don't,
you know,
they're on top of the stuff
that you can get on the ground.
So that's very good.
But when it comes
to the kind of the base mods
we do want to retain,
like, you know,
that an item has,
we do want to retain
for the most part
the kind of thing
of like those,
that part of the item generation
is random.
It's just that,
and it's just that
on top of that
you get the more deterministic
things that you can add
in addition to.
And then when you do it
that way it works really well.
So socketables work really well
as a crafting system
for that reason.
So on that topic
we've had this,
talking to you
it's like you're always
saying to me that like
this rune system
is our crafting bench
but players don't
keep asking for a bench anyway.
Right, right, right.
So obviously there's like
a branding issue
or a functionality gap there.
It is funny
because I was actually
saying the other day
that like
if we had literally
had that system
be identical
except that the way
it was themed
was that there's
a crafting bench
you go to
and craft extra mods
on the items
which literally
would be functionally
the same
and required materials
that are effectively
the runes that you get
then I feel like
people would be thinking
that we've got
a crafting bench
but yeah,
ultimately that is
that the rune system
the socketables
are what replaced
the crafting bench
and the POE1
style crafting bench.
I guess it must have
also been like
with that initial
kind of output
of them
was just not as many
options as
100% as well
so that is the issue
and that's because
they were relatively
late in development
so now we're just
sort of expanding that
and we'll continue
to add more socketables
probably with every release
right, like
we'll add more categories
and we'll do different things
it's like expanding
the kind of type of mods
because there is a thing
where it's the more
like in the base
mod pool for items
there can only be things
that are really fundamental
and so anything
that's kind of out there
we don't want to put
in the base mod pool
because then you end up
in this sort of situation
where you get items
and they've got random shit
you don't care about
like the crafting
is where you want to have
all of the kind of stuff
that's like very build specific
and so adding more mods
to that pool
so that you can do that
is the right idea.
Why is it that
you can't
socket and ruin some things?
Like non-attack weapons
for example?
Well
it was more just a choice
for asymmetry
where we just wanted
these things to feel different
there was also just like
a little bit of a like
in the future
we'll add some system
where we can do
something else there
and so just not having
everything be completely identical
much like how
you know
the quality on those weapons
works differently
where it affects the skill
as opposed to just
you know
base damage
I do think it is something
that we should be
probably looking into
sooner rather than later though
Yeah
because the asymmetry things
it's good to have
like not everything
be super homogenous
but
because we're talking
about the importance
of it being that
extra layer of
control of your items
which you just don't have
if you're doing spellcasting
Maybe we'll add an
Arcanist's bench
and theme it that way
for those ones
Alright
you forced my hand
I have to bring this up now
can we get some sort of
like cohesive
all in one
bench for disenchanting
salvaging
selling for gold
Arcanist benching
at endgame
I get in the campaign
having these things
be separate
but like at endgame
it's so much
clicky clicky
easy work
happy enough with them
just being next to each other
putting them next to each other
and you know
No
Alright
I'll think about that one
Okay good
I planted the seeds at least
Yeah yeah
I've done my part
Alright
There's ways
I like the
sounds of that
Well at least for endgame
Yeah
I don't want the world
to not feel like
it makes sense
Absolutely
Endgame you've got your
hideout
It would have to be
a hideout related thing
Yeah yeah yeah
That makes sense
I mean
people are putting their
NPCs within each other's
personal space anyway
so the lore goes out the
window at that point
Yeah for sure
So we've also got
Fractured
Crafted Veer and Orb
from the cleansed monsters
How rare are those?
How do you quantify
rarity like that?
They drop from the monsters
I can't remember the exact
number but like
I think I was kind of
saying like one per biome
which is the kind of
total blob of
cleansed monsters
but then that obviously
does get affected by
things like pack size
and all that on top of
that
So is that like five
maps or something?
Well it depends on how
many of them you kill
as corrupted
Yeah
Because like
because there's the
ones you didn't
that you didn't
cleanse while you were
you know getting to the
nexus
those are the ones
that then become
cleansed
so you kind of have to
choose like when you go
into a biome I'm going
to beeline straight for
the nexus
and then cleanse
everything
or am I going to just
fight them all as
corrupted to get the
rewards from that?
So you're kind of
choosing one reward or
the other based on
what you decide to run
Okay so you can kind of
leave the nexus for last
if you want to
Yes if you want to
choose it to try and
get more fractured orbs
Oh no it's the other
way around
So do nexus first
then it cleanses all the
maps and then now you
can get the most chance
at fractured orbs
or you can fight them
corrupted before going
to the nexus if you
want to get the rewards
that the corrupted maps
have
And we have like
for example the
corrupted bosses have
their own uniques now
Yeah so you're going to
There's a bunch of
new modifiers and how
they you know so
there's like random
corrupted strongbox kind
of things and all that
stuff so you kind of
really are like I'm
going to you know have
a look at the mods
I like this I'm going to
do this then this then
this then the nexus and
then I'm going to do the
rest cleansed
Does the cleansed boss
have its own uniques as
well?
Not yet
It does have
It guarantees a fractured
although as well
Oh okay
So you can get the
Yes the boss
And you'll display
If you hover over the
map and it says like
contains I can't remember
his name
Then you run it and
kill it you will get a
fractured orb so at
least you will know that
will drop one
Yeah yeah
So with the fractured
orbs being away
fracturing that's
obviously super powerful
for crafting
Are there any fractured
items dropping pre-fractured?
I quite liked that
I think we went with no
in the end
Yeah not currently
We were going to do it
but then we decided not
to but we might do it
later
Yeah so an extra item
Is there a particular
reason for it or
the thought process?
There just kind of
wasn't anything that
really fit that exactly
I think
At some point you'll want
some new thing
Yeah probably
Personally I would
rather just drop more
orbs
Honestly let people
choose how they want
to use them
I like it from the
perspective of dropped
items matter
like when you're seeing
a rare
Yeah but they kind of
already do
they kind of do here
anyway because
because you need that
as the thing of the
fractured
so it's kind of
not necessary I think
There's other little
subtle things like
for example
the cleansed monsters
within cleansed maps
can't drop equipment
as a little thing
so they have much
higher
obviously they're
dropping things
more like
waystones, tablets,
currency
they don't get to
drop any of the
armor or anything
so they're more
like currency sources
as like an
interesting subtle thing
If you want more
currency then play
cleansed maps
So we're going to
have a lot more
essences, a lot more
omens, potential
ability to get
fractured, recombination
with the new
more accessible
at low and mid tier
recombination
Design 4.0
This is
yes recombination
has certainly
undergone some changes
This is a huge
huge leap forwards
compared to
0.1's crafting
So was it just about
that you had to
establish that really
like humble baseline
for crafting
so that you could
then go crazy
Honestly I mean
look on some level
it can just be
you know like
you need an economy
you need to see
how things evolve
you know we just
don't want to do
too much at once
I mean although
this may seem
like quite a lot
It does yeah
But the thing is
is like
but in terms of
the initial system
it's like if we'd
have had all that
at the start
I think that we
wouldn't have been
like you know
we'll put it this way
it is hard to take
this stuff away
so that's why
we have to be
a little bit careful
as we do this
Yeah I guess you
needed to kind of
assess the fundamental
things like the
no scours
the no bolts
and stuff like that
as well
because then you
can have a better
idea of how to
build off that
which I'm super
excited for
crafting
Oh yeah
Oh you're going to
have a new craft
for every league
right that's how
it is these days
Oh yeah
I expect a crafting
system for every league
thank you
Something like that
that's somewhat
actually our intention
so
I love it
love it
perfect
so let's talk
about Endgame
then because that
had some humble
origins as well
with the initial
implementation of
P.O.E. 2's
Endgame
obviously trying
some new things
being a bit
experimental
not necessarily
just wanting to
copy P.O.E. 1's
Endgame
but how far
if your vision
was 0.1's
Endgame
was it
what you want
I would say
that the main
problem that we
had is there
wasn't enough
overlapping axes
of randomness
as we call them
where effectively
you need to have
it so that when
you go into
a map
there's just
chances for
random shit
occurring
and then
that random
shit
might happen
alongside some
other random
shit
and now the
thing together
is a new
scenario
so effectively
if you look
at what we
actually added
here in terms
of encounters
whatever that
means to you
we've added
more than 40
probably something
approaching 50
encounters
and that's
if you count
things like
each rogue
exile is a
separate one
and each
spirit is a
different one
so those are
the things
but
the big
difference
between the
ones we had
before and
the ones we
have now
is that most
of these ones
can overlap
with other
things
so you have
a situation
where you've
got the
Asmary Wisp
that happens
to infect
the unique
boss of the
area
and then that
leads to a
combat situation
that you haven't
had to deal
with before
or then you've
got some
essence thing
that oh crap
this other
wisp caused
the thing to
turn into a
boss
it's all that
stuff combining
what happens
when this goes
with the unique
strongbox
and it's
all that
combining
stuff
and that's
what leads
to the
situation
where you've
got an
exponential
explosion
of possible
combat
situations
and then
sometimes you
just run
into stuff
that you've
never seen
before because
of that
because of
this combined
in some
interesting
way
and that's
something that
definitely
POE 1 has
got very well
because it's
got so many
of these things
that have been
added over time
and it's also
something that we
took care to make
sure that each
league specifically
did
so what
POE 2 lacked
was I think
that
and so that
will mean I
think that the
end game is
overall just much
more engaging
obviously we're
going to be
adding more
content and
more of the
other stuff
but fundamentally
it was specifically
more of that
type of stuff
that we needed
to do
and honestly
I don't think
we've even got
enough yet
we want even
more
we'll keep on
adding that
stuff but it
needed to become
a focus
and I think
part of the
reason is that
when we're first
working on the
end game
it's like we need
to come up with
the big ticket
items
what are the
league things
and the maps
we need to
come up with
all that stuff
it's the little
detaily things
that require a
bit more time
and stuff to
work on
even though
they're actually
relatively efficient
to make
we can make a
lot of them
when we do
sit down and
design them
making a new
strongbox
sure it's work
but it doesn't
take that long
but it is
that stuff that
adds all the
flavour and interest
so we'll just
be continuing to
do that through
the game
even yesterday
we were having
a conversation
about making
it so more
of the maps
even just
regular maps
have more
interesting little
things that
happen in them
more like what
the campaign
has
so we haven't
got there yet
but through
early access
we'll definitely
be introducing
more of those
little details
everywhere so
you get the
interesting things
happening
so a bit like
those exploration
mechanics in
campaigns
100%
we just want
to make sure
you feel that
same way
through the
end game
as well
and with
the leagues
as well
and like
there's really
only so much
randomness that
can occur within
a breach in a
map and so they
will end up
feeling ultra
repetitive
whereas
again in
Piri 1 you
had the boss
that could
spawn occasionally
you had five
different factions
you know things
like that and
it is very much
our intention to
expand on all
the leagues to
have way more
random things
occurring
mini bosses
spawning
whatever else
you know I
have a whole set
I don't want to
spoil them all yet
because that's
a whole later
thing but
definitely want to
expand on all
that you know
even expedition
only has the
one boss
it had four
in the
predecessor
you know like
we need to
get back to
having all of
that depth
of combat
and all of
those mechanics
and it will
help hugely
while also
making sure
we're adding
new ones of
course but
what we
definitely have
learned is
that our
minimum
standard for
new ones
is going to
have to
it should
include all
of these
things from
the get-go
right
otherwise we're
just signing
ourselves up
for like here's
a thousand
things we need
to improve
it'd be nice
to actually get
some of them
finished so
that's going to
be a goal
going forward
for sure
but I think
it's like it
is where our
type of design
shines because
like adding
content is no
longer a process
of like you
know we work
on a thing
and then the
players get to
play you know
like it gets
into a situation
where like adding
content is more
value than just
the content
itself it like
because it adds
to everything else
too and so
that kind of
makes it feel
like the world
gets like larger
in much larger
proportion than
what you have
and so like
you know it's
an n squared
thing where like
you know yeah
the square of
all the stuff
we add so
like basically
it'll feel like
it's ramping up
in terms of
interest as we
add more content
rather than just
feeling like you're
just continuing
like every
rather than every
leafing like you
just add the
same amount
it'll feel like
it gets even
bigger each time
yeah when you
add as merri-wisps
that's not just
about adding that
it interacts with
all the other
things that already
exist that it can
exactly go ahead
and effect
so that's tackling
one of the
ultimately I think
the biggest things
is just that like
the core
mapping of running
an empty map
was boring
and that's never
what you want to
be obviously
so like some
of the issues
there I guess
as well that
were exacerbated
by that problem
was the fact that
the maps were so
big and that there
were so many of
them obviously
that's getting a
lot better with
the maps themselves
becoming much
more interesting
but it seems like
this corruption
and cleansing
mechanic is
breaking up and
giving you something
to progress through
as you move
towards the next
tower or next
boss or next
other mechanic
I mean I guess
there's always
something on your
screen that you're
pushing towards
it looks like
well we want to
try and
honestly I don't
even think we're
even quite there
yet like we really
want to make it so
that you feel like
there's lots of
quests as it were
in endgame like not
necessarily directly in
the form of like here
is a quest objective
but like yeah but you
sort of have this
feeling of like yeah
there's like different
stuff that you're
like that you feel
like oh there's a
thing you know like
exactly right you need
to ideally like every
time you do one of
those it's like
there's another one
just on the horizon
that you're thinking
about so yeah if we
can achieve that then
then we'll have
succeeded but yeah
it'll keep adding
stuff right like just
more and more things
because obviously you
know you need to have
enough just core there
to be able to get to
the point of it
doesn't feel like
you're just repeating
the same thing over
and over again as
well it seemed like
this like explorable
world map thing that
you did for endgame
being like looking like
a physical actual map
was really wanting us to
explore but that wasn't
really much of that so
you kind of yeah well
I mean ideally we can
it's just about content
really at that point
you know you just
need to add more and
more and we'll keep
on adding more and
this should this
yeah and zero to
oh I think there's a
long way to improving
that for sure so with
the corruption mechanic
now you're going to
see some corruption on
the map and you're
going to want to go
there because it's a
system that you can
interact with
exactly it's your
skill points yes
yes so you're
unlocking skill points
from that which means
you're unlocking more of
the atlas tree earlier
on your first nexus
you have to run out a
tier one map and it
will drop two skill
points it'll give you
your two first two
skill points awesome and
then you're like all
right where's my next
nexus that's where I'm
going for my next two
and then your next one
your next one and you
have to do them one
tier higher every time
so you're the second
one you go to at tier
two to get your skill
points and so on and
so forth it's not just
it's not just grind 10
maps yeah that was
that was terrible
good good I love it
so yeah it is very much
like let's go and
clear these corrupted
nexus and then it's
like well and there's
the whole mechanic around
it but yeah if you want
to just like fall I want
to get my points as
fast as possible just go
nexus to nexus to
nexus and get as many as
you can if you're like
oh I can't see any
nexus maybe go to a
tower to reveal more
and then you know what
you're doing way less
frequently mind you thank
goodness yes but yeah
it's a lot more
objective driven as
opposed to just again
random grind and random
exploration there's at
least and you should be
seeing a pretty decent
chunk of unique maps
I was gonna ask yeah
I call them unique maps
yeah it's funny because I
was pointing out the
other day the distinction
between a unique map and
a normal like there is
no distinction anymore we
shouldn't even look at
that way like it should be
that every map is like
unique in some sense
there's not a unique map
we do have an icon for
it because they are kind
of in a different echelon
but yes technically
unique map is a name
that's a holdover for
Imperial 1
yeah because they can
you can use mods with
them with waystones
anyway so there's no
actual reason for you
to be any different than
a normal map
you can craft it and
enhance it and juice it
it really just comes down
to how rare they are
relative to other things
right and how rare are
they how like
I mean uh
maybe in terms of
player screen
yeah I mean look
as I said I think
how many screens
um how many uh
I had the numbers
I just don't remember
them um
well I mean as I said
they should be common
enough that you feel
like there's always some
kind of objective you're
excited about
honestly
more common than I was
initially comfortable with
and then after trying it
I was like okay actually
this is like
yeah this is this is
reasonable so
yeah I feel like you
initially probably want
them to be common
enough that you're like
almost getting tired of
those map layouts so
then you're incentivized
to add more
the good thing is by the
way by adding more here
we didn't just keep them
the same commonality as
the two that existed
yeah like they are just
more common um it's not
like the reason part of
the reason the it wasn't
as common before is
because there was only two
and yeah that would have
just been repetitive and
boring um one of the
other restrictions is
that like um the vault of
kamasa was restricted to
the val city biomes
so to speak and that
was one of the citadel
biomes that's like one
of the rarest and latest
you know so it's like
we've not only made that
more common within that
biome but a lot of the
new one in fact all of
the new ones aren't
restricted to those city
biomes and thus they are
appearing more frequently
and some of them are like
oh you want deserts
because they give you the
essence map or you want
the mountain because they
can give you this and that
you know so like ideally
there's a little bit of
just like you see the edge
of a desert and you're
like oh my god please
yes okay so that's I was
gonna say there's like
idea of exploration is like
I felt there needed to be
something in the biomes
where like you're actually
pushing into a biome
because there's that one
node that like affected
your drop slightly but
obviously that's not much
the one that was the
shattered lakes for example
as you can probably
imagine only spawns in the
water biome and so there's
a little bit of like you
know and and so does
untainted paradise and so
does one other so there
are actually three special
maps that can spawn only in
the water so go to the
water
and otherwise how easy is
it to find you said there
was an icon obviously you
kind of have an idea of
what biomes is it like
also something that's
pretty visually oh there's
art there yeah
spotable on the map
yeah so the one we
looked at with the
megaliths which had all
the storm and lightning
well on the map it has a
bunch of storm and
lightning cool that's
awesome cute that's
great so we mentioned
the atlas passive tree
and you're seemingly I
think you're getting
better progression of
that but definitely an
issue I had with it
personally was that it
felt very top heavy
both for the core one
and also for especially
for the league
mechanics where like
the league mechanics you
don't get points until
you kill the bosses which
to me feels like the end
of it for most players
that kind of was the
original pitch of that
and I wouldn't say that's
really changing here but
there is more we want to
do with that and I think
that it could be made
better but zero to I
wasn't getting a change
there to that side but
in terms of the actual
core atlas it definitely
is you know like you're
getting that earlier you're
there's more it's a
bigger tree there's more
interesting stuff
there's subtle changes to
getting them in the sense
that like for example
the difficulty zero
pinnacle bosses are way
lower that's actually good
that's actually a very
good point so yes
difficulty zero is now
like half the life that
it had before and so
that's like a pretty
substantial change
difficulty four is
currently the same as
what it was before so
it's same top end but
like easy and more
accessible for more
people at the bottom
end and then also
because of like you
know due to the
reliquary key working
the way it does all
pinnacle bosses can drop
all uniques at all
difficulties except they
are like substantially
less common at
difficulty zero but you
feel way less bad for
running them at that
point now right so
again it's just opening
that up to a lot more
people to farm and it's
not so much dependent on
if your build can't do
difficulty four you're not
really a viable character
kind of mindset so much
more easy onboarding for
those which will give you
your first set of points
certainly a lot easier now
that being said not if
you're playing the most
broken build of all time
because you probably
nerfed into the ground
let's be real so with
your new build we'll have
to see how that balance
goes with the new broken
build yeah for sure
one of those specters
yeah yeah anyway um
the ultimate point being
yeah you're you're
you're certainly going to
get those initial set of
points easier than before
um however yeah you are
right there something
isn't quite right there
still and i do need to
kind of explore we are
going to do more with
this like later we've
we've talked about this
issue but we didn't have
time to do anything about
it in 020 as much but
um certainly by the end
of early access um i
think that that system
will probably look quite
different part of it
also as we're talking
about before adding all
that those extra bits of
content to the leagues
it'll help give more
interest to the to the
trees and more nodes we
can add to actually invest
into because i if you
think about a breach
there's only so much you
can actually modify right
now right there's there's
a level of radius speed
density of monsters and
like sure there's the
standard stuff with
monsters but like you
can only go so far when
you don't have all of
that depth of different
factions and different
bosses and different
mini bosses and
different you know
itemization or
additional things with
you know catalysts and
whatnot like you are
quite limited in how
expansive a tree can can
be and so it'd be nice
to get those things in
and also kind of look at
the trees at the same
time and reevaluate how
that works just so we can
have them be more
interesting while we're at
it right um but yeah
and now with the pinnacle
bosses if you're like
halfway through a level
you don't need to oh
maybe i'll do that when i
get the rest of the level
now yes that was a that
was a good change um so
yeah uh as as he was
saying the um as you
were saying the the you
no longer gain experience
or lose experience anymore
from um from pinnacle so
you could just feel free
to do them anytime um so
yeah i think that's just
a straight up upgrade and
um i think that you know
it's not like you were
playing pinnacle bosses
for experience so uh
yeah it does the downside
is no it's not an issue
really um yeah it also is
a nice thing of really
just keeping like if we
add more leagues for
example and we end up
with a domain of timeless
conflict problem where it's
just like rotations to
level to max level like
ultra yes we don't want
that type of like at
least now we can say
like maps are the way
you level like that is
what you're doing and
sure you might get some
sort of unique map
rotation here and you
know maybe maybe not i
don't know depends um
but hopefully we can
avoid that but either
way like it's just
really you're playing in
maps to level and that's
what you're doing and
there's something nice
about that at least
until we've added delve
well sure i mean there's
going there will be future
parallel in-game systems
confirmed i know you want
to do something i guess
yes yes you're a fan
you're a fan i mean you
made the end game look
like delv so yeah
but yeah the um there
was that's been a long
term problem and when i
need to we need to
properly apply to the
other game as well um
that the whole like not
can't do my content
because i've got a level
and i'm like even if
you're only like 15% in
like oh yeah it's just
it's just not as bad it's
just not as bad in pwee1
because the leveling is
faster yeah it's true
it doesn't it hasn't it
hasn't been on our radar
as much um yeah so
speaking of like map
progression there's been
some fundamental changes
there you're telling me
that uh now you can no
longer drop maps below
your current level of
map it's correct so
yes you'll you no longer
get if you're playing you
know a t5 map you're
only going to get uh t5
maps or if there's a boss
there a t6 map but we've
also smoothed the way the
whole progression works so
we've actually um the
map drops are way less
random now entirely um
when you kill the last
rare and a map um that
has a uh you it can
affect it at t1 that was
a hundred percent chance
to drop another map of
the same tier um and
then as you go up the
tiers um you can still
sustain that using
waystone chance so
effectively it's like
it's de-randomized that
a lot and then the way
there are several ways
that you can get
upgrades so um in terms
of like getting going up
the tiers so one of
them is is that um when
you kill a um a boss
that's a guaranteed plus
one upgrade um then
of course you can still
cube them um up you
know three to one uh
recipe to go up a level
um or you can run it
corrupted and if you're
running a corrupted map
then um because it drops
the same tier that's like
a sort of guaranteed
when i say corrupt i mean
the one that barlob
corrupting up plus one
um that that lets you um
do the uh run them the
same level as well so
you've kind of got those
three options but it's
much more intentional now
it's like if you're going
up maps it's like you're
deciding okay this is a
thing i am doing you
don't just kind of have
that like it doesn't just
happen so um it's kind
of supposed to make the
jump like if you're just
looking to sustain you can
do that pretty much
guaranteed and um uh
unless you're dying more
than the number of times
you've got portals which
is obviously you know the
thing now now that you
can go through portals
again um the uh you know
the sustain is going to be
a lot easier if you are
dying um but then it's
like once you've achieved
that it's like you
effectively can sustain
forever like the the
cases where people just
drop off the bottom and
have issues should be
like way less common
ultimately it's way less
random way more
deterministic yeah yeah
and uh ultimately you
can as long as you are
able to do the not die
all the time you will
sustain that tear forever
right assuming you can
roll enough um you know
yeah that high enough
mod count and you know i
there is a boss here i'm
going to go up a tear
yeah and you go for the
boss you kill the boss you
go up a tear and if you
and then you sustain that
tear forever as long as
you can do the difficulty
yeah yeah and it's just
very clean and if you're
adding more mods um which
you do need to be doing
uh to continue to maintain
100 percent um ability to
to to to go up tears um
then and if you're doing
that early you're getting
more maps than what other
people are getting which
means you can do the
cubing as well like it's
just kind of like it's
sort of it just much more
effectively gets the um
the thing where you know
good players can advance
at the right speed um
normal players don't fall
off the bottom of the
curve it kind of solves
all those issues like
without but also you're
not going to have just
like hordes of low-level
waystones that you don't
need um as well so you
know like and and just
know it does there are
still you can get to the
highest tiers relatively
quickly you have to prove
you're good enough your
character's good enough but
if you're you're doing it
you get there right it's
pretty quick and you can
take it at your own
leisure as well and that's
completely fine so it's
not like oh we've made it
way longer to get to tier
15 like none of that is
really the case it's just
that before you could luck
into getting to tier 15
quickly um with some level
of you know biasing the
luck of course uh or you
could just be like what the
heck i'm like constantly
running out and have a
really bad time right and
so now it's just way way
more like predictable and
um honestly it probably
has way more of an impact
on the sustain problem
which we didn't really
which we talked about
which is the respawning i
would argue this thing has
like way way way more
impact on map sustain than
the respawning does um i
mean obviously if they're
paired then they relate
both because yeah if
because the the the the
guaranteed drop comes from
the final rare so if you
were just dying you would
never get it so the
respawning is necessary in
order to make it so that
that's gonna happen um for
players who you know like
and and and and obviously
you know as it gets more
difficult that's and you
get less portals you start
to get to the point where
you're gonna run into
trouble but if you're a
good player you should be
able to get up into the
top and sustain very well
yep you mentioned the
idea of maps dropping
magic by default yes that
something you're still
doing or um i believe it
is um but actually wait
but there wasn't a
concern about that which i
wanted to talk to you
about later maybe not
yeah well we'll talk
about that later because
um the concern was raised
that i think is valid so
uh yeah we were going to
make it so that maps drop
magic and above but we're
actually there might be
issues so we'll discuss
that uh later on well
non-decided yeah undecided
yeah you thought it was
decided i just got a week
left we've got a week
left it's fine
still figuring uh it
sounds like much more
deterministic progression
but yes that's the main
of the power that you
have that's the main
it just should be am i
strong enough to do this
yes i can do it all right
not am i lucky enough to
do this and am i strong
enough to do this great um
one of those axes get
out of here love it um
so we've got rogue
exiles populating the
maps now how common are
these guys especially with
unique since you get their
unique guarantee i love
that um it's one in uh
eight percent one and one
and twelve and a half to
start with but of course
atlas tree be atlas tree
um so you can speak into
that and is there like a
map modifier for that or
something to guarantee it
uh there are i think in
this case there are this
one is the exception
whereas that you can get
normally guaranteed of the
other things we wanted the
exiles to be one that you
can't just guarantee all the
time they don't always have
uniques yeah um but when
they do they yeah they're
using them the air the air is
very cool like how it works
i mean they can have zero
one two i mean yeah there's
nothing stopping them from
having uniques in every slot
what but like it is the
chance of that would be it
is absurdly rare um i assume
it's just roll per slot
basically right yeah
it's roll per slot so
yeah yeah yeah but you
might have a line of
fraction of a fraction of
a percent like all of them
but still like five or
something like that yeah
you can have them and
they have quite a lot like
because they're a player the
assumption is that their
other gear is also
relatively good so they do
generally drop more bias
towards dropping higher tier
rares and stuff like that
yeah they're doing that
like full set of items
because you've killed a
player yep cool i like that
i always love that little
thing and i feel like it's
even more important here in
piri too so right that's
awesome but just some of
those will be unique maybe
we wanted them to be less
common than the other
content but like way more
exhilarating when you find
them yeah um but of course
again you can speak into
them um at the cost of
other things that's your
choice um is there going to
be some sort of like
warning that they're coming
or are you going to know
they're in the map ahead of
time or are you just gonna
get ambushed by these guys
leave some of them up you won't
know they're in the map ahead
of time much like anything
random you run into but they
talk though and they they'll
say they'll say something
before they they uh they
monologue before they
they do i don't know if i'd
go quite the level of
monologue when i said some
insult you i'm not joking
like some do literally insult
you and um i believe one of
them is one of them is one of
the monks is a pacifist and
he's like i don't want to do
this don't force my hand he'll
do it anyway i'm not i'm just
you're just like running
away exactly don't make me
do this don't force my hand
you can just run away um you
know i i really like the um
here's a occasional spike in
difficulty and again it's
important that they are
relatively rare for that
reason as well um but i do
want it to be when you find
one you are very excited to
kill it and of course even
though they portal out you
still have your number of
portals you have so unless
you're running like a full six
modded waystone just get back
in there and and he's gone
but or you're not
whatever you've lost your
uniques or non-uniques
whatever they had but either
way just move on you know
i mean you guys were somewhat
forgiving with this you
didn't make it so that they
take your items
yes that would have been
good that's a that's an
event don't give me that
idea that's maybe a one week
event or something in the
future
just take one of your items
and then you got a nameless
system where you can find
them and try and get it back
in the future
and you had the tame rogue
exile gym
i don't tames the room
higher higher
higher
higher exile
you run up and you can
quickly be like take a million
gold
just give him a little snack
like yeah you want to follow me
i mean to be fair that would be
a fun system
it actually would that's
actually not a bad idea
running up and just being like
hey i'm here give me a hundred
thousand gold and i'll be your
ally
i know you've tinkered with the
idea of a hireling system at
points in the past so
and now you've got your
mercenary hireling system right
right
you recruit the one with good
uniques
we'll see
go on now a little bit of a
rabbit hole here
so we did have some league
mechanics come over from path of
exile one
two
path of exile two
uh you're going to be looking
to port more over are you
going to be doing some unique
ones that we haven't seen
before
i mean we're definitely going to
be doing more unique ones
that are you know that are just
completely different outside of what
we've done in pere we won uh
absolutely
um but i mean we like the i
think that like
sort of the hope in the long
term is that each
like you know as we kind of get
you know past the end of early
access and as we're sort of you
know just going out that each um
time we do something we're both
adding a completely new league
mechanic but also potentially
bring something back
as well kind of like as another
additional kind of like here's
another fun thing
so um that's probably sort of
what i imagine will happen but um
it kind of really is case by
case like some things we don't
want to bring back some things we
do you know like in our in my
opinion can change on a dime as
well like if someone suggests
like a new way to interpret
something then i might be like
oh you know actually that is
great
so um you know it honestly it
people assume that we have a
full plan of little everything
but it's like in reality it's like
it's very much responsive to like
what's happening and like you know
the the plan the plan we the the
actual plan relates to the things
that like it definitely happened
right you know you're talking acts
you're talking classes you're
talking like all that stuff is
like definitely you know like
that's happening it takes a long
time produced it sort of happens
in the background you've got
outsources armies of people kind
of working on that stuff and then
all the kind of like more
incidentally stuff is very much
like oh you know let's do
something cool let's just make
this why we do this you know and
we don't have a you know i don't
have a plan for the next you know
12 strong boxes it's just you know
come up with an idea and like you
know that's cool um you know just a
fun little project for a designer to
to work on how do you feel like
some of the ones that were i felt
somewhat definitively part of
exile one in terms of clear speed
like breach for example have settled
in the peewee too do you feel like
they're in a good spot or were they
a good idea to bring over to the
game um look i think breach is i
mean breach breach is fun right i
wouldn't i certainly wouldn't want
to remove it um i don't know about
like i mean there's probably been
some balance changes i mean it was
squarming too many it has let's just
say that without a doubt it's much
better now to two standards yeah and
um it's too like currently on pewee
too it's just too out of control
this needs to chill there was a little
bit of an assumption made where it
was just like well you'll get
overwhelmed by monsters and it's
more a matter of survive as long as
you can and then of course because
you get self-propagating herald
builds that literally can kill
anything which by the way heralds
don't self-propagate anymore just
just just get that out of the way
right now the power of the characters
kind of yeah yeah distorted the league
balance in a way where it's like we
have to you know make some changes so
yes yeah like it's coming down a bit
i think we saw that one coming yeah
well 100 i mean look there's a lot
of things people will say they saw
coming but um it certainly does end
up being the case that like the
patch notes are uh you know when we so
by the way we're not we aren't
releasing them at the end of this
live stream we're going to be
releasing them next week um but they
are going to feel like a bit of a
nerf fest for sure because um like
there's a lot of things that needed
to get you know let's let's talk
balance yeah yeah all right all right
my expectations and anticipations are
that this first one is going to be an
absolute wrecking ball of chaos and
carnage and see where things land yeah
but then maybe over time it'll become
a sledgehammer and then like a fine
carpenter hammer sure that that
definitely should be the case as i
said earlier it's like 10 000 things
will change this time 5 000 things
will change next time then hopefully
we can have it every single time
people people should really be going
in with the expectation that like
nothing they knew about how the game
was balanced before is the same just
forget everything yes forget
everything you know
exactly so uh yeah basically we'll uh
that that kind of just means that
like you know everyone who's finding
builds like do it again like you're
you're going to find more shit that
is like outrageously broken again but
it is not going to be the same shit
that was broken before um so uh yeah
attribute stacking get out of here
yeah yeah exactly
so i mean it's it's it's the the hope
is though that yes you're right it'll
stabilize to the point like like i i it
will take time but we will get to the
point where we no longer have things
that are easy to become outrageous with
right like the idea is like it shouldn't
be that you can just slap a few
different a combination of supports
together and then like you're just
like destroying pinnacles in 14
seconds you know like it should be
that it's a long time yeah okay sure
uh but you mean 40 that sounds like
terrible yeah exactly not even on
pwe yeah that's that one seconds
with no items right but uh anyway so
the point is the point is is that like
the first time you fight a pinnacle
it should be a bit of a fight but then
of course you do get back to the
ability after you know like with like
kind of like continuing to expand
like continue to develop your character
post pinnacle to the point of being
able to annihilate them in seconds yeah um
but it's just like that has to be
earned it can't just be that like
just a combination of supports that
you can get trivially will do that or
you're like a common unique you know
and then that's yeah exactly right so
but it can be but once you put if you
get temporalis you know it's like well
now you know like now you've got some
you've got some shit going on but it's
it really has to be that you know
there's there's there is an economic
factor involved in becoming ridiculous
yes um and so it's when that's not
the case that we have a problem that um
we need to hit shit with a big giant
balance sledgehammer yeah so originally
i was gonna come in and like ask about
all the specific things but we just
assume that like it's not gonna be
chaos so i like the idea instead of
focusing on kind of like your core what
are you what are you aiming for what
are your goals what are your like what
are your metrics
a number of like damage slash how fast
you kill a pinnacle boss yeah that's
your that you're aiming for and then how
much players can exceed that and you're
like
yeah so it really should be that you're
not killing as i said not killing
pinnacle bosses that fast um at the
moment like a good sort of benchmark for
like just a guy walks in and uh like
has kind of got something that's like
not stupid but also like not like doing
something you know like not not crazy and
we kind of imagine they should have about
50k um dps um doing something like that
but at the same time anything up to 500k
dps is 10 times you know is is also
okay and well that that'll take you from
taking a three minute fight down to like a
20 second fight like you know that's your
range of like potentially acceptable yeah
kind of things going on but if you're
doing above uh that then you're in like
we're probably going to nerf you territory
at some point so um that's kind of like
think now it's worth mentioning that like
we've lowered like the life of pinnacle
bosses to get that to be right and sort
of things like the difference between a
t15 boss and a pinnacle boss was just
way too much um so uh that has been um
that that's been sorted out um like it's
things like that that we just need to get
things in the right place here um so
that's our sort of expectation um now
obviously people are going to still find
ways to get 10 million dps somehow i'm
sure even though we're like nerfing many
things um but um the thing i think that
when we're talking about nerfs and how we
want to do my key thing that i want to
try and achieve always is that whenever
we're nerfing something we're only nerfing
the thing that was particularly um like
like we're nerfing as little as possible
to make it so that the average joe who
works in and just tries to do stuff is
not getting affected by it yeah it should
only be the like ridiculously broken synergy
thing that kind of like has some way of
dealing with it that's um uh that's
that's like that's actually affected by
this and um i'm struggling to think of an
example of tom ahead maybe you've got
some of like you know a way that a
targeted nerf that kind of i mean like
say uh lightning conduit you're not going
to reduce the base damage of it because
someone's able to hit for 150 million
with one hit from it like that comes
from the compounding like top end levels
of exposure stacking conductivity and more
so shock effect right so it's more about
like take away from the shock effect scaling
side of things there and increase the base
damage even you know like do changes like
that where it's like for an average person
it's now better and for someone who is
absolutely i'm abusing is not the right
word because like they're doing the right
thing technically by their standards um that
are using all those extreme factors you
know bring those down a little bit keep
those regulated and like it'll increase the
average user's experience while not while
narrowing you know bringing this down and
bringing this ideally up a little bit in a
lot of cases i like the idea that i thought
some are reassuring to hear that there was
actually kind of like a math here like
ultimately you're saying bosses have x amount
of hit points it has 500k hit points and so
we expect players around 50 yes right so
that's a that's a clear number like we know
that oh yeah and we're okay with you killing
that like 10 times faster than we expect
right but it's when you get it down to one
second exactly 10 times is fine right and the
problem with the more dps you have it is now i
have to dodge less yeah i get more crowd
control as a snowball you know it is it really
is so you're always gonna be incentivized to do
that and um yeah it you get to this weird thing
where now it's just like okay well i think you
after a while i was like i haven't actually seen a
pinnacle boss fight that lasted more than two
seconds that was really sad to me probably the
saddest thing about the early access launch to
me was seeing the first pinnacle boss fight and it
just like and it's like oh you know like it's
like nobody you literally nobody had to care
about the mechanics the first time i gave it so
many skills exactly right like there's so many
skills and all these things and it's like none of
it mattered but so that's sad yeah um so yeah we
ideally was in a situation now i am i hope that
doesn't happen again but honestly it's probably
wishful thinking uh yeah yeah 10 000 things
before there's still gonna be yeah there's still
gonna be more and it will happen every time and
people will find stuff and but we'll but
look this again by the end of early access i
want to say we're going to be in a real fucking good
spot with this in a way that is not going to have
so much abusive stuff and getting rid of that
whole i feel like i have to play x it is it is
that very demoralizing to players when they played
their thing and all of a sudden something comes
out and they're like oh and so the way the way you
will know that we're successful is because you get
more diversity in class in classes because it
means that there's no longer the thing that
everyone has to play because it's easy to i mean you
definitely saw that where it's like the comments
of any build guide it's like oh another archmage
build or exactly it's just heralds exactly it's
like this isn't even a build this is just herald
again you go look at like what are all crossbow
people playing and crossbows is actually the least
used weapon type and so you specifically start
there and you're like okay well here's a bunch
of people using these skills hand of wisdom and
action hand of wisdom and action hand of
okay well never mind the crossbows are relevant
right yeah even without stat stacking still
better yeah and it's like okay well you know
obviously take some away from there and then
it's like okay well what are you left with well
you're still left with probably crossbows are bad
so what do you have to do and it's like you know
crossbows now for example just a quick change is
like instead of using one-handed um one-handed
damage mods for added damage they use two-handed and
their base damage and then um all the skills now
have a higher growth per level because they scale
with other external factors like attack speed less
because they have the reload time so yeah they
will be getting more damage per level whereas before
most skills were very consistently growing per
level so almost every spell would get the same
amount of damage per level regardless of everything
else it had and this is how you got things like
spark just being the dominant skill you know out
of control because it scales not only that it
scales obviously the number of projectiles
kind of out of control and with projectile and
duration and other multiplicative scaling factors
you end up with just like well of course i'm just
going to spark everywhere and so now it's like
well spark has these other multiplicative things so
it should get less damage per level and this
wasn't probably one and was the right answer and
we somehow didn't replicate that exact thing that
we did yeah everything is at the same damage
growth yes we end up with exactly the same so
now every single skill we're being looking we're
looking at it and going you can you're going to
scale more you're going to scale less you're going
to scale more on the damage axis because they have
other things that scale and this just means that
like when you're asking well what skills have
changed the answer is literally all of them
no skill will have no skill will have the same
damage as before it's like a complete you know a
complete rebalance of the whole thing expectation
wise it means that any skill that didn't have a lot
of things you could do for it we'll just get we'll get
more damage uh yeah that should be the case but i mean
even as well like when we're looking at things like i
sort of mentioned it vaguely before but like i'm
trying to make sure like we are trying to make sure
that like the combos that work early games still work
late game um which is kind of another important
element of that too yeah yeah so crossbow has been
buffed a lot and i also had the other thing that was
definitely getting a lot of buffs as warrior as well
i mean we'll we'll see how that looks i mean
everything and everything up and everything down
it's so hard to even like yeah yeah it's it's so hard to
have like a cohesive message with a single like this
class is better yeah yeah because it's just i mean it's
easy for mercenary skills or for crossbow skills because
i can look at those numbers and just be like okay
everything's clearly higher yeah but then in others it's
like it's so it's it's too easy to say it's like warrior
was like in many cases there was a lot of things that
it was actually not bad like it was good in many ways but
then it didn't it didn't have anything that was outrageously
broken like how the other classes did yeah and it didn't
gel with all players in many ways as well we've also
done balance changes on literally every snse class as
well yeah um you know pathfinder has like two extra
notables and some changes you've got a new notable on
chronomancer you've got um a change like you know
chrono was way too much too much utility stuff like
where's just my like good thing you know so like you got like a good
there's my bonk node yeah yeah less less niche more something and then
we've just done that on every single class we've upped
upped a lot of the undertaken or bad things and we've downed a lot of
the really good powerful things that were over the top so
this is why we've gone back to the more conventional patch note cycle of
a couple days beforehand maybe yeah i mean look
absolutely if they were ready you would have them
they're not ready because we're not finished right like and giving someone half the
balance changes doesn't make allow them to even make educated decisions on
what does it help you so it's completely pointless at that point
so we'd rather give you everything all at once instead of just some like here's
you know but even if even once you have the patch notes like don't even be
under the mistaken illusion that you'll be somehow able to determine what the
best builds are from that like uh this it's because it's such a big
difference it's hard to take things into context because you can look at it and
say oh okay so like this thing got buffed but this thing got nerfed it's like
okay but you're linking just two things you're not linking all of the other
things yeah exactly so you know yeah we'll try though we'll try sure
give it a shot do your best look when the game released you uh had to learn
everything you just might have to do it again
and again every single patch after every major patch after this you know you're
going to have to have less and less of that and your familiarity will be able to
come in and be useful um so at least from a balanced perspective at this point
like you know it's not like we've structurally changed the campaign and all that so you
have still a lot of information and knowledge that is going to help you play the game
better anyway from the on your you know second i mean a lot of people made maybe
made multiple characters but for a lot of people this might just be their second
character yeah so they're certainly going to be more equipped and we've had the
races so you've been able to see how the best people oh yeah oh yeah
there's some definitely some good tips to learn from there oh yeah
that lever skip with the portal beautiful my favorite
um on the slightly bigger picture as well like life and armor versus energy shields are you happy
with kind of where either of those are at or what do you what do you kind of hope to achieve
with them energy shields certainly i mean primarily due to grim feast um and like mana
stacking being a little bit out of control have been that's been too strong and more the inside
of defense for sure um expect some pretty drastic changes there um as for armor well you know it's one of
those like accuracy kind of things right where it's like dexterity and like you know where it's
like honestly our next point with that is honestly just to get in a room and just be like all right
let's pretend it didn't exist and we were coming up with the game from scratch and uh you know we're
like okay we have strength what would we want the ideal defense to be and honestly might even extend
further than that and really just see firstly to make sure we end up if we don't end up at the same
point make sure we end up as better maybe we do end up at the same point and we do just go okay here
are some other changes that we need to make around physical damage in particular and something like
that but it's one of those things where at this point we just need to like review it from literally
back to basics and see where we end up because it might be something completely different but like
it might also end up being relatively the same and maybe it was the better answer but either way it's
worth the discussion with the time because you know it's i wouldn't say we're happy with it and
i wouldn't say we're necessarily like all the way unhappy with it but it's yeah there's something not
not quite right going on for sure you're still fundamentally questioning some of these things and
willing to go back to the drawing board on them which is quite interesting well 100 we drastically
changed how evasion works and i would say it's for the better you know and we should be exploring that
with everything and um you know so we just need to do that process still um you know that being said
you know as we make things more like the shield block better as we um buff the ascendancies or
nerf them and and you know on the other defensive arcs um you know things like armor will become better
but yeah again it's not quite right but i don't have enough information to say you know where it will
look what it will look like in the future so yeah okay cool um so let's talk about recovery as well
because that's another big thing i remember early on exile con discussions about the importance of
limited recovery in making combat matter you know so that you could have situations where you're
attritioned or where like the hit that you took matters for the next hit that you take and you know
just back up the full but um it's pretty good in boss fights honestly i feel like recovery is
somewhat limited that still happens a bit but uh certainly in clearing you have access to tons of
recovery with yeah cannibalism and things like that it's certainly out of control and it's a
little bit of again partly due to the fact that um kill speed and clear speed just was way higher
than we had expected and what we balanced around and um because if we were balancing around what
people are currently doing with the the upper echelons of builds you'd like you know you'd have to
have effectively every average player and average build just could be completely it would be
useless for them um now there are ways around that of course but um part of it is like a lot of the
recovery mechanics like if you're talking about things like on kill and based on damage doubt
it's it is a rich get richer problem and um so yes there are cases that are problematic and then
there are just characters that are too strong and there's a little bit of both going on i wouldn't
say we've targeted any recovery specifically here really it's not been a main goal i'm not going to
say that there aren't little bits changed here and there but it's more about you know we've really
made sure to just it's kind of hard to say exactly what we've done because again this is probably
everything we're going to have to look at next time because there are so many changes that it is hard
to even like understand how this is going to fit into once the dust clears you might be able to see
100 like we're at the point where we do need a little bit of like all right we need another round
of testing for this because yeah you know and again i'm going to stress it is actually impossible
for the amount of changes for us internally to be able to be certain or test all of this yeah but the
the vision is is still that idea of like more stricter recovery or less powerful recovery than
what well it shouldn't certainly be like here's one little one little piece and now it's fully
solved right like yeah having heaps of recovery should be something you can achieve but it should
require a decent amount of investment or high tier item okay itemization right like for sure it should
be possible it just shouldn't be trivial yeah so and on that note then for like vision what's your
vision of what path of exile 2 is supposed to be because i think some people are still like unsure
about is it supposed to be just kind of more like path of exile 1 a faster game or is it supposed to
be a slower game a much more different thing like this is a hard thing to communicate but it still it
gets asked a lot and i feel like people are still a bit unsure it's funny though because like once
again it's not i don't view it as just a pure speed question it's about like is the combat engaging
and fun yeah and also are you getting to the point where you never get to engage with bosses
like if you're never if if if the first time you fight a boss you just destroy it without seeing
any of its mechanics then that's a problem and it doesn't really say anything about the pace of
combat like if you look at some of the um the hunter stuff we've got there like it's incredibly fast
paced when it comes to like dashing around and stuff but you still have to engage with things and
that's the key element for us so um you know like obviously players want to get ridiculously powerful and we
still want to let them get ridiculously powerful just has to be earned it has to be you know like
after a certain point and like after you like once you have finished your character once you've sort
of done everything then yeah you should be just like you know like like crazy and like beyond the
point of any of all reason it's just that you have to earn it you have to get there right and like
that's the power growth thing that's like it's really hard to sort of just like smoothen that out
across the whole game but like that's ultimately the goal right you have to kind of get to the point of
like that you constantly feel you're getting stronger you always feel like the next like oh i got this and now
i'm better and now i'm better and now i'm better and keep on going and you have to scale that all
the way to the end because the moment that you get to the point where you're just trivializing
everything too early it's like well the rest of the game just becomes boring after that point right
it has to be that you know there's the level of that that you still still have to get and so kind
of based on that just earlier discussions about like damage and boss time to kill and things like
that it sounds like the time where you want that to be starting to taper off like the players can start
to cheat that a bit is after they've done pinnacle bosses well you should feel that way multiple times
throughout the game but then later you still then get to a new level of challenge the store
requires to engage again like if we're doing our job correctly it's like you you reach a point of
feeling like you're a god and then you're like oh shit but there's new god like shit above me that
then makes me have to then do the exactly exactly right so you you have to keep on you have to keep
on with that it's actually really hard to take you back from feeling like oh i'm i'm all powerful back
down to like i'm feeling you know and so you have to kind of get that that in there as you want that
dragon ball anime arc yeah for sure right there's always a new level of super saiyan after the previous one
exactly right that's what you have to be able to do and so yeah it's just smoothly taking up that
up that power level curve um you know all the way to the end yeah so i think like when it comes down
to things like movement speed when clearing it's about like if you're able to just ignore everything
because you're moving yeah exactly if you're able to ignore everything then um then then you obviously
will move really fast if you're not able to ignore everything suddenly your clear speed is like not as
big of a thing so so long as there are still things that are challenging you as long as you reach the
next tear and like everything's harder again then you're good i feel like a difficult like a
point of the difficulty here between the communication of this with you guys and some
of the people in the community is that i feel like you're not really looking at it in terms of pwee one
versus two you're just you're just trying to answer that question specifically yeah it's not really
about like it being like pwee one or two exactly right it's just about making the combat good it's
either the combat is fun or it isn't yeah yeah and there's a sort of spectrum of stuff there but i would
say that you want to be able to engage with the boss you want to be able to fight its mechanics and use it do
it's skills and you want to feel like you can overcome those over time and get better and you
want to engage with monsters and you want and yeah there's probably some people who are like no i
don't i want to just press a button and loot drops on the ground and i don't have to look or do anything
and well so that's an interesting point is there's this uh let's let's say the quote unquote mythical
average build um is are they able to switch their brain off and watch netflix on the second monitor
only if they're doing like maps three levels under what they should be doing or something
or should that be able to happen at kind of like once you're at your your tier of godhood
yeah but i actually want to address that because like okay so i'm watching well okay right now i'm
watching deep space nine funnily enough but but uh but uh you know i'm watching deep space nine as i'm
playing as i'm testing the game right it's like you just you develop a muscle memory and that muscle
memory can include using multiple skills and doing like multiple things and that's still to me more
engaging than just holding down a button you know so you're saying this like watching things on the
secondary thing isn't about the game being easy it's just a skill issue i'm just saying that you
like you you you your your your muscle memory can develop for more than just using a single skill
you just you know like and and we've always sort of said that there's this thing like okay sometimes
sometimes you pause you pause the show right sometimes that happens because you come to a
thing that's like uh this is an update to the classic you know second monitor i love how this freaking
watching something on the second screen has become such a fundamental part of the community's just
grabbed it and it's become a thing forever but it's up it's been updated now like this is the
update you want you want them to have to pause sometimes it was a philosophy set for a different
because i feel like i've said that 10 years ago about how like sometimes you get the spike in
difficulty you know like now you have to do this to me yeah i guess that turns into pause the video
at this point but uh yeah but no but look if i i i play this way as well right look it's not like i'm
you know like once once you get to a certain point it's like you know obviously you're going to want to
you know the music you've heard it in lots of times you know like you want to have something else going on that's
that's fine um but uh i still think that there needs to be the ability to um have um uh you know
to to have something engaging from time to time that you have to do deal with so yeah it's always
been a bit of a silly a silly thing because you've got so much element of choose your own difficulty
in part of exile right like exactly do harder maps do easy maps but um i mean but look people always
want to choose the harder stuff right so therefore that's what they're judging it against that's true
and so that's why you do need a level of economic gating to make it so that like you know you can't go too
far with difficulty without um uh you know without having to prove the the economic stuff on some
level so that you can yeah you're dying and losing the map exactly you're losing the map um so um yeah
that like we have to think like all that map sustain stuff is so tricky for that reason yeah that's
exactly right um yeah that sounds like some big advancements in that regards um so i've got some
kind of random tale questions here um are you planning in the future on i don't think it's probably
happening this time around but on changing campaign pacing at all like i feel like some of the zones are
probably a bit too large and a bit too empty um i mean that's more about adding more stuff to them
than it is about making them smaller like um there's still a lot more events and campaign that
we haven't added yet that i'm still doing there's like big lists of you know things that we never
got time to do so we'll keep on getting to those and the argument there which i i do believe in is an
area should be able to be large if it has enough interesting things the frequency of interesting
things is high i mean i mean yeah like the size of an area is completely right like imagine we had
imagine there were no load screens you just walked from place to place like you wouldn't be thinking
about area size exactly it's just is the density of interest enough it's true um you know like the
the fact that there happens to be a load screen between one place and the other is not really
the wrong is directly yeah proportional to interesting exactly right so yeah so so to me one thing we do
need to obviously do and we have done in some areas is just making sure that if it is a large area um
it's not just interesting things to find as well it's also making sure there's enough monster variety
that way it's not just so repetitive yeah exactly yeah yeah where you've got like almost different
there are some where i would say the area is uh large enough or you're in there long enough such
that there isn't enough and there isn't enough monster variants and so it gets a bit repetitive
yeah it's completely true that anytime someone says oh this area is too large i'm like well okay
so what monsters are we changing what uh what events are we adding that kind of stuff right because
that that's the way that you change around like them there are areas that are very large that no one
complains about because they're you know stuff they got a lot of things there's also like there are good
i don't know how many you know people are going to play this or how many people stop playing before
uh 0.1.1 but like you know it's worth noting again like areas have like the fast travel thing now as well
yeah it's only between checkpoints and um you know there's there's some of that stuff which i'm hoping
again when people start playing from scratch they get to see a lot of the improvements we did before as well
and see how they feel about it again and it's worth mentioning through campaign we've got both the
wisps and there's also strong boxes as well through campaign like they feel a little bit different
as you know there's just as you play through you're certainly finding some things you wouldn't
have tried soon yeah yeah the what the shrines i'll have them actually in the campaign soon yeah cool
art wasn't quite done right or something like that yeah yeah it might be a bit weird the ones in
end game it works a little bit better narratively but using that asset throughout the campaign it
would feel real random so um it's just a matter of as soon as the art's done um
chucking those in as well oh great so that could be a after it would certainly be shortly after but
but also like every time we do uh like that we're expecting people to play through again like we'll
probably tweak like which the content spawns are different areas and we'll just like fiddle around
a bit so that then you play it just feels a bit fresh and you know things going on there yeah you
kind of got me there i feel like each of the zones i'm trying to think of that like feel like they're
way too big is like they're also just coincidentally empty yes so i guess that is maybe
perhaps it's the exact same problem happens in maps by the way yeah yeah i mean yeah we talked
about that like the exact boring empty map when when when when the maps when people say the maps
too big yeah just not i think i i think i've phrased it to jonathan yesterday when we're talking about
it as every screen looks the same as every other screen it wouldn't matter where i'm standing in
the map it would look i think the map you were talking about was step like we were looking at step and
being like okay well what's actually like it's a big square yeah yeah there's not there's nothing going on
and even if there was stuff going on i mean like it's funny because like it took us a little while
to even come to an understanding of like what needed to change there because i'm sort of saying
like okay well um you know like uh it's very random it's like you know do you find the cold plains and
d2 as to be a boring area because it's ultimately kind of similar um but the answer is well there's
buildings sometimes and you get like you know there's just like you just there's just a little more
going on than that way so like we need to make sure that maps feel that way too yeah yeah yeah
um there has been a few pervasive crashes and issues oh god yes yes well i'll tell you what
the entire engine team have basically been entirely focused on that for three months and it's been
horrible because um so i mean it's kind of a long story and i don't know if i should go into all of
it but ultimately um the issue is that um on nvidia cards the remaining issue at least is that on video
cards if you're using a driver that's bigger than i think 560 point something like basically after that
point the game crashes and if you install an older driver than that it doesn't um and um like like
the crash happens in the in the driver in the gpu um nvidia is just like not really much help you
know like and so it's like just trying to nail down what it even caused it it's just so hard when it's
like and the thing that sucks about it is like it won't reproduce on anywhere except production and
alpha and like a moment you change you look at it like we can't reproduce it anymore and yet for some
people it happens all the time and it's just like it's so horrible um and like you know the the
what we've we actually come up with a somewhat ridiculous idea um that was now implementing
which we're going into 020 with by the way which is that um and this will seem stupid but like how
about we just don't crash which tell me about this yeah yeah exactly so basically what we do is what
we're now changing it to is that if the gpu driver crashes if the gpu driver crashes what we do is we
create a new uh a new um uh device and then upload all the textures to that um the game is paused while
this is happening and then it unpauses and then uh the game keeps going and so that is what that is
what we're doing to solve this crap and it's like it was it's kind of ridiculous that this has to be
the solution because like we like it just it's it's just mysteriously in the nvidia driver we have
like and we have tried to find a workaround for this it is just like so difficult um and um so that
in zero to that's what will happen so do the while we're here like do the players have a workaround
like well like yeah yeah you can you can install the driver earlier than what about vulcan does that
matter uh yes uh well but no not entirely it does still happen uh in vulcan but well it's a bit
unclear uh about that particular thing about whether or not that that that's this but i figured it
might be no no it is it is it isn't it isn't it isn't the driver but um i mean yeah like if you if
you install an older driver it will go away um like so all of this time when people have been
saying the classic armchair developer meme it was like why don't you just add a bit of code that says
if crash equals false yeah well you know something like that basically yeah basically do the engineering
to allow us to just recreate the entire like gpu context uh and then there you go and then don't
crash and that is actually the solution we're now doing with but um it's it's like the thing is the
other one that sucked though was that stupid damn full system freeze because i'll tell you what if
the entire system freezes there is just nothing you can do to find out what the hell caused it
because like you know nothing there's no like crash report there's no logging there's no literally
nothing right and it's like that happened um that that happened when um the the windows november
h2 update shipped and then things just started mysteriously freezing and um my god that was hard to
track down and you know you asked microsoft about it they're like oh we'll look into it and it's
like nothing happens you know it's like jesus christ guys like you know like like it's it's it's it's so
annoying i can feel your frustration is incredibly frustrating because it's like we want nothing
better than to fix this shit um so that one was fixed like um there was some spin lock implementation
that like i don't have any understanding of why it causes it to happen but we tweaked it a bit and now
it doesn't happen anymore and it's like there's no rational reason why this should cause the operating
system to freeze and it's like there's not even a good answer at the end there's not even like a here's what
was wrong it's just like this random particular sequence of operations being done causes your
entire system to freeze for no reason after this windows update and it's like well cool you know
like what do you what do you do about that like it's just it's just it's just terrible and um so
yeah that one sucked um but basically now i mean it's funny because we've fixed so many crashes that
weren't the crash so like general stability apart from that crash is incredibly good now 99 yeah like
maybe probably yeah and it's like and it's like and it's like the thing is we'll we'll fix a crash
and we'll be like oh maybe this is the crash and then it fixes like two percent of crashes and you're
like well that wasn't the crash but at least it looks good to fix right like you know it's it's it's
it's it's so annoying um yeah but as i said we have a workaround now that's good that that will
read basically recreate the graphics device if you might get a pause and you'll get a pause for three
seconds and then um you know like roughly depending on sounds like a and then it will continue and the
game will pause it you know i obviously just make it clear we don't want it to remain like that
obviously yes yes obviously we'll still try and fix it but at least it means you're not crashing um
and you're certainly not freezing anymore that's sorted out um and then you know we found another
one recently which was like okay so this this is another stupid one right like so anyway so there's
the whole like intel um cpu issue like on 13th and 14th generation intel cpus where like there's
some freaking voltage regulation problem that causes cpus to break in a certain way um and uh if that
happens then like the thing that will break is that like um the decompressor will like like it'll
decompress something and like one bit of it will be wrong like literally one bit in there and then
it fails like a hash check and then that just causes the game to crash and so the fix like you
know it's like things like that will happen as well like you've got you've got stuff like that and it's
like well once again it's like it's like it is our problem we have to fix it because it's affecting
real users but like the solution um to stuff like that um yeah it's just so annoying to find um and
you know so yeah anyway it sounds like you've improved a lot of the unrelated crashes and you've
come up with a good workaround at least hopefully yeah that sounds like a massive improvement but i
also just think your your obvious frustration is very validating for people who have been frustrated
with this exactly but the thing and the thing that's the most annoying about it is that like all
these uh the engine team who are spending time fixing this and they're not able to spend time
working on performance issues which you know is something else that we need to be obviously
improving over time um so uh you know there's been a few performance improvements but like not nearly
the number we would have had if we had all you know seven of those people tied up like you know
like like working on uh performance improvements so you know that's uh that that's been the most
frustrating thing about it crashes first yeah 100 but it's like yeah when they're when they're kind
of we have been chipping away at some decent ones though yeah no we have we got some pretty yeah
good performance problems resolved yeah i mean there's that ice one that was really bad yeah you know
there's things like so like the worst offenders we're certainly fixing but um and like i have no doubt by the
time we get um you know like like each time we do a new release there'll be it'll be even better yeah
great um you know and and yeah by the time we get a full release i'm sure it'll be like very good and
i mean speaking of i know it's like tangential sort of as well obviously with we had a lot of woes
around the release but we've done a whole lot of back-end engineering work to make it yes you know yes
yes so um yeah the the launch should go smoother as far as like um you know it was pretty good it
was wow it still was five hours of yeah yeah yeah yeah but like five hours could be no no no this time
this time i mean i'm tempting i'm tempting fate here but like we've made significant improvements to
um the ability for the realm to handle stuff so so five minutes this time well i mean we'll see right
you never know what's gonna go wrong sometimes get caught out by something random yeah yeah it should
be much better this time yeah yeah i hope you get enough players to stress your theory yes that's
always a good thing to aim for uh we'll just run up with a couple of the random kind of chat questions
before we finish up today um any possibility of ascendancy respects is that something you've
considered especially with all the changes going on um we're sort of not in love with it um like
it's just one of those things where like i feel like it's key to the identity of the character and
like respecting like the the journey of the character like it does get pretty significantly
compromised if you um if you allow for that but i know mark is especially strong strongly yeah i mean
the answer is going to be the exact same same as last time which is like i don't know exactly or i
don't know how to articulate exactly why i feel so strongly about this and so do a lot of the team
members of like again it's just that your choices should matter and you know it's obviously something
that i was okay with impure we won and so there is probably a world where i will be okay but
there's got to be some level of work involved to achieve it that isn't to just pay a little bit of
gold and then you're done or whatever like i want to find a way to do it if we're going to do it in a
way that is like grounded that's interesting and it's difficult to we're not i wouldn't say difficult
but like requires some actual work to do so um that would be the compromise i'd certainly be willing
to explore which i have been thinking about recently because i know every single time we come to a
expansion it's going to come up so the trial of respecting or something yeah there'll be something
where your character has to undergo some sort of challenge or something to do it and i know you
could argue while doing the trial is that and you're not entirely wrong but something a bit a bit more
sacrifice a few enemies i'm sure we'll have a conclusive decision or at least a level of
articulation one way or the other by the end of early access um but uh for now yeah it's just
going to take me a bit more time to figure out what i want to do there um is dynamic switching
between keyboard and mouse and controller coming at all that's not in zero to oh but it will be
coming on its way yes like and i'm really hoping by zero three oh like we should be able to get that
that is a very key feature um it seems like it's going to be hard to juice loot uh to loot juice maps
with only one portal on i remember this this question has already been answered well actually no
because this is a concern we have to figure it out yeah so in the next week we will actually be
looking into this one there's a few problems around it still there are other things to come
up like yeah you know you also don't want it to be that if you did use your one portal you because
it's your portal that's used not everyone's portal that's used because when it says that's actually a
good point yeah it's a good point i think we mentioned up to six players yeah yeah and so when
it's six portals it's six portals for up to six players which means technically it's 36 entries and exits
out of the map right and like that changes things in a way where it's like when it's down to one it's
like you don't want it to be that oh i failed the map quick ziggy come join my party get in here and
finish it for me um you know you don't want to kind of have that style of um play happening so there are
still some things we need to figure out with this because it's going to promote some uh what i would
probably classify as degenerate behavior as well as the fact that yeah you're probably like oh my
inventory's full zone out oh what the okay sweet and sure you can add a warning but i don't i don't
know if even restricting it to just one inventory of loot like that is good right i i would personally
prefer that it's one death not one you know entry so there's there's some stuff we need to figure out
but again jonathan and i need to talk about that and actually solve that so that's interesting yeah
because the death seems like the important part so as long as there's not like a way to cheat it
it seems like almost like you'd want to allow people to come and go as they please until they die
right which is a a potential solution um yeah again can't say for sure but yeah 100 that person
is right for bringing that up and uh it is on our radar for this coming week to have a weekend as
well to have a solution for yeah um so with this new league not having a specific like league mechanic
is it still a challenge league does it still have challenges um it's actually no there's no
achievements or challenges yeah i'm pretty sure we weren't going to do that for a little bit yet
there's not really maybe later and later in early access but for now not really yeah um we're just
trying to keep it more about the game and the mechanics and less about you know make the game
first the achievements and the achievements will certainly an achievement system and stuff like
that will certainly be there with the full release and we'll reintegrate all of that at the time
uh is there any plans for stash tab expansions um like for example rune storage oh 100 right now i'm
actually trying to at least add the affinity without adding a custom tab those two things appeared um
from the implementation standpoint so we might want to try and divorce them so we can have
affinities without it oh yeah wanted to get those in this patch but unfortunately they just didn't
quite make it so like i mean it's actually quite likely to come in sometime like like in a point
release after like like within the zero to as soon as the patch is out and stable and we're on top of
things it's going to be like all right we need to get all those like ux or quality of life things
that we blatantly missed out on yeah yeah um for example the like being able to add bookmarks to
your atlas and write that is one that is something we designed some stuff for it we just haven't got
it yet so i want to say it's like 80 implemented right now yeah yeah so it'll be soon as we can
we'll get that in there all right that is excellent and on that note we'll wrap things up today thank
you so much jonathan thank you so much mark thank you very much for coming thank everyone for
thanks for having me here great time thank you very much everyone and i'm ziggy d and thanks for
watching
see you