in three two one they should be able to hear us and now they should be able to see us so sorry
about the delay everybody we are here thanks for waiting and uh take it away gazi with the intro
all right hi everybody and welcome to tavern talk we have lost track of which episode this is but
this time we have jonathan with us yet again to talk about poe 2 how are you doing um pretty good
uh you know obviously the response to the uh live stream we did was kind of crazy um like the uh
yeah i mean i don't even know what we really expected but uh certainly we there seems to be
a lot of hype so uh yeah we're uh that's a bit scary but i think we're doing pretty well
oh for sure a big congratulations on the reveal it was fantastic the intro scene i think it blew
everybody away absolutely astonishing i mean dm what do you think about the reveal like i'm rating it at a
12 out of 10 so far it's been the best one yet i mean obviously everyone liked it i would say that
kind of expected it to be good because i was able to get the early sneak peek and you know
see it in la earlier on so when i saw i was like okay yeah this is going to be pretty well received
one of my questions i did have for you to go right into it we're going to do general questions and then
we're going to pretty much almost immediately go into like more specific questions and these are
questions mostly just pulled from the community that i really want the answers to but one of the
general questions that i had for you was it seems like there's been more and more an emphasis on
exploration and world building and path of exile too you know you saw things like the skulls on the
maps is one such example you've used for this before so i was kind of hoping you could walk us
through the process that happened when you guys started to realize we really want to have more of
a focal point on exploration in the game so i mean to start with with the story stuff like that i mean
like you know we really want to make sure that we're doing better than what we had
um in poe 1 with regard to story like a lot of people get through poe 1 and they never even
realize what it is like what the story even was but it's for exploration as well i mean like
the there's just you really want to have that fantasy of like you know of well i mean you're
playing a fantasy game right like you're just like and i think exploration is a huge part of that
so there was a um thing that happened you know in terms of like the you know the icons on the map
and everything like that there was kind of a moment when we realized that um people just uh
people actually didn't realize how much content there was in the game um like there was a situation
where like you know people like walk past things they wouldn't know that maps contain stuff so we're
like okay um you know uh when people are dying to bosses all the time there is stuff out there for
them to find they're just not actually finding it you know they don't know that it's there so um the
icon on the map thing was just like a really good step towards actually making it so that you realize
oh you know what this is actually a game where if i explore i will be rewarded and there's been quite a
lot of other things like that we've done as well like you know we've tweaked the random level
generator we've done like a like to make it so that you've got things like where when you if
you come to dead ends we try to make sure that there's stuff in dead ends for you to find
and of course there's this like the particular encounters that we have like uh you know like
like every area we try to have like two in some cases there might even be three like sort of just
like handmade like little things you can find and we're actually keen to expand on that as well so
um one of the things that i'm keen to do is to have a larger um a larger pool of these kinds of
things in the game than what you get um the first time you go through an area and they can be random
and then we could even consider having it so that um when we do the uh you know when we go between
leagues the set of them that gets picked for each uh for each area could be randomly selected from
those like we don't have that at the moment but it's like something that i'm very keen to do because
um i think that you know obviously replayability you know it's an action rpg it's like a huge thing
um by having more of these things you just want so like every time you go through the campaign you
just get a feeling of like oh there's stuff here i haven't noticed before there's stuff there i haven't
uh that the you know like just little things and i think those little things really um contribute
and we even started doing that a little bit um with uh poe one once we sort of realized we wanted
to do this stuff um even with poe one we started saying okay every league when we put one out we
want to have like 20 30 just like tiny changes to the campaign that we can do just so that next time
you go through it you just sort of feel like hey um you know like here's just something random that i
never noticed before and i think that that's like it's funny because it's not really a headline
feature like when we're announcing the you know a poe one uh league it's not like saying oh here's
like a bunch of these little things uh like it doesn't really uh get anyone very excited but i think that
when you actually play through it there's just that feeling of like you know oh man i never saw
that before and it just kind of gives you just a better experience so i think that feeling of just
like you know just finding random stuff is is is really important and we want to do that as much
as we can that's really funny that you mentioned that because like i don't know how many times i've
gone through the campaign i play the game for 10 and a half years and every time i see something new
i'm like how have i missed this after a decade of playing this game because it's not in the patch
it's always so surprising yeah yeah yeah um guys you want to go with the yeah i think we just jump
into we've made a list here to make sure it's structured because we have a tendency of asking
repeat questions in the past we'll try to make sure that's not happening this time uh so the next
question we have we're going to jump into is that a poe 2 is focused a lot on new player experience
eliminating a lot of requirements for going to third-party tools or third-party sites and a commonly
asked question is that if we're going to be able to search and look up say monsters and their
abilities in game sort of like a necronomicon or wiki in game can we expect to see this um this is
something that i'd be super keen to do especially because of the fact that some of the monster models
are so awesome you don't really get to appreciate them from game camera perspective like uh you know
so like every every every weekend um my friends come over um and i like to show them like you know
hey here's what we've been doing on poe 2 recently but the thing is i've got the tools
i can like open up the what's called the asset viewer and like hey look at this cool monster
you know like show them close up and like hey look and there's also funny things like the animators
make all these idle animations uh for the monsters that you basically never see uh like with a bunch
of character to them and stuff like that that are really awesome and the players never see them
because obviously you never see a monster not attacking you um so like there's all sort of stuff
so one day and we don't have this in the game right now but one day i am very keen to make an
actual sort of beastery uh you know of of like here's all the monsters in the game but like you know
we can actually see the model and like appreciate it a little bit and then obviously when you do that
that would be a great opportunity to be able to show like all you know various abilities and
things like that it'll be sort of handy i think for people who are wanting to play spectres and
you know to be able to have a big list of all that stuff so i think that'll be a really cool thing to
do one day but yeah we don't have it at the moment i just think it'll be really awesome to kind of show
off the work of the artists who uh have made all these awesome monsters um and like yeah some of them
are really kind of gruesome like there's this random guy just to pick a random example called a pale
fishman and it's like this tiny little thing on screen that you barely even see but if you like zoom into the
model it's like this crazy like uh um like huge like warped thing between a human and a um uh one
of those angler fish with the like dangling light thing on it and like if you look at it real close
you can see there's like a sort of screaming person kind of under there that like there's a mouth and
like the idle animation like is like kind of crazy with like all this like yeah like there's just stuff
like that in there that it's like um you know like you really don't appreciate that when you just
like blast past it and kill it in like half a second because it's just some random small monster so
yeah it would be cool for people to see that stuff what was the name of that because we can get the
idle animation when we're racing as a specter what was the name of it that's true it's called a pale
fisherman i actually don't even know if it's in the early access because um i think it might be an
act four monster um so uh yeah in fact and the other thing as well is when i'm when i give names like
these these are like internal code names that's like the name of the folder that someone put it in
rather than like the actual like law name in the in the game so uh i don't know if it'll even be
called that in the final version but uh you know yeah it's just uh it's pretty interesting to see some
of that stuff i'll see if i can find it speaking of animations i want to go off script here from
our list already and ask you about the cinematic uh was something that i want to make sure i ask you
about because it's kind of the first you know full like major cinematic that you know has really been
revealed so far so was it difficult doing your first cinematic and did you guys get the result and
the response you were really hoping for absolutely so yes it was definitely very hard i mean obviously
we've never done anything like that before um you know like i sort of had to i mean i wrote it myself
and um like you know we there was a new zealand company um uh who we who we commissioned to kind
of uh to work on it um and uh they've done um obviously some cool stuff before but i don't think
they'd ever done like a thing that's this long um you know uh like on the on the sort of scale i guess
um so uh that was certainly you know like i mean they did a really good job you know right like it's
they it's really awesome but um yeah i mean look it's kind of like
i was really concerned right because obviously the comparison is like blizzard and all the crazy
cinematics like that and to be honest like the the quality of the animation is not what blizzard does
right like i mean they you know like we we do a lot of things in order to make it so that like it it is
like i want the content to be really awesome but it's like in terms of just the raw like you know
like amount of millions of dollars that they probably spend on these cinematics right like we don't we're
not at that level um so uh you know we're not there but i thought i just i was really hoping
that you could get a feeling of like the world and the kind of you know i want to make sure that
people understand right from the word go that like there is a brutality here and uh you know like we
we're not sort of pulling any punches when it comes to um the kind of things you can expect in the game
um so that was kind of what i was going for um and uh the thing that i actually based it on um
is i was thinking about a lot about um uh you know the the riddick movies yes um you kind of got the
thing you know the classic like you know like a team of guys go in all over confident and then
they get picked off one by one that's kind of what i was imagining i was like okay how are we
going to do this and um the uh that's so that's kind of what i was thinking about as uh as we were
writing it i love that riddick series that was the first movie i introduced my fiancee to when we
first met all right right probably not the best choice and also it also has that sort of idea of
the flip of um you know like the the you've got the the team you're following are like the bad guys
but you kind of think of them as like but they're kind of yet the main protagonists and it's like
you get that flip at the end where um you realize that the the bad guy hunting them all is actually
the good guy so yeah i was pretty i was pretty happy with that one as well pretty well done
pretty well it was fantastic so yeah that was it was a lot of fun absolutely uh moving on to the
next question uh for clarification this is a kind of a big one a couple mini questions in it
so for clarification can you explain how deaths in map work because there's been some confusion
on why six portals if you die you can't go back in as well as experience penalty still be anything
we'll start with those two yeah so basically when you die in a map um you can't resurrect uh in the
map and i think that that is okay like we discussed this quite a lot right because we were like we've
got six portals we could have it um so that you can revive six times like you did in pewe1 but the
thing we were really worried about is just compromising the combat like we just really don't want to make
it so that you um just just you know effectively like i mean obviously there's a limited level of
cheese but it's still cheese on the boss as far as we were concerned um so the reason for six
portals is it's still important that you're able to pull out six inventories worth of uh items from
a map if you're by yourself you know like you still want to be able to do that um and yet we also don't
want to make it just one portal with unlimited uses because once again that limitation on like the amount
of stuff you can pull out of a map i think is also kind of one of those things is important
and there's also a slightly more mundane reason which um like seems a bit silly but you know the all the
map devices that we've already sold those are microtransactions that we need to support going forward in the
store uh and all of those have six portals we can't really change that so uh you know that's
kind of just like one of those things that we just kind of have to maintain backwards compatibility for
for that reason so um yeah there was a lot of discussion around this though but um at the end
of the day the main thing that won out as far as is we just don't want to compromise the combat we
want to make sure that if you know if you're going to kill a boss it has to be like one you know one
life you have to survive it you actually have to properly kill it um but of course we can make those
encounters harder because of the fact we don't have um uh you know a map boss in every area so um you know we get to
ideally have that uh that still being fine and what about experience penalty when dying is that still
going to be a thing with us um you know that's actually a very good question um when we so we
removed it from the campaign at the point where we um made it so that we added checkpoints and
everything and then at the time we were like oh but in maps you get six portals so therefore um
they still haven't it now i actually it's still there right now but i it's not something i've like
thought about honestly for like a little while now so it's probably good that i have another
conversation with mark about it to see whether we still need it the reason why i think i would
still like it is because not necessarily it's not really at the beginning of maps but as you get
towards the race towards 100 having death like set you back um so that you have to actually build
somewhat defensively when you're like racing for the for 100 i think it's kind of important so the
experience penalty is really serving a really important role there but i suppose the question is like
it may not be as necessary when you're talking early maps right like it's really it's really that from
like 90 to 100 where it kind of starts to matter that the death penalty is there as a thing so um
we could theoretically think about like you know i mean basically what i'm saying with that is like
we could fiddle around with the equation for it a little bit but yeah the purpose of it really is
to make sure that as you're um uh coming towards the end you know as you're getting to level 100
that like a mistake actually costs you something rather than just being like a nothing in the road
um in order for that uh in order for that race to 100 to actually be meaningful um because you know
like if you can just grind your face into the wall and still not losing experience and just like dive
you know it's like you get to 100 but you died like 2000 times it's like well did you really
achieve the same thing as the guy who didn't die at all uh so you know that that's kind of the reason
why it exists that's a fair answer uh the follow-up questions to this little chunk we got here is
loot and what happens when you're going in the party play in maps and what happens to the the loot
there in the loot split between the parties as well as what happens if x player dies what is the loot to
that player all right so um so okay a few things about this so number one we have changed how the
loot scaling works for party members and what i've actually tried to do is be a lot more intelligent
with regard to what types of items do you want to see more of and what types of items um don't matter
about having more of so an example of this is like um if you're talking about currency right
obviously you want uh double the amount of currency we've got two players because all players want to
take currency but this is also true for things like rings and amulets because rings and amulets
aren't kind of like uh specific to any one like person right like like like i mean obviously the
mods can make them either way but everyone wants a ring everyone wants an amulet if one drops
um so effectively we also do plus 100 for things like that as well but if you're talking about armors
well there are six different armor types and so if you look on average um you only need to increase
the number of um armors by 50 in order to be able to wait is it even 50 it might be
okay i might be doing the math wrong here but effectively there's an amount of armor increase
that you need in order to kind of on average make it so that everyone's still getting the stuff they
want because certain players only want certain um armor parts of the pie right due to the strength
and thing and uh for weapon types there's even more weapon types so the chance that two players are
actually using the same weapon type um is generally much lower so effectively what that means is that we
can not increase weapons by the same amount to increase other stuff so what that means is
is that when you um the sum total of all of that means that the stuff on the ground
from each player increases by some number like 28 percent if you actually look at it in raw drops
um but the actual what what makes up that 28 percent is like way more of the stuff you actually
want and not as much of the garbage that you don't want in order to make it so that you don't get the
crazy spam on the ground with party play that you uh previously uh might not might have gotten
um so i think that that system works very well in terms of just making it so that you um
uh you you get the right items in i guess it just goes to the general philosophy that we have
of uh we're trying to not drop as many things but make sure the things we do drop are more
important and better as you um as you go up so um that's kind of like the uh yeah as i said just
part of that philosophy there i feel like there was another part of the question that i've forgotten
now so maybe you can remind me what it was uh the last part there there's two more but the one of
them was uh let's say you're two players playing and one player dies what happens oh yeah on the
ground that belongs to that player so to say um so i think that so we usually use temporary i think
temporary allocation is still i'm pretty sure the rules for this are basically the same as what
they were in p we won um at least at this at the moment um so basically if you've got temporary
allocation on then the allocation will disappear and then the loot will just become allocated to
you know to be free for all once uh the timer expires and if it's permanent allocation then
obviously it stays uh like that although we definitely should make it free for all once you die
even if it's permanent i assume uh i don't know if i've actually done that uh oh it does work that
way in that case it'll just work then so it's just the same as in p we won in this regard
um so uh that that should be fine um so uh yeah i mean effectively like that um so yeah i wouldn't
say it's like changed a huge amount in that particular regard um but um oh yeah yeah so
actually what was the last part there uh last one has to do with trials now we've only seen sanctum
and ultimatum version or the 2.0 version of it uh so the real question is two two ones one is the
sanctum no hit run and um the questions are what happens if one player dies if two players goes in
and the other one is the reward system there as well i guess okay so this is one of these tricky
technical questions that mark would probably be better at answering because he knows the
exact details let me think about that um i don't know that i've even had a discussion about what
happens to the rewards and sanctum now generally speaking of course when we're doing things like
this when you're paying party play with a thing like sanctum um the uh like the map uh well sorry
to be technical the map owner but you know effectively the person who who paid the cost
the person who uh put the key in um they're the person who kind of gets like the the progress
so they usually get to be the one who decides what the uh what actions to take and what rooms to go to
i believe though that if you um want to go through and ascend that they're all like you can both do the
ascendancy so that means if you want to do like the ascension at a party then that's absolutely fine
you get the reward there um but i believe that the items that come from like key uh the the chests
and stuff like that um i believe that they belong to the person who paid the cost of the coin that
they that they used to enter um is my as my understanding of that i could be wrong about this
but i think that's correct so uh yeah there's a few the i'm i'm sorry about this i don't have like
completely clear information about some of that stuff but um yeah uh that that's one of those
things that mark tends to be uh often addressing uh as far as working out those things mark really
is like so i one thing i should mention is that mark plays like i'm i could be wrong but i think
like 90 of the time when he's playing he's playtesting multiplayer so he's the one who really
cares about getting all that multiplayer stuff exactly right whereas when i'm playing i'm like
a solo player all the way right like i just for whatever reason i'm just like a solo player so
ideally with the both of us paying attention here uh we should make sure that things are good in both
solo and multiplayer but um yeah he uh you know he's got a bunch of designers he likes to play with
um you know i mean you know like the design team effectively like he plays multiplayer with the design
team all the time so um he uh he's the one who usually sorts out these like specific little
multiplayer details all right so since we're talking about loot there is one question that
people have related to loot due to some early access footage we've seen where there's like tier
one tier two tier three advanced gear etc so i was hoping you could break down what that's referencing
yeah so effectively um when you get um uh magic find gear so like increased chance of rarity
we wanted to try and make it so that the gear that you get from that um is better and not just in
the way of just getting like you know more more rares i mean it does do that as well uh don't get
me wrong like you're still getting more rares more uniques and so on but we wanted to make it so that
you could scale uh rarity by a huge amount not necessarily in a character but also because uh you
know when you've got a monster uh that you've juiced with various map mechanics all that stuff is adding
rarity and not quantity um so effectively to make sure that rarity is something that um that really
increases the power so um the way we do that is there's five uh and i don't know whether rishi will be
unhappy about me spoiling the exact workings of this but um there are five tiers uh to start with
that you don't see that you can't see that change anything because those don't change anything about
unidentified items but they do change the percentage chances that you get uh certain things so they uh
for example you're getting um uh you know chances to upgrade currency to higher types of currency
you're getting um like the chances of uh not not spawning items with uh base types that are lower
level than what you would need so effectively sort of clamping the base types that you're going to get
into like a smaller range at the top and like on these kind of things while also increasing like
uh you know magic and rare and uniques and stuff like that it also increases the uh like it starts
to open up like uh those tiers start to open up like what types of uniques can go into the pool
and to be clear here there's always a chance that you can upgrade through these tiers regardless of how
much magic find you have right you don't need magic find to get this it's just that magic find is
effectively increasing the chance you upgrade through them and in total there's actually 10 tiers
overall but at tier um at tier uh five it starts to uh modify the um uh the the properties of
unidentified items and that's why we have to start marking uh the the uh the rares as being like and
so that's what so when it says t2 that actually means that's like t5 internally of what it's rolled
and then so the tiers going up from there each of them say you know t2 t3 t4 t5 and um what those
what the reason why we have to say that is because when this item dropped we uh clamped the mods that it
can get to be uh in the upper tiers and the higher tier you get the higher they can go so if you get
a um uh if you get a t5 uh rare the mods that it can have are from a very very tiny uh portion of them
right at the top uh of all of the of all the tiers of those mods so you know that the roles you're going
to be seeing like the life you're going to get on the damage you're going to get on this kind of
thing are going to be uh top notch when you see that um so effectively um uh the uh if you if
and and the reason why i think that's important to show is because you kind of want people to feel
like okay um like because the number of items that drop aren't really increasing you need a way to
see on the screen when something drops like how valuable is the thing that i just saw and so
showing those tears on the rares also really has that effect of like okay like if you see like you
know five or six t5 rares drop you know you got a really good hit whereas if you see a bunch of like
t2s you know you didn't get such a good one so um that's kind of important i think just to get that
feeling of uh of of of being important it's actually really interesting because we've been fighting so
much this thing of like like the way that you made like a way you can make drops in an action
actually feel good is just by dropping tons of crap on the ground um but the problem is that like
it really is kind of a like an annoying element because like while it can feel good it's like it's
just it people want then you know they want to use loot filters and they want to use all that stuff and
it's like okay well i mean that's great and everything and we'll support that and that's fine
but like ideally we can actually make it so that you don't have to worry about in the first place and so
you need to find a way to give people the hit of dopamine uh without having to just do that by like
dropping literally covering the screen i mean there's still room for like dropping a lot of
stuff right i mean like we want to make sure bosses feel like you know there's a good list of stuff
there but it's like ideally you get that by the value of the items like you know that the value of
that stuff is really good and i suppose on some level item filters are even sort of achieving that
anyway because if you're using a filter to get like you're not seeing very much anyway so it really
is all about the value so it's like it's impossible we just need to make sure that the game is doing
that as a matter of course rather oh filters oh sorry i did that oh you're good we only lost you the last
half second there okay so since you bring up the concept of loop filters this was a question we're
gonna ask later so i might as well bring it up now is that like official confirmation loop filters
sounds like art support yeah so they're supported exactly the same way they were in poe1 there's no
reason for us to drop support for something like that um and um you know if you want to use them you
can and i suspect what the main reason people will use them for uh in poe2 is not so much filtering
things away but more highlighting things that are valuable that um you might not otherwise uh recognize you
because like there might be higher base types or things like that like a lot of people have filters
that like uh you know um highlight certain things that might be good for uh various reasons so you
know things that um have like some for example people might like want to be doing things like oh um
you know like i know that this uh you know like things like you know items having sockets and stuff
maybe you want to change the text color when that happens or things like that like there is little
there are icons and stuff for that stuff uh there but uh we try to keep things like relatively visually clean
um so uh and and and also we don't want to kind of make try to make too many value judgments for the
player about what um is important or not um so therefore we try to like not do too much of that
stuff but obviously players you know come up with their own schemes for what they think is important
um so then i suspect they'll use loot filters mostly for the ability to change how loot is rendered as
opposed to filtering it out i gotta say this isn't so much a question as much as a comment for me
personally but i really appreciate the approach of something you said there which is allowing the player
to determine what's important i find that to be like a very appealing sentiment so i hear that's
part kind of the reason i've been falling in love with the you know the poe game lately um anyway on to
the on to the next question here uh so this one is going to be an obvious one if i didn't ask everyone
would be mad uh so there's six classes uh that are coming to early access some of them have already
been showcased but they're not in there namely the druid and the huntress so i think people are curious
about are they coming soon what's going on with these classes yeah so they'll definitely be coming
relatively soon i'm not going to promise a date but uh certainly the next two classes you see will
be those two like in terms of in early access um we just at some point look we really wanted to launch
with those two classes we expected that we would be launching into early access with those two classes
but um at some point it was just like um you know the we and i think i've even said this before but we
really underestimated what it takes to finish a class i think um like uh it it takes a lot uh you know
it's because and the thing is it's it's like you make a bunch of skills and you're like oh yeah you know
made the skills that's the class right but in poe it really isn't because um you know you need to
make sure they can all be supported well you need to make sure there's uniques that support it there's
passive tree stuff that supports it it's like a whole thing of like getting all that stuff into a
good state it's like plus also the skills plus also thinking about all the stuff that can happen
with other classes and like how does it tie in all the mechanics like it's just a goliath task um so i
think the huntress and the druid are not far away um the druid we still have one form um that we still
need to uh get finished um so uh there's like uh that there's still some more skill work to do there
um the huntress uh i think we mostly have like working prototypes that we're happy with for most
of the skills but like there's still a little bit more to do but yes just all that other sort of
finishing work around like tying it into all the other systems making sure everything's good
um that we need to get done um and you know it won't take us too long but you know
at some point we just had to say like hey you know uh can we really do this for early access with
all the other stuff that we're doing and we just felt like we couldn't so um you know we we decided
to to cut for now uh get to it later and you know we make these kinds of decisions all the time
there's like a ton of content that's like you know we're trying to get it in we try as hard as we can
and then we're like oh you know what we just couldn't get it in but i think um uh you know that's
just game development right but the nice thing is it's all sitting there right we don't throw anything
away uh we've got it all there waiting in the wings which means that there'll be a bunch of
content we'll be able to introduce really quickly when you say speaking of one forum sorry go on yeah like when you
say one forum could you like give us a number how many forums are we talking about so there's three
so there's three primary forms for the druid but there's a couple of other like random shape shifts
around um like the kind of you actually saw one of them right there's the shape shift on the uh on the
on the ascendancy the demon form um so there's a few other things bits and pieces like that around
the place but um yeah this the druid sort of has three primary forms and um that's because we want
to try and like the um other classes we want to make sure that there's combos between the forms as well
um like there aren't just it's not just like a reskin melee right like each of the forms kind
of has like skills that have like things and we want to make sure there's mechanics between them
that they can kind of you know the cross class kind of even within the archetypes of the class um
synergy like that so um yeah the uh the the the the one that's um no i'm not going to spoil it
actually yeah i'm not going to say anything about it go ahead go ahead no no no no no you're more than
welcome to yeah i've been it so this is probably a good time to ask this thing because you're talking
about uh you know the additional classes here um does that mean we can basically expect changes to
the passive skill tree because obviously there's the six starting nodes now so when you add the
other classes there's going to be new branches i'm assuming added for each one of these classes at
this point or were they going to double down on previous ones so um yeah well i'm look i'm sure
the passive tree will receive massive renovations or through early access like i just have no doubt of
that um that it's it's every every time we change anything a huge passive tree changes are a result
um and uh it's taken a long time to iterate to even the point we are now and i'm just sure there'll be
more um and like the thing is until you really play it like properly you just don't even know what
you're what's missing um so uh you know actually one other thing i might mention just because um i
don't know if it's like hugely well known but um the starting area of the tree for each class
actually changes there's actually three variants of the starting part of each of each tree for each
class so effectively um we actually did this first when we were playing the witch and the sorceress
um so effectively if you're a if you're a witch you get one variant of the starting area and if
you're a sorceress you get another variant and then if you're neither of those two classes then uh you
get a there's a third variant that can go there so that all the other classes when they go there they
get slightly different stats again um and uh the reason for that is because um the initial reason
we did the witch sorceress thing is because there's this problem that you have with um where players
when they see a node that's got multiple things on it and one of the things does not affect them
um people just really don't want to allocate a node like that even if the values on it are the
same as what they otherwise would have gotten so when we first did this when we had one variant for
everyone um the uh the witch sorceress nodes were like plus eight percent uh or whatever minion and
spell damage right and we found that sorceresses even though a sorceress would just like would
otherwise get just eight percent spell damage sorceresses would just not take that because it's got
this minion thing on it and they don't want that so um by having the trees be separate it just sort
of prevents that problem um immediately and the other thing it kind of also was just like when we
realize that we can swap those two out we're like well hang on we might as well have a third variant
as well for other players because that will mean that there are some times when we have like balance
things that are a bit annoying we're like we can't make a node for a class in the starting area as
good as we want because that would mean that other classes would all be incentivized to go there and
take it because it's like too powerful if you know what i mean so effectively with that we can like
balance the what what the uh you know because it's relatively close to get to the adjacent uh classes
area um so effectively you can sort of just balance that so that it like kind of works a little bit
better so um there's not going to be anything in the starting areas that you like don't like stats you just
can't otherwise get right it's not gonna be like that but it's just more about like tweaking numbers
and make a few cases like the sorceress and witch where we just have to make sure that you know for
for new player clarity we can make sure that it's like just the stuff they're going to want and not
the stuff for the other class um but as you get out of that then they all become the same but yeah
as i said we're making a lot more changes um as we go through too all right that was a very in-depth
answer there i actually didn't know about the changing of the starts that's uh that's an interesting
tidbit there okay so you did mention and you know i gotta ask because you said classes and content
coming to the game i am a notable blight enjoyer yep so you know i you know i'm gonna ask uh can we
hope can you tease me with anything give me some hopium copium that you know maybe blight can come
to path of exile too at some point well i will say this blight is a relatively easy league to add
compared to some others so when we're looking at leagues of like here are some leagues that we can put
in like relatively easily that is one of the ones that uh you know uh would be relatively
relatively simple for us to do obviously one of the reward system it previously had has now been
moved to a different thing which means that blight will need a new reward system and uh you know we've
got ideas for what we can do about that but we you know we we've got monsters we can use for it uh
we've actually got a bunch of environment art from act five that um uh that would suit blight uh
perfectly well uh i'm not sure if no have we shown any that no i don't think we have all right yeah
yeah well anyway there are some uh uh there's some there's some there's some stuff uh that uh we can use
very easily so it's the kind of thing that we could do relatively easily when we're looking to
add uh new league uh new leagues to the game so i'm just hearing blight login that's what i'm hearing
when you're saying yeah okay well that's that's good that's good news i'll pass it off to gazi
because i've been asking a bunch of questions related stuff i just personally want to know oh that's
fine later on in this podcast we're going to hit the minion rant sections don't worry about it
uh but we can start with um a classic simple answer question and it is how many ascendancy
ascendancy points are we going to get in total yeah so same as poe one it's eight uh eight points
so effectively you've got um the last uh the three you can get um throughout campaign uh three like
three sets of two i should say uh so six points throughout campaign and then the last one uh you
have to be an end game to be able to get all right the other question we have here is poe 2 looks
like there's a significant amount of ways to increase power on maps how does the juicing
compare to poe 1 for end game mapping now we saw a lot of it in the reveal but could you elaborate on
it um well so first things first we definitely want to make sure the juicing is still a thing
right like we were we were we before we did our whole end game push i think that that uh you know
in recent times i think that that would have been a big problem uh that we would have had where there
wasn't enough ways to juice maps um but i don't know that you'll be able to get to quite the level
that you can get in poe 1 uh certainly we want to make sure that it's it's big though um and like
it's honestly it's a little bit hard to say because you know the the way that this can go down i mean
look we think we can know like all the things but you never really quite know exactly how it goes until
you get like master players because trade is a huge part of the economy for how juicing works like
it's like okay so we've shown people how you can overlap uh tablets and towers and all these sorts of
things like that and like get all these pants but the question is is the sustainability in a trade league
such that you can like do all of the juicing mechanics that po2 has to offer at the same time
continuously and i don't actually quite know the answer to that because as i said it's like
it's really a trade economy thing that you need to have to be able to say uh what they can do and the
juice is substantial if you can get everything all at the same time the question is can you do that
every map or can you do that only some of the time and i honestly can't say until the trade sort of
starts to happen um it i think it's going to come down a lot to just play and for us to just find out
like you know like once we hit that trade economy we actually start playing what does it feel like is it
working well um but the thing is we still want you to feel powerful and part of part of the feeling
of power actually is pack size right um like you need to have enough pack size so that uh because
you know because when you've got a bunch of aoe abilities obviously the more things they hit the
more damage you're effectively doing overall so like the more pack like pack size really is like a
way to make a player feel powerful and so that's why we need to have ways of juicing pack size and
we've got ways of juicing pack size in the game but then we also have to be a little bit careful
because um you know the the that that that is what can lead to things getting completely out of
control and they're just not you can't understand what's going on in the combat and things just
completely fall apart so um yeah as i said i we have to be careful but i think it is still
substantial like we you still need to feel like a god so you know i i think i think the juice will
be high but i do believe it should be lower than pwe1 at least by a little bit um yeah that's fair
on the topic of uh power and juicing things up as something that we've seen in many games throughout
the years is how games start a rpg games they start off kind of slow and more of a strategic
gameplay approach and then the the best patch just comes through the game evolves the meta of power
creeping and speed clearing just goes to crazy numbers and then everyone's upset when they're
then toned down or the number squish is happening so i guess the follow-up question would be if what
are the plans because i'm very confident there are plans to manage severe increase in power creep
moving forward so you don't end up in that category where you're one-shotting the entire screen
um i think that we just have to be careful and honestly i would say that in pwe1 we've shown that
we can uh i mean look pwe1 obviously did get pretty crazy but at the same time like we had a lot of
years like a lot of years where things kind of didn't go didn't didn't weren't like that and i think
that effectively i believe we can still maintain that um our numbers don't scale as fast as some games do
and they don't go quite as exponential which means that we're not going to have to be worrying about
trillions of damage or anything like that uh you know having um you know and like it's it's uh it
could be so i don't think we're gonna have to ever do a number squish or anything like that like we've
never really felt like the need to worry about that um but uh yeah i mean you know it's just a matter of
keeping keeping on top of it and there are certain people in the company who just um you know are just
are just very careful about stuff so i mentioned rishi a couple of times like you know he's kind of the
one who does most of the work for the item system and so on so he and he and he's and he is definitely
a force of conservativeness when it comes to uh when it comes to like making sure that things don't go
crazy and so that's really good to have because it means that like me and mark are often the ones
being like no no numbers high numbers high and he's like like no no keep them low keep them low so i
think together with that we kind of come to some kind of medium ground where we don't uh kind of uh get
things too out of control um but uh yeah as i said i think that it's just a matter of you know
just being careful um one nice thing that we also have is with the league format that we have is that
we get to add power and then at the end of the league we get to decide like you know was that too
much can we take some of this away do we want to keep it you know that kind of stuff um like that's
a very important tool um so we kind of never really like it means we don't have to commit to things in
the same way that the game that didn't have a league type process does um because the expectation
from players and i think this is almost sort of a community thing the expectation from the
community is not necessarily that all the content that we add is going to stay added um and i think
that's a really important factor to have an understanding of in a game community because
it just gives us so much more ability to like make decisions after testing them um and um it's funny
like you know i say that as if you know oh yeah you just test all of your stuff on the players but i
mean to some extent that's true and because the the you know you never really know uh like you can do
all the testing you want but you never really know until the community actually get a chance
to play with it and you see what kind of stuff comes out of it so um yeah i mean on some level
we really are testing the stuff on the community and it has to be that way i just don't know of a
way uh like no matter how many qa tests we throw at it i don't think we could find every single
possible uh level of power that can come out of something like that so um yeah like it's just nice
that we have the ability to say you know what um this thing here we're going to put it back in but
we're going to nerf it or this thing here just it can't exist like it interacts with too many other
things and it's too broken um you know it's really nice to be able to say that all right
um kind of a random question i have due to the use uh you mentioned this in the i think it was the
ziggy q a afterwards but that the early access server is going to be maintained so meaning you're
going to have leagues you know separate but then the og one will go back there and that is going to
be separate from like the eternal or core server as well right there will be an early access one so
question for you i have then is uh the early access characters one i'm assuming you can still
you know play them etc on the server or and two can you still create characters on the early access
server afterwards or are they kind of grandfathered in and make sure you have all the characters you
want for the um i think we probably won't allow you to create new characters there just because um
uh i think that even just if you're a new player and you're like oh you've got places i mean i suppose
what we could do is allow you to create characters there if you've already got one there
um that would be an option but um i kind of don't really think we need to do that like as i said the
main reason we're doing that is just because if you're someone who's like not even really paying
attention to what's going on and you're just like you've got some level 20 character and you're like
oh i just want to keep playing the game right we don't want to disrupt that person's life too much
um so i think that that's why we don't want to just get rid of all that stuff completely um so uh
yeah i mean the thing is though that like you know if you're playing a high level character almost
certainly your build is going to be bricked in some regard right like there'll be some element of it that got
modified or something like that you know um but then of course you'll also have like uh legacy
items um which will be kind of presumably funky assuming that we have to modify balance which no
doubt we will have to do um so uh yeah like you'll have all that stuff so i mean look there's just no
reason to delete the data right like we're not going to make an effort to make sure that everything is
you know like is is uh uh still works like in terms of your builds and everything but we're also not
going to do anything that we don't have to do in terms of deleting it either right like we might as
well just let it be there um so uh you know and it's also just like nice to have like oh here's this
character i got you know back in the day like it's nice to just have that around so uh you know it's
just a little memory of that so um yeah there's just no reason for us to delete it so speaking of
builds getting bricked if i reference one of the interviews we actually did on uh on here is you
had mentioned righteous fire as an example when we were talking about cosmetics and mtx and you're
saying that it's fundamentally getting changed and i was hoping to ask for pox here shout out to pox
can we get any information related to a righteous fire or where that is going it's kind of wanting
to follow up with with that that you had mentioned in previous so it's it's not an early access right
now because it's not a class that is not uh it's one of the skills for a class that's not going to
be an ea um so you get that a little bit later um but it is going to be in uh we have a we have a
prototype of it and you know we've got it working away that we're happy for it to work um but uh yeah
unfortunately just not an ea or at least not an ea at the start right when we add the character it'll
it'll come in it's going to be in significantly changed or or it is very different but it's still
fundamentally you know it's still fundamentally a thing where you're lighting yourself on fire and
there's fire damage around you and that kind of stuff right it's just that you know like the exact
mechanics from a stat point of view like if you looked at it on the screen you'd be like oh yeah
that's righteous fire but if you look at the stats it's like worked quite differently there we go
thank you i had to ask for pox fair enough speaking of uh uh bricking uh a very common question i
believe this was a scene is shown in the reveal but bricking the atlas as you can if you die in a
map you can't do it again and so in the start what happens when you break if you break all the
starter maps all around yeah yeah so we have the ability to re i think effectively restart your atlas
if you completely cut yourself off you can uh do that um i don't remember what way it is to do that
but it certainly came up when you're first talking about there just has to be some way uh to allow you
to uh effectively restart your atlas from scratch if you need to um i would hope that most people don't
uh do that um i should hope i should hope that you manage to survive it like you know when you so
there's four uh connections to the starting point um so you'd have to dive you'd have to dive four times
in a row in order for that to happen to you and then if that happens it'll automatically re-roll the
atlas so you can kind of just try again immediately but um yeah hopefully not too many players have to
do that uh and run into that issue um but uh yeah i mean look we wanted there to be consequences for
um for failure right we wanted to so it's like oh crap you know now i have to find another way around
like the the the web of connections is dense enough that usually there'll be some other way around to
get to something that you want um but then but bear in mind there won't be too many right like if you
then die uh at another one of the entrances to get to some piece of content uh that could uh that could
definitely cut you off so you know there are some consequences for death like um you know uh and
with that in mind it obviously means that things like the experience penalty at low level certainly
we don't need to be uh don't need to be as uh worried about because you know there's consequences
just from the death itself in the atlas but um yeah you know i think it's just a um the the reason
the other reason why it's also important to do that by the way is um because of the fact that you can
fail a map it means that the things that we can have on the atlas can be more valuable right
because if we have things that um uh you can just try again then you've always got these problems
where like okay if you uh go into the map like let's say you wanted to have a map that's just
full of chests um that uh that that that you know drop stuff for whatever reason let's just say we
wanted to do that right um it's like if the failure it really has to be that you can only enter that
map um they can only create that map one time um because otherwise uh you know like at what point do
you say well the map is completed um like there always has to be things like there always has to
be some kind of condition like that so by effectively just having the rule of like a map can only be
created by you one time uh it means that you know yeah the valuable stuff we can put on there like
monsters and things like that like if you could you could have mods on the atlas that like you know
increases the number of rares by a ton and that's fine because you know that you don't have a
situation where someone just kills half of them and then uh dies on purpose and then goes back in and
kills them again you know that kind of stuff like effectively like we have that's the kind of exploit
that we're trying to avoid here um and so it just allows us to have much more valuable stuff on there
uh we do by the way have a bit of this problem in campaign that we have to worry about like
uh because you know you can respawn a checkpoint at any time and so we have to make be really careful
about this stuff because you know i mentioned before that at the end of dead ends you'll get
rare chests well if you can set it like we had an exploit before we fixed it where like you know if
you get a if you get a checkpoint that's close to a rare chest uh because at a dead end you can die
on purpose respawn at the checkpoint just open the chest again and again um and so yeah yeah so
effectively what we have to do is make it so that when you um revive from a checkpoint
all of the things like uh like like like uh chests and rare monsters they have to stay dead uh even if
you opened them or killed them after you did the checkpoint um for the next version until you
recreate the map and get into it from scratch again because um that stuff uh would be exploitative if
you were able to um you know to not save that when you after you died so like a few little things you
have to worry about with the checkpoints for exploits that but thankfully um in maps you don't because
there's no you know you don't have to worry about that that element since you die you've done
i have a follow-up to that because i did i felt like when i played the test of the campaign now
the game is very different from when i played tested last time in la and there was one mechanic and i kept
saying gearing and getting skill gems it felt so good i felt like i always were given the tools i needed
when i was progressing and i had no idea about the mechanic till you told me at the event about this
um loot table rare that randomly was regenerated in the area and if you didn't kill it that would
that would be available in the next zone to give you like a flask so i'm guessing that feature is
also for this you don't you can't farm that i'm guessing but a lot of people don't know about it
so maybe you can explain elaborate on it yeah so effectively what we've done in the very very early
game in order to make it so that um to guarantee a certain number of skills and things like that
is that um there's a couple of encounters where if you um if you fail to find the encounter in the
first uh area for example then when you go to the second area we will drop the item that you
would have gotten if you'd found that first encounter just to make sure that if you didn't
run into this but you did run into a later one um then we like forward that on to the next area and
then we do that like a couple of times with a few different encounters kind of it's kind of all
stuff uh like in the first like sort of 10 levels this kind of stuff just to really make sure that
like people actually get some of those important drops like when you're level sort of 15 20 missing
out on one skill gem is like not really a big deal but when you're really low level and it's like
you've got very few skills if you miss out on that crucial upgrade of getting like the next tier of gem
um that can matter so much that we just can't really allow it to happen so we need to have as
many chances as possible uh for people to find those things but at the same time we didn't want
to just spam you with that type of gem because then it's like oh i've got tons of these well you
know like it would feel value like wouldn't feel very valuable if you if you did find them all so um
we want to all of those encounters they do have loot that you get like there's still a reason to do
all of them because they have their own unique stuff as well but effectively if you then but if you do
miss some of them you're still getting some of those really crucial things like gems uh skill gem upgrades and
things like that in those first few areas um i actually think though that some of that problem
might be slightly ameliorated by the fact that we've got the map now where you can see all the
encounters so i think that in some cases people might be looking at there but we still have that
system just because you know it's nice to be able to um you know to just make sure that people don't
fail in the very early game no so speaking of the map i got just a couple questions related to the map
one is when we're talking about uh you know breaking the map and not being able to go to certain areas
if you fail too many um does this account for like bosses too for instance like pinnacle bosses and
are they linked together where you fail the maps around it you cannot go do the boss now yeah
oh because if you fail oh sorry uh the cities with the uber bosses those are extra special because if
you fail um uh if you fail one of those if you fail to kill the lieutenant uh then the boss will
disappear from the uh the uber boss will disappear from the uh from the center of the city as well
um so those ones are like you really have to be able to do those fights and it will be quite
challenging uh that one of course is extra challenging because you need to find another
city right um so uh the uh that one's going to be uh something that i think will uh be quite
challenging um so yeah like that's for like the ultra pinnacle content like that seventh system which
has the uh the um the uh i don't want to say the name because we didn't spoil it uh but the uh the
the that pinnacle boss encounter um that one that one will be quite hard to get to
okay so speaking of pinnacle boss encounters got a couple more questions related to this
um are the bosses i hear there's what you said tier one through four correct
uh so you're talking about in terms of loot drops and things like that i think i've talked about this
before in terms of difficulty ramping i i don't think that we got clarity on whether or not you
can modify these maps meaning can you like modify the okay so you're talking about the uh the trees at
the end where you add the difficulty yes exactly yes yeah so yes there's four tiers yes that's
correct and and so beyond that can you then you modify the bosses themselves are the bosses static
and you modify on your tree only or are the bosses almost like maps you know how you can modify like
invites for instance from poe one so can you further modify these um so uh let me think about that uh so
generally speaking not so i'm pretty sure the breach stone can't get mods um can simulacrums get mods
uh i don't know i'm not sorry i'm not actually sure um uh ultimatum ones the ultimatum ones can
um because those ones have that extra mechanic for modifying him um i'm actually not entirely so
like look what i will say is in general um like it's not like the it isn't the same for every league
like for each league we can decide what we want to do there but generally speaking for those four
in gaming uh things the main thing you're going to be doing is modifying the um the difficulty
using the tree uh like that and um that difficulty scaling um uh does introduce things like you know
it can even modify things like how skills work and like you know the number of minions that a boss
might summon and things like that like there's all sorts of stuff like that um but it isn't random uh
what you're doing there on the tree um so uh for the for the for the for the pinnacles it really is
just kind of mostly just that difficulty uh change okay got it i think the reason people were asking is
they were wondering if like there's a hardest baseline challenge where it's like this is sort of a
baseline you can use on can you clear the hardest content so people were wanting some uh clearly
on that for the pinnacle whilst it definitely is the case okay thank you very much uh so another
another question i was kind of wondering when i was looking at the map i know this you use the example
of like the paradise for instance you get the bonus experience and that is obviously on the beach
because it's tropical so i'm assuming the uniques are zoned out to the biomes that you have
specifically and if that is the case the since the biomes are determining maps do these unique maps
also have drops associated with them essentially where i'm going with this is are certain biomes
going to help you target farm certain types of items absolutely and we want to do even more than
just what you were saying with the unique maps like we want like we have just certain map like this map
has got this theme and therefore it can drop this more of this item and stuff like that like we
absolutely and the thing is this is one of the great things about the new way that the atlas works is that
with the previous atlas we couldn't really allow for target farming in that same way or when we did
it was always a problem like with div cards and so on um where uh you know i mean obviously we
modified div cards you can move them around now but uh generally speaking it was the case with the
odd atlas that if we made it so a map had something special um then everyone would just play that map
continuously forever um so with the new system we effectively can say that you know it's okay to have
wild variants in between you know the value of certain things because you know you're limited by having
to find more of it and if you happen to know that the thing that you want spawns in desert biomes
and then you're using towers to find those desert biomes and then you're looking around okay like
finally i'm just going to go through all the deserts you can absolutely do that in the case
of untainted paradise that one requires being on the border of um the the water and um and uh the uh
and a forest so only forests next to ocean um i believe will cause that map to spawn um and then
like we can do other things like that as well like we have special spawn conditions about like you know
when you get this and this that's when this can spawn uh and so that's like a way that we can kind of
like triddle around with the rarity but also if players learn these things uh then they can know
what to look for uh when they're exploring the map um as far as like finding that stuff as well
so that can be a bit fun so i'm assuming that's going to influence things like racing etc but another
another uh question i have in is does that mean that the people's individual map because you said
it's infinite it's you know generated etc so does that mean each person has a completely random
different starting point like for instance maybe i'm more prone to find tainted paradise
you know sooner than a different person i mean it is certainly true that you can roll well on
certain things like you know there's nothing limiting the fact that you could you could find
five untainted paradises near where you started and another person couldn't right but i think the
law of averages will just mean that uh in general it kind of ends up averaging up to the same kind of
thing um so uh you know i i like it is an interesting point that you make about racing because it does mean
that if you're looking about the race to 100 it is possible for one person to get luckier than the other
as far as what maps spawn for them but then by the same token it's possible for someone to get lucky
on what items drop for them or some other one of a million things so the longer you play effectively
the more the law of averages happens and the more kind of it just comes down to play skill rather than
randomness um but uh yeah ultimately you know everyone gets a different experience there
and uh when you reset your when you when you do the thing where you run out of um
where you no longer have any nodes to explore by the way that does change the seed of your atlas so you'll
get a new random uh a new random layout as well um so uh yeah so that's just worth mentioning just
because that's good that's good enough so you can actually re-roll the complete layout if you want um
by dying four times uh well yeah but i think there might even be a way to do it without dying i'm not
100 sure on that i can't remember whether actually how they what the way to trigger this was but um
yeah that is a thing okay so atlas rolling meta coming up soon yeah but here's the thing right
because we we made sure we did think of the one thing like you're not going to get an untainted
paradise uh within the initial fog of war uh that you can see uh when you first uh enter the atlas so
you know like we're not gonna we don't allow that special stuff to spawn right in that first uh circle
so i do have one follow-up here before i send it over guys really because i'm just kind of thinking
based upon this concept so if there's certain biomes that are going to spawn certain types of
unique maps and maybe certain biomes are more prone to certain type of item drops etc but the i the maps
themselves i can't like take that untainted paradise put it as a consumable and then trade
it on the market does this mean you're expecting much more social play where it's like hey i found
this unique map who is expecting this unique map and having people actually looking for other players
that their particular you know atlas has the maps that people are particularly looking for is this
something you guys are expecting and planning around here i think i think it could definitely happen
for sure um as for whether that's good or not i guess we'll find out like it's really sort of hard
to know what the sort of social dynamics or something like that will be but yeah absolutely
it's something that i i have no doubt will start to occur and the concern with this stuff is always
um you know do you start to get um and sorry the name of the server of the thing is of the discord
server that's incredibly infamous is slipping my mind right now but uh you know the uh there's an
infamous discord server where people do trading for things like that and so there is a concern
that it's like you know i'm effectively trading uh access to um something like that
for uh you know out of game uh which is always concern but uh i guess we sort of decided that
we were sort of hoping that it doesn't end up going that way just and we're so excited to sort
of change the atlas over to this method that um this is uh you know just something that we decided
you know what i think we're willing to take the risk on that one uh but i mean it's sort of an
interesting one like if that becomes a problem we might have to find a way around to solve it um i
guess we'll sort of just have to see uh i mean look yeah we'll see what happens all right fair enough
answer i'll send it over to gazi i think he had a question uh yeah well we'll throw in one and
rewind back in time a little bit to an interview you did with a d4 streamer voodio and in there
there was a question regarding uh competitive game modes and races and whatnot community events with
you know with scissorin has the gauntlet event that's been very prominent with and the question
was about that being in pwee 2 and you answered yes now what we want to do is have you spill more of
the beans here and give us some more details can you give us anything are there any plans in the
works etc etc so at the start of early access we won't be able to do any of that stuff we just
haven't had time um but look it's definitely the kind of stuff that i like to do like i really like
those sort of pve but yet competitive uh type of events um like they're just really fun to me um so
uh you know i i have no doubt that we'll be doing some of that stuff it's just that yeah like for
early access we just haven't had time um the custom league system will come back in pwee 2 as well
so you'll be able to do that stuff and that sort of helps people organize their own races and things
like that uh which we'll have there it won't be once again not day one of ea but pretty soon after
that we'll get that in and like by the way the thing that's blocking that is literally just like
some of our web developers need to port the interface for that over to the path of xl2 website
right it just hasn't been done yet so we just as soon as i've done they've got that in order then um
uh then that'll be available so um yeah like we're absolutely going to do
i think a lot of people really like the the old school races that we used to have many many years ago
like the descent races i love that i love that it was 12 minute races like everyone can participate
in that because they're like the race to 100 we talk about that a lot right but that's a very like
that's a lot of dedication and time invested but these shorter races and an hour half an hour endless
dell like i think a lot of people would really like to see them come back again i i would as well
the funny thing about that was is that as cool as it was and as like much as the community liked them
for whatever reason it just didn't really result in people like it just didn't really result in like
actually more people playing and that was kind of the reason why we found like and like because so
it just it really sucks because it's like well this is one of those cases where it's just a mercenary
decision of like this while everyone loves it it just doesn't result in more players so that's like
if we're talking about spending time doing all that stuff versus adding more content to a league
launch that definitely adds more players unfortunately it just had to go to the leagues but the thing is is
that it was just really cool and so like if we had if i had some spare designers up my sleeve
um then i would 100 get them working on this because uh it's something that is just super awesome
and um i look i what i i definitely think we should try it again as well for pwee 2 like you know times
have moved on a long time since back when we were doing that stuff so i think it's worth another try
and see like does that stuff actually heat up into an actual um uh you know into into a scene of
racing and so on that actually like causes you know there to be like you know like like just interest in
itself coming to the um coming to the game so um yeah like look i have no doubt we'll try some races
um just not immediately and uh before i send it over to uh dm again yes or no are you in favor of
having a battle royale pwee 2 events uh well i mean it would certainly be cool let me think about this
is it more skill-based gameplay now yeah so i'm actually just thinking about this i'm just i'm just
thinking as you're saying this like okay so how how would the new system translate uh to a battle royale
format because one of the things that was interesting i think about the pwee 1 version was the like
the randomness of what skills you found i would in pwee 2 of course you've got the uncuts i mean that
probably is fine but i don't know it's kind of like it wouldn't really be hard to do to just try it
i think you know the thing with something like a mode like that is it's really easy to just like try
some random stuff but to really make it actually good would require quite a lot more work and um at
one point we were actually pretty keen to make like an actually good version of the battle royale thing
because you know when we announced that originally like when i said one day development it really was
just like you know like one like it was a limit of like one day per developer of how much time they
were allowed to spend on that because it was like literally an april fool's joke uh and it turned out
like it's kind of like one of those things that's like fun for uh like for for a few days uh but uh it
didn't really have like long lasting good gameplay because like no one had real i mean we didn't we didn't really
test it right we just kind of just like did some random shit and put it up there and it was kind
of cool um so uh that was that was a fun little experience but um we did discuss like should we
make an actual proper version of this like would this be something that actually works well and we
were kind of almost did but um i don't know just like other stuff other stuff happened we didn't
end up doing it but uh you know what maybe we should have another just like random fun battle royale
and poe 2 event just even if we don't like you know just another one of those just like ultra kind
of garage style just like you know everyone just hey everyone just like make some random stuff and just put
it in there and just see what happens it could be fun i think so i'll send a ball i used to do
i used to i used to do way more like way back in the early days of poe 1 i used to do just like way
more rando stuff like that um that and i really enjoyed doing it but um for various reasons like um
uh it's kind of like i don't know like i just never really like i find this stuff on so in a random
example of this is i was like okay you know what i'm gonna do i'm gonna i'm gonna have a level one dps
competition so we had a competition for like what uh what what is the character that can get the
highest dps at level one and um then what we decided i think we gave away like we're like okay
if whoever wins this we're just gonna give like a t-shirt or something there was just some random
like prize that we were just gonna give away um and um i was like man this is really smart because
like if you use other characters to like rush your level one character but then make sure they never
get any leech any experience that you can like get all the quests and like get all of the like passive
points that you can get when you're level one and there's like quite a lot you can do
and it's like then it's like okay what's the minimum amount of experience you can possibly
get by killing the mandatory bosses uh like uh in order to get the quest flags like it was like
all these like little things i was like man people are gonna have so much fun with this stuff
and um then we got all these like kind of negative reactions about it of people being like oh you know
you have to cheat you have to moldy box to do this competition like there's like are you saying
you're endorsing doing this and there's like all this random stuff that the community kind of
reacted negatively about with this um because because i guess they were kind of feeling like um
oh you know like some guy who's like willing to spend all this time and like find the best level one item is
going to be the one who wins it it's like well yeah that was kind of the point right like i was
hoping that a bunch of people like some random like total basement dwelling people would be like
you know i'm going to spend like freaking a week on this and like find like what the best possible way
with like all these steps is going to be and then that person will get a prize right like it's just
a completely out there thing um and um you know that is what happened uh but for some reason people
got angry about it and i was kind of like you know um i guess i just don't understand like to me
that's cool it's like it's not like this is some big feature that we worked on right it was just a
random idea i had so like i i really love doing that kind of stuff and i feel like um you know
like it would be cool to do more of that but it kind of requires i guess a certain mindset in the
community so i don't know uh like there's always this worry whenever you do something like that of
like why are you wasting time on this when you could be doing some other thing right um so uh yeah
that's always that could be a concern
i missed all these i'm just sitting here thinking back because i think the reason this came up in
conversations on previous podcasts we did with pox pox was going through all of the different
battle royales and pvp modes and all these fun events and i realized there's all these fun events
that i missed out on being you know i knew her head to poe so i hope at some point those do come
back i mean you never would have experienced uh you never would have experienced descent which
was another one of those kind of like kind of relatively quick to make things that we did
where we just kind of remixed a bunch of content and put in a random order with like special
chests and everything and it was kind of a race event for a race that wasn't the game um and it
honestly didn't take that long to make um but uh yeah it was it was pretty cool it was fun it was
fun making all that stuff it was it was really fun it was it was incredibly enjoyable well what you
missed dm the best one was like we i remember you guys put the br into a twitch rivals and it was
just massive it was hilarious well plus one for minigames coming in the future um something that i
didn't maybe i'm just dumb but i didn't see it in any of my early play tests i didn't see it in
any of the interviews or any of the footage you guys showed gym quality is obviously a thing we
have like gym lean legionnaire for instance showing you plus quality obviously it's scale not support
was a difference made but how do you actually do that from my under i didn't see any gym colors
anywhere so i'm curious to know what's going on with gym quality and the impact that you're hoping
gym quality will have in the game yeah so effectively what we've done is we've made gym quality a late
game thing um because uh so it's kind of an end game that you get it um it's not restricted to any
one um system or anything like that but it's just something that starts dropping in end game only
and uh effectively um uh yeah they just increase like various things now gym quality was one of
those things that i think was a bit over complicated or like there was things where like we want to try
and do a little bit better when it comes to like what stats we're choosing to scale uh to make that
a little bit more fun um i don't have a full list of what they are anything like that yet um mark this
is actually something that's like coming in really late um like i know gym quality is a thing we're doing
um like like the balance of that has only been done in like the last few weeks um but uh yeah it
is a thing it's like a nice it's nice to have another kind of grind that's like uh you know just
to perfect uh to perfect the gym and there's even a few other things like that uh of like perfecting
your gems i'm there's one other one but i don't know whether it got in or not uh so maybe i shouldn't
mention it um but relating to that so um we'll uh no you can go ahead go ahead okay um you need to
have like quite a few different systems at the end where it's like okay you can just eat you can just
e-card another 20 percent you can eat out another 20 percent with this you can eat out another 20
with that right and so you kind of want to have a lot of those things so um the uh there's the there's
the role of uh fusing orbs which yeah that was the thing i'm i don't know whether it's in or not so
we'll just i'll just leave that as a cliffhanger there um there's uh things like yeah there's you've
got gem quality um you've got uh which i think i think is the 20 percent and then of course the um
gem legionnaire can go above that um now generally speaking it has to improve the skill by 20 percent in
some axis but we're not going to say it's not just going to be just damage like it's going to be something
ideally a stat like maybe in some cases but ideally it's always something that's kind of a
bit more interesting than that um so uh that's the hope anyway and uh because of the fact that
it's not just damage that means that we can um have it be um something that's sort of end game only
and uh the it's going to be harder to get than most other things because regular quality items you can
um get by uh by salvaging um uh from from other items that drop with quality but i believe that gems
don't drop with quality so every single point of that is going to be hard earned using a um a gcp
i jam cutters prism um so uh yeah that'll kind of be one of those just final grinds uh at the end
game of like getting all of those getting enough of those um and uh yeah i think that should be uh
just you know just one of those extra things that answers that um so speaking of skill gems there
was one other skill gem that we saw teased one time and then wasn't talked about again which was
mounts in particular uh also is going to the ranger right we saw the ranger but
two two questions here which is are there more than just the row amount and are mounts more than
just ranger can i be expected to be a titan double fisting two-handed maces swinging off the back of
a you know a rowa surely unfortunately not so uh the ranger the rangers are sorry the rower i should say
is a ranger well no i mean it's not ranger only but the the bonus that it gives is the ability to um
to to fire while um without slowing down um so uh only only bow well uh yeah only only like arrow
skills are ones you can actually fire off the back of a row um so anyone else could write it um but
it's not going to give you any advantage to do so because um you know it's just like you the main
thing you're getting is the ability not to slow down with arrows um so uh yeah it's it's not like
some larger system really it's just like a thing we made for that and you know we just thought it was
cool um and because the thing is we don't want mounts to be like faster so the reason why it's
faster for the ranger is because she gets to not slow she just effectively get to not pay the penalty
of slowing down while shooting but um we don't want mounts to just be faster than running in any
case because if we do that then it's like the whole different gameplay consequence and like uh that we
don't want to have to deal with um so effectively uh that sort of limits the number of things we can do
with a mount like that now i think it'll be cool later to do more mounts for more things like you know i'm
sure i'm sure there's ideas that you could have that'd be cool but uh at least for the time
being that's the mount that we've got and uh you know we uh won't be uh i am hearing for the sake of
role play cosmetic andy i do get to at least sit on the mount and walk around in town or something
like that sure sure and we you know we could probably make some cosmetic mounts as well that
were the same in that same vein i suppose uh nothing stopping us doing that so uh you know that
might be fun i mean on that topic i'll pitch you this idea obviously i want some royalties so i like my
skeletons to when they when i mount up to fall apart and the bones of the skeletons to form a
skeletal horse and when i dismount i want to deform the skeletons again okay
you will get exactly one cell it will be gossy behind the mount
i will be so cool um moving on to um uh assembling things question it's crafting related
uh so i don't want to spend too much time on this because the crafting is very different but it's
what we're going to see a lot when we play but i will ask a couple questions about it so let's start
with essences now we are uh confirmed to be able to use essences multiple times where they guarantee
a modifier what we've seen is making a normal item into a magical item guaranteeing one modifier
we've seen essences making a magic item a regaling essentially to turn into rare with a guaranteed
second modifier if you want to um so i guess the first question is regarding essences is this a
guaranteed specific modifier or is it a uh 1x speed modifier or 1x attack modifier yeah so it is listed
as a it's it's one of a group but in many cases um that that for a given item type um there's only one
mod of that type that could spawn anyway um so effectively like in those cases um there it's
completely guaranteed but there's a few cases where um it could be one of a couple of mods but
generally speaking uh for a given item type uh it will just be one mod and uh one the the main
reason why we did it that way um even though mostly it's just a single mod anyway is because we didn't
want to have the thing where you've got the giant list where for each item type it's like here's what
mod you're going to get and like this is kind of annoying so uh we just wanted to say like it'll give
you a you know mod of a certain group and then uh that way you can sort of know what you're going to
get from that um so uh yeah effectively um generally speaking though you're going to know what you're
going to get from the uh from that mod except for like yeah a couple of specific cases i think
okay on the follow-up there we talked about that earlier with the wiki in-game to search for
monsters talked about that a little bit earlier i guess another question in similar fashion we for
crafting is there any idea or desire or even plans to give us the tool to look at the tooltip in-game
of seeing these are the modifiers that can be applied to x to this item to avoid again having to go to
third-party sites and tools so we actually were going to have um so i'll give you some uh
i'll go okay okay so at the event that you even went to dm uh there was probably you might have noticed
the uh crafting bench uh that we still had in that version uh and uh that actually got cut
and so what that was going to be was not only was it a crafting bench but also it effectively served as
your um as as your uh encyclopedia of mods because you could see when you put an item in there exactly
what mods could actually go on it because the the user interface not only sort of had the crafting
thing but it also had kind of like the the you know like here's the mods that can spawn and like
sure some of them grayed out because you can't um uh you you can't you can't craft them on this item
but you could at least see what they were so we actually kind of were working towards something
like that but the problem was that the crafting bench had all sorts of issues which i mean i could go into
if you want but like uh but suffice to say the issue the feature got cut and so now we currently don't have
something like that um and that's a bit of a shame because i do think that being able to see that
stuff in game is good and like we were actually doing something useful with that um so uh it's
possible that we might bring something like that back a little bit later like we did a bunch of ui work
to kind of get this to be the case uh and i do think that it's good to have that stuff in game it's
just that we don't currently have that for mods um and uh yeah that's a bit of a shame i mean
go ahead sorry you won't go ahead okay i was gonna say you know uh not to dive into
the reasons for the cut of the crafting bench as much as to do you still expect it to come or is
it a decision like we shouldn't have this in the game as much as like we it's not rady technically
there's bugs or something you know it's like a to be determined or it's like no firm decision
it was a design problem not a uh not a technical problem so i might as well just go into it right
might as well just go through the whole thing so effectively um we had this whole so during betas
actually we had a lot of feedback um all the time about people saying um i don't have a way you're
not giving me the tools to um to fix the problems that i have with my build right and um the type
of player that we were getting that from a lot was up here we won players right because they're used to
the crafting bench um and the crafting bench absolutely is a way uh to be able to fix problems
with your build so um the first way that we um uh i'm trying to think back so so the problems that we
had with the crafting bench um is it kind of trivialized certain mods and the other the other the
the issue the designers often have is like okay effectively what it does is because the mods you
can get from the crafting bench are kind of like they're not top tier but they are kind of good
enough i guess um so it meant that effectively a rare item was only six so it was only five mods
plus a crafted mod and that sort of reduces the amount of um of of power you can get at the top
end on some level or like like the level or the degree to which randomness can cause an item to be
good relative to the average item which some people would say is a good thing right like or and some
people would say is a bad thing but the point is there was always this contention around this
right with the designers and so on um so that was like sort of one of the issues so then um
the other issue was uh just the way the costing was i think it was just like i can't remember exactly
what we're unhappy about with that but effectively we're unhappy about that so we come up with another
design and the first design of it was what we're going to do is we're going to say that um whenever
you get an item you can salvage a mod off an item that will destroy the item and then you'll get
some kind of juice of that mod or like maybe some kind of essence or something like that like
was you know effectively you'd get some kind of amount of like something for that mod and then
you would build up to the point where you can then put that mod on another piece of gear
so um we uh tried this out and um the problem that we were having was is that if uh we tried like
five different ways that this could work um in terms of like how it could work and generally speaking
there was always this fight every single time of like if we make this like easy enough so that players
can easily do it then the designers start to get unhappy about the fact that items are becoming too trivial
like we're not happy about this like all these sort of issues like that and if we make it so that um
the the players um uh so that the designers are happy then the players like this is just busy work
and it takes me forever and i have to salvage all these items you're making me make decisions and
there was like all sorts of things that like players were just not very happy about it just didn't feel
fun to actually use like i actually was never really happy with it in terms of just the user experience
um of using it so um we so we we we had built this whole thing and like we we balanced it a whole
bunch of different ways um and then we i think we were getting we were a bit too close to the issue
because the other thing that was happening through all of this was like you know like mark often was
like oh you know what if what if we just didn't have the crafting mix like can we just not have it
like the item system does work like there's all these complaints but you know like but maybe we just
don't need it and i know that rishi as well was kind of like yeah i don't i prefer he was like i prefer not
not to have it but then like if it works this way then i am okay with having it it's like
no no one was happy you know what i mean like like this is not a good thing um when you've got a
system like that um so eventually i think i yeah as i said it was saying i was a little bit too close
to the issue because i was like we can't launch into early access without a crafting bench because
the crafting bench is just a thing that players expect and like if we don't have a way for players to
feel like they've got a way to solve problems like resist or something like that um then people are
going to crucify us right like it's a really big issue and eventually and i don't remember who i
think it was rishi even who might have suggested this he basically just said hey so because that's
right because at one point i was like what if the crafting mix just added an extra mod so it didn't
affect the existing mods you just add an extra mod even if you already got the mod on the item
if it just adds an extra mod then it would solve the problems because um it doesn't like uh interfere
with the randomness of the other mods but it also lets you solve your problems so like there shouldn't
be any issue like sort of and that and that will kind of like yeah that'll solve the problem but we still
had the problem where people weren't really enjoying actually destroying and salvaging mods of items
like adding the extra like here's another thing to think about uh and the item system was just
something that people weren't just didn't it just wasn't fun so then rishi said okay well you're
talking about adding uh an extra mod to all items well we already have the socket system that we created
for um uh for ultimatum for the for the val orbs because at the time what they did is it could add one
socket but you didn't have existing sockets on items it was like what if we just allow exist sockets to spawn on items
we have a currency that lets you add sockets and we just also have just common runes that have just
like the standard mods um and this took basically no effort to implement because we already had the
stuff for sockets we already had like uh basically everything we needed and it pretty much exactly
was filling the function that the crafting bench was supposed to fill uh but yet it didn't have but
yet it feels fun because you don't have to have this busy work of having to salvage mods uh like you
know uh like salvage mods all the time um so effectively it just was just a way better solution
and as soon as we tried that it's like you know designers are happy players are happy everyone's
happy um so it was just immediately just uh just way better so um yeah but it does mean that we just
don't get that nice encyclopedia of mods that we had before um so i mean that that still exists right
like we could put that in a moment's notice we have the system but um what worth what i'm thinking is
is maybe we can find a way to get something of that nature in later on without it requiring um as much
busy work so one thing we discussed was like well what if we had this as an end game thing because like an
end game you wouldn't have uh as much of that tension problem of like because in order to make
the balance work for the amount of juice you need for a mod to work both at early game and at late
game the kind of balance you need to do is like kind of annoying with like massive exponential scaling
factors and like stuff like that um so uh you know that that was a one thing's like maybe it would
work if it was any game only system so i yeah i guess that's a bit of a ramble but effectively all
that is to say uh we've got the sitting in the wings we could theoretically bring it back the
problem is a design issue not a technical issue it's just like we were never happy with how it played
um and so yeah maybe one day we can make a way for it to work i appreciate you going into the
detail on it because it's actually it's really cool to hear the thought process behind it instead of
just hearing it's not going to be in the game like actually hearing the process of how you you came
to it i appreciate the answer going guys you're going to say some sorry um i i do think about like
the whole idea with the crafting bench so we're not going to have a crafting bench it's being replaced
by sockets featured uh i think it's it's pretty fair the way that approach is it seems to solve the
situation but we also have the idea of micro transactions of bench bench uh micros that
needs to be supported in pua2 what's stopping so i think so i think that for uh for now at least i
believe that the salvage bench um obviously it's like way less of a big deal um but the salvage bench
you can still have that in your hider you can still rethink that how you like and then if we do add
the crafting bench back then you'll just be able to reskin that as well um there are also a couple of
other things that are basically benches so effectively you'll be able to reskin those
using crafting benches that you've already bought um as long as they're in the game then you have
that so effectively that's what you get for now um i do that understand that it's like a little bit
weird because um the uh you know the bench is not like the salvage bench is not as big of a deal as
what the crafting bench was in poe1 so like uh the the you could argue that the reskin has less value
in that sense but it's still a thing you can put in your hideout and still use in that way so
you know we still have the compatibility there but think of it this way like it might be a
a far-fetched idea where like think of the crafting bench of you putting your item in that
you want to craft on and then implement the feature like rog pog crafting so you have a menu say hey i
want to use the chaos orb you click on that one it will tell you this is what's going to happen to
the item then you have to click craft now we have a proper use of the crafting bench it features some
pwe1 to pwe2 i think people would like that with the idea of like showing the modifier that can apply
to the item it's like one of the things pwe2 is so far is doing really good job at is preventing us from
utilizing third-party tools and sites to the extent that it is and that could be a step in
that direction again just spitball in here um but um i want to move on to another part of this question
because otherwise we're going to sit here for another couple of hours um and it is about metacrafting
we saw the omens uh allowing you to have the metacrafting approaches um so this question is from
empyrean so shout out to him for this by the way um the question is can we use multiple metacrafts at
once or multiple omens at once for a craft right i believe that you can't but i could be wrong about
that but my understanding is it's one omen at a time um so uh yeah that uh does i think they would
probably get too powerful if you're able to use more than one at once uh i guess you haven't seen
the whole list yet but um effectively yeah uh one at a time is the is the main is the main idea with that
all right well next yeah we're going to move over here to uh ascendancies and trials related
question real quick so we saw the ascendancy we know how you do it you do it through the trials
one of the things that we were trying to get some clarity on is do you get points uh from the trials
based upon how you how far you progress in the trials or is it the type of situation where you're
going to do multiple different trials to get the points i know there's like the coins associated with
it so i was hoping we could you know hear how you go from you know your first two your second
two etc in terms of points so effectively as you get higher level coins uh for example if you get
coins in the case of sanctum so as you get high level coins um there's like certain level bracket
break points where new floors open up so each floor uh in the case of sanctum there are there are
four floors and then um those effectively if you complete floor one you get two points if you complete
floor two you get your second two etc um but they only the extra floor only becomes available once you get a
a coin of a higher of a high enough level and it says on the coin like how many floors um you're
allowed to do uh based on that coin um so that means that you can't ascend a second time as soon as you
as soon as you get there like you do have to get to a coin from a slightly higher level and the same
is basically true of ultimatum as well so um effectively it'll say on the on the on the ultimatum
how many uh how many rooms uh you're able to do uh and thus uh and basically for that one um it's the
number of bosses uh that like you feel so after you've killed the first boss you get two points after you
kill the second boss you get two and then the third boss you get another two and then the uh the final
challenge at the end uh the fourth boss that uh have you that content if you're able to kill that
one then you get your fourth set of points for that so effectively both in both cases um there are
four bosses that you can kill um uh and effectively once you've defeated you know the second set of
them uh then you get more points and so on and so forth now i think you alluded to this earlier but
just to further clarify atlas progression can be done in a group as well as ascendancies can you
do those in a group so when you go to do the the ultimatum etc you can yeah so everyone will be able
to ascend everyone will be able to ascend if you go to a party um for the for the atlas um the uh the at
the atlas state uh is only one like like it's one person's state um but uh obviously everyone's getting
rewards and so on from that but um like but in terms of like actually like exploration um only
one person is getting that exploration because they've all got separate atlases so effectively
it has to be that way i'm assuming the atlas modifiers go off the person who like opens the
point who's yeah yeah so effectively that yeah exactly exactly okay all right um yeah we'll move
over to uh the next we're gonna go a little faster so we don't waste your time either or occupy too much
of your time we're getting towards the end here yeah um so we saw a lot of skills being involved for
specific weapons in the reveal we saw them open up an uncut skill gem as it was swords maces and flail
um so the questions first is are there more new types or different types of weapons to come
and can we hear a bit about those we'll start with that yeah so effectively all of the um on that list
it does have the full list of all the weapon types now i should mention that like the weapon types
for classes that are sort of designed for classes that we're not releasing yet um we're not giving
um the skills for those out either at the moment uh and that's just because um like effectively the
weapon set of skills there is the class like and then if we so if we're doing that we'd also have
to do all that other work as well um so effectively um there's there would be no point if we if we did
that and um that does actually mean by the way that like swords are not dropping in poe 2 right now
because there's no sword skills for them so there's no point uh in having them do that so effectively
yeah like uh the one the ones that we've announced like those those set of ones that that's what
you're getting at the moment and yeah as throughout early access we'll add some more but effectively
that we do have that list on the side so you can see what they'll all be and um we'll talk more
about like the specific play style of each of those weapons as we get through it but i one i will say
one thing is that the the skills that you get on each weapon type i do want to make sure that if
each weapon type feels very different from one another like i do would say that in uh poe 1 that like
the difference between an axe and a sword is like not really that important um and i kind of want to make sure that like it
feels like the skill set you get for each one is more distinct and um you know that they have and
thus the play style is different so uh yeah we'll uh you obviously see more about that as we have the
more classes fair enough but you said that there were all of them there and in the playtest that i've
been part of we've seen both one scepters and staves but there were no skills related to those three
is that something we're going to see in the future uh so the uh ones ones are kind of like you know
part of the occult line and each wand has its own skill on it so there's actually a bunch of skills
on those ones and um yeah as you play through the game uh effectively those will be part of your set
of um of skills as well uh and then scepters um scepters have uh so there's actually two lines of
scepters there's the ones that are more minion focused and those either give you minions or things
that support minions and then there's the ones that are kind of designed to be more um
uh well more for a different class uh so the there's there's another class as well that uses
scepters commonly um i actually don't know whether or not any of those scepters are in the game currently
but effectively there's like kind of a line of scepters that are designed they give you spirit
um but they're more not so much about minions uh they're about something else so question mark
yeah it's pretty obvious we're gonna get a pal but um pretty obvious but uh effectively um so you've
got that as well so and then and then you've got the um the staves which also have their own set of
things as well so effectively there's actually quite a lot of skills that are represented there
um that um you don't see in those lists because they're kind of separate and actually one thing
i should mention that maybe it wasn't obvious is that anytime something says it grants a skill
that skill is supportable with support gems so like in the um uh in the in the presentation on if
you saw in a sentencing class and that a sentencing class node says grant skill and then some skill
you can support that skill with with sockets uh uh on your character so like that time stop for
example like that's a supportable skill you can put things on that um and uh stuff like that so
that's actually kind of one of those things that's yeah not not entirely obvious from just looking at
it fair enough uh we'll move over to the next question which is with life not on the passive
tree the shout out to kripparian for this one uh are some characters still uh going to potentially
be significantly tankier than others as they are in pue one just to give some more context for the
people watching we're talking about the difference between say a ci versus mind of a matter versus
life stacking armor evasion etc yeah so i mean you can still absolutely get life you know from gear
um but the main way that the tree is going to allow you to uh get uh uh to get tankier is
effectively other effects like to do with defenses right so you know armor evasion and so on and
there's quite a lot of stats around modifying those and doing different things with those i think
there is a lot of scope for that kind of thing um and i think it's more obvious to a um a new player
that if you want to be defensive then go for all this armor evasion or whatever nodes like um the whole
breakdown of like some x percent needs to be life or whatever i think was confusing before
um so effectively now um you know if you want defensive to be more defensive allocate those
defensive nodes and you should be doing fine um we do want to make sure that you can feel a lot
more defensive than some other characters for sure um and uh the uh yeah i mean i guess there's not a
huge amount more to say about that effectively yeah just effectively yes we want to have the
ability to control a lot of defensiveness uh from the tree i'm going to rapid fire a few uh
questions related to warrior ascendancies here so one of them that got shown during the la
presentation that went on i or actually open world games video and then has been kind of spread around
right etc is the effectively the rucksack is back so you have the titan it says plus 20 inventory space
there's been some questions related to quality of life being something that you get as an ascendancy
point related to only a particular ascendancy so uh could you elaborate on the decision behind this
um i guess there's not really a huge amount to say for a say about it like um mark mark was the
one who was like yeah we should probably do this and you know like he uh he'd probably be a better
one to answer that question but um he's he was kind of like you know what i think we'll try it out
right if it doesn't work we'll just change it uh just true of anything we do so you know yeah i
don't think there's some big deep philosophy around this it's just kind of like you know hey uh you know
sure i yeah for context i think the reason people are asking is like well i want plus 20 on my class
you know it's type of questions here well um so uh i do i'll interrupt you real quick there like
there's that as well sure but there's also this idea that your first two ascendancy points like
where your ascendancy points you get two of them you kind of want to get the majority of the classes
giving you something that gives you power whereas this choice is only giving you a quality of life
feature and blood mage first two ascendancies is a negative input for the class so i was curious
about the decision making there ah right so okay well i'll give you i'll go into the blood mage one
at least so one thing i should mention about that is that it does allow you to overcap your life by
double which is something that i didn't mention in the video uh but it's kind of it's kind of
important right so effectively if you're picking up those orbs uh then you can get to double the
amount of life that you normally have so uh yeah i actually i actually pointed out yeah mark actually
mentioned that i forgot to mention that upside in the uh in the uh the the the thing so uh yeah that's
kind of an important element as well uh yeah okay all right yeah um that's actually funny yeah but i
kind of look i i'm i i i know what you mean about the uh about about the one with the the inventory
space uh keystone um sorry uh the ascendancy node so uh yeah i understood right like i totally get where
you're coming from with that okay so i'm going to move on to the next uh ascendancy node so during the
footage speaking of the footage of the presentation i'm sitting there and i'm super hyped about war i'm
going to play a warrior i play warrior in all three tests i want it i want maces seeing the giant
splits all looking good right so then they show the warrior class of the ancestral spirit and the
footage shows a monkey who gets summoned he pounds his chest and he runs away to a tree he just runs
away i know i know and this came up during like we saw that so late as well so okay one thing i think
you guys should understand is the fact that like okay you probably assume that this video was ready
like a week ago well let me tell you we were rendering it out the night before and still
freaking working on it right so there are a lot of things about that video that i certainly would
have wanted to improve the monkey running off into the tree was definitely on the list okay uh like
that was that was in there um like uh yeah like that was that was certainly not not lost on us
unfortunately we just didn't get time to uh uh to fix that um but yes i know you look good
yeah i'm not so much trying to roast you about the monkey it's like everyone wants to know what
the monkey do like there's a yeah yeah yeah what is it what does the monkey do can is there any chance
i mean uh it's you know i don't actually have the finer details on this one um it's uh
you know i actually i actually don't know i'm i i i would have to ask mark about that one he's the
one working on that but uh yeah but the thing but but but it was not it was not lost on me though
that one thing like it was yeah honestly like you know it's people yeah it it it it came on
hot that presentation let me just let me just say that all right so it does more than runs away then
yes yes it does more than runs away for sure it's going to be attacking it's going to be doing stuff
it's just i think yeah just ai failed yeah it does something at some point yeah uh the the the jade
would be the next portion we saw the jade is that defensive only there was a jade ramping stack and
lets you gain jade per second so the question is are you gaining jade as you're in jade form
sitting there and then that translates to a buffs of some kind or do you have to stack jade
in order to be able to use the skill so i was hoping so while you're not using the skill
effectively it's building up and that's effectively acting as a counter of the amount of damage that
you can sustain i should mention by the way that um and i didn't do a good job of explaining this in
the video that you can turn on and off like quickly like you've got an amount of jade and it's like
you use it as when just when the boss slams then you can let go it doesn't just you don't just stay
as a jade statue the video made it look like you just stay as a statue until it runs out but that's
not how it works you just hold it down while and you're jade then you let go and you're not
um so uh yeah like a cargo yeah yes well i mean you just hold down the skill right so effectively
okay so you can use that to tank a bunch of damage and without and i think the design intention here
really is that without dodge rolling you can stay where you are and tank like even an unblockable hit
um uh like you know and then attack follow up immediately without having to like dodge away
and like get out of position um so that's kind of the idea of that yeah so it's like a toggleable
uh ball arctic armor kind of thing then well the thing is so i wouldn't i don't like the word
toggleable to use here it is a skill you were using because like while you're holding it it's there
and then when you're not holding it it's not there and also you can't do anything else while you're a
jade statue right it's like it's like it's like it's like a skill that's turning you into a statue
that's unmoving until you let go and then you can follow up again so um yeah it's kind of like
as i said you should think of it more like a dodge roll where you don't have to actually move like
it's a way of defending yourself against a big attack that um you would otherwise uh get away from
all right well that makes it sound a lot better um so uh another question people are going i'm going to
try and make this a little bit faster here uh party play there was the chronomancer looked awesome
was the one that caught me the off guard the most how does the freezing time work in party play
it doesn't it doesn't stop your friends yeah yeah yeah it only stops the monsters so uh you know
so you can overlap these like have someone go and then the next guy go and then the next guy go
theoretically i don't see why not uh that would work um you know yeah there you go um i'm gonna tell
you i'm gonna cut in here with uh two more quick ones and then we're gonna let gazi had some minion
questions after that we're just at the like the q a rapid fire the last few like couple from chat
here and then we're pretty much going to send you on your way um so uh div cards have been in the
game i believe this was confirmed from the puzzle boxes that were originally that was the first
basically mention of this um so we're hoping to hear a little bit of information about how you want
div cards to be you know presented within uh you know this as well as maybe some timelines because i
saw on the packs you guys are both selling this as well as unique items will come up as support
your packs as well so some information related to all of those yeah so effectively um once we've got
the um uh our ducks in a row to be able to sell that because you know like we were a little bit
worried we were just kind of feeling we were planning on selling at the same time as the um
uh as the supporter packs came out um but uh you know we just run we ran out of time a little bit so
we couldn't quite put them up and we were a bit worried because um uh there's a the way the system
works with these limited sale items uh you've got to make sure there's fairness issues around it so
we're kind of thinking like we should probably make sure we've got a time that we're going to
sell and we have some system for like allowing people to like fair access to them because we're
not going to sell too many of them because every single one of them requires an artist draws like
an image you know based on a description that the player supplies so this is going to be a limited
thing there won't be too many of them sold um and then the same is true of the um of the uniques as
well now these are going to be expensive right because the thing is is that we can't sell that many of
them and the cost to deliver a unique item now is like so much higher than it was back when it was just
some art and a few stats like there's a lot going on with these so uh you know we're going to be
doing that um i understand that you got you got one randomly in a in a box is that right dm i did i
was i was curious for myself i wasn't going to take your time asking but since you're bringing it up
i where the boxes sent out did you guys hand pick like you get this one you just put them in a hat
so um there was a 10 chance uh to get a uh a creator unique uh and a 90 chance to get a div card so you
lucked out uh pretty oh my god um so uh yeah so hopefully people don't feel insulted if they
didn't get one of those because it really was random like i've got no idea who they got sent to
um but uh anyway uh what was it oh that's right so the div cards yes so the div cards designed like
you know they've actually got like a new a bit of a new design as well a fresh coat of paint but
they do fundamentally work uh the same way that they worked before the nice thing is is that because
of the way the atlas works now it's much more reasonable for us to make uh the drop rates uh like
you know like like you're not going to be able to since you won't be able to
just grind a single map again and again and again we can kind of make it like the better
in terms of like how often they drop when you find a given map and things like that
and uh just like you know it's just nicer for us to be able to spread them around the atlas like this
so i think that that'll make the div card experience um quite a lot cooler um and uh yeah i think
hopefully it's just a fun time right like just like a you know like we like doing this community
stuff um you know like it's just fun to have the players involved and things like that so uh you know
that'll be fun and of course the uniques are another whole can of worms uh uh where uh you know there's
there's always a there's always a lot of back and forth with the community members about like you
know how op it can be and all that sort of stuff like that like it's definitely always a thing
so it'll be interesting to see how well you can work with uh our designers on that one
i'm still waiting for my box is stuck in customs or something even though i paid for it
sorry about that yeah yeah sorry about that it's not your fault it's sweden's postal service is
horrible it's terrible yeah yeah so at this point pretty much i think we cut gassy loose to ask his
minion related questions i think he had a little list of these here a little list i try to keep it
short i hope everybody's comfortable um so let's just dive right into it if we label this as the gassy
minion rant uh it is short though mind you uh we can start with the footage we watched earlier uh from
uh conflict creators had the demon form from the infernalist when you popped it all the
minions disappeared in the footage in the reveal you had minions uh we need some elaboration on this
so this is actually something that i think probably does need some addressing um because uh right now
since the demon form is a uh is a shapeshift form it means that your weapons are no longer equipped
because you don't have your scepter um and i need to talk to mark about the balance of that because i
think that's probably not correct um this is just one of those things that um like needs probably
some specific stuff so i'll talk to him about that and we'll make sure that um we sort something out
because that uh demon form is obviously intended to be used with minions it has like a like like
it's got specific stuff so you know like i'll talk to him and we'll see we'll see about that
um so uh yeah that that was happening there for sure all right um but yeah as i said i think it needs
to be addressed um the next question is i i know you love this a lot of people don't but i know you love
it and it is the animate guardian will we see it will it work differently uh not an ea but uh we'll
we'll see we'll see about that oh actually oh no no okay there is something uh there no you know what
it's not an ea so i won't talk about it but there is a there is there are some other things that kind
of take some of the design space of that that um that uh you'll see later on uh but uh there are
some there are some stuff uh i just think that it didn't quite make it uh i'm pretty sure it hasn't
made it yet so we won't have it okay um so we obviously have the spirits being the reservations
resource for both minions and auras so could you elaborate on the uh power balance approach that
you have the mindset for minion players when it comes to reserving your spirits like how are we
supposed to incorporate auras or is it just meant for us to just not have any auras they're supposed
to be for minions so a couple of things i'll say one of them is is that on some level you do have to
make some decisions about you know like do i want more or do i want more minion my hope is is that
there'll be some tension there where like in some cases it'll be more of one some cases more of the
other um however i will mention that um you effectively have an aura on a on a on a stick
um with the scepter because the scepters have a bunch of traditional aura mods um so effectively um
you you you that's what the expectation is usually that if you're playing a pure minion build and
you're not wanting to actually hit with your hit yourself and then you'll probably want to go all
all all in with all of the sort of aura mods on the scepter um and that will allow you to kind of
get that kind of gameplay there uh as well so that would be the intention there yeah speaking of
scepters uh i know we talked about this in la a few times actually and that's regarding weapon swapping
uh when you have a scepter in one hand and now your weapon is helping to a non-scepter set so the
intention the intention is to have it so that you can lock uh one of the weapons to work on both sets so if
you've got one scepter that is uh like really good uh then you don't have then you can effectively
lock that in place so that you no matter what you're swapping your other hand to um you can uh
keep that like you can make sure that you've still got your scepter but i believe that that feature
isn't quite in yet and i don't know if it'll make it for early access or not it might do or it might
not depending on whether we get time to do it follow-up question follow-up question on that is
let's say you have a scepter like that gives you x amount of more skeleton warriors and you're weapon
swapping to without scepters now obviously the worst goes away but if the scepter gives you spirit
that you have reserved for minions in what order what minions will be then disappear when you're
then switching to a set that gives you less spirit than you're reserving um good question
now what okay so
now the answer to this is tricky okay because there's okay so there is a there is an odd
there is another user interface that isn't going to make it for early access all right that will uh
much more clearly let you configure this because that interface has a separate column for each
weapons that you have and you can put up and down the minion counts per weapon set in one grid um
because uh so so that actually allows you to really exactly dial in this exact stuff um but unfortunately
we didn't get time and like so there are a couple of problems with regard to spirit and minions and
that interface that we have right now that are like make it a bit more confusing and so we actually i
like i we literally have like prototypes of this but we just didn't quite finish it for ea but
effectively you can control what minions are going to be spawned on what weapons independently and you
don't necessarily have to have it's not necessarily the case that like certain ones die
because you ran out of spirit it can be that you just have a completely different setup of how you
want your minions to be um on the other weapon set if you want and then that some will some will die
and others will summon based on that so you can use weapon sets to effectively have two completely
different layouts of how you want your minions to be uh if you want uh that that is a possibility
that you have because effectively the reservations you have for weapons are per weapon set um and can
be completely configured to whatever ones now any counts that are like you know if you've got a count
on one that's like three and a count on one that's six then yeah it'll like change the three will
die in order to account for the for the other three but effectively you can do kind of any kind of
layout you want actually between the different sets so the way that you'll see that is if you change
weapon sets right now then effectively the numbers will change and the thing and if you adjust them
then it will effectively unlock the two between the two sets that's kind of the confusing part i
think at the moment because it's not obvious that that's occurring and that's the reason why we
wanted to have that grid layout of having like here's one set a here's weapons at b here's the
counts you have in each one um so to make that very explicit so you can see what's going on there
and it's the same with auras as well where you can have like auras enabled and disabled on certain
weapon sets but it's like not very obvious with the user interface that we have at the moment that that's going on
okay okay um it seems like you have that seems like the solution to have one set for single
target fights and one for clearing essentially yeah you can do things like that if you want
what were you saying i'm sorry oh i got a question uh just because you're talking about weapons
weapon swapping here so dual wielding the thing that i thought looked interesting is dual wielding
two-handers obviously look pretty cool um so i'm kind of curious is is the benefit of dual wielding
two-handers like is it the same as poe one or how exactly does the benefit of of dual wielding
two-handers scale in poe two yeah so effectively it's actually different per skill um so every
skill has got its own decision about how uh dual wielding works with it um in some cases that will
be visual in the sense that you can just see the fact that you hit with both weapons like in the
animation right so like they're just now what we're generally trying to do is make sure that each attack
just like both weapons are inside it um and the animations might be such that like like the idea is to
try and sort of balance that with like what what the animation is effectively doing
um but i usually you'll hit with both weapons in a single attack but there are some attacks where you
alternate and then you are faster and there are some attacks that hit with both at the same time
and it merges the damage packages so that you get like all of your stuff in one like it actually is
just very skill dependent um so uh yeah they you'll have to sort of play around a bit to do that but um
one thing you might have noticed is that um on skill gems now and this is also true in the skill in the
in the advanced skill uh screen um there's different tabs where you can see uh the different like you know
like you'll have like weapon a and weapon b and different tabs and things like that i believe
that's how it works anyway um so that means you can kind of see like how that how that all interacts
and um yeah but effectively yeah different answer per skill all right okay uh i'm gonna move on with uh
with my minion rant and say uh i'm just gonna say one word and a question mark and the word is golems
uh not right now but uh i am sure we'll come we'll come to those in the future all right um
um we'll uh we'll wrap it up uh with a couple quick ones from the minions shout out to creep for
this one and that is the first question here is permanent minions have commonly had lower power
scaling than that of temporary minions in poe 1 and the question is will this theme still be a thing
in poe 2 despite the lack of generating corpses versus bosses so effectively the temporary minions
are designed in such a way that they can make a boss fight make sense in terms of damage and everything
that you can do and the temporary minions are kind of designed in a way to make it so that when you've
got uh your permanent ones plus also your temporary ones then that makes sense for clearing so um this
is kind of a way to have like a different situation for um uh for for bosses versus non-bosses now there
are certainly cases where you've got bosses that have minions and then those ones you can raise
temporary minions and that effectively means that a minion build will have an easier time with those
fights just because like of that you know just because of that um but that's kind of okay like uh many many
fights don't have many uh don't have uh boss is not spawning minions so like it's kind of not like a big
deal and also it's just fine sometimes to just have some fights for some builds are better than others
and that's okay um so effectively yeah the intention is is that with just the permanent
minions that you have um you should be uh uh well with a couple of exceptions there's a few ways to
do a few things but effectively with just the permanent minions you have that should make boss
combat feel correct and it's also kind of important as well because um when you've got a full suite of
temporary minions the amount of minions you can have is like absolutely outrageous and for clearing that's fine but for
making boss combat actually makes sense um having the fewer number by just having only the permanent
ones kind of makes means that like you actually get the like proper combat we're trying to have
uh for boss fights so um yeah i think that that actually does quite work in that way having having
the combination of the two it's funny that you mentioned because that's how it felt playing at even
low level like you had an army it was beautiful yeah yeah uh i will uh ask one last question which is
actually the most important one we saw blood mage we saw infernalist which seems to be like the fire
oriented minion ascendancy but where's my necromancer like is the third ascendancy gonna be like
occult chaos dot curse and minions or what are we expecting to see here i won't say exactly what it
is but what i will say is this one challenge we have with the ascendancies is we don't want it to be
that if you're playing a minion character here's the one ascendancy right like we don't want it to
be that this is always your choice so this makes it very tricky to design because we need to make
sure that there's like something and a variety of these that you'd actually be interested in and um
so that being said look i think like it's a cool fantasy that we want to have the sort of necromancer
type thing but i think that in order to do it we have to make it so it's not just so obviously what
you need to pick um that uh that's the only choice and effectively so this is the design problem we have
so i think that effectively um there's just was a shelving of like we're having trouble solving this
problem we'll just go with these two for now um and uh that's kind of like the the the the the main
issue so yeah that's the thing of the design constraint we're working around with this okay
so now we are uh we made it through all our main questions we have a handful of just like you don't
have to elaborate much just real simple ones that we pulled from the chat right before the the start
and then you know thank you we went a little we went about a half hour longer than we were planning
to hold you but we appreciate you taking the time um so i'll shoot these i'll shoot these last ones
out from the chat here um okay first one strong boxes uh that were shown in the review seem like you
kind of get locked in almost like rich you want to take a really long time for them to come out
this is this is another one of those um i wish we could have replaced that shot um uh things because
like afterwards we're like god damn it like we sped up the freaking spawn rate on that strongbox like
right before we recorded that uh like sorry right after we recorded that and we didn't get a chance to
reshoot it so yes the the number of monsters that spawn from that is much much faster normally uh it's
just that that uh the number was incorrect in that video so uh you should expect the strongboxes just to be
better than that i believe that the smoke thing i i think the smoke thing was just a mod on it
wasn't it um i think it could have been i i think it was the minion pace it was like every time i saw
that when i was watching like uh people react and stuff i was like god damn it i really had a chance
to reshoot that shot like the monkey yeah yeah yeah all right uh so next one here uh mouse plus analog
concurrently like if you have an analog stick plus a mouse can you use them both at the same time this
was somebody asking about an accessibility question we plan to have it so that you can uh swap like so
the ui will swap dynamically between um the console version and the um uh and the the the the keyboard
version um like when you just use each controller but right now it doesn't do that um but that's a
feature that's been really requested so um we're gonna we're gonna get to it we just need to get to it
after the start of ea um but maybe you weren't asking that exactly were you asking about um analog
controller i think they're asking but like like i'm not quite sure to be honest with you really that
the the accessibility but the question in particular uh it says they wanted to use the mouse and an
analog stick at the same time and i'm not sure how that would work because i'm not familiar that is not
something that we currently support um as i said the thing we will support is just the ability to swap
from mouse keyboard uh uh ui to control ui and the main reason for that by the way so because people
are keen to be able to manage their inventory using mouse keyboard um but uh actually play using
controller and um so that's something that we're keen to support once we um you know once we get
around to doing that we shouldn't be too far into early access on that topic we had another rapid fire
question that is mouse and keyboard support for consoles yes or no uh not currently there um i believe
uh it's something that we hadn't really considered until someone asked it very recently um i suppose it
could be done i would have to check in with the console team but um yeah i don't believe it's there
currently all right another really big question which we're going to condense to a rapid fire version
and that is we saw ignite magnitude could you just in a short term explain what magnitude
just a multiplayer on ignite so effectively ignite i believe by default is like 25 of the hit it does
that uh oh geez how exactly is the math well anyway the bigger the hit the more ignite the you
damage you get and then magnitude effectively allows you to scale the ignite just a multiplayer
and this is like with boys as well it is the it determines the dot exactly exactly and then you
exactly uh we had a few questions related to uh separate clients and be able to play both games at
the same time so let's say people will be able to want to play poe one and poe two at the same time
i'm assuming trading or something like that you know um they will be you can do that um it's actually a
a bit weird um there might be um uh like a few slight slight oddities when you do that with regard
to when you change microtransactions and stuff um but it does work um it's something you can do
okay uh ultra wide resolution for instance i have a 49 inch monitor ultra wide resolution poe two how's
that looking um so you can do up to so hang on how big are the what's the ratio of those big ones i believe
that the biggest widest monitor usually is like 29 by six it's a weird yeah it's weird whatever that
number is that's the big ultra wide so we do allow you to go up to that if you go wider than that it'll
start to add black bars um i will say though that like um like qa are not routinely running around
with one of these um so there can be cases where you get like pop it like maybe a few cases it should
generally work but you just might get a few visual things just like like i've noticed cases for example
where it's like the the level is not quite big enough so if you stand in one corner you might see off the edge
of the level very slightly like in a few cases like there's a few kind of like weird things around but
in general it works fine you know it's just that it's kind of not something that we've been like
going out of our way to fix little art issues and when there are issues sure as genre defining
things like minion summoners have been for the for the a rpg world so is cyclone spin to win are we
going to see something like a spin to win skill in poe 2 soon you will eventually just unfortunately
the exact cyclone skill of just hold it down forever and just spin forever we don't have in this
version it is on another class um that will have that um there's are quite a few other skills that
involve swirling around and doing stuff though so um you know it's not like you're not going to have
things similar things like that monk skill which is a little bit different with the the twirling of
the staff it's sort of similar but um yeah the true just like hold down forever and just channel
spinning um that's on a different class that isn't in the air okay um on another topic referring to
peewee one is a spell totem will we see a spell totem in peewee two um you will see it um do we have it in
ea or not i thought we did did we have it in ea or not well look you're certainly going to have it
the question is will you have it soon um i actually sorry i'm actually not sure i mean look it was on
the skill list recently is it still on the skill list well if you're asking you probably isn't right
so it's possible that it was removed from the um from from the sork skill list if um if you didn't see
it uh but so it might have been cut temporarily but look it's it's it's been made it's there it's just
like there must have been some issue with it if it's not there so yeah right here uh how about
modifiers for maps that uh like brick the map for instance you know reflect being notable elemental
immunities things like that concepts for this for peewee too um so we do definitely have modifiers
that are hard and look some modifiers will definitely be something that will be hard on your build i know
we i don't think we've got reflect um but uh you know there are there are just there are mods that are
hard um so it can you know it can happen right there are things like you've got to you've got to have
certain things that you could be a build can be good or bad against i believe um it's notable
though that um the upsides and downsides work a bit differently um because because the uh
upsides are prefixes and the downsides are suffixes rather than having them merged together
um so that means the number of downsides that you face uh it will be lower because there's only going
to be three rather than six and that means that each one is like a bit more sort of interesting in
my opinion as far as like you know like you've got the issue with mod dilution where it's like if you've got
six things affecting you then you barely even notice them because well it's not you don't notice them but it's like
each one is not like as important uh because you know because there's six of them um whereas when
there's three it's like the three downsides actually matter quite a lot so um yeah i think it sort of
changes the gameplay around that quite a bit um but uh yeah sure there might be cases where mods can
can kind of break your build but not try to avoid those if you can um i personally think it's interesting
to be able to play around certain stuff like that sometimes but yeah we don't want to be as harsh as
something like reflectors i would say sure um one question that came up a few times was related to
like an import export for instance for skill trees so for people can effectively copy paste builds in
there it's just a philosophy you guys are for against etc um so they're actually there's a feature that
we never actually finished for this um it's in the game client but i think probably disabled right now
um so it's something that we did plan on doing it's just that the ui for it was kind of crap and we
didn't get time to finish it um but effectively there was going to be a thing where you could make a dot
build file which would effectively be like a skill tree layout um that you could import
and effectively work kind of like an item filter we could throw it in a folder and then the client
will pick it up and then you can select with a drop down which of the builds you want and it just
shows you the layout and you can just allocate this point so we are planning on doing that we just kind
of haven't uh haven't got around to finishing it yet so uh yeah we'll get to it we'll get guide
writers rejoice across the globe um from now till the early access launch 6th of december we're not that
many days off 12 days if my math is right teasers from now till then can we expect yep so
there's definitely going to be teasers the community team have got a bunch of things
or at least they'll be making them um yep it is scary being so close like uh the big concern that
i have um is obviously server stuff now like my big concern is like can we make sure that the servers
are going to hold up um there's a lot of interest um just looking um at the you know the the numbers
i'm seeing from like supporter pack sales and so on like i think there's going to be a lot of people on
day one um so uh my job now is going to be like making sure that that's going to be okay um i
really really hope we can do that because it's going to really suck if we get like launch day
problems um but uh yeah i'm worried we're going to be setting record numbers that will you know be
very hard to deal with but uh you know we'll do our best obviously um yeah that's we just i just that
that's that's going to be my thing to concentrate on going forward fair enough i want to just real quick
follow up on that was because it sounds to me like you're almost surprised by the amount i mean
obviously you know you have a good product you've been making a good product for a while so you're
not surprised you have a good product but what i'm hearing is uh there's a lot of interest maybe
even more so than you were would you say this is accelerating a little bit larger than you guys
originally anticipated or how you know how that's got to be encouraging right it is the thing is is that um
i guess so obviously when we get to um uh to to open you know full release right obviously the
numbers there are going to be ridiculous because it's free you know anyone can play it i guess the
expectation was that because this was paid entry and also like there's just a general feeling around
early access that people have where it's like oh maybe i'll just wait till the release you know like
there's always this kind of feeling of like uh you know i'm gonna i'm gonna wait and i guess my
feeling was that because of the fact we had both that and also the um uh yeah and also the fact that
it wasn't you know like you can't get in necessarily for free i guess i was thinking like
we would probably see sort of similar numbers to what we've seen in previous poe um launches but um
uh yeah i mean just the number of people buying packs and so on i mean it's looking like it's
going to be pretty damn huge and i mean look obviously that was my goal right i wanted it to
be large and the the the part of the whole thing of having so much content in early access is literally
to get this result right so on some level i can't be too surprised um but at the same time
you know there's always those factors of like you know like like i was i was completely certain we
were going to smash it out of the park with regard to the full release i just wasn't certain as certain
that we were going to um have uh records on um concurrent records for concurrency on um on early
access and so it's looking like we will um and uh you know that means we have to make sure that our
servers are up to the jobs uh and it's not really a question of like buy more servers i mean we can always
do that um although even that at some level of scale becomes tricky um because you know like you
you can't just turn up to amazon and be like hey we need like you know 5 000 servers out of nowhere
like you know they're like there actually is some level of like you know of doing that so we're doing
that you know you're getting that all organized but it's also just like the back end right can the
back end handle it um you know we we have to write you know load testing stuff to kind of make sure
that we can like you know try to simulate it but then you know your simulations will never quite
match reality you never quite know uh you know will it actually work so um you know we're doing
our best basically to try and make sure that's the case but um uh yeah i think we could see a pretty
significant amount of people uh turning up early access looking like it's going to be very popular
can't wait uh last rapid fire question we have right now is equip gear even though the gear piece
itself makes you fulfill the attribute requirements there's actually one more question but you know what
i'm talking about let's say you have a pair of gloves they have 20 decks and if you're unequipped
you can't equip the skill gem or whatever can you switch that with another pair of glove with
dexterity without that being a problem uh you can switch uh you can swap them uh when you already
meet the requirements on both you can swap them between and that will not break anything
but currently if you have a piece of gear that will support itself like if you have a piece of gear
where equipping it would give you enough stats to support it unfortunately it doesn't currently let
you do that you have to find a way to get the decks first and that is annoying um and we are
planning on fixing it one day uh we just haven't gotten around to it it's just one it's just very tricky to
implement uh it seems like it's simple but the problem is that to actually do it completely
correctly because there are stats that um affect uh like that i'm trying to think of one out of the
top of my head but it's like if you have a stat for example that says something like this that it
doubles your decks then immediately it's not just a question of like you know adding one and you
actually have to work like you have to effectively work out like okay what would the stats be on my
character if i were to equip this thing including all the changes that would occur from all the
different mods on this thing and then after you've done that then it's like now i've done
none that a fake simulation of that now i need to do that for real and so uh it's like uh it's just
a little bit tricky to actually organize doing that so we will get to it one day because it's a feature
that i'd love to have but um yeah currently it doesn't it doesn't work all right so the last
rapid fire question we have and i'll send you on out is people were asking many times about dlss support
ah yeah we have that nice there you go the answer to that question one thing i will say about it
though just one detail is that um uh the just to get a little bit technical here because you know
i used to kind of do engine programming stuff the motion vectors we have um i don't think
are as high quality as some games have and we're using one of the dlss profiles that's kind of
supposed to be okay with that it just means that some of the motion reconstruction may not be as good
as like you get in some games i think it's pretty reasonable but honestly i'm not a huge fan of dlss
myself anyway like i um prefer um the the the the the un the the you know the raw frames i'm just
that kind of guy i guess um but yeah we have support for it and it works well like it's certainly the
performance improvement you're hoping for it's just that um the motion vectors for some things like
because i mean we're really spell heavy right and so spells are like like all those alpha transparent
effects that's like the worst thing for like upscaling um they're like they that's where you have
all the kind of issues so um that's kind of where you'd expect to see the kind of artifact that you get
from dlss all right well uh that's it we won't take any more of your time uh we'll just take those
questions and go thanks for going you know twice the length really that we expected to be here two
hours i've got a lot of good information is there anything you want to throw out at the end just
because we're about to wrap is anything you want to say ask or yeah i don't know really i think we
probably covered everything but you know i just honestly i just really hope everyone enjoys the game
when we release soon um you know i'm just that's i'm just i'm just really keen and as i said i i'm sorry if
the servers fall over like i'm really like i really really hope we're able to get the service to not
fall over on release day that's just my my one goal now so you know yeah yeah uh we'll do our best
we'll do our best amazing all right cheers thank you thank you very much thank you sir and uh all
right everybody that was it i'm gonna go ahead and go get you off camera here thank you jonathan for your
time no problem thanks for joining us all and all right i'll go i've got the i've got a meeting to go
to so yeah see you later you do that have a good one