just hang out how you were doing buddy
he
Can I ask you guys a question?
Do you guys ever wake up in the morning and ask yourselves, why am I not playing Elden
Ring?
Every morning.
He's locked in, chat.
Two bits, how we don't button.
You weren't a fan of Elden Ring really?
I will.
If you guys did not know, Riker did an interview yesterday.
He asked a lot of really good questions, but I have a lot of follow-up questions for
the questions that he asked.
And I promised people that I would take questions from YouTube.
Someone already kind of answered.
I'll give you all the answers.
It's on our radar.
I want to get inside the minds of the devs.
I want to know their approach to things.
I don't want to know.
I'm not going to ask yes or no questions.
When can we say builds?
I think they already answered that.
They said that they like the idea of an armory.
They like the idea of an armory.
It wasn't the top priority for them to get into the game, but maybe I can reiterate that
it was the top question.
Was it CP Max 205 or something?
And then Sergeant Turtle III.
Every single one of these questions I already had on my list except this one.
Are there questions related to end game improvement?
I guess I can walk you guys through my questions that I have so far.
You would be shocked.
I actually spent a lot of time on this.
I'm trying to be as prepared as possible.
I'm going to need to clean this up and potentially grab more questions from you guys.
I'm actually let me let me change my mind.
Let me do a little bit more work here and then I'll ask you.
It's not quite complete yet.
So they talked about set items yesterday.
They said that set items are fan favorite.
They said that there is, if you think about a character's power, it's a slice of pizza.
A slice goes to skills and paragon and unique and aspects and the athixes and whatever.
If sets come into the game, then it's going to take up a slice of the pizza.
How much of the pizza should it take is what they were talking about.
So one thing that they said is there's no point to implement set items if they're too weak.
I strongly agree here.
Look at the super shitty sets.
I love pizza.
That's what I took it from as well.
That's what I took from it as well.
If you look at last epoch, for example, they release sets.
They're completely worthless.
I actually just filter out set items in my loot filter.
I just filter them out.
A lot of them in Diablo 2, you find a lot of low level set items.
They're useless.
You just go into the black marsh.
You get your, what's it called, your stealth.
Then you make your two spirit items and we ain't got no time for any of these sets.
But they also said Diablo 3, too strong and I agree.
So the thing that I wanted to ask them about is if set items come into the game, where
do they feel is the right amount of power and item slots taken.
I can give them three examples of sets that I think work beautifully.
In Diablo 3, a good example of a set is maybe Captain Crimson's, Ogild's and Guardians.
They barely take up any slots and they have different use cases.
So Guardians is for early game.
Captain Crimson's is if you want cool down and Ogild's is if you want damage.
And another really good example in my opinion is Diablo 2's Talorasha set.
And the reason why is it's an end game godly set but not game breaking.
And two pieces are very rare but not impossible to find the amulet and the chest.
The chest is super difficult but the amulet is very accessible.
This is my example of the three best sets I've ever seen in a game.
Do you guys agree that these sets are well designed?
Don't break the game and add some flavor to the game.
Can you move away from turning D4 into D2 and D3 questions?
Df, I got four pages of questions here.
I got four pages.
I'm asking questions about Diablo 4.
The questions are about Diablo 4 but I will draw analogies to many other games.
I even have a question about Diablo 4 specific unique ideas.
I've put in a shitload of effort into this document man.
Trust me.
I'm not talking about the other games but we can bring up tons of analogies to other
games.
There was an interview yesterday from Riker.
We're going to talk about that.
Here's my question on rumors.
They said yesterday that they like rune words and they see a future.
They initially had rune words coming in but they didn't have time to finish them.
But here's the problem.
Here's the thing for me about rune words.
Rune words to me again is an iconic system.
Iconic system of D2.
But the announcement that they had for rune words wasn't rune words.
It was like a prefix and a suffix and it was like a totally new system with the same
name.
My question is when the team talks about the work that you've already done on rune words,
is it an improvement or an expansion?
On the original rune word system or is it something with a different direction?
This is the thing that threw off the community the most when they initially announced this.
They said rune words are coming to Diablo 4 and then they showed us what it looked like
and it wasn't rune words at all.
So I want to know, it sounds like it may be coming sometime in the future.
If it comes in the future, are you starting with kind of Diablo 2's base of that system
and expanding upon it and changing it and making it work in Diablo 4 universe?
Are you actually going to give us something different?
The interviews in one hour exactly.
On Rikers interview, they took 15 minutes answering each question.
Yeah, I watched Rikers interview for three times over.
I watched it three times.
I'm pretty, I would like to think hopefully this is true.
I'd like to think I'm pretty prepared today.
I watched it three times.
That's why the title of this is CJ's questions in the beginning.
I want to, and I messaged Blizzard.
I said, I would like to continue some of the conversations that you guys had.
The interviews in one hour, guys, one hour.
They did, they talked about all of these.
They talked about all of these and Rikers interviews, guys.
I know.
I watched it three times.
I have a different question.
Riker asked, are rune words coming in Diablo 4 and their answer was they like rune words
and they see a future in Diablo 4?
That's not my question.
My question is, when rune words come to Diablo 4, are they going to be rune words or are
they going to be something different because when they initially announced it, it was something
different.
That's why I want to talk about it, Caramon.
That's why it's my first question.
That's exactly why it's up here.
They talked about aspirational and pinnacle content like three different times.
So...
Yeah, yeah, both.
It would be both.
Okay, charms.
Let's say last epoch, we get art.
So PoE, D3, don't have them.
D2 has them with no dedicated inventory.
Last epoch has them with a dedicated inventory.
Will they ever come to D4?
If yes, would they have a dedicated inventory?
I already have that as a question, Luna.
When is Diablo coming to Diablo 4?
If Joe is smart, he would be in the chat taking notes to prepare.
So let me clarify the situation here, guys.
Never actually individually or one-on-one too much, but I have been talking to Borgio
and Adam.
Me and Joe and Adam had a lengthy conversation about how great Elden Ring is and how all
great all the Souls games are.
By the way, I think both Joe and Adam beat every single Souls game.
Bloodborne, all three of the Dark Souls and Elden Ring.
So they're gamers, right?
I am not going into this interview with a machine gun looking for blood, right?
I am not looking to embarrass them.
I'm not looking to put uneasy pressure on them.
What I want to do is I would just like to get some answers for the public on the most pressing
questions, right?
I want to know what is in their minds and on the team's minds for the future of the game.
So that way we can estimate what we are going to be getting out of Diablo 4.
Like honestly, I think this interview might have some impact for some people on whether
they'd buy the expansion or not.
Because if people like what they're hearing about the future of Diablo 4, maybe they
will have more confidence in purchasing the expansion.
You know what I mean?
This interview is not my personal opportunity to get answers to these questions.
This interview is to go out in public with a bunch of lovely people like yourselves and
ask them some deep questions and see so you everyone else can hear all the answers.
So I'm not going in here for looking for blood necessarily.
You lost 10 million ruins today.
Can't you just go pick them up though?
Maybe just some bruising.
Any question regarding PVP?
I know.
Let's put this in here.
Could ask that.
Give me a second here.
Rob sent me a message and said, racks, if you can squeeze these two questions and get
them in.
So let's try to ask them.
Yeah.
Let's go up here for a second.
Right.
You got five questions in.
Well, I have one, two, three, four, five, six.
I have six, well, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
I have seven questions that came directly from CJ's interview, follow-ups to questions
that CJ asked.
And then I have two other additional things and then I have many, many.
Here's another five questions.
I really want to know this.
A lot of people in the community say, Blizzard never tests anything that they do.
They just throw stuff into the game.
We are the beta testers.
I think people deep down know that that is not true.
So I would like to know how does testing work for Blizzard?
You have an idea for something.
Oh, we're going to do the avatar.
You put together the monsters and the layouts and maybe you get it into a testing phase.
Then what happens?
What is the internal process for testing?
Another question that I wanted to ask at some point, I can delete all of this.
Another question I wanted to ask is Microsoft's impact.
I don't really know though because the problem with this kind of a question, the impact on game
development, here's the problem though.
Let's, I don't know if we're ever going to get, I don't know if we're ever going to
get an answer here because if Microsoft negatively impacted their development, they would
never say it.
They wouldn't, they would, like, they're either going to say Microsoft is great.
We love them or that's not true and they're not going to, and they're not going to answer
it.
I guess we could ask it a different way though that's not offensive.
Maybe we could say the Microsoft takeover and then I guess we could ask them, have they
mostly been hands on helping you guys, providing resources, providing guidance, or are they
very hands off letting you guys do your thing?
They trust you or is it kind of like a mixture?
There's two people, they already said the Microsoft impact is positive, they already said that
Microsoft is hands off, not even the internet can agree.
Okay, hey CJ, can I call you CJ is here?
Wait a minute.
Can I, do you want to chat on Discord for a second?
I watched your interview three times by the way.
Okay, you called me CJ, you called me.
Okay, CJ is here.
We turn off the music, guys.
Remind me to turn it on like CJ is Riker.
Let me message him.
Hmm.
This will also give me a good chance to test my Discord audio here.
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
Hey Ryan, how you doing?
Yo, can you get, okay, he's got to be too low, right?
I turned him way up, can you give me another one?
Here CJ.
Jank 1, 2, testing 1, 2.
How's the volume there, guys?
Up, down or perfect?
Okay, I'm actually getting every answer.
Okay, let's go up slightly more.
Last try one more time.
Jank 1, 2.
It could also be maybe I'm a little on the low side.
How's that?
Okay, we're good.
Hey man, I watched your interview yesterday.
I don't know man, you have like a flow, like you've done this before, you have like a
flow to the conversation that I don't think I'm going to be able to match man.
I'm just rough around the edges, I'm just diving right in, man.
Now you're going to have a different style and I think it's going to be really good that
we're each going to have like different kinds of interviews that are going to get different
kinds of answers.
Like there are some questions that, because we did like, I kind of what you're going
to do in here, we're getting some questions from the audience and I'm like, that's a
big question.
You guys can go ask that tomorrow, where I know it's a bit more granular, it's a bit more
on point.
So yeah, no, I think I'm excited to see you, because you also have Adam Jackson, right?
They're bringing in, they know what to expect from you.
So I'm bringing Adam Jackson to cover those really specific class talking points.
Oh God, I don't even want to know what that means.
Yeah, so I watched your interview, I really liked it.
Again, I added another page and a half of follow up questions to your questions.
Your questions were good, but yeah, I guess with my questions like listening to how you
brought them up, I have some like very, very pointed questions like, how do you feel
about this?
I guess two questions for you.
How did you feel about the interview in general and was there any really pressing thing that
you wanted to get out of your interview that you didn't have time for that you want me
to revisit today?
Oh, that's a great question.
I mean, I got through maybe half of the questions.
I was like triaging them as I was going through them just because I was happy with the interview
overall.
I recognized that I asked some big questions, especially up front that necessitated very
long answers.
And that's something I need to think about going forward is being able to maybe pepper
in the smaller questions up front that can give smaller answers just to get more in there.
Like I would have loved to have hours to talk with you and get through everything and
also ask those follow up questions and stuff.
But I know the Microsoft one was something that was high up on the list.
I don't know, like I was hearing your concerns and I had this, I was going through that same
theory crafting of what can they answer, what are they going to answer?
So yeah, possibly one way of framing it would be what if anything has the deal with Microsoft
a lot of you guys to do now that you couldn't do before because obviously they're not going
to, you know, crap talk Microsoft.
But it's kind of one way to see if there are days being impacted at all by this kind of
stuff.
Okay, keep going.
What else what else would you have asked is good.
Let's see.
One answer that would have been a big, I skipped it because it would have been another big
answer being, well, what's like the most challenging part or what has been the most challenging
part to work on of default to date that can help give insight.
I like to ask questions that get insight into their process because sometimes, you know,
they'll do something and we'll react to it and be like, it'll be obvious on our end or
it'll seem straightforward on our end.
But it's because we don't understand the thinking that went into something.
So I like to ask questions that make me understand what they're thinking.
So sometimes things that seem simple and easy for us to do, like, well, you know, this
was easy.
Why don't you just do this?
That was really challenging to put together, which could also shed insight into, well,
going forward, why don't they just do this?
It's just a flipping a switch, right?
It's like, well, actually, you know, this and that.
You know, I actually, I actually agree with you.
So a lot of a lot of people will actually, not a lot of people, that's not the right way
to phrase it.
Some people think that when we have the opportunity, and this is like a rare thing, I don't think
I've ever been able to speak to Blizzard freely openly.
And they have just like, you know, throw whatever you got at us.
And you can look at a snapshot of Diablo 4 at any point in time and say, I like this.
I don't like this.
Will you buff this build?
Won't you buff this build?
This balance is off.
Da da da da da.
But that doesn't help me project how I think the game will be in the future.
The thing that will help me do that is, what do you guys think over there when you're
in your chair?
We can see all the reddit threads of what people think you think.
But what I want to know is what do you actually think?
And then all of a sudden we can start to figure some things out that will actually, you know,
happen in Diablo 4 rather than focusing on a snapshot in time.
That's a great way of framing it.
Yeah, I also like to avoid any questions that are just basically thinly built suggestions
because we have our ways to pass our suggestions under them.
Right, we have platforms.
We can make a, you know, you make a YouTube video with suggestions, the depth see that
they hear that.
An interview is some like it's kind of like wasting time basically passing along a suggestion
when we know we can get that feedback to them.
Yeah, you know what I actually, I watched your interview multiple times.
I watched a little bit of your follow up conversation as well.
One of the first things that I was going to ask them, you actually touched this multiple
times in different areas in your interview, but talking about kind of like the really end
game, the aspirational content.
I heard them say Lilith was mechanical mastery.
It wasn't based on gear and that it, you know, I agree that most people thought that that
wasn't fun, but I don't know if it wasn't fun because of the hit boxes of the waves or
because it was just challenging.
But then later on, they talked about, again, you asked them again about the aspirational
or the pinnacle content.
And you said, well, they can make players weaker, they can make monsters hit harder, they
can have more health.
But in general, for it to feel like an ARPG, the decisions that you make before you go
into a fight should matter more than in the fight itself because otherwise you're playing
like a souls like game.
But they did mention that when they do have aspirational or pinnacle content, if they
properly label it to the community, then the backlash actually really isn't there as
long as it's properly advertised.
But I would say like, again, my follow up question to that whole idea there is what about
skill though, because the Uber Lilith was the moment in the game where I feel like I
actually triumphed over a tremendous challenge, a peak ahead of me in my Diablo 4 journey
that I finally overcame that I didn't just win because I found a shackle or I got a
perfect role.
I actually had to learn some mechanics, play well and win.
I wanted to ask them, is there any plans for stuff like that in the future?
It doesn't have to be AOE, one shot, crazy hitbox, things like that.
But it sounded to me like they were kind of moving away from that entirely and that honestly
makes me sad.
I think that's definitely worth asking, whether they're planning to add any skill-based
end game or pinnacle content.
One question that I didn't have a chance to ask was, what is your philosophy towards
adding new end game activities to kind of get an idea of what kind of new stuff we can
expect to come or if even say like, no, we're done.
We think we're in a good place now with it.
And I don't think that's the case, but to try to see where their minds add with regards
to what more they're going to add.
Would you see the update from last epoch a few days ago about their one-year roadmap?
I wish I had a chance to.
I'm definitely going to dive into that before the weekend.
I just been slammed.
Yeah.
So it is a spoiler alert if I tell you a little bit about it right now.
Go ahead, please, too.
So in every single quarter, they're making significant improvements to the end game.
Like my title, my title is like last epoch update and my thumbnail was end game, end game,
end game.
There's this every quarter, end game, end game, end game, changing this, adding this,
this new thing, da da da da da.
And again, I'm not trying to ask like, question, like put a gun to their head or whatever,
but I wanted to, I don't know if it would be rude to draw an analogy to that and be like,
you just saw last epoch update and it looks like there's a title wave of many end game
updates coming in their future roadmap and it looks good.
I mean, that's, that makes me happy as a player because like they talked about in your
interview, there's a huge difference between what's fun to do one time and what's fun to
do repeated times.
And a lot of people rip through the campaign and do a couple of echoes.
Like, okay, then what?
But I think these constant updates to end game are going to, are going to do well over
there.
And I want to ask them, is there ever going to be a roadmap for Diablo IV that looks like
that end game, end game, end game, end game, every single time end game, end game, end game.
But what, yeah, what are my questions would have been?
Do you guys plan to do a roadmap?
Yeah.
Give it to me straight because let's be honest, you're the, you're the voice of reason,
you're the sweet little angel, everyone loves you.
And I'm like, you know, like on the shoulders and I'm like the devil with the pitch fork,
is it, is it very rude if I ask a question like that?
Give it to me straight.
I don't know if I might, might have cut up there for a moment, but I, I actually did
want to ask if they were going to do a roadmap.
I don't think they will and I think the reason is they don't want to pigeonhole themselves.
They might even touch about this in the past.
I think I anticipate the answer to be that if they're not going to do a roadmap, it's
because they don't want to pigeonhole themselves into a specific path.
And then if something else comes up, right, and some other fire they have to put out,
they got to rearrange the roadmap.
Now they're going to piss people off because they have to push things off.
I think that will be the reason they would not want to do a roadmap, but I still, it
was a question I did want to ask.
I don't think it necessitates, you know, framing in the context of another game.
If you want to, you could, but odds are they probably haven't seen that video either.
But I mean, roadmaps in general, I think is totally fair play to ask.
Okay, I'm going to ask it maybe in a, in a quote unquote, softer, softer way.
Okay, what else?
What other pressing topics are we missing?
I mean, I have four pages here.
I don't think this is ever going to happen, but I forgot if I managed to ask this, but
I want to ask whether the scope and size of seasons we've seen in two and three is about
what we can expect going forward.
So whether the vision for what seasons are has changed since launch.
Okay.
Without being able to find the question specifically, so I'm going to kind of ramble here the question,
but basically we've seen in the past couple of seasons, there's the season launch and
then there's like maybe one or two things that happened during the season.
I see there are like the Abattoir of Zier or like a mid summer or sorry mid whatever mid-winter
event where there's like a couple points that happened throughout a season that I guess
is intended to bring people back.
Just I'm wondering like what is their intended cadence of I guess content roll out like
is it again is what we have seen sort of what we can expect going forward or do they plan
on having more content beats throughout a season or fewer kind of what they're thinking
there.
Actually, I want to know what your thought is, what do you want to see in a season?
Do you like everything happens on day one and then nothing changes for the rest of the
season or do you like to see some other little content drop, you know, two weeks in a month
in or what would you like as someone who plays these games a lot?
Well, let me tell you something CJ that happens to me a lot.
I don't know if this happens to you, but one thing that I get spammed all the time on
the internet is Rax's opinion doesn't reflect the community's opinion because he plays
the game all day.
So Rax doesn't speak for us and whatever he says can be taken with a grain of salt and
is not going to help the community.
I hear this shit and I on every platform every single time.
So what the mid-season events have been are fun little very low time required, very
low effort, cutie, patuity things to get some cosmetics.
That's what they have been.
And I think that the majority of the people that play casually, which is I understand
is 95% of the people that play the game probably really like that and that event probably
kind of aligns with what they're looking for.
So does a mid-season event need to change from their perspective?
Maybe not.
The thing for me about what has not drawn me to them is the events and mostly the rewards
have not seemed very great.
Like for example, if I got to, if I did the winter event and it let me transmog as a snowman,
like I'm actually a snowman on my horse, I would have done that because I mean I can be
a snowman.
But what they currently have doesn't entice me to log in and complete the event for me
personally.
And it's not because I just play in them.
People say, oh, it's because Racks plays in them.
I like events that are timed and have some kind of a little competition to them.
It doesn't even have to take a lot of skill.
It could be, I don't know, who finds the most Rudolph, the Red Nose reindeer things in
the snow for the event and you win a prize.
And maybe there's a cap on how many noses you can find per day so that way the casuals
don't miss out.
But I love what P.O.E. does.
Like P.O.E. takes their game, gives you a completely different version of the game and
has a little bit of a race to it.
Bro, I'm never going to win those events ever.
I'm never going to win prizes.
And I think that that's way more fun than the season events that Diablo 4 is doing.
So that's a complicated answer in that what they're doing right now is probably fine
for the masses.
But if you want my answer, I haven't been enticed to play them at all for those reasons.
How do you feel about it?
Yeah, so I mean, I guess if we're speaking about what things we have gotten, I would say
for the most part, they're okay.
Like, I don't love the season events.
I don't hate them.
It's something to do.
It doesn't take particularly long.
It's not exactly thrilling.
It comes in at a point in the season where we're pretty much already kind of done.
And it's just sort of maybe giving us a couple more hours of play time.
On top of that, so we've had that and we've also had Avatar of Zer that also released later
in the season.
That was in season two.
Season three, we had the gauntlet come in later on.
In both those cases, that was content also not for me.
So it's not something that I engaged in for very long either.
I do like that there is stuff to come back for, but I think I'm like you and that I would
like it to be something that I guess I personally would be more invested in.
So what would make you more invested in them?
That's a great question.
And I think, I don't know how familiar I was with Hell Divers.
And I know anytime I bring this up, people are like, it's an entirely different game.
It's an entirely different show.
Okay.
But to me, it is like the perfect example of live service done perfectly because it's
a game that cannot exist without it being a live service.
It justifies in every way it being a live service.
They're content roles.
And so I'm not saying that this is what they should do in RPGs, but just to frame what
they do in Hell Divers too.
They have a patch.
They have a patch once a week with generally there's new content that rolls out on a pretty
regular basis.
And they have stuff in their patch notes, but they also have stuff that's not in the patch
notes.
And that tends to be like balance changes towards their weapons and stuff.
That's definitely in the patch notes.
But then new enemies popping up, that's just sort of people discover it while they're
playing the game.
And they sort of like have little teasers going up to it like a week before like, oh, on
this planet, I saw a mech and I could get in the mech guys.
I'm actually driving a mech.
What the hell?
They added mechs in the game.
And like two weeks later, they give us this major mission to actually unlock the mechs
for everyone.
So they sort of tease it in the game.
First, people are like discovering stuff in the game and say, oh, what's this cool stuff?
And so the game is changing and evolving over time.
And it's not all just like one patch where they say, this is everything that's coming.
And now there's nothing left to get excited about and discover.
So for me, I've been loving Hell Divers.
Like I don't really play games outside of stream.
And I've been playing a ton of Hell Divers with my friends and having a blast.
So I don't know.
I really like the way Hell Divers is doing things.
I wonder if there's any way to integrate that kind of stuff or something of that into an
ARPG.
So you like the main thing for you is the element of surprise and discovery.
You don't quite know what you're getting into and you have the feeling that when you're
playing, you might uncover a little diamond in the rough kind of thing.
Yeah, that's definitely a part of it.
And I think in the ARPG sense, we don't want to be changing builds because in an ARPG,
you are investing heavily into creating your build.
So it's not like, oh, this new weapon.
And now I need to like redo all my character or whatever.
But like if it's content that we're doing like a dungeon or an enemy type or a raid or
you know, whatever, sorry, raids, not the word, you know, what is some kind of boss or
an Uber, like new things to engage with as opposed to things that are changing our build,
right?
Like we want to stick with the same build that we're building up because we're investing
time into it.
But if we're getting a balance change every week, then it's like, well, why am I even
bothering to grind up all this gear?
It's going to get nerfed next week.
But I do think there's places, especially with this big open world of Diablo IV, justify
the open world, make things happen that attract us to different places to go there, you know,
check out whatever dungeon that is or whatever pit runner.
I don't know.
Yeah, the, I'm trying to think of analogies in Diablo IV.
I have been surprised a few times.
I didn't know, I remember in the vampire theme, I didn't know how the ambushes that the
ambushes were going to happen.
I almost died.
Yeah, that was cool.
And I was testing on the PTR and I ran into a goblin pack.
They didn't put that in the patch notes.
Oh, yeah.
So that, but those were probably kind of like maybe too small in scope for what you're
talking about.
You're looking for something a little bit bigger than that.
But I, I mean, as someone who degenerately blast the game, you definitely, you definitely
notice those things.
Surprise, they didn't put other kinds of goblins in the game.
Maybe that's another thing I could ask them about.
I don't imagine maybe over time that something's a little, little do you know?
You want to know another thing that I really enjoy in games.
It's in, it's in like all the different games.
It's in POE, it's in Elden Ring, it's in Diablo III.
I like it when you're playing the game and there's like a very rare chance or like a secret
that opens a portal somewhere entirely different.
And it asks you the question, do would you like to go in here instead and see what's in
here.
And when it's like, you know, it's challenging or it's rewarding, then it can be really
fun.
Like when the vault spawns or the POE side areas, when I went through the campaign as a
beginner, you know, you see the side area, you really want to go do it.
It looks fun.
You know, you find out later, all you just skip everything and just run through it.
But the idea of it is there, Elden Ring, you open a chest and it teleports you to an
end game zone and there's like a big drag in in front of you.
It's like, ah, should I really go fight him?
Probably not.
I told him he might drop me like his tooth or something and then I can kill everybody.
I wonder if that would be another kind of thing that you're describing.
Can you give a like imagine we're running nightmare, you're running nightmare dungeons in season
for it and on your 40th one, it just drops a gold portal and it just says leads to a place
that does not exist.
It doesn't have to be the cow level but anything.
And you'd be like, holy shit, what is this?
I have never seen this.
Okay, let's go in.
Let's see what we have here.
I think that would be absolutely amazing.
And I guess so question for you and for, you know, Chad as well, because I know some
people they want everything to be launching at the start of the season.
But what if that happened like a month in like no announcement from Blizzard, but one month
in to the new season racks is playing and suddenly a portal opens and no one knows what
the hell this is.
Everyone is seeing this for the first time on racks of the stream and he goes in and
it takes him to the cow level, for instance or whatever, something else.
And now all of a sudden people are like, well, there's this new level and people are
going to start logging people who like they were done with the season.
Now they're going to start logging back in to try to find this, this new secret level.
Oh, data miners.
I don't think a data miners.
Who the thing about data at the interesting thing about data mining is, um, so
there's a massive push to, you know, find the cow level and we have like, I think we
progressed as far as we can into the into the quest or whatever.
And but the thing is, is what data mining is, there is no data mine for an area called
the cow level or anything with a mysterious name or mysterious mobs.
Like they've looked at it very, very thoroughly and it's just not there.
So it's kind of hard to, I don't, I don't know how you hide
anything from the internet anymore.
They did this already with sellers.
I would say yes on a very, I wouldn't say on a minor level, sellers are cool, but
you kind of have to, the thing about sellers is you got to, again,
when I see a seller nowadays, now that I played the game for a while, I'm not dying.
To dive into that seller, I got bigger fish to fry the surprise that could be
waiting in the seller is usually not worth the time invested to check it.
It's it. That's why I don't, I don't know.
Do when you see a seller, CJ, if you're doing hell tide, if you're trying to get
some boss mats, if you're leveling up your nightmare dungeons, do you get on your
pony and ride over to a seller to go check it out for a surprise that might be in
there?
Sell large, what, what is this?
The little, the little random, I'm trolling you.
Yeah, no, I don't, I don't care at all about sellers.
Yeah.
Okay.
You got me on that one.
I was like, what?
Yeah, I think it's a great point.
We're like, if they are going to add these, these transformative things, they,
they need to be significant enough that we would care about them, right?
Like if, if, you know, a month into the season, they add like a flower in a
town, like, it's not something that's big and exciting.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Okay.
Before I let you go, are there any final things?
Because I got one thing I have to do before we start here is I have to
organize these probably by order of importance.
Because I don't think I will get through like, I don't know, like any of this,
but I'll try.
Is there any other critical question that you would like to get an answer on that
didn't get to yesterday that we haven't already covered?
I'm going to think of that a moment longer, but I will also say, I ordered my
questions in order of importance.
And I realized I should have also kept in mind how long each of these
questions would take to answer.
Because I had to start triaging throughout the interview and skipping some of my
important ones just because I knew that they would be really big answers.
And so I was jumping down to still important, but very shorter questions.
So something just to bear in mind, I guess, as you're also asking those,
I don't know if I don't think I got to ask about map overlay.
I know some people still care about that.
It's probably going to be a shorter answer.
Oh, PVP again, not a super priority thing, but I did kind of want to ask,
are you guys happy with where PVP is now?
Or do you have any plans to expand on in the future?
Trade, you've opened up trade in season four, any plans to give us some tools
or something to increase the quality of life of trade.
So we have to go to external websites.
I have a, that's my number three.
I will get to that is social features trading group finder, clans,
and asking about, you know, trying to avoid third party sites.
Beautiful.
Yep, I have that.
So I can do like quick hits here.
So the quick hits I have are how do they feel about loot filter?
How do they feel about PVP?
How do they feel about SSF?
How do they feel about offline mode?
How do they feel about
ladders?
We can put...
Here's one question I wanted to ask.
I mean, it's kind of low priority, but I wanted to ask the
mic you borrow before he left, tweeted that Diablo 5 will come much faster than Diablo 4.
Do you think I would ever get an answer to the question of,
have you guys already started to work on Diablo 5 or plans about what Diablo 5 would be?
I mean, even if the answer is yes, do you think that will ever...
Do you think we'll all even get a yes or a no answer out of them for that or no?
They wouldn't say whether they start or work on Diablo 5.
They might start, they might say they've been thinking about it,
which I mean, honestly, whether they've started working on it or not,
like it's an easy answer to say, well, sure, we've thought about Diablo 5.
You might want to ask,
bring up the Ibarra quote specifically and ask what they think about that or what they think he meant about that.
Might be a way to allow them to say something on the topic.
I'm just going to eat it.
Just get rid of it.
I ain't got no time for any wishy washi questions that aren't going to get an answer.
Another thing that I saw a lot of people,
another thing that I saw a lot of people ask about was the campaign.
So a lot of people liked the campaign, probably like the most polished,
polished experience that Diablo 4 delivered and the campaign is one and done.
Now, people don't...
There's some people despise the thought of doing the campaign again,
especially like the escort quest with the camel or whatever that was pretty brutal.
But I wonder if Diablo 4 could be a game where you could actually
choose and it would be a legitimate choice where you could benchmark, okay,
what is leveling up and hell-tight in the overworld look like after you spend three hours doing it?
You are essentially at this level with this kind of gear.
And then you time a campaign run for three hours and you expedite the camel quest or whatever
make it get rid of a lot of the stuff that no one wants to do a second time,
but for the most part, to keep the whole campaign intact.
And then after you get done with that, you're at about the same spot and let people choose.
Do you want to do the campaign or do you want to do the overworld?
Because right now, if you do the campaign, you're just a million years behind.
That's actually a really clever way of doing it because yeah,
I'm my first thought upon hearing like the campaign, just exactly what you said.
I'm like, oh god, like don't make us have to do the campaign again.
But that's actually a really clever way of working it in where it's still more efficient to just
slam the health hides. But for those who want to do it, you're not going to be terribly far behind.
All right, man. Well, I appreciate you as a person.
I appreciate your professionalism in the interview.
I think you cracked the egg and got into actually a lot of really good topics.
I know a lot of people are big fans of yours. You've been doing this for a long time.
So big respect, man. I'll try to do round two of this and see if we can get
see if we can get some more questions answered here.
Well, your axe. Appreciate you. I look forward to your interview.
Best of luck. You're going to kill it and I'll be watching.
All right, man. Guys, round of applause for CJ.
Here we go with round two of the interview for Blizzard. Thanks, man.
Okay. I need, okay. So a lot of these questions up here, I think, are important.
What I need you, I don't think I have, I only have 16 more minutes, not even 16.
So I have the top questions for you. The important thing here is the order.
I'm going to ask these questions first. It's just follow up to CJ's interview.
So I'm going to, I'm going to ask these questions first.
Actually, don't really care about this. I'm not going to have time. Let me just delete it.
The top questions for YouTube, I'm asking the social features is way too important.
I must ask it. Here's the,
this is supposed to be here. Social features is going to get asked 100%.
I already asked this question. I can delete it.
This is really not that important. Just delete it.
Maybe I can put it down here. Let me organize this for a second. Give me a moment.
Um, okay. Let me look at this.
This is probably lower priority. I'm going to put this lower. I don't really care about
how Microsoft, I don't need this question anymore. Let's put this here and delete this.
I really want to, I really want to talk about this. I really want to talk about the target audience
of Diablo 4. If they were willing to talk to me about it,
I'm going to move this lower. Maybe here.
Let's go like, um, let's go like that. Okay.
Okay.
I didn't go here.
It's actually a way I want to know when Ubertoon Lord is coming out.
Did I put the campaign somewhere else?
Um,
got another question that we need to ask. Yeah, map overlay. Another question that we need to ask.
Is
something about balance.
This is kind of like a generic question.
We can keep it, but maybe I put it much lower. Let's cut this out.
This I think is a very, this is a very good question.
I really want, I really want to ask about this.
Okay.
Um,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to set a timer for 40 minutes.
And then when I get to 40 minutes, I'm going to go to the quick hits and I'm going to ask all of them.
Just real quick,
knee jerk reaction to what do they think about these things.
So let's set it for 40 minutes.
And then I'm going to ask all of them.
What time is the interview in 11 minutes?
Okay.
Okay, I think this is important.
I already asked all of these. So I'm
consolidating my list significantly.
Social features. I need this to go here.
This needs to be tabbed over.
All right.
Okay.
Okay. So let's look at the order here that I have and let's see if this is
pretty good or not.
So the first thing I want to talk them about is pinnacle content.
I'm going to ask this first.
They talked about it a lot in CJ's interview.
I want to ask them, is there ever going to be skill involved in the endgame?
Or is it all going to be about gear?
Along with that, let's ask for a roadmap and is there main focus the endgame?
That's the thing I care about probably the most.
I think I can delete this question.
This is so, I don't do that.
They always say that they deeply care about feedback.
And one super mysterious thing about Blizzard is how do you actually receive the feedback?
Do you guys have meetings about it?
Can you walk me through like to someone is Adam?
God, how many atoms are there?
There's Adam Jackson.
There's Adam Fletcher.
How many atoms and Joe's are there?
Is there a team that gathers it all and then you look at it and then you have a meeting about it?
I want to know how do they process feedback and how do they test things?
I want to hear from them how they do it.
The state of nightmare dungeons, they made them better.
You can teleport to them.
You buffed Glyphdxp.
They're putting more things to do in them like events.
You lower the cast time to 0.75 seconds.
They said in CJ's interview that they want to iterate on nightmare dungeons.
I want to ask them, have they considered more qualitative ideas,
not only with the current state of nightmare dungeons, but in the future?
For example, can we carry multiple objects?
If you have two rocks and two pedestals, if you go rock, rock, you're already guaranteed to backtrack.
Stuff like that.
Is there any reason why we can't reduce the cast time further?
You miss 100% shots you don't take.
It's not necessarily that I mind freeing prisoners.
It's I mind freeing seven prisoners.
Why is there seven of them?
How about like three where I just click them and they're free?
And then the slay all with one monster behind.
I know that there was a fix for little things to follow you,
but that doesn't work all the time.
And it bricked some of our nightmare dungeons.
Don't get into drama questions.
Right, I do.
I don't think any of this has any drama to it.
Wait, there's no drama here.
Okay, I'm done.
So they're setting up and their discord is broken.
Their discord is broken, so we're going to do it in Zoom.
So they're going to send me a Zoom link.
That there's something wrong with discord.
So we're going to Zoom.
Okay.
They're they're not trying to back out.
No, they're not trying to back out.
Yeah.
Yeah, M3X did Seattle.
Um, all right.
Okay.
Yeah.
Let's see how Zoom is going to go.
All right.
Let me, I guess we're going to join now.
Let me, uh, let me switch my screen real quick and see if I can join the Zoom link.
Be right back.
Alrighty.
Click on this.
Open the Zoom meeting.
Here we go.
Join.
That should work.
Let's try that.
Okay, I'm in.
But let me see.
I think I have to start virtual camera on OBS.
Let me start the.
There we go.
Does that work?
There.
Well, kind of.
I'm not going to move this down.
Maybe.
There.
That actually kind of worked.
Okay.
All right.
It was a mic issue that was disabled Adam Jackson's mic.
I'm flexible, man.
I am flexible.
We do whatever.
Whatever works.
I'm big chilling over here.
Big chilling over here.
All right.
Um,
yeah.
I'm sitting here.
Let's see if Adam and Joe can come in here.
All right.
Well, while we're waiting here.
I guess there's, I guess there's no issue in me.
Coming back here, right?
Okay.
Let me see here.
Let me get rid of this webcam.
Maybe.
Let me get rid of this.
All right.
What's up?
And I wonder if I can show.
Hey, what's going on, man?
What is up?
All right.
Can you?
It's happening.
Can you guys hear him fine?
Is he fine?
Up or down?
How?
How is it sounding guys?
Can you talk for a second, Joe?
Do you just testing the ups and downs?
Now what's what's up?
How do I sound, chat?
Yeah, I can see it's way too low.
I'm going to turn you way higher.
Let's try again.
I can just start.
I can just start screaming.
Hey, how do I sound right now?
Okay.
Is that better, guys?
Up more, up more.
Okay.
We're going.
I have you at 100.
Okay.
This is dangerous.
I'm going to.
This is going to get dangerous when I get excited about something.
So we're going to watch up it up.
All joys me.
Hey, thanks so much for coming on here, man.
I'm really excited.
Yeah, this is going to be a blast.
I'm looking forward to the conversation.
Hell yeah.
Where's my partner in crime?
Where's Adam?
Is he Jackson?
You want to know what he's faking all of these technical issues?
And he's just like, you want to know what?
I'm going to call him sick and I'm just going to have Joe solo this.
Yeah, it's fine.
Let's do it.
Just sign him up for a whole bunch of stuff.
Okay, so what I'm going to do here,
try my best to be as prepared as possible.
Cool.
But of course, I'm probably not prepared at all.
So that's just the way life goes.
No, no, no, no, it's all good.
Hey, and one thing up front right up top here is like,
I have a lot of things I want to say, but it's okay if you want to interject.
So if it's not rude, I'm not going to take this being rude.
So if there's the things you want chat for or things you want clarification on,
like please, please, please interrupt me.
It's all good.
I feel like I feel like I want to give that preface to everybody I talk to now on stream, right?
I would never interrupt that sweet and jellic mella fluis voice speaking of that.
I'm going to ask for questions.
And people hear me, okay, I've spent the last 45 minutes troubleshooting my mic and
expend the worst.
It's okay.
Dude, is that a paper towel roller by your bed?
How do I get one of those?
I have kids.
They're very messy.
It's part of the life.
Dude, that is that's the most ingenious thing I've ever seen.
We're pretty creative over here.
You can hear me, okay, though.
I'm very concerned about this.
Expond.
Okay, thank God.
I mean, chat, can you hear them?
Sounds perfect for me.
How is it for you guys?
All right, cool.
Because I changed, I fucked up all my computer settings and now everything's terrible.
But as long as it works, I'm happy.
All right.
Okay, I'm starting a 40 minute timer.
Then we'll do rapid fire at the end to try to hit as many as possible.
That sounds good.
Sounds good to me.
Thank you so much for being here, guys.
All right, yesterday, C.J. Riker did an interview with them.
So he asked a bunch of great questions.
I want to do some follow-ups to some of the questions that you guys talked about.
So one thing, the topic that I think you guys probably covered the most in the interview,
you asked for a different parts was about aspirational and pinnacle content.
Some of the things that you said that was Uber Lilith at the start of the
Diablo IV was all mechanical mastery.
If you don't dodge the waves, you're dead.
There's pretty much nothing you can do about that.
And a lot of players didn't have fun just, you know,
getting crushed by her waves.
Talked about there's different lovers to pull on the difficulty.
You can make players weaker like Nightmare Dungeons sigils.
You can make monsters hit harder.
You can give them more health, more crowd control.
And I heard you say that the decisions that you make before you go into the encounter
should matter more because it's an ARPG.
It's about hunting loot.
It's about getting powerful.
And then you go in and you have a big advantage.
And you finally overcome the difficulty.
And another thing that I heard you guys say is when you guys introduce very difficult
events like the Avatar of Zier, for example, when you properly advertise it as something
that's very difficult, you didn't get any negative backlash or too much negative backlash
for the difficulty of it because it was properly labeled.
So with that huge preface in mind, my question is,
do you guys have plans in the future of Diablo 4 to build in these very,
very difficult encounters that do require skill, that do require you to go in with an event
or with a boss, learn their mechanics, and that is going to be another supplement
besides getting gear to winning.
Thoughts on that?
Yeah, sure.
So I can just kind of, I'll start off.
So yeah, everything we talked about yesterday, you just did a good job of covering again.
I appreciate that. But when we think about what the future of aspirational content
needs to look like at the game, we do want to leave opportunities for this kind of a
mechanically complex content players to engage with and we experiment with it a few different ways.
So I don't think that the L-Eco-Low-O-Think counter, it's a really good example of us
like diving really hard into mechanical mastery works for players to really have to be very,
very active in terms of their dodges, nor survive.
But we do want to continue to experiment with these ideas and try more things,
particularly when they are advertised in the appropriate place.
Adam, do you have thoughts on this?
Yeah, originally I did and it was like a very long-winded answer,
but I don't want to take up too much time on this. I guess what I'll say is,
you know, everything kind of exists on a spectrum when we're talking about things like
difficulty or a lot of game design topics and ideas.
Like in this spectrum in my mind, it's like, you know, how hard should the theme be versus how
how much should your gear going into it matter, right?
I think we're still trying to find out what the best answer is for the things that are really,
really hard like Uber Lilith or these crazy difficult fights.
One of the things that we're doing in season four that we started doing in beyond that one of
our encounter designers came up with a great idea was adding this, I think you probably
seen our A-Rex, but that's a second debuff idea where you can screw up getting hit by a wave
a couple times, but then after that you're probably just going to get one shot and die.
And so that gives us this kind of happy medium between pure one shot mechanics and things where
you have to be perfect in your dexterity versus the other way where you can just like out gear
everything. There's some other things that you can go into of like, you know, the difference of
the most powerful, at least powerful mid-powerful builds and how we do difficulty, maybe we'll
get that a different answer, but that's the TLDR. I think we're still trying to figure out what is
best for our game and what our players like. You know, in my heart of hearts, I'm more like U-Rex,
I love the very, very crazy hard things. I don't mind one shots personally in my games, but I
don't think it's best for this game. It's not millennium. We have to play it. Yeah, I don't think
that it's best long-term, but having a little bit of that kind of stuff sometimes I think is okay.
I think it's more how much and how we introduce it and how we frame it to people. That's the
simple answer. Okay, so kind of like one thing that you guys are liking is kind of like the soft
and rages where over time eventually it gets so difficult that you're eventually going to lose.
Yeah, 14 does a good job with this as well. Like they have this idea, like, you know, if you
miss up a mechanic, you get a guest deck and deep off, it can escalate and get worse and worse
as the fight goes on. It's an interesting way to allow for some mistakes or current for some
learning to happen, but really like and to punish you, but not immediately spike you in any encounter.
Awesome. So one thing that some other games doing is they release road maps of kind of like in
the same topic of end game of things that Cali, stop it, sit down. Sorry about that.
So for Diablo IV, will we ever see road maps come out kind of showing like detailing what might
be coming in the next six months to a year? I know that there is some challenges with that.
Like if you guys change your mind, then like the community gets really mad at you. What are your
thoughts on that? I think it's important that can be knows that we are identifying problems, you know,
and that we we are listening, as I've said before. And I think that a road map does a good job of
expressing some of this information, but it does to your point does lock us into a schedule. So I think
that we're kind of like thinking about how we want to approach like explaining these sorts of things.
You'll recall back in like season two, I mentioned at the very end of actually between when we were
wrapping up season two and AOC was out and we were getting ready to begin talking about season three,
I mentioned that we had identified a lot of itemization issues and things we wanted to make
upgrades to and I'm going to have updates which turned into the season before and season four.
Now I want to make it clear that we identified a lot of the issues that players have been talking
to us about for a while, but we weren't able to like immediately resolve those sorts of things.
So I don't want one thing I occasionally see from players when they see a long road map is they'll
see something that they care deeply about it like really really towards the end of a year and they'll
ask them like well, do they not think this is important? Do they not care about this? And I think
that there's a way for us to talk about these things that players feel they they they have confidence
like that we are looking at these problems and we do have plans. So I think we're just working
through exactly the way that we want to approach this. Yeah, I think I'll try me in a little bit.
One of the things that you're going to hear is a constant theme from me and other designers say
this with different words, but there's this idea that there's there's rarely really perfect solutions.
There's really only tradeoffs in the world and this is actually comes from an economic term.
This says that there's never solutions only tradeoffs, but you know when you ask us things like,
you know, why don't you do X or Y or why don't you provide road maps the way that our brains
immediately go as well? There's pros and cons and which decision is best trying to get the most
pros that we can with the least cons that we can, right? It's simple example of road maps is the
pro of road map is everybody's on the same page. We showed out, hey, we care about these things and
the community knows what to expect, right? Obviously that is a desirable thing to do, but there's big
cons that maybe we have that you don't see and this is where most design discussions end up of people
asking, that's what do you think it's developers? Is that we try to explain the cons to you so you
understand the full picture? You know, the cons of a road map is we're locked in now. We promise
things to you that we may not be able to do for whatever reason when things end up changing down
the road, right? Life has a way of screwing with your plan, especially when you try to plan things
more long-term. This isn't just a game design, but anything. So we try to keep promises and keep
promises like one of my things I'm really passionate about as a designer is when it comes to
interacting with the community, making promises and then keeping them. So I'm extremely careful
of the promises that I mean this is just my strategy of how to build trust with people and the
community and just life in general is I'm very careful of what promises I make and then I make
damn sure when I do that I keep them. And so to do that the longer our road map goes out the higher
chance we're not going to keep those promises. Some things, for example, that we've ceded in the past,
um I remember it was either our season one or season two campfire chat. I made a list of things
that our team wants to do longer term. One of those things on those lists was making scaling
mechanics for legendaries that kind of suck. And we finally we're doing that in season four, right?
You know your earthquake legendaries all of those we finally made them scale with your weapons
and make the damage go up. I also talked about at the time and we haven't delivered on this yet
in my opinion, but making ultimate meaningful and scale in a similar way. It's on our radar,
something I want to do, haven't done it yet. I didn't give a date because I don't know when the
day is because our timelines and schedules and priorities change quite a bit based on community
feedback. You know, if I made the promise like, hey, we're definitely fixing ultimates,
then we're born when it happened because I have to spend my team's time on doing that other thing,
but this other thing came up that I think is way more important for the game. And that's just kind
of how the nature of our job goes. Thank you for the super detailed answer and that is a perfect
segue into my next question is kind of like an edition of Mythbusters kind of. So a lot of people
in the community, a lot of the people that are angry in the community about, you know, whatever it
is they're angry about at the time, they say that they're passionate about something.
Passionate. Very passionate. That's the, that's the word we're looking for.
Structively passionate, yeah. Constructively passionate. So one thing that I, they have like the
mean video of you guys saying feedback, feedback, feedback. And then on the internet from a bunch
of different angles they say, Blizzard doesn't listen to feedback. They don't do anything. They don't
even test their game where they're beta testers. So I wanted to ask you guys, could you give us some
insights into how your team actually processes and internalizes feedback? Is it like concatenated
for you and you guys have a meeting and you discuss it like that? How do you guys go about testing
things internally to kind of debunk all of these myths that you guys are just working by yourselves
and never listening to anything? Do we know it's not true? You want to go first Joe or?
Yeah, I think we both probably have different things you want to say about this. So I think that
the point on feedback, I think you're that that's being brought up, there's like kind of two
things like one are the designers in a corner entirely by themselves, like just making decisions
with no information being good at them. And the other version is like, is the team listening to
the community, right? And then how do we process these sorts of things, right? So the
starting from the does the team listen to the community like side of this thing? You know, we are
always reading everything on that it's getting posted on right, we're getting everything it's posted
on the forums, we're going through our socials on a regular basis, we have teams and people like Adam
Fletcher, you know, the community director, he's going through and like kind of gathering a lot of
this information for us and and in places where we don't like I personally can't read every thread
in every social media site, right? I can't, but I can't because I there's other things I also do as
part of my job, but I do read a lot of stuff, right? And a lot of things get sent to me. So a lot of
that stuff can get like kind of pulled together for like reporting purposes and brought to us, right?
And I think that's really, really useful. We also have a lot of internal feedback that we get
from the from the team, like so when we start working on something, we we were able to like kind of
give a presentation to Dio for all that team to get an idea of what we're trying to do. We have
regular play tests, we're like a large people all get a chance to kind of give us feedback on a
regular basis and we can keep checking in with them as time goes on. So that's I think that's a
a starting point for these things, but it's it's really important to us that we are like hearing
things from the community because that's kind of telling us like are the like are the changes that
we're making right now? Are they effective? Like are people having a good time with these things?
Because we can look at all kinds of data determined things, but like here when people talk about it's
also really, really important when they have when players have needs that aren't met, you know,
it's our job to find ways to kind of like bridge the gap there, make sure that they're they're
they're being heard and the game is going to be more fun for them, but what do you want to talk about?
Yeah, so firstly, I would say different game companies, different teams and even different teams
within a bigger team have different cultures and ideas in ways that they process feedback. So
I'll tell you what I do on my team and kind of what D4 kind of does is a larger team, right?
So on the live team, we are probably the most interactive with feedback because we're doing
the live changes. We have to be very connected to the game to make the decisions. So I give this
speech a lot to the people on in my group of your job as a designer is to go and find the problems
with the game and then you are the filter when the community comes in and brings up things,
whether it's a streamer giving things, I post things all the time from streamers, I post things
all the time from Reddit threads, I post things all the time from our forums, anywhere that you can go
out and go and also personal play experience, nothing replaces that as well. So we actually
dedicate every day at least some amount of time that everybody in my group is either playing an
internal build of future things coming out in the game, which I'm playing through season 5 right
now and I'm really far in it, or they're playing their live character in the live game because
you need to understand the game and understand the problems. And the way that I do things,
what I've been trying to tell my team and I think we're pretty good at, is while you are
parsing all this feedback, you are and playing the game yourself, keep a running list of notes
of crap that sucks that you want to make better or ideas that other people had that you think are
good ideas that you want to make better. Now of course not every idea is equal right you don't copy
every Reddit thread and every single thing that someone says, we are the filter of trying to figure
out, remember I talked about those trade no perfect solutions only trade offs, this is where we're
like hey they brought up an idea and we think it's good now we need to explore if I can actually
work in the game and this is where we come up with our list of things and priorities that we're
going to do, that's a starting point. The other, that's one of a few starting points, the first
starting point is you know community feedback, our own play experience. Another one is telemetry
and that's just a fancy word for data. We have the ability to see data all over the game of how
many people are equipping different legendary aspects, how many of people are engaged with certain
types of content, we can see what's working, what's not working, what people are actually doing
versus what they say, usually what they say will match with what people are doing but there's
a mismatch that we have to have a discussion of like hey how important is this actually?
And then another way is internal testing tools, again we have a group that give us presentations
and people who their job is to look through data and do focus sessions and all kinds of other
fancy tricks to come up with stories and understanding the different types of players we have
of what they're doing and how they work and they give us presentations on different topics that
we're interested in or they find their own topics of things that maybe we didn't think of that we
may have missed. And then last but not least we have internal people you know we have a big team
of people working on this game and we have certain feedback avenues via emails or channels that we
give feedback to each other because on new stuff we can't rely on telemetry or the community
or all those other things and that's where things are a lot harder. I think Joe went into this yesterday
a little more deeper so I'll just go also over it but this idea that Diablo is a freaking huge game
that takes forever to play and really truly understands our systems are so interconnected
so there is no substitute for actually going through that 80 plus hour experience and playing
everything. The part that makes that really hard and where I think the community gives us a hard
time sometimes I think a little bit of his warranty but it's just a cursed problem is what I call
it which is another concept I'll go into later is that to really test our game you need to
spend your life playing our game in many ways or a lot of time more times more hours than what
you normally would expect someone to work at a job right so we can't tell people hey you must
spend all your life playing this game but also by the way you have to design and create the new
things too right so that means that internally it is really hard to play test the full amount of
our game as a designer we have to rely on we have people in QA and other playtesters that do play
this content we either direct them of things we want to test and play or they just find things on
their own that they think hey they bring it up to us okay we think this is a problem and we have
to purse that but there isn't enough time for a single design or every designer to play the game
fully all the time but we do still play it a good amount and we use those internal feedback mechanisms
to make things the best that they can and this is where I think there is that little disconnect
sometimes with the community where yeah we would love to polish things and play it now I would
love to play season five two hundred hours before it comes out I only get it for you know 50 hours
right and we have to use our guts and existing ideas and telemetry to figure out if the decision
would make a right and then we use after we launch the game to really fine tune and make it perfect
right and that's kind of the overall process of how things work yeah one last thing I want to add
here too is that even we're just thinking about like a feature like we're talking like adding one
thing like to be like the pit for example good example because it's it's to come in new coming out
in season four if you sit down you play the pit for an hour one day you're going to feel a certain
way about your experience playing the pit you're going to feel differently if you play that for
two hours a day five days straight you know and you and you experience it through that entire process
you're going to have a different relationship with the content at that point and players are going to
go you know 10 20x that number by time they're done playing in season potentially so like what's
really really important that we get the reps in on these features make sure they're they're really
resonating and they're singing they're doing everything they need to do right so I think if there's
there's a lot truth everything that happens talking about everything is a lot trade-offs there's a lot
of things we need to do and this this kind of links to the PTR the PTR feedback for season four was
hugely valuable because now suddenly we're able to like take take what we already know about the
season and then multiply that like 10 20 50 fold as we get tons of players going in checking things
out not just from the telemetry but also just the feedback we're getting from content creators from
players themselves like we've got a lot of really good data for that so it's been it's been very useful
for the same reason to add and talk about yeah I mean I go go ahead sorry no go ahead one last real
quick thing is this is where you get things that seem obvious to players that were bad ideas but
sounded of really like really good ideas worst in the room talking about it that simple example
given season four is when you temper your items or things and there's like a really nice thing
that plays and you can see it it's visual yeah skip it easily right that kind of stuff is where
sometimes things fall through the cracks of hey doing this 2,000 times is actually terrible because
you've got to wait forever versus well we want to have a moment of celebration and for the cool
thing to be cool balancing these things is what can be harder to do internally we're obviously we've
messed up enough times and this is true for every game company so I'm not afraid to admit it but like
you know we've made that mistake enough times that we now we're very cognizant of it like we make a
new feature or a new activity like hey how does this feel if you're doing it for 200 hours is this
still going to be something that people want to go through right that's a question now that we ask
all the time but even then there are times where we have to kill otherwise good ideas or we have
the fluts a little bit because we do need some presentation or some tutorialization or some other
thing to balance that even if it makes the you know 2,000 times experience a little bit worse right
the answer's not always so obvious I guess but we we are receptive to like when the community tells
us clearly hey no we want it to be this way we're gonna do it that way I mean it was a lot of
great points I mean the the I'm very glad that I asked that question because the thing that
is refreshing to me the thing that I I wanted to hear more than anything is that you guys have a
chance to actually play through the game and not only to hear that you guys play the game as almost
part of the job description but it sounds like you actually put a big effort into that that I
mean that makes me feel that makes me feel great honestly that's that's so great to hear I'm so
glad that's part of the process um talking about some of the current uh modes in the game let's talk
about you talked about yesterday the state of nightmare dungeon CJ did a ton of iteration on it now
we can teleport to them you just buffed glyph XP you said that you'd like to add more fun things to
do to them in the future you guys made events better now I saw goblin packs I think on the ptr when
you put the vampire ambushes that was good you reduced the cast time down to point seven five
seconds so we're gonna have new things coming out for it um my question is is going forward it looks
like you guys made a ton of qualitative changes to it like you just make it a little bit easier to
access all of these different things rather than riding around on your pony to every single thing
and everything takes forever when you are designing future things is that kind of at the front of
your mind with things like oh maybe at nightmare dungeons we can carry multiple objects because if
there's two rocks and two pedestals if you go rock rock you're guaranteed to backtrack I mean I
have two hands and then have you thought about reducing the cast time even further I know that one
comment was if the cast time is so low then people may not even see that they interacted with something
but maybe that could be updated via like a like a little quest thing oh quest pick up two rocks oh
it highlights oh now pick up one rock and another part of it was it's not it's not just that I have a
problem-freeing prisoners I have a problem going to dead man's dredge and the quest objective is
I have to free seven prisoners like how many people got caught here is qualitative stuff still at
the front of your mind when you're iterating on these things and in the future events that you're
going to make so I think that there's a couple different pieces to pick apart here right so I
with nightmare dungeons they're building upon the the dungeons we had in Diablo 4 right and these
were supposed to be these really like kind of interesting little content things you can find all
over the world they all had little bit like little bits of like environmental storytelling objective
big storytelling some side quest point to these dungeons as well and we want players to feel like
they're kind of they're going on a little bit of adventure when they go into these we didn't we
didn't initially make the content in these spaces to feel like there's like blast corridors if
that makes sense right so I think that as we as we think about what different players are looking for
and what what we can do to improve the experience for everybody we don't want to lose the kind of like
um the contextual unlike fantasy underpinnings of what players are doing they go into these spaces
to your point like you know it's not that you hate freeing prisoners no but you don't like that it
might take you know point seven five seconds to do it is there's one question maybe and then
there's another one where it's like we don't want a free seven so you kind of want to be like a faster
more punchy experience but it's not that you don't like having to click those objects as part of
your experience going through a dungeon I think that like there's uh I think there's an expectation
when players are like doing some of these actions there's a response so having just a quiet like
a quest tick for some things I'm not saying that this is a we would only ever make this decision
and a quest tick for things like freeing a prisoner it is it is feedback is it as impactful as having
the moment where you get to see your character unbinded on the binds I'm not so sure you know but
in the end is that value it's to Adam's point earlier about like you know it's about making trade-offs
is the is the idea for the player who does care does care about like kind of going slowly
to space and trying to find the collectibles and trying to do all these things for that player is
it is it going to be a big miss for them if they click on stuff and just kind of like it has a quick
update doesn't feel like anything has really changed so it's where like where we want to optimize
things I think when you look at content like the like the pit you know um and it's a lot of things
we didn't help out as well no we've made a lot of attempts trying to make sure that the content
feels like there is less friction you know it's going through so like when you get into a flow state
that you're happy with uh you can kind of maintain that that that pace so and we made a number of
changes you already called out tonight we're done it to also kind of support this so I think it's
a question like how much further do we want to go within nightmare dungeon specifically right
because I think we've already said that we're looking at this for other other pieces of content
um I don't know where we're going to fall necessarily for the uh for the the channel time for
clicking on objects and freeing them it could be that it comes out a little bit lower
it could be that we decide we want to make changes to make it more more instantaneous we haven't
really made a decision you know we'll continue to be looking at feedback as we play and also from
like different players like players which are just playing the uh the apple for the first time
want to kind of hear what their experience is like as well
awesome uh so here's kind of like a here's kind of like maybe a huge question but it asks very
directly um so what is kind of the future of the overworld in Diablo 4 when we first released it
was kind of the main thing you used it to do everything and kind of the first experience was
that 50 to 100 grind now one to 100 is much easier and the focus is probably you know having
enjoying that journey going to the pit and anything in the future that you're going to release
a lot of the things that seem to come out though the abattoir and the challenge riff thing
and the pit they're all instant things are there big plans for the overworld is that still like
the defining characteristic of Diablo 4 are we moving away from that so we you know Diablo 4 and
the fact that we have this like big contiguous sanctuary is still a really big part of Diablo 4
now uh i think that we want to continue to expand the the lamass the areas where players can
explore that's still an important part of things but in terms of how players are engaging with
the experience overall we do expect that um one of the one of the downsides of the uh of the
the open world uh is that it is a it's a fixed layout right so if we think about like the
sorts of things the players like to play in a in a in a like a replayable content fashion right
it's not normally in place where you like really want to keep running through exactly the same
galaid and the fractured piece are exactly the same area you know of kristin it's it's usually
you're trying to like find like different things to kind of engage with and like our dungeon systems
are places where you can really do a lot more of that i think we push it really well within
health tides you know there's lots of things happening in health tides uh they're pretty
procedural in terms of how things are spawned in and like what sorts of events you might find as
you're kind of wandering around uh but in terms of like having a lot more like flexibility to
create different experiences we have that really more in other systems but i think for this is
like uh going back to some things i talked about the other day there's sort of like the experience
the player has with diablo is a is a big game right and uh and i don't say that to suggest that any
any any ones needs are less important just that there are a lot of different needs different players
have different expectations so when some players come into diablo like they're here because they want
to go through like this epic story you want to play their they really want to play a sorceress
and they want to like see what happens a little if they want to go explore all they want to find all
the things and all the zones uh and they want to get really really powerful and then they're going to
they're going to take a break until the expansion comes out that's just the way that they sort of play
these games it's how they that's how they play right for those players these moments is the explore
the world it's really really important because that's their experience with diablo it's like their
exploration of the overworld i'm going and finding all these side quests talking all these characters
and that's their relationship with the game for players who play seasonally you know they it's
once you've kind of like uh uncovered all the applications that you found all these things
and done this stuff you don't there's not usually a lot of reasons why you want to go and have
that same moment of discovery again you can't really recreate it we talked for a while about like
moving little statues for pound season to season so you have to collect them again it's it's
another another one of my brilliant ideas so uh we didn't we didn't do it of course right but like
we had the idea of like every season we'd move where the uh the little statues to be found so
players have to go find them again but then the next conversations immediately like well okay so
people are going to go on to max or whatever and they're going to go immediately see where the
node map is for the next set of alter-lilits they're going then that's now their new homework they
have to do at the beginning of every season they have to run around on their horse and go play
every single one of these and it's like is that fun now if clearly not for that for that player
it but it wasn't it was necessarily horrible the first time players do this like that's like that's
like that's part of the fun of like almost like an open world game in any way it's kind of like
exploration and finding things so i know that i'm i'm getting to go long but so i think that the
the the underpinning point here is that the the overworld diablo 4 so really really important
as we think about how to make the best use of it for uh like replayable content you know how
tides a good example of this blood harvest is really really uh really really helpful for kind of
giving us some like ideas of what players are really excited about things that we could do better
like the like kind of light social gameplay of some of the creatures and things um and i think we
have other ideas we can team to explore in that direction i think legion events and boss events
of things we can team to like kind of iterate on and think more about you know but uh i think that
in terms of creating like like really compelling replayable content i think it's going to end up
in more of the space where you have like more procedural control over how like the dungeon is
formulated or like what players can expect to encounter as opposed to these these more fixed outdoor
locations does that answer your question? Yeah so i guess laughing at me i didn't answer the question
no no these are such in-depth answers i'm i'm just scared i'm looking over at my questions i'm
i'm never gonna i'm trying to figure out how to skip around for all and so i guess so i'm so sorry
no no no this so the the main takeaway that i'm getting there is the overworld is an
a super important part of it like a first players experience discovering everything but then it's
hard to recreate that magic for the people that comes season to season to season and that's why
it goes more to instance the stuff is kind of i guess the summary of the story of that's the
reason yeah i think we're also just on a regular basis looking for new ways to engage with the uh
with the open world in ways they're gonna be fun for seasonal players as well like so we're
we're continuing to find like just experimenting with things see what makes it like fun and new for
players okay i promised i would ask this so there uh maybe there might be a player out there that
you guys have heard of and have maybe added i don't know it hundreds of hours of over time to the
team rob and rob yeah you familiar so he had a rob love rob he is a good guy he's a good guy he
had uh two questions about the pit these will probably a little bit more straightforward but um
i guess for for endgame activities is do you guys ever think about or worry about i guess
fishing so like it gets to a point in the pit where oh you're fishing for the right mob type or
you're fishing for the right boss or and then you just leave kind of like what happened in Diablo 3
or oh i'm gonna go get aha very on and hopefully that it procs the the amazing shrine for me so
then i can finally win and do you guys off the top of your head know about how much the health
and the pit was buffed by and i i'm guessing that the main idea for there is not only to add difficulty
but to actually because the the when you were going through the pit the bills are so strong that you
delete the the rift part of it in two minutes like clockwork every time and the monsters don't even
get to do anything so i assume like the part of the reason for buffing it is to actually even let
them get a hit on you and see what they even do yeah uh i can take the first part of the question
at least i'm actually able to do what's the other part um so talk about fishing um yes uh
fishing for stuff keeps me up at night and i hate the problem and it's a really hard problem to
solve um remember that no salute you know rarely perfect solutions only trade off staying right so
this very much applies to this type of problem right a core thing that we want our game is and when
it comes to combat and effects and legendary powers unique powers and whatever is we want to push
y'all bull make cool shit right so i wanted to respect your need to make cool stuff right and that
involves doing things that aren't necessarily completely deterministic because i think completely
deterministic things after a while get kind of boring right when you know that you're going to
get this the fact or accept all the time or you do this and get this like we do it a lot by the way
so i'm not saying that's not a good design but just you need to have some spiciness some really
cool crazy things right and that that unique uh uber unique power is one of those um on the flip
side though it means that when you make really hard content uh doing things like wanting to make
cool stuff uh fishing gets in the way of that a lot of time especially in randomly generated
content which is what you know the pit is in many ways so that is why we have to do things that we
that by the way we as designers don't like like removing the fun shrines or the things that are
going to break because then you just find the shrines that you know break the game in whatever way
and that's all that you're doing and that becomes the game yeah um this is a core thing about ARPG
that i in my opinion after working on it now for years and i've been involved in pretty much
every game genre extensively as a player and many as a designer um i think ARPGs are one of the
hardest if not the hardest genre to design for uh MMOs are really high up there too um there's a lot
of other genres i think are very difficult but ARPGs are a special slice of of awfulness when it
comes to trying to make things fun and also make them interesting um and this is one of the reasons
why so as far as like this exact design of the spear uh we're keeping it in for now um i would be
very sad if we had to redesign it because it's the only way to get through high pit tiers that would
make me personally sad but because that is the most difficult thing to do uh we may have to make a
tweak to it but we're not doing it yet we're gonna see how it plays out um but i think that the
conversations more interesting of conceptually like you know is this a problem yes absolutely
does it mean that we can't do things that would otherwise be cool and awesome for your average player
yes absolutely but we also think it's best for the game because i think fishing for the right
pile set the right mob like restarting a thing over and over to be able to progress is not fun
and therefore we have to design the rest of our game knowing that that is a thing um yeah i was
adding that to like i think that you know we definitely see fishing as a problem so much so that we
built the gauntlet you know for the trials feature we're fishing specifically as the thing we're
trying to account for or we said all right if we if we have a competitive content feature players
going to engage with and it's randomized then players aren't really competing until they find
exactly the right seed that they manage to roll to compete against because that's the actual
optimal seed that they need to compete to compete on it's only against this monster family or only
with this dungeon tile out or only with this like these set of shrines whatever it is so instead what
we did is we made a highly deterministic content type that changed it or weak and players went
to say like well why is it so fixed like this is boring like i want i want something like i want
to do that's different changes every time but then you kind of fall back to that same point that
brought up about like curse like these trade-offs for all the problems that we have then we have
we have to decide like all right so we okay with the idea that like players are going to go into
a like a gauntlet run and they're going to have a wildy disparate experience potentially between
our person a and person b and they are just continually running the other content over and over again
in the hopes they eventually get a good seed and that might be the way that they're able to place
because the difference could potentially be vast between one thing in the next so it's uh you
know it's copkate space something we definitely think about the other part of your question was uh
what do we do about the uh what do we do about uh like how scaling in the fit the HP uh how much
did it go by yeah so we did make some big changes there uh so basically what was happening in
the ptr is that uh monster scaling monster health scaling was pretty mild uh in the pit going
to the first hundred levels it was basically virtually nil you know from level 100 on
more or less right so we ended up putting it in a place where uh like the tier 200 pit is
like okay so like uh like around tier 150 pit is like close to where a oz was you know for like
tier 25 uh uh uh uh uh a oz runs and tier 200 goes beyond that so it's pretty it's pretty
considerable the scaling has been increased we still want to be gradual as you're kind of progressing
through uh because we want you to feel that you have a place to push it's not like so like
because a oz was 25 tears extremely extremely chunky when you went from tier to tier as you got
deeper and deeper inside here it's a little more gradual as you go further and further and further
and we think that's going to be good experience overall um because it's ultimately a lot of the
material to really want from the pit you can gain by the time you're like doing like tier 60s you
start to get like little bits of the desire that you need to kind of start finishing off your masterwork
items and then that gets more and more efficient as you go deeper and deeper you know but there's uh
what we do want to have these like really really difficult challenges we made it we made a a decision
at the launch period of the game where we took nightmare dungeons uh difficulty and we kind of
scaled it in a different way you know whereas like initially they were extremely challenging going
up to tier 100 and we ended up making a reduction in their difficulty uh going into season one uh
where we basically rebalanced things such that like the tier 75 old nightmare dungeon was the new
tier 100 nightmare dungeon and players no longer had that like that measuring stick that really
really difficult content anymore because we can't take it away if we want that to still be there
in the pit I mean I think if tier 200 is far beyond abattoirs year 25 especially with some of like
the balancing and the bug fixes to a lot of different builds I actually I don't know maybe I'm
wrong but I expect that to be pretty challenging I don't think people are gonna do that as a cake walk
um okay so we have eight minutes left I'm I already cut off my timer there's no way I can get to
99% of these questions so uh how do we feel about maybe doing a little rapid fire
just that okay sure yeah this was talked about yesterday if I remember correct this was the
so these are the top top questions from youtube so I promised I would ask them so here we go
um this was the number one question by far and it was touched on a little bit yesterday
is there an armory coming I heard yesterday I think if I remember what you correctly you said
that armory is great the team the team likes it had to prioritize some things will an armory be
coming to Diablo 4 so we can save our builds uh if you can answer it yeah I mean this is a problem
that I think that uh the players have I think I've already mentioned that we're like we're in the
business of trying to like solve uh player problems uh it's a thing we're really excited about
it's the thing we it's the thing we would like to do and that's all I can say right now
they're excited about it guys okay uh there's lots of different ways to expand the game and as uh
Joe put it yesterday different slices of of the pizza to give you power again from youtube it seems
like the most requested way that people would like to expand power or change their builds is to have
this skill tree expanded is that something that we can look forward to at some point coming to Diablo 4
is the team passionate about expanding the skill tree in multiple ways maybe you'll even give us
an ultimate button so we can get another skill you never know uh yeah I'll I'll take this one
I guess and let's say some more uh I would say I we have nothing to announce about the
guppies to the skill tree it is a little bit more of a complicated problem because we want the
skill tree to remain as an easy gateway for new players and returning players to come back and
kind of know what that is and we didn't want the complexity and have to of our game to be there
so it comes with some nasty trade-offs that I'm not sure that we're willing to make but we are
open to the idea of adding some more depth to the skill tree but we don't want it to be super
complicated it's not going to be the P o e in cyclopedia we don't we don't want that at least
not for our game we want to be crafting in other places yeah if I could show like the like seeing
how different players like again there's a lot of people like this is their first Diablo game
like seeing what players did with the skill tree in testing yeah I think they're very surprising to
you in your audience they take they take all the generators and max from the 5 absolutely yeah and
other things like that um it's it's a tougher problem that I think a lot of people give it credit for
and I don't know that the juices work the squeeze if we go too far but
hearing that people want more we've heard that loud and clear but nothing to announce in the near
in the immediate future okay the next one for repeated and summoning content now and in the future
of the game are there plans to let people just resummon these bosses without resetting the instance
because that eats up a lot of time for the people that do want to farm up a bunch of things and
kill some bosses yeah this is a really this is a really good idea um there's a lot of things
they get cleaned up oh when a plate when players were set a dungeon that makes it a lot easier for
us to do this in the first place uh let me take that back to team I don't I don't know that we've
talked deeply about like exactly when we could deliver something like this but we definitely see it
as a we definitely see it as a something that you can improve so yeah we'll we'll take that back
all right um last one from youtube here will the campaign receive further attention so
will well first of all obviously probably the story continues with the expansion but
another way is currently when you start up a new season of Diablo you can you can go through the
campaign again if you want or you can probably now go farm in Helltide and the Helltide is going to
level you a million times faster for a million million more rewards it's not close at all
and some games let you force you to the campaign some games in the before you don't have to
if you guys thought about maybe editing the campaign slightly for a replay maybe taking out like the
camel escort for for example and maybe benchmarking oh how long does it take to do a campaign just
normally playing what is it three hours for us I don't know what it would be and then benchmarking
what it would be to do it in Helltide and kind of have them at the same point at the end of those
journeys um to allow players a real choice in how they want to start out their new season because
the campaign was such a fan favorite on the launch and it was very well done sure so I think if
there is a like the quest team has a lot of really cool ideas of things you want to do to allow
for players to like replay the campaign or to make it uh to kind of edit it a little bit in some ways
you suggest I think that uh it's a thing that we're thinking about as we go uh but the we know that
we want to make sure that we are prioritizing the piece of the game that need work first if that
makes sense like I think that the idea of being able to replay a campaign is it's very very exciting
uh and I think if there's really neat things we can do and we do have plans in the future for
uh for this stuff as well I don't want to like make it sound like we're not committing to anything
and we kind of do we want to do something like this it's just that there's a lot of other
we're like replay features like health hide for example that we thought are we're going to
get a great position to like lift up and make feel like more exciting for players so that's been a
more of a priority for us but I do think that there's opportunities there for sure
something there I want to point out this would help when the communities discussing things or
when you even are with us is this idea of opportunity cost I don't know if you know what
are you familiar with that term racks yeah economic yeah get up something to gain something else
cool then then I don't have to explain it but yeah the opportunity cost comes very heavy into play
when we talk about features and suggestions and things from players I think a lot of times it
can be frustrating as a member of a community because I'm a member of gaming communities too so I
know how it is I'm like hey you know this thing we obviously it sounds like a good idea and we all
agree it's a good idea why don't the devs do it right away and most of the time when that is true
it's because of opportunity costs it's that the excited opportunity cost or something that you
didn't realize makes it harder than it seems um but opportunity cost you here it's like do we do
boot re-border do we redo how all the boot works in the game and your entire leveling experience
with our updates to the helltide or do we make a campaign have parity with not doing campaign to
level up right now campaign campaign have parity the non-campaign obviously is a good thing but I
would argue very heavily that loop being better in a loop based game is more important and impacts
more people in a better way more in a more long term way and then there the list goes long
long forever forever of the things that you could do versus what you have to decide to do and then
the other part um kind of alluded to your last question about uh re-summony bosses is that I would
say in that one like yeah obviously good idea better player experience in there I would say the
reason why we're not doing it just knowing how the game works a little bit more is it's our game
wasn't structured that way and we have to do a lot of things to make it structured that way and the
ants did actually do it is harder than most people would think and that is why um both of these things
are obviously good ideas that we would want there's different reasons why we haven't done them yet
doesn't mean they won't happen but it means that it's why they're not happening now or yet um
and that's a better way to frame it when people are talking to each other because like hey what should
the devil to fourteen do first or now or hey you know maybe this is a little bit harder could you
explain why x harder would be a good question for an interviewer for example right because then
you're going to get actual insight into why rather than just complaining that it's not happening
are you providing uh rags feedback on this i mean i might be giving feedback on the
feedback that's part of my job too but i mean i like productive conversations is why and i think the
community would rather have more productive conversations then their only avenues to complain
and not know why things aren't working the way that they want to i think people want to know how
things work i think they want to know how things work i want to educate people so that we can
have better conversations about games i mean i i'm gonna lose or guys i'm always here if you guys
ever want to talk which we're we're we're actually at time um i have one more all right i mean
probably probably the the one that i i'm just going to ask a fifteen-part question then to
to abuse the one more i guess i love it gamer at heart probably probably the the most important one
that's still left on the list is about social features so there i have three main topics of so
i just i can't believe how many questions i put here that was so stupid and me i mean there's
no no chance at all anyway um social features so the there's three main things trading group finder
clans so with trading um what are your guys thoughts on putting an auction house
esk type of thing just to allow trading and to avoid third-party sites obviously not a real money
auction house um people are begging for a group finder um i don't know why people have kudis
i play by myself but i guess people want it and then clans i understand uh i understand there's
a big difficulty with clans not just implementing them like they were implemented in diablo three
but diablo three clans mean absolutely nothing it's just a second friends list there's no
achievements to do there's nothing to unlock there's nothing to work toward but then if you put
that in the game opportunity cost the thing that the economic principle we keep talking about
then if you build that in the game then people have to belong to a clan
and otherwise they feel left out which then leads me to another one of my million questions about sss
but whatever so for social features trading group finder clans what are your guys' thoughts on
those three for diablo four let's get going so uh for trading okay uh trading in season four
players can trade legendary unique uh there's so i can have to like uh go and actually meet up
to do those trades there's not gonna be an i'm a trading function there are things we talk about
with the guards like the trade chat channels make it a little bit easier to navigate um in terms
of like creating like an actual auction house user interface it's a thing a team is discussed uh
it's not that we've land on we really want to see what the reaction is for players uh in season four
and what the experience is broadly for players in season four how many players are actually trading
you know because i imagine there's gonna be it'll be different for different types of players right
um but i think there could potentially be room for an investment there because we don't want to
just push players just to like third party sites but we were at a point where we're like well do we
really want to like go and make a whole if it would be an opportunity cost would be a big investment
to go make an auction house uh for diablo four for example um without knowing exactly what the
desire for it is going to be and we didn't want to like wait to like let some of these things be
tradable in the meantime uh so that's the hell version we're not opposed to what we want to see
have things going season four uh for the with the guards to the uh like uh group finder i think
is the way that you call it um we do want to make sure that there are easier since
for players to use to find parties of players who are doing things that interest them uh we do have
a social team on diablo four they've been thinking about clan stuff things like this things that
make socialization more easy between players uh i think they'll be saying stuff to share in the
future so there's things we're thinking about and there are uh and then with regards to uh
last one clans of course clans uh we also have ideas of things we want to do to update parts of
the clan functionality to make it just a little more engaging to give more purpose to parts of clans
you know this is a thing that we are we have designs for and things we're thinking about i can't
announce anything today just to say that we recognize there's some parts the social features in
diablo four that can be leveled up made better and there's process we see players going through
as part of regular play and seasons we want to make easier and more streamlined for them
well i i got to be honest it was it was actually an honor to have you guys come here i really like
you guys i love the diablo franchise since i was kid this actually meant a lot to me i have a
million more i have a million more questions but i know we're at a time want to be respectful of that
thank you guys thank you guys for coming here and uh speaking so open and honestly i'm a loser i'm
always here if you guys want to go again i mean you guys got three three three hours uh i got a lot
more questions but i guess who's is is DM going next or i can just pass along a million more i'm
sure that i believe so yeah i'm on with him to get you guys right yeah all right it's been a blast
it's been super fun thank you rax really appreciate it um i will say we're trying to get in front of
the community a little bit more and talk about these things it's something that i i really like doing
and i'm pretty passionate about and i'm looking forward to doing more so thank you guys for being here
talk to us hell yeah let's do it again thank you guys uh everybody in chat say goodbye to the
lovely people at blizzard and we'll i guess we'll see in season four thank you all thanks guys
all right coming back
uh okay how do i how do i like this so all right i'm back
dude i can't even explain to you how many questions i had to skip man
dot yo dude i had so many more questions like oh man dude look at all the questions i missed
first of all i missed all of these almost all of these and i missed
loot filter ssf pvp offline mode ladders p how did the ptr go map overlay we kind of talk
about this charms who were too lord the cow level why isn't diablo and diablo four what are the toughest
challenges of your job how did the microsoft take over impact you guys what are the scope of your
seasons in the mid season events can you make community goals and events why are world bosses
loot pin yadas what about pets and followers who is the target audience for diablo four
four talk one of the talked them about i just have i don't know man i don't know man i i was i was
pretty disheartened man i had so many more questions
oh i had so many more questions man
i
feel like i feel like i spent too much time talking
like i spent too much time maybe phrasing the question maybe
then i could have gotten a couple more in
and i purposely didn't i purposely didn't like i wanted to have a conversation with them
about every topic but if i have a conversation with them about every topic i only get to ask two
question
man dude i wouldn't ask them so many more questions
I super over prepared for that, I guess.
Well, did you enjoy the conversation?
I'll tell you the most shocking thing to me.
I literally said it in the interview.
They block out time for the developers to play the game because they said the only way
you're ever going to know anything is by playing the game.
I thought that was pretty good, man.
What's the cliff note version?
Okay, so, should I close it one second?
The TLDR version.
The TLDR of pinnacle content and will skill ever play a factor is, I think the way I would summarize their answer is, yes, they're will, but they're still trying to find out what the right level is.
The roadmap, they said, has a lot of pros and cons.
The pros have to outweigh the cons, but they feel committed to giving the community promises that they keep.
When I asked them, how do you actually, how do you, by the way, there's so many people subbing and doing super chats and somebody gifted 50 subs, Mr.
G point gifted 50 subs.
Thank you.
So many people are subbing and stuff.
I actually, I don't know how this happened, but it actually got, actually closed the notifications somehow.
That was an accident when you reopened this.
Thank you guys.
Sorry, I was just a thousand percent focused on trying to suck blood from a mummy trying to get everything I could out of that.
There's a million people that subbed with prime and 56 month resub from maximum.
That's crazy.
So there's so many of them.
Thank you guys.
Make sure I didn't miss anything crazy.
Sucking blood from a mummy.
Never heard of that.
Like a mosquito sucking blood from a mummy.
Extracting water from a stone.
Same analogy.
You sure sucked them hard, racks.
Thanks, man.
I sure sucked them.
All right.
I thought, I thought I almost threw this question out.
I actually thought this was the best question I asked them.
Because they did say we read the Reddit threads.
We watched the streams.
We watched the YouTube videos.
We read the comment sections.
We go to the forums and they said we play the game.
That's the only way you will ever really know to play the damn game.
I thought that was the best part.
On Nightmare Dungeons, I essentially just cried and asked them.
Stop making me free seven prisoners and reduce the time further
and let me carry multiple objects.
And I think the answer was maybe.
Overworld's future.
This is maybe the answer that kind of surprised me a little bit.
I was kind of, I mean, what they said made perfect sense.
They said the overworld is super fun kind of the first time through afterward.
You can't really recreate the magic.
We need to just get you to the events that you want to do.
Like, I can't argue with that logic.
That makes sense.
But I did kind of expect them to, I guess I expected Diablo 4 to double down on the overworld's future kind of more than what I heard.
I was actually kind of, this is probably the most surprising answer to me that.
The overworld in general is not not totally a one and done, but that's, that's what I got out of their answer.
You think you want it, but you don't.
Well, I just got done playing 130 hours of Elden Ring.
And all I did was roam around in the overworld.
And all I ever think about in my life is when am I going to play Elden Ring again?
And when am I going to do new game plus and 30 more playthroughs of it?
I understand it's a different kind of game.
This is an air PG. You don't have to tell me.
I played it trillion different games.
But my point is World of Warcraft, one of my fun is, one of my favorite things, World of Warcraft, get on the pony and ride around and go see what we can discover.
And there's, you know, there's so many things to go do.
I wouldn't say that overworld is, I think I want it, but I don't.
In fact, I think one of the most fun game modes in the game is in the overworld, Helltide.
I think Helltide is more fun than Nightmare Dungeons.
It might be more fun than the Pit, but probably not. The Pit is probably more fun currently, but it's way more fun than World Bosses and it's way more fun than Challenge Riffs.
So, I don't know.
I don't, I don't think, I don't think they should abandon the overworld.
That is not how I feel about it.
These were Rob's questions.
They actually said this in CJ's interview.
They said this that the Diablo 3 had some cool things that they could borrow from and some things that they didn't like.
So they actually kind of pseudo admitted that it is kind of like Diablo 3.
But I wanted to ask them, where do they, do they often take inspiration from the past games?
And they said yesterday on CJ's stream that there will be new things that are, and this is a quote, distinctly Diablo 4 fresh and exciting.
I wanted to ask them about this.
I wanted to ask them, are you actually innovating on ARPGs?
Distinctly Diablo 4 fresh and exciting.
Do you actually, are you actually planning to release new things that really the ARPG world has not seen?
Because that would be exciting.
I wanted to talk to them about set items.
They talked about it yesterday on CJ's stream.
I had more questions, man.
I wanted to talk to them about rune words.
They said that they like rune words.
They were working on it and they're going to come into Diablo 4.
But I still have questions.
I wanted to talk about charms.
I asked all the questions from YouTube.
I forgot to write their, I forgot to say their names.
I should have said their name.
I forgot.
I should have said their names.
The interview is over, yeah.
Seeing names adds time.
And then I was out of time.
And then I said, well, probably the next best thing I could ask is about social features.
It didn't sound like they have anything coming for trading anytime soon.
It sounded like they actually, I was surprised.
They actually sounded like they had something for Clans coming.
And they didn't sound like they had anything for trading.
What did they say about GroupFinder?
What did I think about the interview?
Well, I liked the Callie literally just walked up to me and farted.
Thanks for that, Callie.
Thank you.
Did you see Callie trying to crawl on me the whole interview?
No, it's not even a drive-by.
She runs up far, so then she sits there and wags her tails.
She doesn't go anywhere.
Nothing to announce, but it's being discussed.
What is my overall opinion about their answers in the interview?
It's hard to judge because it's hard to judge like being in the moment.
I probably have to go back and rewatch it to get the full to absorb the full amount of information.
But it felt like they were being very honest.
I don't know.
I thought that they were giving good answers to the questions that I asked.
Adam Jackson said at the end was exactly how I feel where he said,
it's not really that valuable for you to ask me like a yes or no question.
And I give you the answer and you post it somewhere and no one ever knows the why behind anything.
So what would be much more helpful is having in-depth conversations about opportunity costs.
I'm glad that I studied economics in college because they were actually talking about a lot of economic principles.
Is like do you know what an opportunity cost is?
Yes.
I love economics.
I love math.
So that helped.
One time the one time college actually pays off.
They were talking about their problems, their problems.
But that's exactly their problems by transitivity become our problems.
If Blizzard has a problem, it's going to become our problem.
If Blizzard has a problem implementing something, it will become our problem as players.
If someone has a super chat here, never call yourself a loser Ryan, you are awesome.
Thanks for saying that man.
I'm a loser.
I just sit around and play games all day, but I appreciate the sentiment.
What did I major in in college?
Math.
I almost got a triple major.
I almost triple majored in math, stats, and economics.
I also went pretty far into psychology as well.
I like school.
I always, my corporate job for 10 years always gave tuition reimbursement.
So I always went to school.
So I got my bachelor's in math and then I had, I put a huge emphasis on stats, economics, and psychology.
I got my first master's in PNC insurance, the CBCU, and then I actually went for a second master's.
I'm about a third of the way done with it with an MBA.
I just like school.
A lot of people hate school.
I loved it.
I like to go and learn.
Not from MIT, from the University of Nebraska.
You got a triple major math computer science and drugs.
Well, one of them will make you way more money than the other.
Just watch Breaking Bad.
I'm a corn husker.
Yeah, we have the, we used to have the best football team ever in the history of football.
And now we have the worst team ever in work garbage.
We don't, we don't, we don't talk about the current day.
Don't, didn't we get the number one pick though?
We got the, got like the top court.
We have like, now we have like the godliest quarterback ever and we have the rest of our team sucks.
You graduated with your cyber security degree this December, hell yeah.
I didn't go to high school.
I went to school.
High.
Yeah, we have real.
So we have, we have Nebraska has racks.
That's a Y equals MX plus B.
Good old algebra.
Yeah, did you hear what they said?
You should hear how most players built, you should see the data on how most players built a skill tree.
Like what's the dumbest thing that they could do?
What do they do?
Put five points in every generator and Joe was like, yes, I was like, Jesus Christ guys.
Maxroll.gg. What is wrong with you guys?
So yeah, if you guys like college football, the Nebraska corn huskers are going to be super interesting to watch next year.
Because we have the greatest quarterback ever and our, the rest of our team is absolute YMCA rejects.
So how far can one god quarterback take a team of losers?
It's going to be like space jam.
It's going to be like space jam, but for football.
I'm sorry to say racks, but ever since you stop making barb guides, you stop following Maxroll.
If I don't write the guide, you don't want to read it.
I can tell you the people that write the barb guides over there like snail and is it sloth master and snail?
They put a lot of effort into those guides, man.
They put a lot of effort into those guides.
You can snail is a many, many, many time rank one Diablo 3 player on almost every single class.
He's one of the greatest players ever.
You can read a guide from snail and feel good about it, man.
He's one of the greatest Diablo players of all time.
It doesn't have to be me.
Who writes the sorcerer builds?
You ever heard of a guy named North War?
North War.
Everybody follows North Wars builds.
Nobody does more math in Diablo 4 than North War.
Nobody.
He is the best sorcerer guide writer in the world by a huge margin.
It's not even close at all.
There I am.
There's no way.
It's not even close.
Rob's the math guy too.
Rob's the math guy.
You guys remember Rob was on Maxroll for three years.
Rob's the math guy too.
Rob's the math guy.
What changes are coming?
I didn't catch the stream.
It wasn't really an interview about, it wasn't really an interview about changes really.
It's not like a spoiler thing where they can like, announce a bunch of new things on the stream.
It's kind of understanding how are they going to make the game.
The high level takeaways are challenging content will be in the game, but it's never going to be all skill based again.
Mechanical mastery is out and your gear is going to be a huge portion of you winning.
What I took from that.
They're really unsure about road maps, but they have no problem making certain promises and keeping them.
Kind of sounded like a note to me from the road maps.
That's how I interpreted the answer.
They said that they block out time for the team to play the game.
For example, he's going to have about 50 hours in season five.
He said that that's by far the best way for the team to learn the game.
I don't think there's any other way you could in there's no other way to approach the question.
The only way you will learn is by playing the game.
You will never learn by sitting in an ivory tower theorizing about the game.
This was very refreshing to hear.
This was just me essentially just complaining and I want more qualitative stuff.
Kind of like maybe this was just me bitching about everything.
The overworlds future was surprising to me.
This is the most surprising answer.
I said the overworlds really fun to explore the first time or two and then people want to get to their events.
That's probably true.
I mean we have a big overworld here.
There's got to be something we can do with it.
You're coping.
They said no to instant interactions.
I don't know if they said no.
They said that they thought that they could bring it down further.
I'm pretty sure they said that right that they'd look into bringing it down further.
Well no guys.
It's not that the overworld is not going to expand.
It's very logical that with the expansion there will be new zones and things to ride around in.
It's not that the overworld is never going to get bigger.
What I was asking them is the overworld is going to be a defining feature of the game.
Are we going to be spending a lot of time in the overworld for future activities?
What they said was the overworld is kind of a one or two time thing where it's interesting and then people want to get to where they want to go.
Certainly the overworld will be expanded upon, but that's not the same as is it a defining feature.
Okay.
Let's do some polls about how you guys felt.
How did you feel about the interview?
Everything about it.
How it was done, the questions and the answers.
Everything is a whole.
You thought it was godly, you thought it was great, you thought it was me, you thought it was terrible, you thought it was horrendous.
Create the poll.
Let's pace the poll if you want to vote.
There it is. I pasted it a million times results.
Let's see.
How did you guys feel about it?
The whole entirety of it, how it was the everything about it, me, all blizzard, everything lumped into one.
All right.
It's pretty good. I'll take that.
That was what I was going to ask from you guys.
What band the 22 people?
I wouldn't give them a band somebody for having an opinion that didn't align with mine.
If people state their opinions and they're different than mine, as long as they aren't being toxic about it, I don't have any problem with them.
It's when people voice opinions to me and they're being toxic about it that I swap them away.
What feedback do you guys have about how it could have been better?
It's really not up to them to do better. It's up to me to do better.
So it could have been a longer interview. What can I do better?
I need to ask questions quicker.
Not be a simp. I was being a simp for Diablo 4.
You know, I hear some content creators get called this.
Some content creators get called a simp. I actually don't get that too much.
I'm kind of surprised to hear that.
It's usually just not feedback that I get very often.
Joe needs to talk less, but here's the thing though.
It's kind of like Adam said at the end of the thing.
I think it is much more helpful to have insights and deep dives into conversations than to do the rapid fire.
I could have asked 50 questions if I would have done it.
Will there be charms in Diablo 4?
Will there be set items in Diablo 4?
But last epoch has set items and they're terrible.
Diablo 3's entire game is based on overpowered sets and it pretty much ruined the game.
Diablo 2 has some godly sets and some of them are completely useless, even after the repass of what they did of them.
So when you tell me set, if they would say yes, sets are coming into the game, that doesn't tell me anything.
What I want to know is what do you think about sets?
Let's have a conversation about what works about sets and what doesn't.
That's the important thing to me.
So when you say Joe talks too much, I would not coach him to talk less because I want to have conversations about it.
One hour is too short of a time to ask detailed questions.
Most of the segments should be rapid fire, otherwise you don't cover anything.
If you had two or three hours, it would have been a different story.
Barely any questions were covered.
Yeah, I think that's the main point of feedback is more time.
Well, some of the questions that I started off with, which I thought were the most important, they already discussed it yesterday.
And I cannot assume that people watched Ryker's interview like I did.
So I wanted to start off with, here's what you guys said already.
Okay, here's what you said yesterday.
Now here's my question, here's the part that I'm missing here.
Yeah, I mean, again, if I could have had a conversation about things when Adam Jackson was talking about balancing the campaign, I mean, I have a pretty simple solution, which I, which I think is, I mean, again, opportunity cost.
How long does it take them to do it versus what's the benefit added?
I can go through, I can go through halty and play for whatever, five hours.
And I'm level 65 and I have a full set of basic ancestral gear and I have two or three legendaries that are good for me.
That's where I get in five hours or something.
And then I go play the campaign and the campaign takes me five hours. And when I'm done with it, I'm level 43 and I have mostly yellows and two legendaries.
And then I say, okay, if you design, redesign the campaign completely with all the new smart loot and this or that or this or that, then it's a huge undertaking, right?
So what about this? Lead the campaign as it is. Forget it. Just leave it as it is.
And the only thing that you do is cut out some of the ridiculous parts like maybe walking around the snake 300 times or the camel escort quest where you're sitting there for 20 minutes, the slowest camel ever following it.
And then you say, all right, the time now is four hours or something or whatever it is. And then you benchmark that compared to about where would you be gear wise and XP wise.
At the end of the run, you could do it. You could do it very cheaply actually. You could just play the campaign. You kill Uber, you kill Lilith at whatever level 42.
And once you kill Lilith, you go to level 60 in world tier four, you just you just ding 60 boom you're 60. You're in world tier four and you get a little good Lilith drops Lilith's goody bag and she drops you a decent set of eye level, whatever 800 and sustrel gear put it on. It's about the same.
That requires almost no changes in the campaign, nothing you didn't change anything. And when you kill Lilith, you just ding roughly the level and roughly the gear that you would have had if you would have played in hell.
That sounds lame though, but that sounds lame to you. People love the campaign.
The whole point is to give another choice. People who say that's lame, that's you.
I would personally love that.
See.
Some people in Diablo 4 would rather do the campaign again and arrive at the same spot than run 15 helltides.
You're not in the what? Let's not leave it up to interpretation. No guessing. Let's just ask the question.
Assuming reasonable campaign changes, meaning you don't have to wait for the camel for an hour, which is more fun to level if you arrived at the same point for the same amount of time.
I don't expect I'm not expecting this poll to be lopsided. I'm expecting it to be a balance.
Hell tide blasting or the campaign.
Let's see if I'm wrong. Let's just see what happens. What would be more fun for you?
I spammed it. What would you rather do if you arrived at the same point and they made some basic quality of life changes to the campaign?
Okay, I didn't actually expect the campaign to win, but...
This is what I expected it to not have a landslide victory for either of them.
So what someone says is stupid to you is way more fun for 420 people, KW.
You
Guys, another thing is
This is this if they took this development time other than the opportunity cost of development time on some other feature.
This situation is just a win for everybody. Even if you're just hell tide blasting, it does not hurt you for the campaign to be an equally viable option for the people that want to play this game.
What's the problem?
And guys, some people say, Rax, your solution is really lame.
You just beat the campaign, you ding 60 and you get a goody bag.
Yeah, I mean, that's pretty lame. That's not as good as them redefining the whole campaign and putting in special loot drops to align and making it perfect.
But the entire point of why you wouldn't get this change is the dev time opportunity cost, right?
It takes a million years to fix that, whereas if they just did a gooy bag and made you ding a certain level, then they could implement it maybe in a day.
And then if they can fix it later.
Right now you're not going to get night now if you do the campaign, you don't get anything. You don't get jack shit.
You don't get any XP and you don't get anything. It's a huge, huge, not even close to hell tide.
Stop wasting time on meaningless garbage. Jesus, the game has much bigger problems than this.
Some of you guys.
I know fourth grade was hard.
It's hard to cover a lot of different ideas and aspects of a topic.
I know that that can get really complicated for some people.
I can see the smoke coming out of some of their ears from all the way over here.
That's why I'm saying fussy. That's why I included this portion to expedite the campaign on a replay a little bit.
We don't have to walk the camel again.
Wait, there's a fourth grade after fifth grade.
Fourth grade is coming, man. And for some of the people in chat, it's where their journey ended.
I like the camel. Don't take it away from us. Well, we just proved today that Satan does exist. Drag a shot right there.
He's a shot right there. Like the camel. Satan does exist, guys.
They should have an uber fight of the camel and you have to walk him across the desert in it's kind of like a Mario Kart race.
The timing is really, really precise. You need like frame perfect inputs to get the camel to turn left and right.
Yeah, and there needs to be landmines.
And if you successfully beat it, then you unlock a key to go into the catacombs to fight uber tomb lord.
And uber tomb lord's mount is the camel.
The inner US already over. Yeah, if you blinked, it's already over. Rob just sent me a clip. I don't know what this is. Let's just click it.
So we ended up putting it in a place where like the tier 200 pit is like around tier 150 pit is like close to where AOS was.
You know, for like tier 25, AOS. Yes. And two or 200 goes beyond that. That is insane. Scaling has been. Oh my god. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank you so much. Thank
you super and deeper deeper. Thank you super and deeper. You know but there's you but we do want to have these like really really difficult. So we have these like really difficult. So we have these like really difficult. We do want to put these like really difficult. So we ended up putting it a place where like the tear to you."PIG and PIG smiles. If the, if the barb is happy. Then we're happy. If the barb is happy. Then we're happy.
We got a message from Adam Fletcher.
I know that you had a ton of additional stuff.
Maybe we can do this again sooner rather than later and we can hit up even more of your
questions.
All right.
I mean, I got questions.
I can come up with another hundred questions.
Adam to save the day.
Rob probably loves the camel.
He better not.
Maybe better not.
Okay.
Should I call Adam and Joe?
I guess three later.
Let's go.
Let's go again.
Part two.
Okay.
I didn't know this.
It's Rob's birthday today.
I have nine, huh?
It's his birthday.
31.
That's one foot in the grave.
Should I just when DM's interview starts, should I call them?
Be like, what?
No.
You guys got your schedules confused.
This interview was my interview.
Part two.
DM's is later.
The back.
Okay.
And then DM's going to be like, what the hell?
I'm kidding.
I'll just send DM my questions.
He'll do a good job.
Excuse me.
I'm 34.
How are you even alive?
I'm 37, by the way.
There's DM right there.
Please no.
DM.
I'm sure you have a list of questions.
Would you like another list of questions that I didn't get to get to?
To add to your list?
Dude, 45 minutes, man.
Is not enough time.
Send them your way.
You'll carry the torch.
All right.
Fix this document.
In fact, I'm going to do it right now.
I already asked this.
Well, let me do it this way.
I already asked about aspirational content.
I already asked them about the roadmap.
I already asked them about feedback.
I already asked them about the state of nightmare dungeons.
I already asked them about the overworld future.
I asked them about the pit.
Didn't ask them this.
These are all done.
I already asked those.
This was kind of asked already.
I wanted to prod at them deeper, but I'm just going to delete this question.
I'm not sure if DM was aware of this.
Maybe this question doesn't make any sense anymore.
I'm just going to delete it.
Charms.
This is a good one.
That's a good one to ask.
All right.
I already asked.
I asked all of these.
So this is all.
I already asked this.
Didn't ask that.
I want to know this.
I want to know what their target audience is for Diablo 4.
This is already listed above.
Okay.
Yeah.
Here you go.
Anything in anything in orange.
I already asked.
CJ had some extra questions as well.
Okay.
Let me share this with DM here.
All right.
There you go, man.
He has it.
There you go.
Yeah.
That's another question.
I should have asked.
Why is everything red?
I asked about the armory and they gave me a little smile and they said, we like the idea
of the armory and we know people want it.
That's usually their cutie-pity way of saying that it's probably maybe coming soon.
That maybe season five.
How am I feeling about the pit difficulty?
Yeah.
Like I said, live on the interview, if tier 25 is 150 and 200 is beyond, Abattoir tier 25
with the bug fixes and with the balance changes, that should be in theory extremely difficult.
When will North War release his guides?
I know he has a lot of guides to work on.
I don't know the exact timing, but I do know that I don't know the exact timing, but I do
know that the Maxwell people have been blasting.
Obviously, before the season comes out on Tuesday, the Maxwell team has been blasting
to get the D4 guides out.
Please tell me I will not be playing hardcore in Diablo 4.
I'm 1,000% going hardcore SSF and it is very, very likely that I will die, very likely.
I did a couple of practice runs on the PTR with the no cheat death changes.
I did not survive a single run.
I died on every single time.
And I know Diablo 4 pretty well.
You want another cute thing about me playing hardcore next season?
I have never fought an Uber boss.
I've never fought Uber and Dariel.
I've never fought Uber.
I don't even know their names.
I'm a fighting man.
I never fought Uber or Zero.
I've never fought them.
Not even one time to test them.
Now I will, I fought.
Is there a 200 version of Dariel as well?
Okay.
I will almost certainly die.
I didn't survive one speed run in the PTR.
I died on every single one.
I'm probably going to play, well, first of all, I'll play every class because again, I've
said this like five times today, but I'm a loser.
So I'll play everything except maybe Rogue, but maybe I'll play Rogue too.
I'm probably going to start Necro.
I haven't started Necro.
I don't know if I've ever started Necro and I really want to play with the minions.
I think the minions are going to be fun as hell.
Why not Rogue?
Rogue didn't get many like exciting changes.
I tried several speed leveling things and I died on every single one of them.
I hate minions.
It's not that I hate minions.
It's I hate minions where I'm a babysitter and not the commander of the undead.
If my minions are dumb as hell and not and I have to do a ton of things to make them do
anything, then yes, I hate minions.
What time is DM's interview?
I don't know.
He tweeted it, didn't he?
I'm such a Twitter new.
I don't even know how to look people up here.
Search, search, Darth, Micro here.
One PM Pacific.
So exactly 24 hours from now.
I believe.
And I hype for May 14th.
I am just going to be fun.
I'm almost certainly going to die, but I don't care.
I'll just make another character.
We go again.
You watch the interview already a second time and I was too hard for myself.
My phrasing was well done.
Makes for saying that, man.
Appreciate it.
Yeah, I just didn't.
Time was the limiting factor there.
Is there any need to keep aspects on old characters to migrate them over to the new system in season
four?
You can mind the new system is very seamless, right?
You run around, you pick up legendaries.
Okay, you take a look.
If it's not better than yours, essentially if it doesn't have a greater ethics, you just
salvage it.
Is this going to chain?
Is this going to start chain upgrading your codex of power seamlessly?
I don't think you need to save stuff and salvage it and anything like that.
I think you just play and your codex is going to get filled out pretty easily.
Yeah, that's a good way to phrase it.
One of the biggest values there is the humanizing of the Blizzard entity or the Diablo 4 entity.
You get to speak to the people in plain English.
The real advantage here, the difference between this and a campfire chat for me is they're
willing to just sit there and say, what is the community want to talk about?
And I tried to make my questions a little bit pointed.
If I leave the question super open ended, then we can get a very, very high level glazing
of ideas.
But if I say, I want to talk to you about pinnacle content.
You said this didn't work.
You said this is going to be a bigger factor than x is going to be a bigger factor than y.
Have you considered z specifically for this content and what does the team think about that?
Then we can start to dig at what are we actually getting at here?
Right, when you leave it very open, it's not even like a negative.
When you leave a topic wide open, they will respond similarly to how they have always
responded.
Right?
If I say, what did you guys think about the PTR?
They have already said a hundred times.
We really liked the PTR.
We got so much feedback.
Thank you for participating on the PTR.
But I could ask them, what kind of feedback from the PTR seem to be the most valuable to
you?
What kinds of things surprised you when you started that can catenate the data and start
to make some decisions about it?
That's better.
We're actually going to learn something out of it.
Rax plays soft course.
You can do community, duriel and and arial runs.
The problem is, the problem is, when I, if I do that, whenever
I have ever done a community run, I have always required myself to pay my own way, unless
someone comes into my stream and says, Rax, I'm literally quitting.
I'm going to go play a wow season of discovery.
If you want my 50 mats, you can take them.
If not, they're going to rot in my chest.
Okay.
If you're actually quitting, whatever, I'll take them.
But in general, if I just log in, what you guys will do because you guys are so nice,
is you guys will pay for me to run duriel 10,000 times until I have every uber unique
because you're very nice.
But if I do that, I'm missing the most important thing about my stream and as a player, I miss
being relatable.
If I just use streamer privilege to just get handed everything, first of all, the game
is boring because I didn't earn anything.
The second thing is, I'm not relatable.
You guys don't have, a lot of you don't have a thousand million people that are willing
to just hand you everything.
When you're trying content and you have a stick and I have X-caliber, it's not relatable.
That's why I don't do that.
Or if I participate in community events, I pay my own way every time.
Am I not trying to be Rob?
Guys, I'm not needling Rob or people are saying ask me, Gold.
I'm not giving this answer to disrespect other people or their decisions.
I was asked a question, I'm responding to the answer for me.
They can do whatever they want.
Interview already happened.
Here's an interesting thing.
We just made this.
This is going to be the timestamps of the interview on YouTube.
This is interesting because let's look at the time spent on each topic.
The problem is, this question had a lot of setup.
I spent at least one minute setting up the question from CJ's interview.
Let's say about four minutes on road map, four minutes on political content, four minutes
on road map, 11 minutes on feedback from the community.
Wow, 11 minutes.
We spent one, we spent one fourth of the time talking about how they process feedback and
how they test the game.
Armory 42 seconds.
This was the rapid fire thing though.
You got to talk faster, ask speed run questions.
I mean, I was trying, man.
I was trying.
I wasn't yapping fast enough.
What stood out the most, probably the feedback section, the fact that they said that they
build in time for all the developers to play the game to learn the game.
I would say that was the best news for me out of all of it.
I think that let's do one more poll.
I don't want to become a poll Andy.
I do have a question.
For those that watch the interview, let's see, what was the best information about or
from the interview?
The devs play the game every day.
What are some other choices?
The pit actually having difficulty.
The overworld being dead.
It sounded like an armory is coming.
Armory coming we think.
For towels next to the bed.
Yeah, they actually feedback listen to from all sources.
I mean, that's good enough.
We don't have to fish for these.
Let's just go with this.
Which of these four, would you say was the best news that out of these four choices,
to spam the poll in the chat?
If you care to answer.
All right.
So people are what I'm gathering from this is people are excited about different things.
It was a little bit more balanced than I thought it was going to be.
I wonder why that is.
Why would they block that?
It's like to protect the integrity of the poll or something.
Devs play the game every day is not a best info.
That is their obligation.
I don't know if every gaming studio blocks out a certain portion of their day every day
to just play the game.
I wouldn't say that's an obligation is a stretch, but I'm glad that they do it.
The people actually think that the devs don't play the game.
I think most people thought that the devs play the game, but there's a huge difference
between playing the game and your entire dev team as part of their daily job plays 50
hours of the new season each before releasing it to the public.
I think that's not those are not the same thing.
I was not expecting that.
What is SSF?
Solo self-found.
All right.
There's so many people here.
I would love to just blast all day, but I actually think I'm going to relax a little
bit.
I could stream all day, guys, but I think I'm going to wrap it up here.
I'm going to raid Rob because it's his birthday.
Let's raid Rob.
Wish him happy birthday.
See what he thinks.
Really appreciated you guys being here.
You guys left a lot of comments.
I took the top five comments on YouTube and I blocked out time to ask your questions.
Probably the most insulting thing, the thing that pisses me off that people talk shit
about me all the time, and that's fine.
You're a streamer.
That's what's going to happen.
The one thing that pisses me off the most is when people say that I don't care about
the community.
I don't represent the community in any way.
I don't give a shit about the casuals.
I only care about the blasters.
It's complete horse shit.
That's why I let you guys post all of your questions.
And when I'm running out of time, I asked every single one of your top five questions.
I didn't do it as a PR move.
I did it to make sure that your questions got answered.
That's the thing that if you really want to piss me off is saying something like that
to me.
One guy, know it happens a lot, my friend.
Trust me.
You wouldn't believe how much people talk shit about me.
But I'm not going to focus on that.
Today was a great day.
But remember this, for all the people that say I don't care.
I asked the top five questions from YouTube and I didn't have an opportunity to ask many
questions.
Rob's still streaming.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you so much, guys.
I appreciate it.
Tomorrow, I'll probably play Diablo IV.
I haven't played in a long time.
I mean, I'll be honest with you.
The five-year-old in me just wants to keep playing Elden Ring.
But I'll probably play Diablo IV.
My theory crafts and things might look at some Max Roll builds.
I need to make a tier list.
It's just so hard to say, man.
It's so hard to say that the tier list, I'm going to make it just because people like the
video, but it's so hard to say.
I'll see you tomorrow, Frosty.
Frosty, hopefully you got some ultimate mean content from that.
You already know Frosty is brewing something.
Thanks for being here, guys.
By the way, there were a million superchats, subs.
Flip said, hey, I am watching your Elden Ring playthrough.
You can only play the game once for the first time.
Thanks to the creators.
I can watch someone else experiencing for the first time.
Thank you for uploading it to YouTube and bless you.
Thank you, man.
Flip I hope you're here.
If you're not here, I'm going to private message you just to make sure.
Sorry, I didn't see that until now.
Everybody on YouTube, thanks for all the subs, thanks for the likes, thanks to the superchats,
thanks for everything.
Sorry, I was super tunnel visioned on the stream today.
I wasn't even looking at the notifications today.
I'll do better.
I got to the end of the Final Fantasy VII rebirth and then I just stopped playing it.
I'm literally at the point where the bad thing happens and I'm at the point where the bad
thing happens and I just stopped playing.
I don't know, it's just not the same as Final Fantasy VII, man.
Have a great night guys.
See you tomorrow.