I have to say, it just went way beyond my expectation.
It's like nothing that we had in D4.
Pure hatred, their Mephisto's army.
They wanted them to feel a little bit more different from your typical demon family.
Everyone's quality was top-notch.
But at the time, we didn't know if it was going to work.
I think where we landed is going to turn some heads.
This is not your normal thing.
It's the living form of hatred.
The new monster class that we get to introduce, they're called hollows.
These hollows have actually been around for like millennia.
Mephisto at some point did go to Nahantu a long, long, long time ago.
And these hollows were a reaction of Mephisto being in Nahantu at the time.
And then they went dormant.
Bringing Mephisto in the Soul Stone seems like the right thing to do for Narell.
But it has a chain reaction that I don't think anybody was prepared for.
The hollows are really rife throughout Nahantu now that Mephisto is back.
And just visually, like horribly disgusting.
And sort of made up of the things that have been consumed by the hollows.
Yeah, they're an extension of evil.
Infecting wildlife and other monsters and people with this thing called ichor.
And they're just sort of going mad.
When we're designing the hollows, the main thing that we wanted to push was just if hatred came to life, what would it look like?
So we're thinking this black goo that's kind of like formless, but also have this red anger energy inside of it.
And then with concept, we just want to make, you know, cool monsters.
What if it's three legs?
What if it's no legs?
What if it has like three arms?
So we pushed a lot of like options and exploration.
And then from then on, like everyone from narrative to design and concept would talk about it.
It's like, okay, we like this one.
And then we can push it and move it further.
The hollow family is made up of four members.
The swarmer, the spitter, the caster, and the brutes.
A big thing for me was that the family need to be overwhelming without just relying on pure numbers.
So they're going to get stronger over time if you let them fester their hatred after all.
The swarmer can teleport and attack you from behind, from the sides.
The spitter is a slug with legs.
They spew out this vomit stream of who the brute is.
The big, hulking, slow guy of the family.
He has the shield that's buffing and making the rest of the army stronger.
The caster is responsible for creating new swarmers.
They also will channel onto a specific hollow and view them with extra hatred.
It makes them stronger and more deadly.
The hollow caster's role serve as an elegant, hovering, yet menacing dungeon character in a game.
It really informs many of our design ideas.
When we want to make a new variant, we want to know in which specific area we are going to see that character or creature.
Readability is like the main focus.
We went through several iterations on the design, the texture, the materials and the camera testing.
The day after she gave in, what was it, 10 different variations?
I was like, okay, now we are talking.
The emission on the spikes really did an awesome job to both on the CineVet and also to improve the readability.
And in the end, we have the version that we were both happy with and handed it over to the tech artists.
We had some really strong narrative direction in understanding how big of a role hatred played.
And we knew that we needed one look to tie it all together.
This hatred has one source and it's all about Mephisto.
For the hollow specifically, we identified that we wanted to do some special work with the materials, with the shaders for those characters.
Shaders are the code that runs on the GPU that takes in all sorts of inputs like textures and lighting and position and outputs what the object's surface is supposed to look like.
We wanted a shader that was capable of adding this sludge layer, this hatred layer over top of it and making it dynamic and animating so that it really looks like it was constantly undulating or writhing.
So once we had this shader function, we were able to apply that in all these different contexts, like the monsters, like the environment, the character armors even.
Most of the shader work was done by Alex, who really took that shader function and made it work in all sorts of different contexts.
And we also have the hatred add-ons to these characters, these tentacles, these writhing hatred growths all over them, which was a procedurally generated process that was largely run by Skye on our team.
The Hollow's boss was kind of born of this idea of what does a pinnacle hollows really look like.
We have the hollows family, and that was pretty well defined by the time that the hollows boss kind of came up for concepting.
Our artist, Victor, had a lot of cool ideas for horror themes and really wanted to push visuals with contortions and like breaking the neck of this monster all over the place.
That's where we had the option to go, like, and we'd push it and really get that idea of what hatred and the hollows are all about.
This inky black ichor that latched on to a once powerful spellcaster.
It was such a great source of power that this particular hollows monster turned into the priestess of hatred.
I'm Victor Lee, a principal concept artist on the Diablo team, and I concepted the Priestess of Hatred.
Victor Lee is one of the OGs from Diablo, and he's known for creating a lot of dark imagery.
And every time we want to have a monster or boss, he's done all the greats, even Diablo himself.
One of his monitors on the side of his desk is just like a dark black eye staring at him.
And so when we needed something that's pure darkness, like, we had to tap Vic.
I feel like when we're talking about hatred, I kind of imagine, visualize it as like a black, webby-like thing.
So I thought a spider configuration would work for this.
So I did a few variations, some with souls, human souls trapped in their abdomen.
It's like a purgatory because this creature consumes humans.
I had this nagging feeling for a long time that why I felt it's not working, no matter how interesting the design is,
I'm not pushing the boundaries.
So I basically rethought the whole thing.
A lot of our creatures are just like raw aggression.
It's just muscly and just brutal.
Maybe this one is more insidious.
What if the human figure is not controlling the hatred, but it's the other way around?
Like the hatred is actually mocking humanity.
It's like dragging a puppet around.
So what I did is I kept the human figure as a focal point, but the rest of the creature is this moving mass of basically a ball of hatred.
It broke a lot of rules, but I felt, I just felt like this just fits.
So I went ahead with it and rendered it out.
I was looking at the concept for the first time with the designer on the feature, Charles,
and we were kind of in this stunned silence for a little bit because it was this reaction of,
this thing is so cool.
And then we started thinking, how are we even going to make this thing move?
Typically, our monsters are bipedal or they're quadrupeds.
How's it going to move?
We can't rely on walk cycles anymore.
How's it going to rotate?
We can't rely on, you know, the built-in rotation stuff without looking weird as hell.
It was clear that in order to make this like animate and look natural,
we were going to have to pretty much dive into uncharted territory.
We wanted it to move in a very unique way.
We wanted it to somersault through the air and be super unpredictable and zippy
and just have like ridiculous animations as those tentacles are flying all over the place.
We have that narrative and kind of drive to make it formless.
And with our conventional rigging that we can do that.
We were doing prototyping before the feature even kicked off.
Like we were already meeting with animation and tech art to say,
hey, we have this thing.
We think it's really cool, but we need help figuring this out.
So we had a lot of early collaboration, which was really what set us up for success.
When the animator came back with it, going from post to post rather than your normal animations,
I was like, yes, that's it.
That's what hatred should feel like.
When you first find the Priestess of Patriot, it's going to look like a lifeless human corpse.
And you're like, this doesn't look like a boss fight.
I'm in a boss arena.
What's going on?
But as you approach, you see that the body gets pulled into a giant pool of Patriot.
And then out of that pool of Patriot comes this giant mass of tentacles.
And that is the boss.
So after animation, it gets to come to me.
And I get to do all of the really cool visual effects at the end.
Show what those tentacles are doing when they impact the ground.
When they slap something.
When they hit the player.
It really brings the entire thing together.
The vomit attack is really gross.
Because there's like this part of the torso of the humanoid that has been kind of hollowed out and now has teeth.
The tentacles come out from the mass and they grab the humanoid and kind of pull the body back.
So that the slit in the belly opens up and all of the hatred just pours out a straight beam.
It's pretty gross.
The Hollows are just such a unique family.
From the moment they spawn in on your screen, you can tell that they are different.
They have just such unique behaviors and animations.
We were able to execute on a vision that's really just so different than what we typically do.
The whole process made me feel very proud of our whole team.
Everyone just got it.
They understood what the monster was.
They got the vision.
And it just worked.
The eye on the screen has many functions.
It keeps me in the right frame of mind.
What we are doing is dark.
It should be horrifying.
I should feel the fear while I'm doing it.
It's a reminder of that.
The eye also serves as a warning.
Like, get moving.
Don't dwell too long and wander around, you know.
Get this thing moving.
Get the work done.
Hello, Diablo community.
Welcome to another Diablo 4 Campfire chat.
We ended with a creepy eyeball.
We were just talking about it.
out. This one is our
Patch 2.1 PTR
Campfire Chat. I know we were
just here last week when we were talking about the midseason
update, but this one is kind of like the big
one because we're going to be talking about everything coming
at Patch 2.1 and Season 7.
I am joined here by Mr. Colin
Feiner, Mr. Charles Dunn,
who have appeared on prior Campfire
Chats. We were going to have Adam Jackson.
He is unfortunately not
feeling very well, so we hope he gets better
soon. And we do also have
another guest here who is
live from Albany, Blizzard Albany, and that
is Mr. Dan Tanguay, who's
going to be talking a little bit
as well about what's coming up
for Patch 2.1.
He's showing off his red
Diablo 4 jacket. We have our new
black Diablo 4 jackets as well.
Look at this. Models.
How are you, Dan? Hopefully you're good.
And he's not sure if he
can hear me.
But either way.
Either way.
A few things that we do want to
talk about before we actually do
jump into everything.
Obviously, PTR is coming up soon.
We are doing this stream a little
early this time, mainly
because the Thanksgiving
holiday is coming up here in the U.S.
And so we are going to be talking
about some of the contents before
even the patch notes are ready.
We do plan on having a blog
immediately after this stream,
so players can actually check out the blog
and read a little bit more about what we
talked about today.
But the patch notes will be available
next Wednesday for players
to actually check out.
So it will be before the U.S.
holiday here, so everyone can
kind of dive deep into the patch notes
for PTR.
PTR is currently planned to start
on December 3rd.
So that will be after the U.S.
holidays here for Thanksgiving.
So there's a ton of stuff that
is coming up for players
to kind of jump into.
But I know what we want to do
is really just dive straight deep
into all the new stuff
that we do want to talk about.
So for the first thing
we do want to chat about
is just Season 7
and what that's going to be.
So we're actually going to jump over
to Mr. Dan Tanguay
in Albany
to kind of walk us through.
So Dan, do you want to
take over?
Oh no.
Dan can't currently hear.
All right.
So I don't know what happened.
I mean, you know,
maybe we don't have
satellites working
or something like that.
So instead,
I guess we'll just start
with classes first.
Sure.
So Mr. Charles Dunn,
do you want to talk about
class changes that are coming
with Season 7?
I know we talked a little bit
about this last week
with Adam Jackson.
Just a reminder,
Spirit Born,
expect that to be
addressed for Season 7
and we will actually be
talking a little bit
about that now.
So Charles,
take us through it.
Yeah, absolutely.
I'd love to talk about
some of the changes
coming to all the
different classes
in Diablo 4
as well as some broader,
more systemic updates
that are happening
that kind of affect
all classes equally
in a way.
Yeah, so like I said,
just going through
individual class by class
and seeing some of the
new stuff that's coming
for a lot of the
classes.
Let's start with
the Barbarian,
I believe,
the first one up.
Yeah, so Barbarian
is definitely a class
that we think
a lot of the classes
have been performing
pretty well across the board.
They're always a step
under the Spirit Born,
but Barbarian
maybe a step and a half
below and so we're
looking at a lot of buffs
across the board
for them here,
specifically looking at
some stuff with
Hammer of the Ancients,
buffing that number up here.
A little bit of a rework
to the Walking Arsenal
passive.
Previously,
it was,
the bonus was just 8%.
Now we're going to be
giving you a bigger bonus
and when you have
all of them active,
you're going to get
more attack speed
and some bonus
crowd control duration
which we think
really plays into
that kind of build.
Additionally,
we're also updating
Earthquakes
that has been
one of my favorite
builds on Barbarian,
right?
Just seeing those
big earthquakes
come out everywhere.
Leafquake is the best.
Leafquake,
I absolutely love it.
The visuals on that
is just top notch.
So we're really,
we took some lessons
from what we did
on Rogues in the past
with their
stun grenades power
where a lot of the
legendaries that talked
to stun grenades
also had kind of
this extra bit
where it increased
the damage of all
of your stun grenades
so that you kind of
got these synergistic
builds with the
various aspects
all together
and we're extending
that over to
Earthquakes now here.
So we're adding on
basically,
hey,
all these ones that
talk to Earthquakes
just,
they increase the
damage of all of them
overall.
Yeah,
it's a little bit
less finicky too,
right?
Because now it lasts
after the Earthquake
expires or if you
leave it.
Absolutely.
So we think this
would just be a much
more comprehensive
build overall.
We've also got
a new legendary
that talks directly
to Earthquakes as
well,
ups their damage
and increases
their fire,
turns it into
fire damage.
And I think this
is really cool
and we're going to
see some more
stuff as you actually
get onto the PTR
but I think
Earthquakes and
Hammer of the
Ancients might be
a build that
you're going to be
very interested in
combining those two
with some of the
stuff that you
will see
come PTR.
Alright,
let's move on to
the Sorceress.
Sorceress,
one of the key
notes that we've
noticed with
Sorceress over
the whole lifespan
of Diablo 4
is that
players often felt
like they were
pigeonholed into
burning builds
in particular.
Firebolt enchantment
is probably
the most used
enchantment by far
enemies.
Because it was just
kind of a free
way to apply a
very small amount
of burning to
enemies.
But that was what
you needed to turn
on a lot of the
passives in their
skill tree.
And that was a
powerful build,
powerful interactions
but we felt like
that was making
everything a little
too homogenous.
You felt like you
had to do this
in order to access
a lot of these
passives.
And so we decided
that we really want
these burning
synergies to really
be benefiting builds
that are dedicated
to burning type
builds.
And not just ones
who are splashing
it in with
Firebolt enchantment.
And so with that
in mind we did a
rework on the
enchantment to
increase the
or remove the
burning damage
from the enchantment
and change it
over to this
which has a
healing component
to it.
And then we also
updated a lot of
those burning
passives to really
play better in the
dedicated fire based
builds rather than
being something that
you just want to
splash into everything.
Yeah, hopefully
there's a lot more
build variety.
Absolutely.
Yeah, that is one
of the main
driving goals
of a lot of our
updates is increasing
that build variety
so you don't feel
like you have to
take this checklist
of mandatory things
before moving on
to what you actually
want for your build.
So an example here
on Devouring Blaze
you've got a bonus
previously it was
bonus critical strike
damage against burning
enemies no matter
how much they're
burning for.
So you just apply
that little bit of
burning and you
would get this.
Now instead you get
a bigger bonus but
it's just for your
pyromancy critical
strike skills.
So it really encourages
hey you're a fireball
build, you're a meteor
build, something that
wants to do those
big fire crits.
Devouring Blaze is now
even more valuable
for those builds
and it's not something
that you necessarily
need to or feel
compelled to splash
in other builds.
Alright, on to the
next one.
We also did some
updates for Ball
Lightning.
So Ball Lightning
the previous upgrades
like kind of these
mages Ball Lightning
and wizards Ball
Lightning were about
stunning enemies
or spawning some
crackling energy
with admittedly
some kind of
complex conditions
you had to jump
through a lot of
hoops to get these.
One of the things
we really like to do
with a lot of these
updates is simplify
them down and
streamline and really
focus in on what
the interesting
factor is.
Yeah, it makes it
a little bit more
modular too, right?
So there's more
builds the less
sort of focus that
initial step is on
that skill.
Absolutely.
So we've got the
Mage's Ball Lightning
here that now is
just increasing its
damage against stun
enemies.
It's really that
payoff for a lot of
the lightning stun
effects and then
Wizards Ball Lightning
is just always going
to be generating
more crack energy,
just more consistent
generation there.
All right, on to
the next one.
We've got some
of the new uniques
that we want to
show off here on
the sort, talking
about Ball Lightning.
So this is actually
something interesting
we're doing this
season where we're
making two uniques
that are in the
same slot and
they're going to
modify the skill in
a different way.
So they will be
mutually exclusive.
So you can take
either this one here
which turns Ball
Lightning into a
kind of like a
bowling ball, really.
You send it forward,
it goes pretty fast,
and when it hits a
target it's going to
explode and kind of
splash outward.
And I think this is
really cool.
It offers a switched
up play style to the
way you're familiar
with Ball Lightning
which is kind of
slow moving forward
or if you pick the
other unique, you can
actually retain the
old gravitational aspect.
So we can go on
and take a look at
that one here in
the next clip.
Right, so a lot of
the Ball Lightning
builds in the past
were using the
gravitational aspect
that caused it to
rotate around you
and we've updated
that and kind of
reworked the
gravitational aspect
so that now that
functionality is built
into this new
unique and also has
some additional
bonuses to encourage
this kind of play
style.
and obviously the
gravitational aspect
that used to do
this has been
reworked into a new
cool effect that
you'll be able to
demo out on the
PTR as well.
This is like a fun
trade-off now on sort
of how you want to
use Ball Lightning.
Yeah, it really helps
it be a bit more
build defining which
is our goal for a lot
of the uniques is
hey, you get this
unique and it feels
like it's very
foundational to your
build.
One thing I do want
to call out here is
the inherent affix on
this right up near the
top that Ball Lightning
can be cast while
moving.
This makes it a lot
smoother to just be
moving around and
just keep on clicking
that Ball Lightning
and you're not going
to have to stop like
that very short
half-second stop to
cast it.
It just feels much
smoother and this is
one that you really
this build just wants
to be on the move
and that encourages
that.
All right, so let's
talk about the Druid
next.
So this one, Druid
is this season a lot
of Werewolf updates.
You know, Season of
the Werewolf.
I absolutely love
Werewolf builds and
I think they've been,
you know, maybe a
little bit behind the
rest of builds over
the course of Diablo's
history and so this
season a lot of our
updates are really
focused on building,
making that build come
up to par.
Yeah, like pure
Werewolf, right?
Pure Werewolf.
Not mixing it with
other things.
Yeah, a lot of times
you saw some like rapid
shape-shifting builds
and those are fun,
those are great, but
you know, pure Werewolf
was really, wasn't quite
hitting the mark and so
that's what a lot of
our focus is.
Let's take a look at
some of these updates.
So we've got updates to
Shred, you know, the
main core skill for
these Werewolf builds.
Previously, the Raging
Shred upgrade was just
a combo attack that
applied some poisoning
damage.
So now it's going to
still do that and apply
a lot more poisoning
damage, but it's also
going to cause them to
take even more poisoning
damage for the next
five seconds.
So this is, you know,
your kind of finishing
move on your combo or
your core combo, but
then it also enhances all
of the other poisoning
damage that you've applied
through something like
rapies.
All right.
We've got updates to
Boulder.
Now this isn't necessarily
with the Werewolf theme,
but still Boulder is a
skill that we saw a good
opportunity to improve on
it.
We had two upgrades on
Boulder in the past,
the kind of the two
choices, and they were
both fairly similar.
They both dealt with
critical strike chance or
critical strike damage,
and we thought that was
an opportunity to rework one
of them to give it a
different identity.
And basically the
identity was Poison
Boulder, like just a
giant ball of poison.
What does that look like
or what does that do?
Changing the damage type
always helps sort of
branch out and make it
feel really different.
Yeah.
And we have some really
sweet visuals for it
too.
I'm not sure if we have a
video on that.
I think we'll just have to
rely on that in the PTR.
Yeah.
People will see it on the
PTR, but yeah, it's got
some cool visuals
associated with it.
Yeah.
And so that one will be
very cool.
Definitely check that one
out.
This one I'm very excited
about because Blood
Howl, as we see, has
always just generated
spirit, but now...
Yeah.
It was always just
generated some spirit,
but you still do that,
but now it gives you even
more increased damage
until you shapeshift out
of werewolf form.
So going back to what
Colin had mentioned
about really focusing in
on pure werewolf.
That was an area that
we felt, hey, we want
to really reward you
for staying in the
werewolf form and really
committing to that
identity and just making
sure that felt like an
appropriate payoff, and
this is one of the areas
that we're doing that in.
All right.
So let's talk a little
bit about one of the
updated legendaries.
So the aspect of the
Blurred Beast.
So this previously was a
legendary that just
caused your shred to do
some bonus damage to
poison enemies.
It was fine, but it
wasn't too enticing.
But now with the new
update here, you actually
still do more damage
just all the time.
And depending on how
far you're traveling for
shred, you're going to
do some bonus hits.
And it looks so cool.
Your werewolf is dashing
across the screen and
then just doing this
multi-hit kind of attack.
And so if you're really
close, you're just going
to get maybe one
additional strike.
But if you're at this
further distance, as you
see in this clip, you're
going to get the full
four hits.
So it's really about
positional gameplay a bit
more than it was in the
past.
And you get very heavily
rewarded for it when you
do kind of execute that
properly.
That's awesome.
And it's going to be
really great for like
movement, just moving
around across the map,
which I know movement is
always a big thing that
players really, really
want.
People have always been
asking for.
So it'll be cool to see
people just kind of like
just bouncing around as a
druid with the aspect of
the Blurred Beast.
So very cool.
Yeah.
It's always great where
we can inject like changing
how you play also, right?
Because you can imagine
like launching into a
group of enemies, then
picking out specific
targets that you really
want to launch to.
And that's how you
optimize that build
combat wise.
Absolutely.
This is one of my
favorite ones in this
patch, actually.
Big fan of a lot of
these druid updates.
Aspect of Wolf's
Reign.
So this is a combo kind
of legendary combining
the powers of Hurricane
and your wolf
companions.
So when you cast
Hurricane, all of your
wolves actually spawn a
little mini Hurricane of
their own.
And these will do bonus
damage for each of your
Act of the Wolves.
So it really encourages
these companion based
builds that already have
this wolf pack of, you
know, five wolves
following them around.
Now your Hurricane
affects all of them.
And, you know, they get
bonus damage for how
many you got.
So you really want to be
stacking up as many
wolves as you can.
They all get Hurricanes
and you just get to
shred through the whole
screen with that.
That's super cool.
All right.
Moving on to Rogue.
So this is one that
Shadow Clone has been
probably the Rogue skill
that I would say
maybe wasn't quite
hitting the mark
compared to most
other skills.
And that was for a
variety of reasons.
And not to get too
technical here on the
details, but for a lot
of the effects that
you have with your
legendaries and your
passives and those
kind of things,
historically Shadow Clone
behaved inconsistently
with those.
It wouldn't necessarily
pick up all of the
bonuses.
It wouldn't trigger all
of the effects.
And the end result was
basically that your
Shadow Clone dealt a
whole lot less damage
than you did.
You thought, hey, I'm
hitting for, you know,
millions and my Shadow
Clone's hitting for,
like, thousands.
Right?
Yeah.
And so we really
looked at that
comprehensively and
thought, okay, we need
to kind of rethink how
Shadow Clone works
across the board to
really bring it up to
par to make it behave
the way you expect.
And then also extend
that to a lot of the
other summons in the
game.
The summons like your
Necromancer skeletons,
your Druid companions,
and so on.
So we did basically a
rework of that entire
system.
And the long and short
of it is that they
should just work a
whole lot better going
forward in this season
where they're going to
trigger all of your
lucky hit effects.
They're going to
interact with all of
your damage modifiers
and multipliers that
they previously were
inconsistently working
with.
So just one example
here, a very simple
example.
You've got Wind
Strikers aspect.
This is a very simple
legendary that just
says, hey, when you
critically strike,
gain some movement
speed.
Now, in the past,
that was only when you,
your player character,
critically striked
with one of your
skills.
And it would not
happen whenever one
of your Druid companions
or your Shadow Clone
critically strikes.
But now, all of that
will work.
So your companions or
your summons or your
Shadow Clone critically
strikes and you have
Wind Strikers, now your
character gets that
bonus.
It's huge.
Yeah, I really can't
overstate this, like how
many new interactions and
synergies this unlocks
with not just Shadow
Clone but all of the
summons in general
across the game.
But with Shadow Clone in
particular, we've got a
new unique item and this
one is Assassin's Stride.
And the effect here works
with mobility skills and
your Shadow Imbuement.
Once again, kind of playing
up that combo aspect.
So all of your mobility
skills are going to always
be Shadow Imbued with some
bonus potency.
So they're going to do some
more damage.
damage.
And whenever you damage an
elite or boss with a
mobility skill, there's a
chance to trigger an instant
free Shadow Imbuement
Explosion.
So those of you who like
playing Shadow Step builds,
one of my favorite ones with
Rogue, you know, just like
Adam had said before about
jumping around the screen
with werewolves, you can do
that with Shadow Step now
too.
And you're just going to be
getting a lot of those
resets and kills much
quicker as you leap out of
the shadows, trigger a Shadow
Imbuement Explosion, and then
move on to the next pack.
of enemies.
Really cool, unique for
that kind of build.
Additionally, Caltrops may be
the skill that was the most
kind of clunky on control
wise to use.
Thank you.
God, seriously.
If you've ever tried to use
Caltrops, it can be a
struggle sometimes where your
character would leap backwards
and you wouldn't go in the
right direction, wouldn't hit
the enemies.
We've updated the animation
here to just basically be a
lot, very similar to the
Smoke Grenade skill where you
just pick a point on the
screen, your character throws
it, and it just goes where
you point it.
I am the king of like
Caltropping one minion out of
like a hundred and then also
falling, like jumping back
into like a giant mob and
going like, well, I didn't
calculate that correctly.
So this, that update, I've, we
were talking about this
beforehand, like before we even
went live and I was like,
thank, thank the effing God.
I was like, oh my God, please.
So yeah, it's, I'm excited for
that.
Caltrop should be so much more
usable now and we think that
this is a really good change
going forward.
Yeah.
All right, on to the Necromancer.
So Necromancer, we've done some
improved itemization and updates
to the overpower synergies,
specifically the Rathma's Vigor
key passive.
So previously it would just give
you some, an overpower once
every 12 seconds and, or when
you overhealed for some bonus
life and now we're just tacking
on a big chunk of overpower
damage to it.
We definitely felt like these,
these pure blood based overpower
builds were just not quite
hitting that mark and, you know,
just pumping the power into
these pure builds through the
Rathma's Vigor key passive,
we think is going to be very
helpful to make these builds
really shine.
On to the next, we've got the,
one of the new uniques.
So similar to what we did with
the Sorcerer where we had kind
of these paired uniques, we're
going to have two uniques in the
same slot for Necromancer as well,
this time in the pants slot.
And they're both going to be
working with Bloodwave.
So this one, Kissimmee's Legacy,
will cause, instead of shooting
one Bloodwave out forward, you're
going to get two that kind of
converge on you.
And this definitely changes up
the targeting of it, the
positioning requirements, and
really the use case because it's
pulling towards you instead of
pushing away.
So instead of being a defensive
skill, it's much more about the
damage and pulling them together.
And then when they hit, they do a
big chunk of damage as well.
So definitely turns Bloodwave
into a much more damage focused
skill and a little bit less on
the CC or the knockback,
crowd control of it.
Yeah, and it plays super well
with that key passive.
Absolutely.
Especially if you want to be
using this for that big damage
moment.
Now the alternative is Indria's
Memory, where it still shoots
the Bloodwave forward, and then
at the end of its path, it will
trap the targets in a bone prison.
So this is a unique that is very
much about combining blood and
bone.
So a little bit less of the pure
blood and much more about
combining the two.
Now additionally, you see we're
using some bone spears here, or
should I say blood spears, because
that is what they now become.
Fancy.
Blood spears, and instead of
costing a bunch of essence, they're
going to cost, or sorry, they
drain maximum life, still cost
essence there, but they drain
maximum life to cast additionally
from a nearby corpse to fire an
extra bone spear slash blood
spear.
So there's a lot going on with
this one, but I think it really
comes together to be a very
strong build when you're using
the bone spear and the blood
wave, and then casting bone
spear reduces blood waves.
Cooldown, that's the inherent
affix on these legs, really makes
a really cool build that I think
synergizes very nicely.
Yeah, it's awesome.
All right, and so on to the
spirit born.
So we kind of warned at the start,
you know, spirit born we recognize
has been one or multiple steps
above most other classes, and
players have fun.
People love playing the spirit
born, very powerful, and we
really like that, but we do have
to recognize, you know, for the
long-term health of the game, it's
important that we have a bit
better class parity across the
board, so you don't feel like
you're doing it wrong if you're not
playing a spirit born.
Yeah, and we have like a lot of
the classes outside of the spirit
born are actually in a really good
spot.
They're pushing pit tier 100 plus,
which is great, and again, we're
not looking to really buff every
class up to clearing pit 150
easily, right?
We don't want to create that arms
race where we just have to
continuously sort of ask you, the
player, to chew through, you know,
20 different torment tiers because
we're just arms racing that power
so much.
Yeah, we do think that kind of our
target there is closer to where the
other five classes are, and spirit
born was just, you know, too high
up.
And it's rather than try to power
creep the whole game, we'd like to
make sure we make some small
improvements everywhere else to the
underperforming builds and those
ones that don't have enough love,
and then get spirit born back down
to a more healthy spot.
And so with that in mind, one of the
biggest offenders, or biggest power
points, rather, on the spirit born
was the Rod of Kapoleki here.
This one is the one that converts
your core skills into basic skills,
and does, it used to do reduced
damage based on vigor cost, and
admittedly, the calculations there
were kind of complex, and so we've
simplified it down a little bit
where they will just gain the bonus
critical strike damage.
It will be substantially less.
Previously it was 1 to 3%, now it'll
be down to 0.1 to 0.5 per point
of vigor there.
We think this will bring it to a much
healthier spot, but still kind of
retain the core fantasy and the core
build implications of this item.
It just won't be pushing quite the
same trillions of damage that we were
seeing before.
We also fixed some of the issues
called out here at the above, like
Viscous Shield and things like that,
scaling in unintended ways that were
just way outside of our expectations.
Yeah, definitely some unintended, kind of
bugged interactions that were maybe
double dipping or scaling too high.
We've taken a pass to make those more
in line with our expectations.
All right.
Additionally, we've got new aspects.
Of course, being a class NBL before,
you're going to be getting new content
every season.
So we've got a new legendary aspect
here, the aspect of endless talents
that causes your razor wings to
increase all of your eagle skill damage,
and razor wing critical strikes will
grant even more stacks.
So you can really stack that up.
You know, it stacks up to 50%.
That's a whole lot.
So you really want to be spamming out
these razor wings and getting those
crits to stack this up as fast as
possible.
Yeah, and this goes back to like just
the prior slide where we talked about
how razor wings and centipede builds
are getting some extra love in this
specific season, which were more so
underutilized in season six.
So with season seven players,
we'll see these new legendary aspects,
of course, and then and how they
actually tie back in with some of the
changes that we're doing for those
builds.
Absolutely.
All right.
We've got some updates to some of the
underused uniques as well.
Ring of Writhing Moon here.
This one would trigger Pestilence
Swarm every 10 seconds.
We felt like that was a little too long
given the pace of combat in our game
and especially compared to some of the
other options at the unique slot,
ring slot.
So we've reduced that down to every four
seconds.
You'll spawn a Pestilence Swarm and the
Vigor generated goes up from one up to
three.
So a lot more resource generation because
your rings are often resource generated
ones.
So we want to make sure this is a
compelling option compared to your other
choices at the ring slot.
All right.
So let's talk a little bit about some of
the broader updates that affects all
classes.
So the one I'm excited about here is the
ultimate updates.
So in the previous season we introduced
skill ranks on ultimates, right?
So you can now rank up your ultimate up
to rank five and that was good.
Gave you some cooldown reduction, some
damage.
But now when you actually fully invest in
it up to that rank five, every ultimate
in the game is going to get a new rank
five bonus.
So for example here on Lacerate, we've got
at rank five Lacerate's damage is going
to be increased by 40% of your critical
strike damage bonus.
It gives it this scaling factor.
So you can see on the left Lacerate at
rank one is doing about 38,000 damage, but
you rank it up to five and it goes crazy
high up to 119,000 damage because it's
now getting that critical strike damage
scalar.
And so if you really want to build a
dedicated Lacerate build as kind of your
core damaging effect, this is going to be
a great way to build around it and a good
reward for investing all those extra skill
points into it.
Definitely.
I love to see us add more things that
incentivize you to actually put some points
into skills.
Yeah.
So often, you know, sometimes you'd see
if you just wanted the access to the
utility of the ultimate, hey, it's fine
to put in one point, right?
You get one point, you get the utility,
maybe you get some buff from it.
But if you really want to invest in it,
we want to make sure that that investment
in those skill ranks feels meaningful.
And we think these rank five bonuses on
ultimates in particular is going to be a
really good way to pay off those ultimate
builds.
Definitely.
All right.
We've also got some new generic legendary
aspects to really support this style that
talk directly to ultimate skills.
So we've got the vehement brawlers aspect
that causes casting an ultimate skill
increases all of your damage output by 10 to 30%
for eight seconds.
And you also gain additional skill ranks
in your ultimate.
So, hey, we just talked about skill rank bonuses.
Now we've got, you know, a legendary that will
give you some bonus skill ranks.
Nice.
We've also got the Ring of Apoject Fervor,
which says casting your ultimate skill will
increase your damage by 8 to 18%, so a little
bit less than the vehement brawlers.
But it stacks up to 10 times.
So you can get way more if you can cast your
ultimate fast enough and kind of chain it
together.
So this will be really good for, like,
rogues that use preparation to really get
that ultimate cooldown reduction or any build
that really wants to focus around casting
your alt many times in a row.
This one is going to be a great legendary
for those style of builds.
All right.
We've also done some updates to the Rune Words.
And so Rune Words, Vessel of Hatred feature,
you know, has been really well received.
We think that they've really, you know,
spiced up some build variety.
And we're going to add some new runes here
and update some of the old ones.
So all of the invocation runes have overflow.
So the cost of many of them have also been
adjusted to allow you to proc this overflow effect
when you generate more offering than needed
much more often.
And then also the ritual runes,
the ones that, you know, generate the offering,
some of them have been redesigned to have
some larger potential moments of this overflow.
So an example here on the Seer Rune,
this generates a ton of offering,
300 offering at once.
And you get that by casting five skills.
But then instead of just casting five skills
and then generate all of it
and then casting five again instantly,
we've added in this exhausted period for three seconds.
So you can get that 300 offering at once,
but then you've got to wait three seconds
before you start building up those stacks again.
Yeah.
It's like getting, like, large buckets
every, like, couple seconds and stuff of offering now.
Yeah.
This is a good tuning knob to kind of make sure that,
hey, we can give you the strong moment of power,
but then it is followed by a little bit of a weaker moment
where you can't generate that.
Rather than every Rune always just being a steady amount,
we like to have those peaks and valleys.
I really think that leads to more interesting moments
of the gameplay.
Yeah.
It's about potency versus frequency.
Right.
So you get really strong effects,
but you can't do it as often.
Right.
And that'll play right into the updates
with a lot of the overflow
to make sure that when you do overflow,
it feels really good
and feels really rewarding to get that.
So let's talk about some of the other Runes.
We've got some new Runes to show off.
Yeah.
So we've got three new Rune words here.
The Nagu Rune,
a legendary Rune that will gain 100 offering
as long as you're maintaining a summon.
And so as I kind of alluded to earlier
with the Shadow Clone section,
summon is our new catch-all term
for anything that you summon.
You know, it's pretty self-explanatory,
but that includes things like Necromancer minions,
Druid companions,
Sorcerer Conjurations,
Rogue Shadow Clones,
and even Barbarian Ancients
from some of your effects.
Call of the Ancients
and some of the Legendaries that summon those.
Those are all summons.
Igni Rune will generate 25 offering,
but it stores up offering every 0.3 seconds.
So you're actually doing about 75 offering per second,
roughly.
And you actually cash it in
by casting a non-basic skill
to get that offering.
So as long as you're out there
kind of spamming your basic skill,
you're going to be kind of banking up this offering.
And then when you cast that non-basic,
you cash it all in,
you probably trigger the Rune it's connected to,
you get a big overflow,
you get a big moment of power there.
And finally,
we've got the Chalk Rune
that generates,
or requires 20 offering rather,
and this will invoke Druid's Lightning Bolt.
That's one of those,
it's not the core skill,
but Lightning Bolt is kind of that
other power in the Druid's kit,
similar to like Earthquake or Stun Rage.
Yeah.
So enable those kind of builds
to really tap into that effect.
Awesome.
Lots of Rune updates.
Yeah.
Lots of changes coming to classes.
You know,
there's more changes in the notes
that we'll have
that we'll be hitting next week.
So players can look into those.
These are just a few examples
that we have for PTR.
And of course,
really need feedback
on a lot of these changes.
I know there's some people going in chat
going like,
hey,
I'm noticing like,
you know,
maybe you're giving a lot of offering
and then there's a little bit
of a cool down period
or something like that.
Let us know.
Like we want people to try those out.
Yeah.
Like test it out
so that we have the feedback
so that before we go live
with patch 2.1,
we can end up
making any feedback changes
based off of community feedback.
So lots of cool stuff.
Thank you so much
for walking us through
all the different class changes
and everything like that, Charles.
Do we have Dan
available from Albany?
We do have Dan.
I can hear you now.
Oh, there we go.
I was like,
Dan was just like staring blankly
at the camera
and I was like,
yes, I was.
But Dan is actually
going to be talking about
all the new content
that's coming in patch 2.1
with season seven.
So Dan,
do you want to take it away
and talk to us
a little bit about it?
Absolutely.
A couple of technical difficulties
could not keep me
from sharing this
with everybody.
So this PTR
for patch 2.1
is a PTR
of a couple firsts
at this point.
This is going to be
the first time
that we're bringing
the seasonal realm
to a PTR.
So what does this mean?
We've got a lot
of seasonal content
coming up in season seven
and we want to be able
to get all of your feedback
on this content.
It's pretty important
for us to,
you know,
like Adam was saying,
really have those
iteration cycles
where y'all are able
to test and,
you know,
show what's working
and what isn't.
This is also
going to be
the first time
since season two
that we're bringing back
seasonal character powers.
So if you remember
in season two,
season of blood,
they were vampire powers
and you slotted them
into your sanguine circle.
And so for season seven,
it could be a little bit different.
Not vampires this time.
This time it's going
to be witchcraft.
And so I'm excited
to really dig into that
right now
and tease out
what y'all can play
in a couple weeks.
So witchcraft
enables you
as a practitioner
to call upon
the power of the swamp
to do your bidding.
And so you've met
some witches before
in the game
and you're going to meet
some more
in the coming season.
But before I really
dive into witchcraft,
we got to talk
about your enemies.
Now your enemies
of this season
are going to be called
the head rotten.
Now the head rotten
are abominations
that spawned
from the tree of whispers.
And you're going
to slay them
and collect
what we call
restless rot.
And this is going
to be our currency
for the season.
Now, like I said,
you know,
the season is about witchcraft.
So there are going
to be some witches.
And those witches
are going to be
residing around
the tree of whispers.
And they're going
to have some altars.
And these altars
are pretty important
to you learning
your witchcraft.
And so you're going
to travel to an altar.
You're going to make
an offering
of restless rot.
And that's going
to enable you
to learn the witchcraft.
Now,
equipping witchcraft
is going to be
pretty simple.
You know,
we wanted to
take what was best
from a lot
of these styles
of menus
that we've done
in the past
and distill it
into something
that's very convenient
and easy to use.
And the result
is this witchcraft menu
that you can see
in front of you.
And so equipping
is going to be
super simple.
You've got an inventory
on the bottom
and then you're going
to drag or otherwise
move that power
to one of the slots
up top.
And you're going
to have five normal slots,
five normal powers
you can equip
at any point
and one unique power
for, you know,
really special witchcraft
that you can find.
The other thing
is that you can upgrade
your witchcraft
directly in that inventory.
using Restless Rot.
So again,
we're streamlining
the process
to, you know,
make it easy
for players
to equip
and upgrade
their witchcraft.
Now,
obviously,
it wouldn't be a season
without some rewards.
And so let's talk
about those a little bit.
This season,
we're going to have
another reputation
style gameplay
in the form
of Coven's Favor.
Now,
killing Head Rot
will get you
Headless Rot
or killing
Head Rot
and will get you
Restless Rot.
But in order
to advance
the Coven's Favor,
you actually need
to complete Whispers.
And completing
those Whispers
will increase
your rank
and allow you
to unlock rewards,
including items
and materials
and things like that.
In addition,
new to this season,
you're going
to also unlock
at certain ranks
new witchcraft.
And then you will
have new things
you can learn
from those altars.
and then,
because everyone
loves it,
we're bringing
back the Resplendent
Spark as well.
So that's going
to be at the end
of your
Coven's Favor rank.
And of course,
the Resplendent
Spark nowadays
can be used
from crafting,
you know,
a random mythic
unique to actually
targeting uniques
using a lot
of those runes
that you can earn
in the game.
All right.
One last little thing
with respect
to witchcraft.
So we wanted
to try out
something a little
bit different.
And so we've
also created
several powers
that are lost
to these witches,
the Coven of the Swamp.
And so those
you can only find
by traveling
out in the world
and discovering
forgotten altars.
And these forgotten
altars will allow
you to learn
these lost powers.
And yeah,
we just thought
we'd try something
a little bit different
here.
And yeah,
let us know
what you think
about it.
Now,
let's talk about
some of the witchcraft
itself.
You know,
we've talked it up
a bit.
We're going to
release,
it's over 20 powers
for the season.
And we're going
to show you
four of those
right now.
So let's talk
about the first one.
This one's really
popular.
This is the Poison Frog.
So the Poison Frog,
as you imagine,
is a servant
that you can summon
that fights
alongside you.
as its name
implies,
it will poison
your enemies.
And, you know,
if it runs out of
health,
it's going to
explode viciously
with a lot of
poison damage.
Folks are having
a lot of fun
with this one.
Next up.
Next up is
Doom Orb.
Doom Orb is a pure
orb of eldritch energy
that circles around
you and damages
any enemy it touches.
And it can also
launch itself at
distant enemies
before returning.
Also another favorite
at this point.
Vengeful Servant.
So Vengeful Servant,
as the name implies,
is another servant
like the frog.
And this one
will absorb damage
and then rush enemies.
enemies.
And then last
but not least,
we've got one
of those lost
witchcraft powers
I was telling you
about.
And this is
Piranado.
So this one
procs when you
cast other powers.
And so if you
cast a hex
and an aura
at the same time
and inflict it
upon an enemy,
there's a chance
that you will
then proc
the Piranado.
and the Piranado
as you can see
sucks everything
into it
in a swirling
dervish
of fish
and destruction.
So yeah,
that's a peek
at some of the
witchcraft powers
you're going to be
able to play with soon.
But what good
are powers
if we aren't
offering you
some new activities
within the season
to participate in?
And so these
come in the form
of head hunts.
Now head hunts
are
a whisper
driven activity.
And so the tree
is searching
for these head rotten.
The tree wants you
to eliminate
these head rotten.
And so it's going
to help you
by highlighting
areas within the world
where it thinks
there's a lot of
head rotten
for you to kill.
So you're going
to follow the whispers
in order to
find the head hunts
and kill the head rotten.
Now these are
subzone takeovers
similar to hell tides.
They're going
to feature
a number
of all new whispers
mixed in
with some existing ones.
This was an opportunity
for our team
to try out
some new whispers
and really
kind of tell
a little bit
of a story
each time
you're going
out on a head hunt
because whispers
offer us
that opportunity.
Now completing whispers
has a chance
of spawning
a head rotten boss
and the head rotten bosses
are the things
you're really going
to be looking out for
because those
are going to give you
some additional rewards
I'm going to tell you about.
Delivering a head rotten
boss's head
to the tree of whispers
enables you
to earn
occult gems.
Let's talk about
Now we're pretty excited
about these.
Occult gems
are special
socketables
that have unique effects
that help you
fine tune your build.
So
they can only
be slotted
in the jewelry slot
and so this is a way
of basically
having them
coexist
with runes
and
they only
last for the season.
So when your items
transfer to the
eternal realm
at the end of the season
these are going to disappear.
But
in the meantime
I think you're going
to have a lot of fun
with them.
Let's dive into them
a little bit.
So
each occult gem
has built in defense.
We don't want you
to have to make a choice
between
you know
a royal diamond
mineral oil skull
and an occult gem.
So
all of these
occult gems
have defense
built into them
so that
you know
really you're getting
a bonus
above and beyond
you know
those gems
that I just described.
And so
here are some examples
of them.
First up
we've got
the elder sigil.
This
is going to boost
your damage
whenever you hex enemies.
So if you're leaning
into certain types
of hexes
you like using
elder sigil
may be a good fit
for you.
Killing wind
this is going to boost
your crit
and move
for folks
who really
dig
you know
specking out
with eldritch powers.
So if you
equip three or more
eldritch powers
then
slotting a killing wind
into say
one of your rings
might benefit you
quite a bit.
And then finally
we've got dust stone.
This is a legendary one
so it's going to be
even more powerful
than the other two
I talked about.
This is going to boost
when you use
hex and aura
and afflict other
enemies with those.
So each time
you do that
not only do you
have a chance
to proc that
piranado
I talked about
before
but you're going
to increase
the damage
that you output
per affliction.
So you can kind
of get a sense
that the occult gems
are providing you
even more incentives
for you know
creating a certain
type of build
and you know
we are just
really excited
to see what kind
of combinations
you all come up
with.
I think yeah
it's going to be
pretty exciting.
So final thing
is you know
we were doing a lot
with the tree of whispers
we've got the witches
around them
you know
so we thought
well we should
you know
take some of the
quality of life feedback
we've heard from players
and try and address it.
So the first thing
we've done
is we've updated
the town
around the tree
of whispers
we added some
more services
to it
because we expect
you to be returning
to it a lot more
this season
and we've
changed the layout
a little bit
to make it a little
more convenient
to navigate
and move the waypoint
so that it's just
quicker to get
to the tree of whispers
to turn in things.
But sometimes
you know
you're in the middle
of a headhunt
we found
and you're getting
a lot of grim favor
but you don't
want to leave
you want to try
and go fight
the boss
that you just
summoned right.
So we've also
implemented
what we call
the raven of the tree
and a raven of the tree
appears in every
headhunt zone
and that allows
you to turn in
your grim favor
on the spot
so that you don't
have to go back
to the tree town.
Now you're not
going to have access
to all those
other services
so you know
you hit your
inventory limit
you'll probably
want to go back
to town
but in the moment
when you're in a flow
you can go to
the raven of the tree
get your cash
and then keep fighting.
And then finally
we felt like
we wanted to expand
the rewards
a little bit more
for the tree of whispers
so we've added
ancestral caches
it's a pretty low
probability of getting
one but they're there
and these guarantee
you getting an
ancestral item
from a cache
so obviously
you see this pop up
I have a feeling
you're probably
going to select it
so yeah
I think that's
all I have
to talk about
for the upcoming
PTR
so I'll kick it
back over to you
Adam.
Awesome
thank you so much
Dan
talking about
a ton of new stuff
coming for
Patch 2.1
PTR
and of course
season 7
I'm super excited
for all the
tree of whisper
updates
I know
a lot of people
in chat are
especially with
the raven
not having to
go back
to the tree
of whispers
every single time
being able to
turn in grim favors
right there
through the raven
on top of that
also just the
rework of the zone
so everything's
a little bit closer
and I have to
walk all the way
across
to walk all the way
back to the way
point
or to get to
the vendors
and everything
so there's a lot
of big changes
with that
and please do
choose the ancestral
patch
why would you not
and I think
it's important
to remember
we added the
ability to
favorite way
points
as part of
season 6
or the last
patch that we
did
so it's super
helpful with
that witch tone
yeah most
definitely
and of course
people have
been seeing
some of the
new witchcraft
powers
and noticing
some familiarities
of past
Diablo lore
and I will say
we'll be talking
more about
the story
of season 7
as we get
closer to launch
so players
can hear more
about kind of
like the origins
of what we've
been kind of
talking about
here with this
story with
Diablo 4
so thank you
again Dan
for walking
us through
all the content
that's coming
with season 7
and of course
last but not
least we do
want to talk
about some
big quality
of life changes
one really
really big
one that we're
really excited
to talk about
and Mr. Colin
Feiner will talk
and walk us
through everything
thanks Adam
so most of
these are sort
of systemic
updates
so I'll talk
through them
Paragon migration
is more just a
reminder on how
the new Paragon
system works
all of the
Paragon experience
that you've earned
in a season
is actually at the
end of season 6
going to be added
to your Eternal
Realm Paragon
so what that
means is
if you're Paragon
level 230 on a
season
all of that
230 worth of
experience is going
to get added to
your Eternal
which probably is
going to level up
your Eternal
Paragon
and I mention
this because
we added the
really cool
Soulstone
I kept calling it
the Vessel of
Hatred Crystal
but that's a
Soulstone
that really cool
Soulstone that you
get at Paragon
level 300
you can actually
earn that on
Eternal
so if you're not
willing to sort
of put in
hundreds of hours
to get that
in a season
you can work
your way there
on the Eternal
Realm as you
sort of cash
in these seasons
so we think
that's going to
feel pretty good
it's going to be
really nice
as you're like
playing through
multiple seasonal
characters and
then eventually
you'll end up
just getting
enough XP
to actually
earn those
rewards at
level 300
Paragon
so that's
actually
it's not like
I have to
have it in
this season
or something
like that
you know
you probably
end up getting
it in a couple
seasons
if you play
pretty extensively
and you level
up your Paragon
yeah definitely
the second one
here is
now we are
essentially tying
the unique
powers
if you think
about like
the Fists of
Fate
that random
damage rule
from 1
to 200
that's going
to be tied
the floor
is going to be
tied to the
amount of
greater affixes
that are on
that item
so if you have
one greater affix
the floor is going
to go up a little
bit from the 1%
when you get four
greater affixes
it's going to go up
quite a bit
it's not exactly
perfect because we
wanted to maintain
the sort of
specialness of a
4GA with a
perfect unique rule
we've seen some of
those on Reddit
and I think it's
always such a cool
moment to sort of
see those drop
but it's going to be
a substantial increase
to the power of the
floor so it's going to
be nearly impossible
to get a 4GA
with a really
crappy unique
power rule
it's always great
getting a 4GA
and then rolling it
1%
yeah
that always just
feels bad
you never want
to be comparing
like oh I got
a 4GA
well my 1GA
one is maybe
better because it
has a better
unique role
that wasn't a
moment we felt
was really enticing
so we wanted to
make sure that
the more GAs
you get
just the better
the item is
comprehensively
just better
yeah
absolutely
so that should
help quite a bit
and then I'm going
to talk about
one thing
previously on that
which is
ancestral legendaries
they are now
going to
when an ancestral
item drops
it's going to drop
the top end
of the legendary
aspect role
so if you think
in season 6
we added 5 more
ranks to compensate
ancestral being added
rank 21 is usually
where they end up
landing
now ancestral items
when they drop
they're going to be
at the top end
of that
so you should always
be pretty excited
when an ancestral
drops
because it's always
the best
sort of top end
ranks of that
legendary power
that could drop
we saw lots
of conspiracy theories
on reddit
of people going
like hey
I think like
my codex of power
is not getting
updated correctly
or something like that
and we totally
understand
like there was a lot
of confusion behind it
we admit that
on our end
and this just makes
it easier and better
for players
and being able
to grab it
it's not Colin
behind the scenes
on a computer
it was
it actually was
he was literally
just like
making sure
you got the lowest
aspect roles
or anything
like that
yeah
grind harder
so that
that most definitely
will address
a lot of the confusion
there as well
as just make it
better for players
overall
yeah definitely
and then the second
point here is
we've pretty substantially
increased the ancestral
drop rate
across the board
they're not going to be
raining from the sky
but it's definitely
a pretty substantial
increase that
we think is just
going to level up
all the different
activities in the game
and that should just
feel a lot better
we don't want to go
too far where
they're no longer
special
but we thought
that we were
a little bit
too conservative
on our first swing
and this will
affect all torment
tiers right
not just
torment 4
yep exactly
so all
torment tiers
are going to get
this increase
great
and then the next
one
so we saw
that gems
were dropping
a little too
frequently
constantly
getting stuck
on the ground
players were capped
on them
so we are doing
a pass to reduce
them overall
but to compensate
we're actually
adding a sink
for them
so you're going
to be able
to take
gem fragments
and craft
random legendary
amulets
and random
legendary rings
those all
obviously have a
chance to be
ancestral
once you get
into the torment
so it's a really
nice way for us
to sort of
make sure that
you're never
hitting a point
where you just
have so many
gem fragments
they're worthless
awesome
yeah
and then
the next one
I think is going
to be
I'm super
excited about
and that's
class quest
updates
they're going
to work
similar to
altars of
Lilith
do you have
more details
on that
yeah
so class quest
so most
classes
or every class
has this
special mechanics
so like
on sorceress
you've got
your enchantment
slots
and in the past
when you hit
level 15
you'd get a quest
where you had
to go and
help out a mage
to find a lost
home
so for players
who have already
completed that
you are going
to
if you
you do need
to log into
that character
first
to kind of
unlock it
across your
account
but once you've
done that
any subsequent
sorceress that
you make
once you hit
level 15
you're going to
immediately unlock
that first
enchantment slot
and then once
you hit level 30
you'll unlock
the second one
now for every
class the exact
level is going
to be different
it depends on
when that would
normally unlock
but you won't
have to go
through the whole
quest line
to do so
but for those
of you who
really enjoyed
doing those
quests
there will be
a pretty juicy
reward if you
do choose to
do it
but you're
going to get
that mechanic
right off the
bat
that's awesome
and you could
still just log
into your
seasonal character
and do it
to unlock
the class
mechanic
we don't
require you
to log
into your
eternal character
to get this
cool
so I think
that's going
to be awesome
I always
check the
time
like oh
I'm level
I should
probably
go do
my class
quest
I have
definitely
forgotten
to unlock
my golem
on my
necromancers
for a little
longer than
I would like
to admit
well production
spoiled it
as they raise
their hands
up in the air
but the next
update is
obviously a big
one which is
finally we don't
have to say
this is in
development
Armory
Armory is
coming with
season 7
patch 2.1
so Colin
want to go
through it
all
absolutely
yeah
this one
was a
really
niche
request
we had
to dive
super
deep
into the
forum
so that
one guy
who asked
for this
this is
for you
I'm just
kidding
this has
been a
super
hot
requested
feature
we're
excited to
bring it
to
everybody
so
everybody's
going to
get this
update
Armory is
going to
allow you
to save
builds
it's
going to
save
all your
equipment
all of
your
skills
all of
your
Paragon
all your
glyphs
can even
name it
and what
this really
allows you
to do
is be a
lot more
flexible
in the
endgame
right
so
if you're
really
liking
your
fireball
build
but you
got this
really
sweet
ball
lightning
unique
now it's
really easy
to just
save off
that
fireball
build
if you
ever
want
to
come
back
start
building
out
that
ball
lightning
build
so
we're
really
excited
about
this
and
we're
not
going
to
charge
you
for
respeccing
or
anything
like
that
so
you
save
it
it's
yours
even
come
with
some
cool
quality
of
life
things
where
we
actually
mark
all
of
the
equipment
that's
actually
part
of
an
armory
slot
and
that's
really
important
to
know
because
we're
just
saving
the
equipment
right
so
you'll
want
to
know
if
you're
going
to
modify
this
item
that
it
would
affect
any
of
the
loadouts
that
are
currently
using
this
item
yeah
if
you
take
a
legendary
and
say
change
the
imprinted
aspect
on
it
you know
it's
still
part
of
that
build
so
it
might
not
be
the
right
one
so
you
do
probably
want
to
get
multiple
sets
of
gear
if
you
want
to
be
building
up
but
it's
so much
easier to
explore
all the
new
build
possibilities
that
we
introduce
every
season
with
the
new
items
and
updates
absolutely
and
it's
in
all
the
main
towns
it's
even
in
the
training
rooms
which
is
very
nice
and
it's
important
to
note
that
we
will
swap
it
from
anywhere
so
if
the
equipment
is
in
your
stash
or
if
it's
in
your
inventory
you
don't
have
to
worry
about
it
we'll
just
swap
automagically
does
it
which
is
really
nice
it
makes
removed
a lot
of
the
cost
to
switch
around
and
we
think
this
should
open
up
if
you're
playing
a
druid
you don't
have
to
go
make
another
druid
or
go
through
clicks
to
change
out
your
paragon
so
yeah
and
I
think
one
thing
I
do
want
to
note
is
because
this
will
be
in
PTR
we
really
need
people
to
actually
test
it
is
a
brand
new
feature
there's
one
thing
I
do
want
to
call
won't
have
controller
support
it
will
have
controller
support
when we
do
launch
it
with
patch
2.1
the
final
patch
itself
won't
actually
be
controller
support
on it
so
I
just
want
to
caveat
that
now
for
players
that
do
play
on
controller
to
note
that
it
won't
be
there
for
that
specifically
so
tons
of
the
balance
and
items
are
related
to
that
new
rune
words
reworked
rune
words
as
well
we
have
of
course
all
the
season
seven
stuff
that
Dan
talked
about
with
the
witchcraft
powers
and
of
course
our
new
gems
the
occult
gems
so
we
want
players
to
actually
jump
in
and
try
those
out
and
with
all
the
quality
of
life
fixes
that
we
have
so
I
know
we
do
want
to
jump
into
Q&A
before
we
oh
PTR
updates
I
forgot
sorry
I forgot
about
PTR
updates
I
can't
even
follow
my
own
agenda
that's
like
sitting
here
on a
piece
of
paper
Adam
but
we
do
have
some
PTR
updates
really
quickly
that
I
do
want
to
talk
about
because
as
you
guys
remember
the
with
2.1
the
prior
PTRs
we did
character
copies
before
account
copies
from
your
main
accounts
things
are going
to be
a little
different
for
patch
2.1
this
is
way
better
for
players
if you
guys
remember
back
with
even
the
patch
2.0
PTR
we
actually
did
an
account
copy
and
it
was
like
weeks
and
in
advance
and
people
were
like
whoa
this
is
like
my
barb
from
like
you
know
it
feels
like
yesteryear
or
something
like
that
now
we
are
giving
the
flexibility
of
players
being
able
to
actually
account
copy
over
to
your
PTR
account
so
take
all
your
characters
from
your
normal
account
and
move
them
over
there
are
a few
caveats
we
do
want
to
mention
though
is
that
it
does
replace
everything
once
you
do
that
multiple
times
so
but
each
time
you
do
that
it
does
replace
bounce
between
PTR
and
your
main
account
on
the
normal
game
servers
and
let's
say
you
get
new
gear
you
can
move
those
things
over
just
note
it's
going
to
wipe
everything
on
your
PTR
when
you
do
that
if
you
also
utilize
the
let's
say
you
don't
actually
utilize
the
account
copy
over
and
you
actually
use
the
account
boost
or
the
character
boost
that
we
actually
have
within
PTR
just
note
that
if
you
do
account
aware
but
it
is
just
a
caveat
that
we
do
want
to
mention
for
players
but
it
does
allow
for
way
more
flexibility
being able
to carry
that stuff
over
definitely
there we go
but
new
additions
for the
boost
that we
have
for
PTR
obviously
we'll
end up
having
the
new
unique
items
within
the
character
boost
that will
be
available
in
Season 7
PTR
we'll
have
witchcraft
powers
the
witchcraft
progression
items
that we
had talked
about
earlier
part
of
the
PTR
boost
so
it
gives
you
guys
the
tools
of
being
able
to
test
everything
and
getting
us
feedback
for
anything
that
you
guys
want
to
change
before
the
Season 7
and
Patch 2.1
actually
kicks off
cool
now
we can
go to
Q&A
I do
want to
call out
quickly
just a
reminder
that
we will
have
a
blog
up
immediately
after
the
stream
for
PTR
patch
notes
will
be
next
Wednesday
again
this
is
due
to
us
streaming
a little
early
for
the
holidays
just
to
make
sure
that
everyone
was
here
to
do
a
stream
for
PTR
and
then
PTR
is
planning
on
starting
December
3rd
so
players
will
be
able
to
jump
into
PTR
then
of course
it
is
just
PC
Battle.net
easier
for us
and more
flexibility
for us
to be
able
to do
updates
and
everything
from
know
we
have
a
question
teed
up
so
if
you
have
questions
please
put
them
in
chat
and
we
will
get
those
you know
we'll try
to address
as many
as possible
for the
end
of the
stream
I have
to like
reach
over
there's
like
a
plant
here
that
no one
can
see
but
will
all
the
PTR
content
be
did
split
it
out
we
will
say
that
all
the
PTR
content
will
be
available
day
one
so
players
can
jump
in
and
actually
check
out
everything
related
to
patch
2.1
immediately
with
day
one
whenever
they
need
to
so
shouldn't
be
a
problem
jumping
into
some
questions
small
petting
zoo
they're
a
person
that
plays
a
lot
of
companions
I
would
imagine
based
on
the
name
so
they're
asking
will
Will there be fixes to Storm and Werewolf tags given to Druid Wolves by the item Storm's Companion?
They have never functioned, would more than double the damage of the build.
Yes, actually, as part of that comprehensive update that I mentioned to summons across the game,
I did take a pass to look at specifically updating how the Wolves interact with Storm's Companion.
And now, whenever they're imbued with a lightning from Storm's Companion,
they do count as lightning skills.
And because the, you know, not to get too technical, but because the way the damage is calculated and attributed,
it should also work with all the things that say, hey, when you deal lightning damage, do something special.
Your lightning wolves are going to be triggering and interacting with all those effects.
It should be, it should work in every way that you're expecting to going forward.
Awesome. Sharky pets.
A question from Narrator Dog.
How does this fit into, how does the Season 7 stuff fit into lore?
Because during Vessel of Hatred and the tree seemed to be on good terms.
Dan, I don't know if you want to answer this or if you want me to answer it.
Up to you.
Yeah, so I'll say, first off, we're not going to get too deep of an answer.
We're going to reveal more about the story as we get closer to the release of Season 7.
That said, we are really looking at trying to build upon the events of Vessel of Hatred with every season moving forward.
And so you'll start seeing changes in the world as we do that.
And I'll leave it at that.
Cool.
You'll hear more soon.
Again, we plan on doing a more grandiose reveal of Season 7 content in the story as we get closer to the release.
So you'll hear more about kind of like the backstory of everything and how the Tree of Whispers plays into everything as well.
Question from Toothless81.
Is there going to be a rework or cost reduction to masterworking?
Veil Crystals have become a huge roadblock with trying to gear multiple alts.
Yeah, I think we are always keeping our eye on the economy.
We did a big pass.
If you remember, we did a stream last week that was talking about tightening up the economy.
So we do intend on taking a look at just generally how things are playing out.
I think alts is something that we need to definitely be taking a look at.
We do want to encourage alt gameplay.
That was part of the big Paragon changes.
So that sort of feedback is super valuable.
It's really good to know that Veiled Crystals are that alt blocker.
We want to make sure that alts are something that players are really excited about if that's something that they want to pursue.
So I appreciate that.
Question related to stacking items.
This is from Marwan Gaming.
Any plans on the amount that you can stack?
Like items, potions, light, potions, keys, and runes?
Wow, I can't read.
Any updates?
Or are we looking at any of that type of thing?
We definitely are looking at it.
We don't have anything to share, but it's top of mind.
I know that boss materials, for example, are at 50.
There are some technical reasons why we have it like that, but it's something we are actively looking at.
Dracronia mentions, do you know if XP wells are getting fixed?
And do you know if there's an opportunity for maybe pets collecting loot a little bit faster?
Anything on the screen for players?
I know that XP well definitely has been reported, and it's something we're looking into.
So we know about it.
We're looking at it.
This is part of the PTR is to find a lot more of these types of problems.
So we will look at it.
As far as the pets, no plans at the moment.
I know we've done a big pass on a lot of things to essentially make sure that when a rare item drops in Torment,
it's just going to get auto-salvaged.
So we do try and essentially make a lot more of the loot just auto-pick-up-able.
Question from MagsPVE.
Will Druid ever see some love for Ravens?
It would be awesome to have maybe a different companion outside of the wolves and everything that they have right now,
or the vines and stuff.
Is there any plans for maybe adjustments to Ravens in the future?
Yeah, absolutely.
Ravens, one of the three companions compared to the wolves and the vine creeper,
which I think are often a bit more of the marquee ones in the companion builds, at least as they currently are.
That's something we're definitely aware of.
And going forward, when we look to make new effects for these companion builds,
I think Ravens might be maybe the next one we start looking at.
Nothing I can commit to firmly at this point.
But it's definitely something that we have noticed, and yeah, it's something we'll keep in mind.
So we appreciate that.
Part of that summoning tag update was really to sort of give us more tools to do things like improve the Raven experience or the Ancients experience.
Yeah, yeah.
I think that summon update is going to be really huge for companion druids and every other build that uses these.
And we'll definitely look at it under that new lens after this update and see where we can make further improvements.
We'll do one last question, but this is like a two-parter question from two different people.
One's from TeampoDiavlo4.
The other one's from Dejal22.
And they're both related to Armory.
Will items in the Armory be locked from accidentally selling them?
And separately, will saved items for Armory builds have like maybe an icon or something associated to them to kind of like call them out that they are part of a saved build?
Yeah.
So when you do save a loadout, we favorite all of those items.
So just automatically that happens.
No mistaken like, oh, crap.
You'd have to unfavorite it, then sell it.
And then at that point, it's like, well, it's sort of on you.
And then the second part is, yes, there is a little icon that does indicate that, hey, this is part of an Armory.
Cool.
So, yeah, you know that like, hey, this is part of a build.
Don't mess with it.
Don't accidentally unfavorite it or anything like that, which is good to know.
So, cool.
Well, we, again, thank you guys for tuning in for our Patch 2.1 PTR stream.
I know there's a lot of news coming down the line for Diablo 4 as we get closer to 2.1.
But we do have a blog that will be going live this afternoon and probably right after this stream.
And, again, our patch notes, the full patch notes for this PTR will be next Wednesday.
So, it's a little bit of a delay, mainly due to the holidays and us doing the stream a little bit early.
Normally, we have the patch notes immediately after the stream.
So, there's going to be way more content beyond what we just talked about here in those patch notes for people to actually check out.
And, of course, Patch 2.1 PTR is launching on December 3rd for PC Battle.net users.
So, really looking forward to people jumping in, trying everything that we talked about today, including the new features, including the Armory, including all the Season 7 stuff with Witchcraft powers and Occult Gems that we actually heard from Dan as well.
So, huge thanks to Dan out in Albany.
And, of course, thank you, Colin.
Thank you, Charles, for talking us through all the content that's going to be coming with Patch 2.1 PTR.
And, yeah, we'll see you guys probably after the holidays, but we'll see you in the PTR for sure.
And we'll check you guys out in Haantu.
See you guys.
Thanks.
So.