In Vessel of Hatred, we travel south to Nahantu,
a region with both deep ancient jungles and vast sprawling plains.
It's the last stretch of land in Sanctuary's eastern continent,
and we've packed it full of experiences for every type of player.
In this expansion, there's a whole lot to explore under the dark canopy of Nahantu.
Nahantu is the southernmost region of the eastern continent
that Diablo 4 has been taking place in.
It's the last region that we haven't visited yet so far in the game,
but it is one that we've been to before in Diablo.
There's lots of new areas.
We have six in total.
Four of them are jungle-themed,
and then we have two that are Red Rock Canyon,
but each one of them has their own unique identity.
When you first arrive in Nahantu,
you're in this place called Lingering Hatred.
This is high treetops canopies
where you're almost walking amongst the branches high above the jungle floor.
Imagine a thick canopy that the light is just barely poking through.
The whole area has been infected by this thing called the hollows infestation.
The hollows are a new enemy that's associated with Mephisto.
They themselves are kind of like a tar-like substance creature
born straight out of the depths of hell.
It feels a little twisted.
There's a sickness to the area itself.
Humans have ventured into this deep part of the jungle
where there's all this poisonous plants and flora.
The dregs actually started experimenting with eating these hallucinogens,
and it put them into this aggressive psycho rage.
The dregs were pretty fun because we were able to push more variety in the monster family.
You have one of these tall dregs and then half of a body of another dreg on top of it
kind of controlling it and telling it where to go and tossing poisonous bombs at the player.
When you come across it, it's very memorable.
And then we've also got the area of Tenghansi
where you've got the Tenghansi Plateau,
which is full of these red rocked plateaus and canyons.
Imagine getting up above the land.
Those gigantic walls have pockets inside where monsters could live.
It offered up a lot of opportunity to bring back a monster family like the Lucunai.
We're bringing them back in a new way here as a fully fleshed out monster family with multiple classes.
What a more brute force looks like, what a caster looks like.
They are very much apex predators, and we're definitely in their territory.
And then there's a little sub area called the Skittering Earth.
The name alone makes your skin crawl.
It's bug infested, and you can see how the bugs have destroyed the jungles
and kind of input their influence on it.
Within the Field of Giants, you have these giant corpses of these long dead demons
that humans have begun to mine away at for their resources.
While they've got a lot of use out of them, they're also toxic to the land around it.
The notion of massive demons walking sanctuary a thousand years ago is really thought-provoking.
Plateau's also got just this beautiful color scheme to the lighting.
It's really lovely to be there.
And then horrific at the same time. You know, it's great.
The mercenaries in Vessel of Hatred are a group of people who we like to describe
as ordinary people with extraordinary skills.
They have the same level of will to fight against the demons of hell.
And there's four mercs that you can collect over the course of the campaign.
It starts with Rahir, a blacksmith and a shield bearer who's more defensive fighter.
He's able to go in there and soak up damage, use his shield as a bulwark against the enemy.
Meet him early on in the campaign and he's one who introduces you to the mercenary network.
You end up finding acquisition quests for three other mercs that you can find throughout the course of the story.
Subo, the drunken archer, is going to work really well for people who want someone who's out of the main melee,
in the back, offering utility and that kind of range support.
Then we have Varyana, a berserker crone who's a melee combat fighter, close range.
You've got a really cool combat meter, a massacre meter where you need to keep killing enemies to get the meter to be filled.
She's got a bunch of really interesting utility skills that you can kind of build in.
Finally, we have the demon child, Aldkin, who's a magic user who can transform himself from human form to demon form and join you in combat.
There's this really great reinforcement ability where you can take one of the mercenary skills and attach it to one of the mercenary skills.
You can also use the skill of your powers so that when you use that skill, it calls them in to do a specific skill.
With the mercenaries for Vessel of Hatred, one of the things we are expanding on is the skill tree.
For Diablo III, you had a very basic type of mercenary, but this time you can actually push a little bit more into the skill tree
and make the mercenary the way you would want to play.
Going through each mercenary progression arc and outfitting their skill tree so that it's complementary to your character build,
I think that's where the fun in the mercenary system really lies.
The Dark Citadel is a new in-game feature that's coming in Vessel of Hatred.
It's an entirely cooperative player experience.
All the mechanics within it are based around you working together with your party members to solve the challenges and face the first cars that are hordes within.
One of the outcomes of the Mage Wars is this giant crater and all the souls that were kind of lost in it from those wars.
The goal of the first Khazrah, who are kind of the original Khazrah, they're using the powers within the Citadel found within this crater to perform experiments to try and bring back their Dark God.
Only recently, people have started going missing. They head into the Khazrah region, they disappear, never to be seen again.
So it's clear that whatever they're planning is about to come to fruition and your job as the player is to get in there and stop it.
Citadel is a place where we take what is the best part of Diablo, combat, and we test it in a different way,
which is adding in cooperative mechanics that you have to manage on top of that.
For example, a boss has an attack, and as a player, you have to collect an item that allows you to reflect the attack back at him.
So there's a little bit of a twitch level mechanic there where you actually have to time your reaction shot.
What's interesting about it is when you get multiple people in there, we're each responsible for reflecting that shot once,
so we all have to sort of master the timing of that move.
You can't do that kind of thing without coordinating as a team, and that's sort of the example of what Citadel gameplay feels like.
When designing the Citadel, we designed a lot of really cool bosses.
And so one of the things that we did is we took that design and made, like, armor sets for each of the classes.
That way you feel like you took their armor and you feel like you're wearing a little bit of them after your victory.
We also have a currency that's dedicated to Citadel where, as you play through,
a vendor can be interacted with to buy custom cosmetics that are unique to the Citadel.
You can play with two people, but the ideal experience is for four.
In order to facilitate that, we've built an all-new Party Finder feature,
and the community has been pretty vocal about wanting this for a long time.
It made a lot of sense to us to pair it with this new Citadel mode.
It really is an activity that's geared towards people who love to play together with their friends or with strangers,
and enjoy that cooperative gameplay.
I cannot wait for players to get into the world.
I'm really just excited for people to see all the little hidden storytelling elements that the team has fit in.
There's interesting things to find and see and discover around every corner,
and it's just a really great experience getting to explore Nahantou.
Hello, Diablo community. Welcome to another Campfire Chat.
This is the Patch 2.0 Campfire Chat for PTR.
As you guys can see, we're in a little bit of a new environment.
We're all doing this from home.
We had to do a quick last-minute pivot about 24 hours ago.
I was struck by some con flu after Gamescom,
but I just wanted to give a quick shout-out to our production teams behind the scenes.
Lucas, Jaden, Rich, they made a quick pivot to allow us to do this,
and for us to be safe, and to be able to still give you guys this exciting information for Patch 2.0.
But to lead us off, I do want us to do some quick intros for everyone here on the actual panel.
So, Colin, would you like to start off the intros?
Yeah, sure. I'm Colin on the design team.
Hello, I'm Aislinn Hall. I'm a systems designer with a focus on Live Balance.
Hey, everyone. I'm Charles Dunn. I'm a class designer working on the Live Balance for Diablo 4.
Hey, everyone. I'm Jeevan Sidhu, and I also work on the systems team.
Awesome. So we got a whole panel here, way more than what we normally have,
because we have so much to actually cover.
We do want to jump into things pretty immediately, but I did want to recap really quickly.
Obviously, last week we were at Gamescom.
We made some really big announcements for Vessel of Hatred, where we announced, you know,
the mercenaries that will be coming to Vessel of Hatred,
along with how that system works with, like, reinforcements.
It's like a new take of how mercenaries play within Diablo,
especially since mercenaries has such a storied history within the franchise itself.
And, of course, we also talked about the Curious Under City and the Dark Citadel,
along with the Party Finder feature that players will be able to actually partake in with Vessel of Hatred
and use that for Dark Citadel and other features within the game.
We do actually have a blog up on Diablo4.com that does do a good deep dive across all of those specific items,
so you guys can actually check that out.
But we have a packed agenda today. This will be a long one, so we hope that everyone will sit down and grab a snack
and join us as we talk about some pretty large systemic changes that will be coming with Diablo 4,
along with some new stuff that we'll be sharing as well that will also be coming with Diablo 4.
So we're going to start off with some progression updates.
We're going to move off into some class and balance changes, along with some quality of life updates,
and then we'll kind of cap it off with a cool new announcement that will be coming with Vessel of Hatred.
So, Aislinn, Colin, I know you guys want to jump into some of these big progression changes that you guys were talking about last week,
so take it away.
Yeah, thanks, Adam. And I'm sure everyone has no idea what the big surprise is at the end.
Not whatsoever.
So, yeah, yeah, right. So, yeah, let's jump into the progression.
So when we launched the game, we had a sort of vision for the game that we felt like was really fun to play through once,
where you'd sort of traverse through these world tiers and you'd be gaining new sacred items rarely,
and then you'd be getting ancestral items when hopping into world tier four.
And as we played the game more and more and as we've gotten feedback, that necessarily hasn't really been super fun.
So we've sped up a lot of the progression to sort of get you into that space that where you feel powerful,
where you have autonomy of your choice in terms of difficulty and challenge and reward.
Diablo is all about that progression, right, and sort of lasting and feeling efficient.
So we wanted to take a step back after looking at itemization.
We've added a ton of itemization progression that we think is feeling pretty good.
There's a lot of ways to customize your character.
There's a lot of ways to progress your itemization.
I mean, we wanted to look at other aspects of the game.
So that came in the form of like what hasn't aged super well?
What are the things that we really enjoy and we see that you all enjoy and doubling down on that?
So two of those things are difficulty and overall just character progression from your paragons, your glyphs, et cetera.
We've sort of taken the approach of like really doubling down and embracing again what has been really fun, right?
Blasting, being efficient, having control over your challenge and reward, right?
Profane Mind Cages is awesome when you can stack it to three and you can hop into those hell ties
and just start getting tons of experience and reward for pushing that challenge.
Key dungeons like Nightmare Dungeons, Infernal Hordes, really pretty much every endgame in the system at this point has a tiering system associated with it.
And we think that's like pretty indicative of like what has been fun and we want to embrace that.
And part of that is, you know, that the idea of I can push really hard to get more efficiency.
Part of that's conquering milestones, right?
It's really good.
It's a ton of fun to hop into World Tier 3 early.
I think I hopped in at level 25 in the latest release just to see if I could do it.
And it was a ton of fun.
And it's sort of all about embracing that gaining power in multiple ways, feeling super powerful.
And then another thing that we really wanted to look at in terms of making this better is alting.
We made a change to make it so that the mythic uniques could be equipped at level 35.
And if you've done that, it's a really badass experience where, you know, roll a barbarian, slap a grandfather on them, and you just blast through the leveling experience and it's a ton of fun.
That being said, we've added tons of sort of power to the equation.
And we wanted to make sure that we also gave you more autonomy to sort of challenge yourself with all that new power.
And we're adding a ton of new power in the expansion as well.
So to cover it again, right, we want to look at expanding the progression in other areas of the game come patch 2.0.
So with that, Aislin actually has a bunch of exciting changes to talk about here.
I do.
Thank you, Colin.
Okay, everyone, I want you to put on your thinking caps because we have a lot of details to cover.
So buckle up.
We, in fact, have a topic screen here because there's so many things regarding progression that we're going to be talking about today.
So the way that we're approaching this presentation is we're basically going to be bringing you through what a character's journey would actually look like.
You know, starting by talking about the character journey and then talking about some difficulty.
Uh, tier changes that are coming and then going deeper into, you know, how you're going to be gaining.
Um, more rewards from those sad difficulty tears.
Um, so yeah, without further ado, let's simply jump in and get started with the character journey.
Okay, so some changes coming to how you're going to be leveling up.
Um, there's going to be a level adjustment.
So we're going to be getting started with the character level.
First of all, uh, coming to patch 2.0 right now in the live game, you know, you go from character level one to 50.
Those are your skill point levels.
And then every level after 50 is a paragon level where you're earning four paragon points per paragon level.
We're going to be splitting those out in patch 2.0.
Um, and so you're going to earn paragon points, which are, which are going to be separate from your character level.
Uh, levels one to 50 represent those character levels.
And there's also going to be a new max character level, quote unquote, of level 60.
And that means that you are going to be earning 10 more, uh, skill points, uh, from what you had been earning, uh, pre patch 2.0.
There's also going to be a re-imagined pace to the leveling journey.
So we have a lot new, a lot of new difficulty tiers that are being added to the game more on that soon.
Uh, but effectively, um, lower difficulty tiers are going to be offering you a slower pace.
If you're a near player, you just want a very casual, chill experience, but you're going to be able to bump it up if you want to.
Like if you're, you know, engaging with tempering, you're engaging with all these systems that are making your character stronger and you want something to test that against.
We are aiming to give that to you.
Uh, and these, uh, difficulty tiers are going to be offering you, uh, improved efficiency, improved rewards.
And the goal is to improve your pace.
If you can blast through these difficulties.
Yeah.
Now there's the mind cages, right?
Like we, we sort of heard, yeah, we, you heard, we heard you like mind cages.
So we put it in the game systemically, like from whispers to hell tide to literally everything.
In the world, like maybe like doing dungeons.
Um, and really it's starting, it's sort of like giving players that choice to do what they want.
And it's not just hell tide now that can push that difficulty.
Yeah, totally.
Like we were just playing on the development team and we were playing in hell tides and, you know, playing with mind cages and we were like, this is great.
Like, I want to just be able to do this or like have this option available to me, like basically whenever I'm playing.
Uh, so that's a big part of these changes.
Uh, moving on here to the number adjustments.
So as a lot of you guys found in footage, yes, there is a, a pretty substantial number adjustment.
Um, so a big part of this is we want to make sure that there's room for growth and we're adding a lot of player power in patch 2.0 and vessel of hatred.
Um, and we want to make sure that numbers don't get so crazy that we cannot even fathom them.
Right.
Um, and so a big part of this is, uh, giving us a good starting points in patch 2.0 where we can afford to grow numbers.
Um, so yeah.
Yeah.
I think it's really important, you know, to have numbers that are like, uh, when you're like doing damage numbers to, to see ones that are meaningful to you.
Right.
Uh, if you're increasing your damage, like even 10 X, but it's taken it from like an eight or nine digit number to a 10 digit number, it's, it's almost impossible to see that kind of growth in player power.
So with, with numbers that are more readable on screen, uh, that, that a makes it much more obvious when you're getting more powerful and just makes the game as a whole easier to kind of comprehend.
Totally.
Yeah.
And it's important to note that like, this is relative, um, in that we're not slowing you down in any way.
This is purely sort of one of those adjustments that we're making to ensure that you can have more growth in the end game.
We're not at the top end nerfing things like crit chance or CDR.
Um, really this is all about having actually like sort of what we set out to do when we launched the game is have more grounded numbers for longer.
That's not to say that you aren't going to get insane in the deep end game.
Right.
Yeah.
You're still going to have a lot of power to game.
Um, and yeah, finally, uh, just going back to this first bullet here on this slide, we're going to talk more about Paragon later, but for now we're going to focus on some other things.
So sit tight.
Okay.
Let's talk about how monsters are changing.
So we've streamlined monster health and damage in a pretty big way.
We took a look at how monsters gain health and how they gain damage over, uh, different difficulty tiers.
Uh, and we've really like honed in and, and kind of universalized our approach to how they're, uh, gaining power throughout your character experience.
Uh, and this is going to be applying to all monster types, you know, normal monsters, minions, which are elites, little buddies, uh, elites themselves.
And of course bosses and all of these monsters now have health that's relative to their normal monster counterpart on any given like difficulty tier.
Uh, and what this does is it really helps smooth, uh, difficulty progression and the difficulty of any experience that you're currently in.
Secondly, we have some changes to, uh, monster scaling.
So monsters are going to scale to a pit tier and we're going to talk more about that as well, pretty soon too.
Uh, so sit tight.
And the big thing here is that monsters are always going to match the player level now.
So on live, we have a world where monsters can be, you know, a hundred levels offset of you and anywhere in between.
And that can be fairly hard to understand.
Um, and so a big part of this pass is kind of removing that elements of the game so that we can focus on what difficulty we're currently in and using that as the judge of how hard or how easy or wherever in between, uh, the content you're currently is, uh, you're currently in is.
And finally, we have some pretty cool combat tuning changes.
Uh, so we've taken a lot of looks at, you know, like the, the moment to moment combat pacing in the game, uh, and monster mechanics across the board have been adjusted to really hone in on player momentum.
You know, you're here to slaughter demons.
We want you to move quickly, uh, through the game.
And we don't necessarily want monsters to be slowing you down, especially normal monsters.
Um, and to achieve this, uh, you know, we've reduced instances of getting one shot, like out of nowhere.
And we've also adjusted boss HP, um, so that they're not quite as grindy after you're moving in from, you know, after blasting down AOE packs in the pit, for example.
Yeah, it was definitely a pain point.
Oh, great.
Oh, go ahead, Charles.
Uh, um, yeah, I, I, I just saying, right.
That's always been the pain point in the pit so far is like, Hey, you're really strong.
You blast through most of the dungeon and then you get up to the boss and the boss takes, you know, five minutes or more.
That's just like such a slog.
Uh, so, so we're definitely making sure it's a more consistent experience, uh, in a given difficulty tier, you're, you're going to have a more consistent experience across boss and other portions of the game.
Yeah.
And we've already taken a lot of steps towards this.
Um, and, and pre the, one of the previous seasons, we set it so that you wouldn't get, um, armor cap penalties as the monster is leveled higher than you.
Right.
So this is really just sort of consolidating a lot of the, um, I'm going to get shit for the blizzard math, um, on the back end to make sure that like a lot of the things are really, um, being reworked on the back end to address the problems we see on live with the crazy exponential scaling of boss health from like four different levels.
different multipliers and the crazy exponential damage that some of the monsters are getting.
If like the, ah, yes, the corpse bow, of course, um, dying in one shot from off screen.
A lot of those things should be much more consistent as you're climbing through those difficulty tiers, which we're going to talk more about in the, in the future or in this presentation.
Very soon.
In fact, like right now, difficulty.
Difficulty tiers.
Like right now.
Let's talk about it.
So, this is our beautiful, uh, blizzard illustration, if you will, uh, of current day.
Art by Colin.
Thank you very much.
I gotta call out Colin.
Yeah.
Oh no.
We've got the.
We're gonna get art for this.
This is art.
What are you talking about?
Yeah, this is beautiful.
This is beautiful.
Modern art.
Uh, yeah, you can see we have the big bone boss.
Very, very sad at the current state of things up there.
Um, so what this is basically illustrating is that there are basically brackets right now on live where various content is relevant.
You have world bosses that stay relevant for a certain amount of time.
You have hell tide that stays relevant, you know, maybe a little bit longer than world bosses do.
And then you have world tiers one and two.
Then you have world tier three, which is, you know, very sad.
Sorry, world tier three.
Yeah.
Uh, and then world tier four.
I'll have a magnifying glass.
You can see it.
Yeah.
Maybe if you look really closely, you can see how long it takes to go through world tier three.
Um, and then world tier four, which has like a bit of a tail, but still pretty short.
And then we compare it to like where our characters power currently exists, which is, you know, you've got level one to 100.
And then of course your journey throughout all of the pit tiers.
And basically what this is illustrating is a lot of these content types fall off.
World bosses don't stay relevant forever.
Helltide doesn't stay relevant forever.
The world tiers you're living on in the open world don't stay relevant.
Um, and eventually it simply becomes about running the pit.
And that's the place where you can judge your character strength.
We don't necessarily want the game to work that way.
We want a lot of activities to stay fun and interesting and engaging for as long as possible.
And so to accomplish that, we've got some pretty big changes coming to difficulty tiers.
So let's dive into the meat and potatoes of this talking about pit arbitration.
And that's just a fancy way of basically saying that the pit is going to be something behind the scenes that's setting the pace of all difficulty in the game across all content types.
So pit tiers are going to match difficulty tiers.
There's going to be five pit tiers per standard difficulty, which is just encapsulating, um, four new world tiers pre level 60, which are normal, hard, expert and penitent.
Uh, and then there will be 15 pit tiers per torment difficulty, and they're going to be four torment difficulty tiers.
One, two, three, and four difficulty tiers are going to derive monster health damage and intensity from the pit tier that is associated with that difficulty tier.
And I know that's a little complicated, but we're going to have some, uh, some supporting stuff to, to show what this means a little better, uh, pretty soon.
And I do want to call out intensity here.
Colin, do you want to talk about monster intensity raising between difficulty tiers?
Yeah.
So intensity is something we played around with in the base game and it's sprinkled out throughout, throughout the game.
Um, but when, what intensity is, is it's a backend system that controls, uh, monster aggressiveness as well as monster intelligence.
So by aggressiveness, it's things like they attack faster, they have lower cooldowns, um, they move faster.
And then intelligence is they predict your movement more.
They'll face you more.
So if you, you know, it has a big swing, it's actually going to try and track you a little bit more accurately.
Um, so it's not just the health and damage that's going up through these difficulty tiers.
The monsters are actually becoming a little bit more dynamic and fast paced.
Um, and we think that feels pretty good.
Um, especially when it's sort of scaling through the new difficulty series system that we have.
Yeah.
This is something we currently, we do have on, on the live game, but you know, in the new, um, patch 2.0, you're really going to feel that difference.
Currently you feel a little bit of difference in between the different world tiers, and that's just going to be magnified.
And your moment to moment combat is, it's not just going to be higher numbers.
The moment to moment will feel different and harder at these higher torment difficulties.
Yep.
They're going to become bigger jerks as you ascend difficulties.
All right.
So let's talk about difficulty gating.
So this is basically how people are going to be moving through these different difficulty tiers.
So the pit is going to unlock, uh, once you hit character level 60, which is the new max.
So the maximum character level in patch 2.0.
So pit tiers associated with, uh, standard difficulties are going to unlock immediately, which is pit tiers one through 20.
You're going to be able to challenge all of those immediately once your max level.
And you're going to need to beat pit tier 20 to unlock the first torment tier.
Once you beat pit tier 20, you're allowed to go into the overworld on torment one.
And then as we see here, there are 15 pit tiers per torment difficulties.
So to unlock torment two, you would then need to progress through the pit and beat pit tier 35, at which point you can now go into torment two in all other activities.
So on and so forth.
So this is basically creating a sorry.
Go ahead.
Go on.
Oh, I was going to jump in and say like, what's kind of interesting is like torment one.
You can think about as world tier three today.
Um, and what we're sort of doing is essentially saying now that level cap is 60, um, you actually can find some of the best items in the game very early.
Right.
Imagine if you were able to just start finding the best items in the game in world tier three.
Um, that's really sort of what we're talking about here.
We're really speeding up when you can actually get to the end game where we've added things like the pit.
We've added things like, um, nightmare dungeons and more end game activities for you to engage with an item modification system.
So, uh, it really is sort of getting you into the fun faster, which also makes ulting a lot more cool.
Right.
It's way easier to sort of get to that point where, all right, I'm in the end game.
I'm going to start looking for awesome items.
I'm going to start modifying my items.
Um, so we think that that like sort of, um, represents a pretty substantial change to how you play the game.
Oh yeah.
For us wondering why we kind of built it around the pit, you know, and why we associated difficulty with the pit.
How do y'all think about that?
Yeah.
So right now the pit is a fantastic razor to judge your character against.
Um, and I think that this overhaul is effectively turning the pit into the game's backbone to use kind of a gruesome term, but you know, we're Diablo, so whatever.
Um, it's basically turning the pit into the game's backbone of like difficulty, uh, and all other difficulties kind of derived from that.
Um, and it gives us a very predictable and understandable pace for you to experience all other activities in the game, uh, based on the pit's difficulty.
Um, and that, that razor is great for pushing difficulty.
Right.
You think about how, um, part of what's really fun again about Diablo is that feeling of progression and that feeling of becoming powerful, then taking on a big ass demon, killing it, getting awesome loot.
And what the pit is going to do is you're going to push that difficulty, then unlock new torment tiers, which is going to unlock more efficiency for you.
Um, and you can sort of think about it as like, we've added not just a world tier five, but a world tier five and six, um, as part of this torment system.
And it's something we can continue to sort of evaluate and build on as characters become more powerful.
And we add new ways to sort of play through the system.
Yeah.
And I think it's also a lot about consistency across content, right?
Currently in the live game, we've got a lot of different, um, you know, levels of different types of things, right?
You've got nightmare dungeon keys, you've got pit levels, you've got infernal horde of tears.
Um, and we just kind of realized that, Hey, the pit is something that we have, you know, really good, um, delineation between the different levels.
So you've got a widespread of, of, um, you know, different tiers for that.
And that's something we can kind of peg difficulty against across the whole game to make a more consistent experience.
When you're in a certain difficulty tier, you're just going to get a more consistent experience across all activities.
Right.
Yeah.
So like when you're on tournament two, you're going to know that all content you're facing is on the level of torment two.
But right now on the live game, you know, you have a, you go into a pit tier 50 and you're like, okay, it's pit tier 50 difficulty.
And then you go into a nightmare dungeon tier 50 and it's a totally different difficulty.
And then you go into an infernal hordes tier eight and you're like, wait a minute, this is extremely hard compared to these other ones.
They're just not similar.
Right.
And so we want to create a more level playing field, uh, so that difficulty is easier to understand.
It's also like a common language and shared experience for everyone.
Yeah, that's definitely a benefit.
And it's also, um, in some sense, leveling up all the activities.
Like I know that there's some people who really enjoy whispers, for example, and whispers just falls off.
Like if you're doing the pit and you're level 100, you're level 90 in the pit, like whispers are terrible, right?
Like you're not actually going to run whispers, um, when you're pushing that deep into the game.
But now when sort of things are leveling up with torment tiers, you have a place to go and sort of juice the efficiency from those different activities.
If you like that activity.
Yeah.
And this, this kind of carries over to other activities, not just whispers.
It's like, you know, your hell tides.
Yeah, the whole world is leveling.
Right.
Yeah.
Like it's, which is another thing like Infernal Hordes is something that obviously was introduced in season five is coming back and is a permanent feature within the game and is also going up with the rest of the content.
Yep.
All right.
So let's talk a little more about the details of difficulty tiers.
So on the right hand side here, you can see this table.
It's basically showing off, um, the associated pit tier with any given difficulty tier.
So normal simply starts on one.
And then like we saw before, it goes up by five each time until you get to torment tiers, at which point it goes up by 15 each time.
So torment four lands on 65.
Torment one starts on 20.
Um, and in, in light of this, uh, we have changed the height of the target.
We have changed the highest pit tier to be 100 down from 200.
Um, and this doesn't mean that the pit tier 100 is going to be the same difficulty as it is on live.
It's going to be harder.
Um, so each pit tier you're, you're going up is going to be harder than it was before effectively.
And we also have this pretty neat new system where we have smart keys.
Um, and what that means is your things like infernal hordes or nightmare dungeons, the keys to enter those activities are now going to follow, uh, the current difficulty tier that you're on.
So if I have an infernal horde key and I'm on torment three and I use it, I'm going to go into a torment three difficulty infernal horde.
And the same is true for nightmare dungeons.
Um, so we're pretty excited about that change because again, you know, coming back to all these things we've, we've talked about where it just kind of makes things easier.
Just makes life easier.
Yeah.
It's a big quality of life change because on live right now you get a bunch of sacred, um, you know, nightmare dungeon keys.
And I'm sure everyone runs a ton of world tier three nightmare dungeons, right?
Um, you definitely don't just pop in to get a sacred weapon, but, um, what, what I'm getting at is a lot of those keys just end up getting salvaged.
And now when all keys can sort of carry weight through various torment tiers, um, getting a nightmare key is this interesting choice of like, well, do I keep it or do I run it now?
Because if I keep it, I can just use it at a later time.
And it's really about giving player, uh, the players that choice on when do they want to run this content?
We're not just going to invalidate that key and say, oh, and torment two, you need to find a new key to do this thing.
Um, so I think it's definitely making key management a lot easier and more fluid as well.
Um, and one thing on the pit, Aislinn that I think is really interesting is, uh, we definitely have rescaled the pit, uh, tier 100 is sort of like our 200 on live.
Um, but I think that's something that, uh, you know, we, we definitely want to keep an eye out on PTR.
We don't have any problems with increasing the amount of pit tiers.
Like this is something we can definitely revisit if we see in PTR that you're all are, are insane, which is something we can definitely revisit.
We really like that. It's a razor and measuring stick, and we don't want to take that away from players.
So, um, that's something that we want to get PTR feedback and we could really use your help in breaking that system and seeing how far you can push it.
Oh yeah, that's a great point. And, you know, like we've said on this stream, there are going to be a lot of new player power opportunities coming.
And so, yeah, please show us what you got, as they say.
Okay, so let's talk about, uh, let's just dive a little more into the details.
Uh, I think we went over a lot of this stuff already.
Uh, but we can kind of go through this slide here.
Um, so yeah, all content in the game exists within an expanded difficulty tier selection.
Like we were talking about, um, I think an important thing to call it here is that, for example, penitent, um, is if you're comparing it just to like kind of understand what it's going to look like relative to live right now.
Uh, penitent's kind of going to end up being like world tier two, if you added 45 monster levels on top of it.
And that's intended to kind of be the upper echelon of like pre max level, um, character leveling.
So if you really want to amp up the difficulty to as hard as you can make it, like going on dependent is, is where you want to be.
Uh, and this is just a lovely little visual aid.
We've got some cool new icons for these, uh, difficulty tiers.
Um, normal, hard expert and penitent.
It gets harder as you keep going.
Um, okay.
So yeah.
And we really want this to be like opt in not progression locked.
Um, and so the vanilla Diablo four difficulty tiers kind of operated as progression tiers.
Right.
And what I mean by progression tiers is the moment you get to world tier three, as Colin was saying,
like you unlock sacred items.
Maybe you go into a dungeon so you can find a sacred weapon and these things unlock so quickly and they drop so frequently that you kind of just got this huge burst of power and you never really got to feel that power.
Um, and we want to make sure that you are like feeling each upgrade you get in the game and it feels really, really punchy.
Uh, and we really want these new difficulty tiers to be player guided.
Like we want you to be able to make your own decisions on when you're moving on to the next one and what's the right pace for you.
And of course these new difficulty tiers are going to give you, uh, improving rewards.
You're going to find more gold, more experience, and you're going to have more loot efficiency per difficulty tier.
So the higher difficulty tier you can fight the game on, the more efficient your experience is going to be effectively.
Yeah.
I think that's really good.
Go ahead, Charles.
Go ahead, Kyle.
Yeah.
I just say that's really like what I view is the differentiating factor between, you know, what current B4 is and, and in the new patch 2.0 is you, if you enter torment one, you can find the best item in torment one.
You could complete your character and get full best in slot and everything.
It's just going to take a while, right?
It's going to be less efficient.
You're going to be getting less loot.
And as, whereas in, in the live game right now, right, you just can't find the best things in world tier three.
You, you are kind of obligated to go to that world tier four.
And now if you're able to clear higher torments with efficiency, that's just going to be the best option for you to find the gear more efficiently, but you aren't forced into torment four to find the best items in the game.
Yeah.
That's something I've really liked about it is that, you know, you, we get to start the end game a lot earlier with torment, right?
Because there's, there's nothing that you're excluded from.
There's no awesome piece of loot that you can't find by torment one.
And so you get to, you get to really start to test your build after it's, it's kind of gotten some real optimization.
I think much earlier into the journey than before.
Yeah.
I couldn't agree more Jeevan.
And like a great example of that is what we're doing with the ladder bosses or the lair bosses.
All of those unlock in torment one, the cost to summon them is static.
It remains the same throughout all the torment tiers.
And what that means is if you can beat it on a higher torment tier, you're going to get way more uniques.
So you get a handful of unique starting in torment one, way more uniques and obviously torment four, but the cost, because it remains static, we're not going to ask you to get anything extra like a city and stone.
That just means as long as you can kill that torment four boss, you're getting way more efficiency out of the boss.
I mean, it really is like this.
It feels amazing to sort of progress through those torment tiers and just unlock way more power opportunity.
Yeah, we don't really have this differentiation of like a regular version of the late game boss, like a regular version of Durial and then the tormented echo of Durial.
That's not really a distinction that we have anymore.
Whereas like previously it would cost, you know, more materials to summon the tormented version, but it would give more rewards.
Now it's the same cost across the different torment tiers.
It's just if you're able to conquer him on torment four, that's where you're going to get the absolute most bang for your buck in terms of resources in to loot out.
Yeah, and I want to just double down on like torment one is where the end game starts now and just each torment here that you're ascending is making your end game, you know, more fun, basically, because you're going to be getting cooler stuff or more frequently.
Okay, so enough about difficulty tiers. Let's move on to some itemization changes.
So item strength, we have what I like to call the item power shuffle happening in patch 2.0 items with item power above five 540 are going to be adjusted to 540.
And I fixed bands in lieu of this, or in addition to this rather, are going to be adjusted as well.
So yeah, items at the new character level max are going to, they're going to max out at 750.
And that's not actually the highest item power that's going to be in the game.
And we'll talk about that more in just a second.
But most items you're going to be finding once you hit max character level will be item power 750.
And you're going to be finding much better item power items from levels 51 to 59.
There's going to be big item power jumps.
So once you start leveling your character past those original 50 character levels, you're going to start finding a lot better gear.
Okay, so let's take a look at what an ancestral item looks like in patch 2.0.
Oh, could we? Yeah, let's, let's take a look here real quick.
So you'll notice here that this item has 800 item power, which is 50 higher than the max 750 that I was talking about before.
You'll also notice on the right hand side that that is the torment icon.
So ancestral items can be found starting on torment one.
They're going to become more frequent as you ascend torment difficulties, but they're still going to stay pretty rare throughout all torment levels.
You'll also notice that the greater a fix on this item is highlighted.
That is because now whenever you find an ancestral item, they're always going to have one greater a fix.
They can roll with more, but they will be guaranteed a single one every single time.
So let's dive in more into the details.
Right. Aislinn is part of finding a greater a fix on live right now is sometimes it's on life per second.
That's like, oh, okay. Got a greater a fix on life per second.
But now when you see an ancestral item, it's always going to have a greater a fix.
And that ancestral I power bump, the a fix bump is going to feel really good.
Even if you miss that a fix, it's still a huge upgrade to your character if you haven't found one of these before.
Yeah. And sometimes, right, you get an item that has multiple greater a fix is on live and it's, you know, it's not at 925.
It's not at the highest item power. And that that's kind of a mixed bag, right?
Like, well, it's kind of good, but it's, you know, a lower lower item power.
And now things with greater a fix is will be definitionally at that highest highest item power.
Yes.
Okay. So let's talk about the details here.
So sacred items are not going to drop anymore.
They're kaput.
You're going to be looking at normal items pre-torments, and then you're going to be chasing ancestral items once you are in torment tiers.
So, yeah, starting in torment one, they're going to start to drop.
As I said, they're going to become more common as you go up.
But again, they're going to stay fairly rare.
They're never going to, you know, be like the only thing that's dropping.
Ancestral items are intended to be where you're finding forever items.
So when you find like a really good ancestral weapon or, you know, of whatever slot that you may not have an ancestral item for, that's going to be a big moment.
That's going to be an exciting moment where you're going to get something a lot better because they also have their own affix band as well.
So these ancestral items are going to have better affixes than their non ancestral counterparts to something to note is that greater affixes only drop on ancestral items.
You're not going to be finding greater affixes on non ancestral.
So when you see a greater affix drop on the ground, you're going to know that that is an ancestral item.
Ancestral items also have two tempering slots up from one on non ancestral and they're masterworkable up to 12, whereas non ancestral are masterworkable up to four.
And finally, they are going to have higher aspect ranks, too.
So you're going to find legendary aspects that become better on ancestral items.
And Charles, we actually added a ton of power to legendary aspects to accommodate this.
We didn't just sort of readjust where those those power bands are coming from.
Yeah, all of the legendary aspects that now scale a little bit further into the ancestral tier.
We basically just tacked on five new levels kind of on top of the current value.
So you're just going to find even more powerful legendary effects than you have currently in the new ancestral tier.
It's going to be a lot of fun to find those.
OK, let's move on to Paragon.
Paragon.
So we have some pretty big glyph updates coming with patch 2.0.
There's been a significant rework to how many ranks you can earn on any given glyph from 21 to 100, which is a lot of new ranks.
But we want to make sure that there's still texture in that system.
Right.
And so because of that, we also have a new legend rather a new glyph rarity legendary.
So once you upgrade a glyph to rank 46, it becomes a legendary glyph, which you can see here on the right.
This spirit glyph is level 50.
So it's past that 46 mark.
It's legendary.
You're going to get a glyph radius increase at rank 15, which is already in the live game.
But you're also going to get another radius increase at rank 46 when it becomes legendary.
And this is making them bigger than they could have been previously.
So you're going to get more space with your glyphs because of this.
And when a glyph becomes legendary, it also unlocks a significant bonus more so than it did before.
And you can see that on the bottom of this glyph here.
It's got the legendary bonus increases critical strike damage by 21.6%.
And it's very important to note that this is a multiplicative bonus.
This 21.6% is not an additive bonus.
So you're going to be getting a lot of power from that bonus there.
Something else I want to bring up is that glyphs are moving to the pit.
So you're going to be upgrading your glyphs in the pit.
You're no longer going to be upgrading them in nightmare dungeons.
And it's going to be an attempt based system.
So when you finish a pit run, you're going to go to the end and you're going to be able to have some chances to level up your glyph.
And increase their ranks.
And if you are in a pit that is 10 tiers higher than your current glyph, you're going to have guaranteed success.
And for every 20 pit tiers that the pit level you're in is higher than your current glyph that you're trying to upgrade, you're going to get bonus ranks so that you can accelerate the process.
Do you want to speak more to that, Colin?
Yeah, I think this is a really important note because you could easily look at the rank 100 and be like, oh, my God, the grind is even longer.
But based on how that upgrade chance works, it's guaranteed as long as you're beating pit tiers that are higher than your glyph.
And then how that bonus map ends up playing out is if you're beating, for example, a pit tier 30, that's roughly somewhere between today's world tier three and four.
You can upgrade a glyph from one to 15 and three runs.
So you think about the difference between today's game and patch 2.0, you're getting those glyphs leveled way faster if you're pushing that difficulty.
And what we really wanted to do here was we've heard a ton of feedback around how the XP system for Nightmare Dungeons feels really grindy.
It also just doesn't serve the Nightmare Dungeons very well.
Right. It's like, how do I get to the end as fast as possible, but nothing in the dungeon matters.
Right. And that what that does is in the pit, it's all about speed and efficiency, and it sort of embraces that.
And we think that that's just really going to accelerate your pit glyph upgrading speed and the chance you could sort of want to be really clear with the chance.
The chance based system is essentially there because it felt really bad when it was binary.
Like when we said, hey, you need to beat the pit tier or you need to beat a pit that's 10 levels higher than your glyph.
And if you don't, you get nothing that just felt really bad.
So the chance is not there to increase the grind or slow down progression.
It's actually just there to protect from like it feeling just terrible to not get literally anything from that run.
So again, to be clear, it's 100% chance as long as you're pushing difficulty.
We think that this fits the content a lot better.
We've heard a ton of feedback around like the pit rewards feeling lackluster, and there's not really a reason to push difficulty.
You know, you sort of just want to hone in on like 90 or 101, depending on where you're at in terms of your progression journey on live.
This system really encourages you to push and gives you a tangible reward every single time you do it.
Yeah.
And I think it's important that there's the consistency of like the communication between right.
So, hey, my glyphs are currently level 50.
Well, what kind of pit tier should I be approaching to upgrade these?
Well, somewhere in the range of 50 to 60, right?
You're just a little bit higher so that you can keep pushing that harder content.
And also, if you have a glyph down at level one, because maybe you haven't paid attention to that glyph, it's going to level up much faster if you are already you already proven yourself proven that you can hang in and pit to your 50, for instance, you're going to level those up very quickly.
I think that's also cool is if you have a build that you feel isn't doing as well as you go up in torment, it makes it a lot easier to kind of snap something back in and catch up faster.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, the further you progress, the easier it is to to level those up.
So here we have a video basically just showing off what the new UI looks like for upgrading a glyph in patch 2.0.
So you can see that it's showing you the current pit level you're on, the current success chance to get a rank up.
And something else I want to call out is that when you are.
Oh, yes. Right.
So this is rank 45 to 46 explicitly, which is the moment where you are increasing a glyph from rare to legendary.
And something important to note about that is that it does cost a fairly significant amount of gym fragments as well.
But it's giving you that increased radius size and the new multiplicative legendary bonus, which is pretty sick.
And here we have an example of showing how the radius gets even bigger in patch 2.0.
I want to call out here that the midpoint says level 21.
That is not correct.
It is level 15 where the radius increases.
But yeah, previously there were only there was only one radius increase.
Now with legendary glyphs at rank 46, there is a second radius increase.
OK, so let's talk about some more stuff related to Paragon.
We have realm partitioning for Paragon now.
And this is kind of getting into all things that Colin was talking about.
We have realm based Paragon points now.
So your Paragon points are going to be shared across an entire realm.
And remember that what a realm is, is like either seasonal soft core or seasonal hardcore or the same for eternal.
Those are realms.
And these Paragon points are going to stay latent on a pre level 60 character.
And what that means is that, you know, if you have, let's say, 150 Paragon points on a realm,
those Paragon points will remain inactive on any character that's pre level 60.
But once you hit level 60 on that character, they will have those 150 Paragon points.
And it's also important to note that any Paragon points you earn on any of your characters in that realm are going to be shared among all characters in that realm.
So if you earn 25 or 50 Paragon points on one character and then hop over to your alt, you're going to have 25 or 50 more Paragon points to spend on that character too.
And in addition to this change, we have a pretty hefty Paragon level increase.
So right now the current max besides renown and altar of Lilith bonuses is 200.
And we're increasing that up to 300, which is going to give you a lot more levels to chase throughout any given season.
Okay. And in light of these changes coming to Paragon, we've made some adjustments to the way that boards work as well.
So because we're offering so much more power with legendary glyphs and they mean so much more to your build,
you know, we're, we're looking to set a maximum for the number of Paragon boards that you can equip at any given time.
And this is also because, you know, on live right now, the best strategy is to aim for as many glyph slots as possible.
You just go off. You oftentimes ignore whatever legendary node bonus you're getting just for the glyph slot.
And we want to make sure that you're really focusing on these legendary nodes and that you're focusing on these really cool legendary glyphs that you're getting.
And, and really think about those choices instead of gunning for like every single glyph, for example.
This also complements the additional, I was just going to say this, this really helps complement the additional 100 more levels.
Like we've heard a lot of feedback that it feels really flat once you hit 100, that there's just no more progression.
You don't really need to kill any of the monsters anymore unless it's explicitly to get the, the loot drop off of them.
And that, that, that kind of feels bad, right?
Like I'm walking through this dungeon and like I get literally nothing out of killing these, these monsters.
So with the board limit, we've packed a ton of power with additional Paragon levels to grind a ton of power with the legendary glyphs.
But it also creates a situation where once you're sort of, you've achieved all those different things, you don't feel so bad necessarily around not getting to that Paragon level 300.
At a certain point, you start to really just sort of really need to hone in on your build and those extra Paragon points are going to start providing you more of a show of sort of how badass you are and give you incremental progress.
incremental progress that's a little bit less sort of demanding that you must grind through all of this content to unlock every part of your Paragon board.
Yeah.
Yeah. And something I'm pretty excited about this is that, you know, sometimes on live, it can feel like my goal is to get a new Paragon board.
And as soon as I achieve that, my goal is to get a new Paragon board and get off the one I just unlocked.
And I think this change really lets me kind of explore the boards and think about what specific route optimizations I want to take.
And lets me personalize that a little more, which I'm a pretty big fan of.
Well, I know we have a, we just went through a ton of content right here with all the changes that are coming for progression to Paragon to itemization.
I know it was a lot for people to hear.
We will actually have a blog immediately up after the stream that will kind of also explain a little bit more of this to players so that they can actually get a understanding of what that is.
A understanding in their own cadence of like what it, what is going to be changing with patch 2.0 for Diablo 4 in regards to some of the progression items.
I know Colin, we're seeing a lot in chat of like, you know, people are noting like, hey, this, this feels a little D3-ish in ways.
I don't know if you wanted to chat or like comment on that a little bit more.
Yeah, I'm happy to.
It's definitely familiar, right?
So we thought a lot about like, what is the right way to address the player feedback of we've gotten a bunch of feedback around like World Tier 5, World Tier 6, World Tier 7, right?
I want to be able to level up the challenge in the game.
I want to be able to get more efficiency.
And we wanted to do it in a way that was leaning into what we saw you all were really resonating with, which is getting to the end game faster.
And we felt like, okay, well, we could add a World Tier 5 and add ancestral, uber ancestral and increase the level cap.
But that would mean you just need to grind more to get to that point where you're finding your forever items, doing item modification.
And we get out of World Tier 6, uber, uber ancestral, right?
And it just sort of made us reevaluate what is important.
And it's what's important to us is getting people into the end game, getting people finding their forever items, smashing monsters, getting more powerful sort of item modification and efficiency.
So that was part of it.
And then the other part of it, I'd say, is I think Diablo 4 more than any Diablo has had a ton of item customization and power along the leveling journey, which really makes the leveling progression feel different, right?
Like if you're tempering, if you're imbuing aspects, if you're really min-maxing your reward scheme, you can really push difficulty tiers early.
If you've played D3 hard is really the only real difficulty, right?
But because we have so many different ways to grow your power, we think that represents a pretty fun challenge of like, how do I take all these pieces and really push as early as I can to get to that max level faster?
And one more thing that's really important to note is the jumps between Torments are pretty enormous.
We don't expect you to sort of play it like today's D3, where you essentially log in, get your Hedrigg set, and hop right into Torment 16.
The jumps are actually pretty enormous between Torment 1 and 2, and it creates this really fun progression through those Torment tiers, and it feels like a meaningful step forward when you get into Torment 2 and then a Torment 3.
We're hoping this doesn't necessarily feel like a two-hour sort of journey through the Torment tiers, and then now you're in Torment 4, and that's how you play the rest of the game.
Awesome.
Yeah, and also, one thing I'll add is, you know, shouts to Twitch chat, everything that you say, hey, you like what we're doing, big dub, we appreciate it, much love for the response.
Also, all the people in Twitch chat who are like, I don't like this, this isn't working for me.
Much appreciation the same, you know, we're looking at what you're saying, we're thinking about it, and we're going to try to incorporate it and make the game better.
And I think it's interesting, I'm seeing the sort of Diablo 3 references, and it's like, from our perspective, if something really worked well in Diablo 3, that's more important to us to do the thing that the players felt like was working for them than anything else, right?
The fact that we've done it before in any form, to me, wouldn't stop us from doing the right thing, you know what I mean?
Yeah, and I just do it the right way.
I just said, do it the right way for D4.
Sorry, go ahead, Adam.
This is the difficulty of doing everything remote, it feels like we're like, it's like a Zoom call, but interrupting each other.
And also, big, big shout out to Twitch chat for calling out Jeevan's cord management.
I've seen that message a few times already.
But, so, thanks Aislinn, thank you, Colin.
I know Colin's going to be joining us more on a couple other topics, but we still have a lot to talk about in this stream.
And the next thing that we do want to talk about is class changes and everything.
And so, Charles will be taking us through all the class changes for Patch 2.0.
Yeah, awesome.
So, before we get into some of the slides and details, I just wanted to thank Colin and Aislinn for talking about all the systemic updates that are coming,
and how we're going to test your character and how you're going to progress through it.
But my topic is going to be a bit more about what are the exact abilities and skills and new legendary effects and uniques that you're going to get to take on these awesome challenges that are set up through the difficulty tier system.
And also, a slight disclaimer, you know, PTR is a very early build for whatever is going to go live on Patch 2.0.
And some of the assets that we've captured here are also still, you know, early on.
And so, some of the exact numbers or some of the wording may slightly be changed.
So, definitely refer to the patch notes, which we're going to be publishing right after the stream for the exact details and, you know, kind of final, in air quotes, numbers that are going to go on the PTR.
And, of course, it still may be subject to change before we actually launch Patch 2.0 live.
All right.
So, with that out of the way, let's start talking about some of the tempering changes that are going to come in Patch 2.0.
So, tempering is a system that we introduced back in Season of Loot Reborn, Season 4, that gave you a way to really customize your items and kind of make your build your own.
And we've received a lot of feedback on the tempering system, and we're really committed to iterating on and making sure this system is the best it can possibly be going forward.
One of the key points of feedback that we heard was around weapon tempers.
So, these affixes that you get to attach to your weapons, right?
Your weapons are your big, important part of your build and your character.
And there was a big disparity here, where some affixes that were on weapon tempering were multiplicatively increasing your player power, right?
Things like double projectiles or things of that nature or bash cleaving, which was a multiplicative bonus.
And others, not so much, right?
You had some other ones that were more duration or size effect, and they just were hard to compare against each other.
And so, going forward in Patch 2.0, we've made all weapon tempering affixes multiplicative damage increases, oftentimes to very specific skills.
And to accommodate this, we already have one bonus projectiles, and now we're going to have new affixes that give skills chance to deal double damage,
which means if it triggers the chance to deal double damage, the entire skill is just going to do twice as much damage as before.
Every hit of it will deal double damage. It's kind of an all or nothing kind of deal.
And then the chance to hit twice is the chance for any time it deals damage, you just get an extra hit of damage.
And this allows you to trigger things like lucky hit procs or anything that counts the number of times you deal damage.
That's going to trigger an extra time with the hit twice.
Offensive tempering affixes, these are the ones that can also go on your weapons but can go on other spots as well.
These are going to be additive damage increases.
And these will often be to broader categories like bonus fire damage or bonus critical strike damage.
And whereas the weapon temperers are often talking to more specific skills.
And so here we can see an example with the shadow augments execution where we have the sever projectiles chance to cast twice.
But now we've got new ones that are chance for reap to hit twice.
So you cast reap and every target you hit, there's just a chance to get two hits on that target instead of one.
And corpse explosion, whenever you cast corpse explosion, there is a chance for the entire skill to deal double damage to every target that it hits.
Additionally, we moved those size and duration affixes, which we think are really cool and really interesting ways of modifying your skills.
We've moved those over to the utility category.
So they're not directly competing with these multiplicative damage increases.
You're not going to feel bad that, oh, I'm missing out on damage just to make my area hit a little bit larger or to have a longer duration on a buff.
So there's not as much opportunity cost to investing in those size and duration affixes, which are still really cool ways to customize your character.
We just don't want them to compete with damage.
And finally, we know that oftentimes tempering leads itself to, hey, I see this list of five or even six affixes sometimes.
We really are going to try to be limiting tempering recipes to at most four affixes that could possibly roll on them, just to give you a little bit better odds of actually hitting the one that you care about and the one that you want.
And just to be a little bit easier to kind of comprehend.
And even so, we're trying to set this limit at four, but oftentimes we're aiming for just three on the recipe, depending on how the grouping them together in ways that make sense.
So this is an active area that we're working on, really trying to make sure that it's not quite it's easier for you to get the right affix out of the tempering recipe by limiting that the number that are on there.
All right. Next up, we've got changes to ultimate skills.
So ultimate skills can now gain skill ranks.
This is probably pretty self-explanatory, but just like every other skill in the game, ultimate skills can now be ranked up to rank five in the skill tree.
And just like every other skill, increasing the skill rank will increase the damage output of your ultimate skills.
But it's also going to give you cooldown reduction on these ultimate skills as well.
So oftentimes other skills, you just kind of get one or the other.
All right. Sometimes it's a cooldown reduction. Sometimes it's a damage or healing increase.
On ultimate skills, you're going to get kind of the best of both worlds.
It's going to be increasing the damage output and reducing the cooldown.
And finally, effects that do grant bonus skill ranks on this, such as, you know, Harlequin's Crest, the Shaco, that gives plus to all skill ranks.
These are only going to apply to ultimate skills that you've already learned in the skill tree.
And this is to make sure that you still can only equip one ultimate skill.
You can't like get plus ranks to to all skills and then suddenly have access to four ultimate skills.
We still don't want that. We still want you to just pick one.
But you're just going to be getting you're going to be able to really juice that that ultimate skill up.
If you really want to make, you know, lacerate be really strong, that's going to be a powerful effect that you can invest more skill points into.
All right. So those are some of the general updates.
Let's now talk about the new content coming for each individual class, starting here with our barbarian.
All right. So sometimes you're playing as a barbarian and you experience a problem, right?
You are standing here and there is an enemy over there.
What to do? Well, a good barbarian is going to throw their weapon at the enemy over there to kill them at a distance.
Right. So now we've got a new skill called mighty throw.
It's going to hurl your weapon at an enemy. It's going to deal damage on impact.
And then it's going to stick in the ground and do some pulses of damage over time.
So even if the initial impact doesn't kill them, there's going to be some extra pulses there.
Additionally, we've got some upgrades for it, just like our other skills.
Enhanced mighty throw is going to increase your attack speed while the weapon is out.
And then you can either opt in a fighter's mighty throw, which is going to give bonuses to that pulsing damage.
It causes your weapon swaps to pulse for more and give you a bit of barrier.
Or you can opt into a warrior's mighty throw, which is going to dramatically increase the initial impact damage.
And it's going to stun enemies on impact.
Let's take a video clip of this in action.
All right. So we've got Barb. Just a simple example here with a few enemies.
You know, throws out this, you know, ephemeral version of the weapon, lands, deals a big chunk of damage,
and then pulses over time before returning back to you.
I was a huge fan of double throw in Diablo 2. So this is really exciting.
Yeah, it looks sweet too. It kind of like bluish yellow, like ancient-y kind of color scheme to it.
The VFX looks awesome on it.
So range barb is definitely happening in patch 2.0.
For sure. If you want to spec really heavily into this, yeah, you're going to be throwing weapons out like crazy.
All right. So we've also got some new key passives and new legendary paragon nodes for every class here.
So for Barbarian, we've got Barbed Carapace. This is a key passive.
So it's going to increase your thorns based on how much fear you're spending.
And whenever you cast a skill with a cooldown, it's going to grant you unhindered for a duration,
which allows you to move through enemies.
And then enemies that are close to you are going to take bonus or going to take damage from your thorns every second.
You're going to kind of pulse damage of your thorns every second.
Now, this is really cool. It really enables a thorns barb, which we had a little bit of support for.
But, you know, one of the big problems with thorns is that you really wanted enemies to hit you and hit you quickly.
And this gives you another alternative to deal bonus damage or to really pay off for building up all that thorns with this new key passive.
Additionally, we've got a legendary paragon node, the force of nature.
Your earthquakes have a chance to spawn dust devils and your earthquake damage is going to be increased by your damage against close enemies.
So this is really plays into these these earthquakes and dust devil effects, which we kind of call sub powers internally.
These effects that are not skills that you cast directly, but, you know, some of your legendary effects will will spawn these earthquakes and dust devils.
This is just a new way to to really power those up and blend them together in the same build.
Additionally, we're adding some new passives to the skill tree.
And this is really helped to to give you a way along with ultimate skill ranks to spend a lot of those new points that you're getting by leveling up from 50 to 60.
You know, those new skill points you're getting. We're giving you some new new ways to invest those.
All right. We also got some new items, of course.
We've got the ugly bastard helm, a new unique helm for barbarians.
And it makes you so ugly that whenever you are berserking, all of your damage is converted into fire damage.
And so that's really interesting. You know, barbarians always had this little bit of like light fire theme.
You had a few different effects that dealt fire damage.
And now if you really want to play a fire barb, this is the unique helm for you.
Also playing into that, we've got aspect of flaming rampage, which causes your charge to deal some fire damage.
And aspect of shuddering steel, which will cause your steel grasp and iron maelstrom to do some bonus physical damage.
All right. Moving on to the druid.
The druid gets a new skill, a new core skill, in fact, called stone burst.
And this is a core skill that's channeled. It kind of has a very unique kind of input mechanism compared to pretty much any other skill in Diablo 4.
And as you're channeling it, you target an area.
And as you channel it, the affected area grows in size over about one second of channeling.
And at any point you can release the channel and it's going to deal a big burst of damage to whatever size you kind of landed on there.
You could tap it really quickly and just do one pulse of damage to a small area or you can channel up for a little bit longer and hit a much wider area,
depending on the exact combat scenario you find yourself in or how the enemies are distributed on the battlefield here.
Of course, we've got our upgrades that increase damage to the enemies hit in the initial radius.
So, you know, really doubling down on that single target capability of a core skill.
And Primal Stone Burst gives you some attack speed and Raging Stone Burst will dramatically increase the spirit cost, but also give it a ton more damage.
So if you have a ton of spirit generation, then that might be the upgrade you look for in Stone Burst.
Let's see a video of this in action.
All right. So you see it ticks up. There's like three different levels, like small, medium and large.
In this one, the Druid kind of held it for a while, but you could release it at any time.
And so here you see just kind of rapid firing a lot of quick, small shots just because they knew that would be enough to clear out the enemies here.
And also while you're channeling it does some pulses of damage to enemies in that area as well.
The channel explosion is so satisfying to blow up just so many monsters.
Yeah, it gets huge and it looks so sweet too.
I really hats off to the VFX artists who worked on making these look so beautiful.
The new skills here.
All right. So of course, Druid also has new passives, a new key passive called One with Nature that really empowers companion builds.
You know, we've heard a lot that players love playing with companions.
They're wolves, they're poison creepers, they're ravens.
And this is going to be the key passive for you.
So all of your companion skills gain an additional companion and they deal increased damage.
And there's also a little bonus basically with the you gain the passive effect of all of the companion skills.
Now, if you're taking this key passive, you're probably taking these companions anyway.
But just in case, you know, your build is such that, well, I just want to take, you know, two out of the three.
Right. I can put wolves and poison creeper on my bar.
But, you know, maybe you you don't have enough skill slots to put in ravens.
You're still going to be able to get the passive effect of that when you take this key passive because we just want you to have tons of these companions really leading leading the charge here.
We've also got Untamed, a new legendary paragon node that plays right into this One with Nature key passive.
Casting the companion skill is going to increase the companion.
Companion active skill will grant you bonus ranks to all of your companion skills for a time to really buff up the damage of those.
Just like before, we've got some new passives coming into the skill tree as well.
I think some of these might have some temporary icons on them.
So like I said, these were from an early build.
Some of the icons or very specific art might be adjusted.
So, you know, bear with us. This is the nature of PTR and early development.
All right, moving on to some of the items or oh, no, we've got a video.
All right, a video of really leading a wolf pack here.
Right. So this this includes wolves with the storm's companion to turn them into light werewolves.
And I'm sure there's some other ones here like aspect of the stampede is probably involved.
You just have what is that seven wolves following you around.
You really get to lead the wolf pack with this.
This is this is the best video in our presentation.
Well, actually, no, sorry. This is the second best video in our presentation.
You guys will see the best video in our presentation.
But I see it's so good. Yeah. For all you werewolf lovers out there.
This this one is going to be really sweet.
I'm really looking forward to playing with this in patch 2.0.
All right. So new items. So they've got the Stone of Vehemmin.
This is a unique totem that's going to empower your stone burst, the new core skill.
So channeling it is going to grant you some damage reduction.
And the final explosion will deal increased damage based on how long you were channeling it.
So this just really encourage you to build it up to that max size and let off a huge explosion and gives you some damage reduction.
So you're kind of standing still for a bit. That's OK. You get a bit of bonus damage reduction.
We've got a little bit more legendaries on Druid than the other classes just because Stone Burst being a core skill.
We know that the kind of bar to make a core skill really viable and useful.
It does need a good amount of legendary items to support it to really make a full build out of it.
So that's why we've added two legendaries here for Stone Burst.
We've got the aspect of Anticline Burst, which causes Stone Burst to deal increased damage.
And if you cast it at or above 100 spirit here, it's going to immediately be at that maximum size.
So you don't necessarily need to channel it as long as you are casting it when you have a lot of spirit.
This synergizes really well with the Earth and Might key passive, which gives you full spirit when it triggers.
So you can trigger Earth and Might and then immediately get a huge stone burst.
We've got an aspect of Shattered Defenses, which alters Stone Burst in a rather interesting way.
It causes Stone Burst or Stone Burst causes enemies to take increased damage from your other skills for a time and reduces Stone Burst spirit cost.
This kind of converts Stone Burst away from necessarily being your primary damage source to being a bit more of a setup skill.
Right. You can kind of debuff enemies and then, you know, you can find some interesting builds where you have other ways of spending your spirit, maybe another core skill or Boulder or some other primary damage source.
And then you can use Stone Burst to kind of set up that build. Really interesting to see how players, well, you know, what kind of builds you make with Shattered Defenses.
Additionally, we've got Aspect of the Rabid Bear, which empowers your Grizzly Rage to apply rabies and increases your poison output.
Stormcrow, which is just lightning ravens. You know, your ravens are not lightning. It looks awesome.
And Aspect of the Agile Wolf, which gives Shred a fourth attack. Shred normally is like a three part combo.
And now it's a four part combo that deals even more damage on that fourth hit. And it's going to knock down enemies as well.
All right. So that is Druid really looking forward to playing some Druid in 2.0.
But let's move on to the Necromancer because we've got a lot to get through.
We've got Soul Rift. This is a new darkness ultimate skill.
So Necromancers kind of had three ultimates already. They had one that was blood, one that was bone, and one that was related to summoning.
And now we've kind of completed it and we've added a darkness or shadow damage ultimate.
Soul Rift creates an area around your character, kind of follows with you, that just constantly deals damage over time.
And it's going to be sucking out the souls of enemies who you're hitting.
And every time it sucks out a soul from an enemy, you're going to gain some essence and you're going to gain a barrier.
So you can stack up this barrier. It helps you be survivable and it deals really good damage over time.
Supreme Soul Rift gives you bonus damage for every soul that you absorb.
And Prime Soul Rift causes the soul absorption to also apply vulnerable.
Let's take a video of this in action here.
All right. So enemies all are all coming up.
The barrier is super useful, Charles, right?
Now that you have another way to give yourself defenses.
Necro has historically had some trouble with that, right?
Yeah, absolutely.
I think that's a really important part here.
And when we get to the next slide, talk about some of the passives.
We'll highlight we're adding a bit more barrier into the Necromancer's kit.
You know, blood Necromancers always had a really easy time surviving.
They had a lot of Fortify and a lot of max health.
And really, the other ones like the Bone and Shadow Necro didn't have quite as much survivability.
And so now we're introducing more barrier in more places to ensure that non-blood Necromancer builds, the Shadow and the Bone and Summon Necros, have a bit more survivability and are able to scale into that late game pretty well.
All right. So as I mentioned, the new passive.
So they have a new key passive called Affliction that there's this new concept of Affliction where applying vulnerable, crowd control or shadow damage over time effects to enemies will apply them with Affliction, which is going to make them take increased damage from you and your minions.
Additionally, when you apply a curse skill to someone or to an enemy who has this Affliction, you're going to do a big chunk of shadow damage.
So this kind of turns your curse skills, your Decrepify and Iron Maiden, into offensive skills.
You can curse an area and then they take a big chunk of damage as well.
And this will scale up with the bonus damage that you've dealt or that you are the bonus affixes that you have for that crowd control, vulnerable and shadow damage.
And along that same theme, the new legendary Paragon node, Frailty, is going to cause cursed enemies to take more damage from you.
And so it plays very nicely with the Affliction key passive.
And once again, more skill tree passives to spend those extra points on.
And I want to highlight Necrotic Fortitude here in the upper right that gives you just a generic passive that gives you a chance, a lucky hit chance to gain a barrier.
And so that's going to be really good for anybody who wants just a bit more bump of survivability and to play into the more barrier focused on Necromancer.
Yeah, going back to Affliction really quick. I love the idea of using my curses offensively, like as a damage skill.
I think that's going to be such a blast.
Yeah, it's really cool to just, yeah, definitely going to be blasting with them.
I think it's really thematic too. I love playing with it.
It pairs really well with the utility changes now that we have way more size increases in utility.
It gives you so many more utility options. Those curses get pretty huge and it feels great.
Yeah, for all of us who just want to win by debuff spamming, I love that one.
Absolutely. All right, let's talk about some of the new items coming for Necromancer here.
So we've got a new unique item, the Unmaker, a unique helm.
This is going to empower the Soul Rift, the new ultimate skill.
Of course, you gain some skill ranks to Soul Rift, because now ultimate skills have skill ranks.
And every 30 essence that you spend while Soul Rift is active will increase its duration up to eight seconds.
So as long as you're active and kind of spending the essence with the Unmaker, you're going to have a very long duration of Soul Rift.
And then for every essence that you gain while it's active, which absorbing the souls does trigger essence gain,
you're going to do a pulse of damage around you, some bonus damage.
And so I really encourage you to just keep Soul Rift up all the time, be constantly gaining and spending the essence.
And it's going to be really, really fun to make that build work.
Additionally, we've got Reaping Lotus Aspect.
This empowers your Sever, your core skill.
Sever will no longer return to you.
Previously, Sever was kind of an out-and-back situation.
Now it just goes out and then it splits into three Spectres at the end, deals some extra bonus damage.
And then that's the end of the Sever.
So it really does empower it on the swing out and looks really cool.
We've got Aspect of Fel Gluttony that empowers your Golem.
Whenever you cast your Golems active, deals a big pulse of damage around it.
And your Golem will then consume corpses to reduce its cooldown.
So anybody who really wants to build around making your Golem as strong as possible, this is going to be the Aspect for you.
And finally, we've got Phasing Poltergeists Aspect, which causes your Bone Spirit to split into three Spirits that deal a percentage of the damage as well.
I think we got a video clip of this one because it looks really sweet.
So you cast Bone Spirit at one target and then it spawns three little mini Bone Spirits to seek out nearby enemies as well.
So it kind of gives you increased area of effect.
And if there's just one target, of course, it'll reconverge back on that same target as well.
But also just adds a bit more AOE capability for your Bone Spirit build.
Very cool.
All right.
So Rogue.
Rogue gets Dance of Knives.
This is a new channeled skill for Rogue.
It's an agility cutthroat skill.
And it also has a pretty interesting mechanic where it has some charges that will recharge.
And how long you can channel it is based on how many charges you have.
It's going to take one charge per second of channeling.
But there's no energy cost or just like a normal cooldown.
Here you can just channel it as long as you have charges.
And while you're channeling it, you're going to be spinning around.
You're going to be throwing knives at enemies nearby.
And you're going to gain some movement speed and dodge chance.
It really is kind of like a spin to win kind of build on Rogue here.
You've got Enhanced Dance of Knives which gives you some charge refund as you're moving with it.
Because that's what you really want to encourage is this constant motion.
This forward momentum.
And Methodical Dance of Knives drops some stun grenades when you finish channeling.
Or Disciplined Dance of Knives will slow enemies and have a chance to pierce through the enemies that you're throwing the daggers at.
Let's take a look at this in action.
So here we've got the Rogue just going spinning, throwing some daggers around at everyone.
And yeah.
This is awesome.
Speed farming.
This is like the best speed farming still.
Yeah.
And that animation is just amazing.
Absolutely.
And you can see there at the end they had the upgrade that dropped a bunch of stun grenades at the end.
Obviously enemies were all dead.
But you know if you use this to get into a big cluster of enemies then you stop the channel, you drop some stun grenades, reset some of your charges and you're good to start spinning again.
A ton of fun.
Yeah.
Those are perfect for like you run into an elite pack after slaughtering a bunch of normals and it just annihilates the elites.
It feels amazing.
Yeah.
All right.
So we've got new passives as well.
New key passive is Alchemical Admixture.
And this is empowering your non-physical damage.
So rogues can do poison, shadow and cold through their various imbuements.
And when you deal three different types of that non-physical damage, the potency of your imbuement skills is going to be dramatically increased for a time.
And the more bonus damage that you build on your gear for bonus poison, shadow or cold damage, the further that potency gets increased.
Really encouraging you to mix and match the different elements.
It's really thematic with the alchemical kind of theme and really supporting a build of rogue that we've kind of had in the game, but really wanted to give that robust support of a key passive for.
And also we've got a legendary Paragon node, the Dance Macabre, which encourages this kind of one two combo of casting mobility or subterfuge skill increases the damage of your next skill, whatever it might be, by quite a substantial amount.
So you can cast your dash and then position yourself, cast a big rain of arrows and it hits very hard.
Very cool and actually impacts your moment to moment rotation as well.
And of course, we've got the new skill tree passives as well.
All right, new items.
We've got the Pit Fighter's Gaul.
This is the Ancestral Unique Ring.
Or sorry, just a unique ring.
It's not necessarily.
You can find it before Ancestral Tier.
And this Pit Fighter's Gaul will empower your smoke grenade.
So your smoke grenade skill will increase your critical strike damage and then leave a cloud of shadows behind.
And while you're within that cloud of shadows, you're going to be constantly regaining stealth.
And so there's a lot of interesting ways you can play off of triggering going into or out of stealth.
And Pit Fighter's Gaul is just going to really enable that when you cast smoke grenade.
We've got an aspect of star shards.
This is a new legendary to directly support Dance of Knives.
And the daggers from Dance of Knives have a chance to shatter, creating more shards of metal that deal bonus damage.
And you can now use combo points on Dance of Knives to further increase the channel duration if you've opted into the combo points specialization.
Aspect of Poisonous Clouds plays well with Pit Fighter's Gaul.
When you gain stealth, you create a cloud of poison damage.
And aspect of Splendering Shards, there's just a chance whenever you're hitting a frozen enemy to create some ice spikes.
So if you're freezing enemies because you're playing Alchem-Glad Mixture and using Coldimbue, Splendering Shards might be a good aspect for you as well.
All right, moving on to the Sorceress.
Let's move on to the Sorceress. The Sorceress gets a new conjuration skill called the Familiar.
This is a conjuration skill that is all three elements. It is a Shock skill, a Pyromancy skill, and a Frost skill.
So there's three charges of it, so you can cast it back to back.
And you summon a Familiar of the element of your last skill cast.
So if you just cast a Pyromancy skill, you're going to summon a Fire Familiar.
If you just cast a Lightning skill, you'll summon a Lightning Familiar.
And same with a Cold, you'll summon a Cold Familiar.
And with the Enhanced Effect, these Familiars will do a bonus effect.
So the Fire Familiar will constantly apply some burning to enemies that it's around.
The Cold Familiar will chill, and Lightning Familiar will stun.
And of course, their damage type is going to be based on what type they are, so that it'll benefit from all of your bonus fire damage.
And that aura, Charles, is really great, right, to tap into some of the passives on the Sorcerer.
Yeah, absolutely. So, you know, there's a lot of passives that say,
hey, you get bonuses against burning enemies, for instance.
Now, if you have the Fire Familiar, that's going to really easily be able to apply that constantly,
and you're going to have pretty high uptime on having Familiars out because of the way the charge and duration works.
Let's take a look at this in action.
All right, so initially, we cast a Frost Familiar here, right?
It's jumping around, and it's landing, it's doing Frost damage.
Then we cast a Fire Skill.
Now we get a Fire Familiar jumping around and kind of dive bombing on enemies.
And then finally, we get a Shock Familiar, a Lightning Familiar here that's going to be a Lightning damage.
So you can kind of mix and match these depending on what skills you use, what combination you cast them in.
And it's really flexible. It fits into a lot of different builds.
Even if you're just a pure, say, Fire Sword, and you just want to do Fire Damage, you just want to do Burning,
this could still fit because you're just going to be able to summon the Fire Familiar.
But it really reaches its maximum potential as you're kind of mix and matching these to suit the situation and apply the debuffs that you want onto the enemies.
And you can have quite a few of these out. For the Sega demonstration, I think we only have a couple of them out on screen, but I think you can have up to like six, right?
Yeah, you can have up to six, and that would make a lot more sense once we get to talk about some of the unique items that are coming with this patch.
But first, let's talk about the new passives. And we've got Enlightenment.
This really also plays into the concept of mixing and matching the elements.
You see it's got all three kind of colors on there. Casting a skill grants a stack of Enlightenment, or three stacks, if your skill was a different element to the one before.
So you're alternating here. And whenever you gain max stacks, you're going to become Enlightened, and you get a ton of bonuses for being in this Enlightened state.
But then it drops off over time.
It's really a reward for mixing and matching those elements, more so than any other key passes we've had on Swerg before.
And similarly, with the Legendary Paragon node, Fundamental Release, each Fire, Lightning, and Cold attack you make in San Ami increase the damage they take from all sources by 10%.
So you really need to hit them with all three types to gain the maximum bonus here.
All right, on to the unique items.
So, Siday Bindings. This is a unique gloves, and this plays right into the familiar.
So whenever you cast familiar with this unique on, you're going to summon all three elemental variants at once.
However, it does come with a bit of restrictions on it.
So familiar's duration is going to be dramatically increased, and it's cooldown reduced, but you're going to have one less charge of it.
So you won't be able to spam this quite as much, but you press the button once or twice, and then you get the maximum familiar result.
They're all over the screen, and they're going to last for quite a long time with this unique glove.
So it's going to be really, really powerful too.
If you're all about this Conjuration build, all about amping up the power from the familiar, it's an awesome unique for that.
Additionally, we've got new Legendaries for the aspect of overheating.
After channeling Incinerate for a time, you're going to deal bonus damage to the target.
And casting Incinerate will refresh and maintain the bonus.
So really just powering up your Incinerate.
Charged Flash, this empowers charged bolts.
And after you hit a certain number of enemies with charged bolts, your next three casts of charged bolts will no longer send out bolts.
They're going to send out big waves of lightning that deal even more damage, and it's always going to be a crit.
And then aspect of Elemental Constellation.
Once again, more about the mixing and matching of all three elements.
Casting one of the Elemental Skills will summon a matching type Elemental Dagger that will pierce through enemies.
And the damage of that dagger is going to be increased if you get all three of the different Element types in that timeframe.
All right, so I think, oh, right, we've got new Mythic Uniques.
Of course, how can I forget?
New Mythic Unique items.
These are the strongest items in the game.
We've got Shroud of False Death.
And I think the really cool part about this is it's just Inherent Apex.
It's going to grant plus one skill rank to all passives.
And this is really awesome as we're adding new passives into the skill tree.
This is just a ton of power for this new unique chest.
And its effect is if you haven't attacked in the last two seconds, you're going to gain Stealth and bonus movement speed.
Now, Stealth historically has just been a mechanic that has been on Rogues and a little bit on Druids with the Werewolf builds.
But now every class, if you get this Mythic Unique, is going to have some access to Stealth.
You can drop out of combat for a little bit and then you get into Stealth and you get tons of movement speed to maybe move on to the next pack or move somewhere else in the dungeon.
And it's a really simple line, all passives, but it's literally all passives, which is insane.
Like, it's incredibly powerful.
Absolutely.
And we've also got the Heir of Perdition, a Mythic Unique Helm.
And this one has an interesting effect.
So it says, give into hatred and earn Lilith's favor, increasing your damage dealt by 60%.
So just baseline, this is a huge damage bonus.
And the second line here says, slaughter enemies to briefly steal Lilith's favor from nearby allies.
So this means if you're playing in a group with somebody else who happens to have the Heir of Perdition equipped, you are able to steal Lilith's favor from them.
Lilith will only favor one of you.
And you actually gain double the bonus of this, right?
If you steal someone else's favor, you get 120% bonus damage.
And they would get zero.
But if you're just playing this solo, no one else has their Perdition round.
It's just a flat 60% bonus damage, which is still a ton and very impactful for a Mythic Unique.
All right. I believe that is actually everything.
Wow, that is so much new class content, new skills, new legendaries, new everything.
And I didn't even get to talk about some of our other, you know, more regular class balance changes, you know, updates to existing skills and legendaries.
So make sure you definitely check out the patch notes.
There is still more changes to come, but we're already really deep into this campfire chat and we didn't want to extend it too much longer.
So make sure you check out the patch notes for all the details on those other changes coming as well.
Yeah, thank you so much, Charles.
I know we have gone through a lot of information.
We're in our 1.5 of this campfire chat, as I said, and I mentioned on social, like this is going to be a very beefy campfire chat.
We still have two more things that we do want to really cover off.
And as Charles had mentioned, there are a lot of other class changes that we didn't actually fit within the presentation, like a lot of balance specific items.
So that will be on patch notes and patch notes will be available on our blog for PTR immediately after the stream.
So please check that out.
We are going to jump into some quality of life items.
And so, Colin, do you want to take us through some quick quality of life items?
I'll be coming with 2.0.
Yeah, I'll go quick so we can get to the super exciting, cool thing.
Yeah.
So the first one here is you can now select your preferred town portal location.
So how that's going to work is you're going to open up the map and hover over any of the waypoints.
And when you right click on it, it's going to set that as essentially your preferred location.
And whenever you town portal, it's going to take you there.
So this is really helpful for when you're doing whispers, for example.
You just set the tree of whispers as your preferred location.
Do some whispers.
When you press T, you go right there.
You don't have to open up the map and click on the waypoint and click on accept.
Like it's all very seamless and it's just removing a lot of the inputs that you have to do to get back to town quickly.
The next thing here is we're adding a dungeon key inventory tab for things like nightmare sigils.
So that just gives you more space for more activities.
So much room for activities.
The next one here is we've done a pretty substantial rework of monster CC.
And this is in the spirit of we want to have really clear sort of delineations between normal monsters and elite monsters.
And we didn't like how often you're getting slowed down and how mandatory unstoppable could feel.
So, you know, I always felt bad to be fighting this huge horde of enemies and you see this elite and you're paying attention to the elite.
And then like this goat man, Mauler comes up and like sneak attacks you and knocks you down for three seconds.
And that's the thing that kills you.
That always felt like bullshit.
Right. So what we've done is we've sort of overhauled a lot of the normal monster CCs to be quick and snappy.
Like you still feel them.
You kind of want to avoid them still.
But they're much less sort of the reason why you die entirely.
So the vampire impale when like the two hander like comes and stabs you and stuns you for three seconds.
That's turned into an immobilize.
So you can't move, but you can just smack them in the face.
And then the werewolf leap is another great example where previously they'd come out of stealth and like leap attack on you and you get dazed and you'd walk around confused.
And now they just does it does a quick knockback.
This next change here is small, but I think it's a blaster's delight, which is all the monsters that had really long death animations all die instantly.
You don't have to wait for the loot to hit the ground.
It's very satisfying.
You know, the big ass like spider hosts that crawl towards you when you kill them, they pop instantly and all the spiders go and hit the walls and it feels great.
The zombies feel really good to it.
Like they pop instantly when you kill them.
And it's a very satisfying experience.
So this should speed up combat quite a bit and it just feels really good.
The next thing here is their socketable inventory tab, another tab for you, for you to put socketables like gems and other socketables.
And then there's also an additional stash tab that we're going to add.
The next thing, if we could roll the clip, we took out just about all the.
All would go up and then like click on the plunger and don't get hit by the spikes.
That's all been replaced entirely with just monster packs of varying sizes.
And it's just way more seamless.
In this case, we only rolled some normal monsters, but sometimes it's a couple of elite packs.
You never really know what you're going to get.
It's like an Easter or a kinder egg, I should say.
And it just helps the dungeon flow substantially, like to just sort of blast through those things.
And then a handful of dungeons have had their procedural logic updated just so there's more variation in the layout.
So when you play it, it's just going to roll out differently.
This is really just iterating on our dungeon set to make them feel much more sort of flow inducing, not slowing you down.
And then the next one here is minor, but actually feels pretty good and it has a big impact on the game.
When you get those Paragon and Level Up notifications, we're actually going to tell you how many.
So sometimes you'll realize, oh my God, I have like 15 skill points I can spend.
And it actually tells you the number and it's a nice quality of life change.
So I think that's everything.
Awesome.
Thank you, Colin, for running through quickly.
I appreciate the efficiency of going through all the quality of life changes.
Now I know Jeevan has been very quiet over here.
He's only chimed in a little bit and we do want to talk about a new thing that is coming to Vessel of Hatred specifically and for Vessel of Hatred players.
So Jeevan, will you talk us through it a little bit?
Yeah, so it's my privilege to kind of talk about a feature that the whole team's been working very hard on that we haven't really mentioned much.
And, you know, we looked at the expansion.
We had all these cool things, you know, torment, new class skills, spirit porn, but we thought there was a hole.
And we wanted to particularly give build crafters a new way to play for Vessel of Hatred.
This is for folks who, like me, whose dream cooking show has nothing to do with British baking, but instead would be called Colin's Kitchen.
So, yeah, let's say, I think some of you already kind of have an idea.
So, yeah, let's let's let's get into it.
Some of you already know we're going to be talking about runewords.
Yeah. So let's let's start with a little background.
So runewords were in Diablo 2, and they were a very powerful way of augmenting gear with socketable content.
And there's a lot of good sort of nostalgic feelings.
They were popular. They were remembered fondly.
You can look on the right. That's one of the most iconic examples from Diablo 2.
So the name is Enigma and you would make it with runes, Ja if Burr, and it would get you some some really cool skills that would come out of it when you put it all together.
And for Diablo 4, we wanted to retain the soul of what Diablo 2 runewords did, which is combining socketable components and creating more powerful items.
But we also wanted to do something that felt appropriately fresh and new.
And we wanted to lean into what's unique about the modern game to make the Diablo 4 version of Runewords and make it stand on its own and really feel like the right version to be given to players.
Yeah. And what was awesome about Diablo 2 runewords, right, was you got the set of runes that made a god item, right?
And it broke the rules, like being able to teleport on other classes, like what the hell barbarian is teleporting across the screen.
We really wanted to embrace that in a way that extended builds and didn't necessarily enforce you must play with this item.
And we're really excited to share what that's sort of manifested, right?
Yeah. And you all have a lot of builds that you started with from the base game and we want to add on to those.
So what are runewords? They're a way for you to make your own spells.
So there are two types of runes. There's runes of ritual and they specify actions from the player that they have to trigger.
So you can see the example here of the Yul rune, which is a legendary quality rune of ritual.
You have to cast a skill which has a cooldown. So, you know, Frost Nova or something like that.
Then you have runes of invocation. And these grant powerful effects as a result of satisfying those runes of ritual.
So the example here, the Gar rune gives you two and a half percent critical strike chance for five seconds.
And you can stack up to ten times, up to 25%. And you can mix and match these.
There'll be a lot of different runes of ritual and runes of invocation.
And you can put them together as you see fit.
So when you combine a rune of ritual and rune of invocation, you pair them together.
You put them in an item with two sockets. Boom, you form a runeword.
And as you can tell, there's going to be rarity. We're going to have magic, rare and legend.
And the higher rarity runes will have more potent conditions or effects.
So one of the important elements of this is called offering, which is the rune resource system.
So your runes of ritual will generate offering and they're meant to feed into their linked runes of invocation so that they can consume that offering.
And the sort of more demanding rituals that we would ask of you as a player gain you more offering.
At the same time, the more powerful invocations that you would try to get require more offering.
And so there's sort of a sort of like shared economy there.
So if you can look at these runes on the right, you get 50 offering for casting a skill with a cooldown.
And this rune only requires 25 offering for it to trigger.
That's where overflow comes in.
Overflow is when an invocation receives an offering in excess of what's needed to trigger it.
But put more simply, it's we want you to have a mix and match system, but we want the pieces to be not super hard that they can't fit together easily when they have some rough edges.
So many invocations can get different bonus effects when overflowed.
Some of them might get increased radius to the effect.
Some of them might get increased duration, but it'll always be proportional to the overflow amount.
So as an example here, the garb rune only requires 25 offering and it's getting double that, which is 50 from the old rune.
So every time you cast a skill with a cooldown, you'll get two stacks of 2.5% critical strike chance or 5% crit strike.
And so that's kind of how you get to play with this system and you get to optimize it in different ways.
And it creates a lot of flexibility, right?
Even like if you do a really demanding ritual trigger, for example, on a really low offering rune of invocation, it's almost a way to start scaling that rune of invocation in a completely different way beyond just triggering the rune.
Exactly. Yeah.
It lets us as developers be more flexible in creating wide ranges of effects, sort of small ones, big ones, and also the same for the rituals.
And you get to kind of decide which ones you think fit your build or are cool.
And we do our best to make sure that you can almost cook up anything.
So a few rules.
Runes can be socketed into items with two sockets.
We've added another item to get two sockets for Vessel of Hatred.
So you'll have your helm, your two-hander, your gloves, and sorry, your helm, two-hander, pants, and chest.
They can only be paired with a rune of the opposite type.
So you have to pair a rune of ritual with a rune of invocation.
You can have a maximum of two runewords equipped.
You can't equip the same rune twice.
And they're available for users who own Vessel of Hatred.
They stack in your inventory in the new socketable inventory tab, which will also have your gems.
And runes are tradable between other players who own Vessel of Hatred.
And they unlock with a quest in the campaign.
Both runes dropping from as loot, but also runecrafting, which we'll get into later.
And they drop at a higher rate in the Undercity, which is a specific place you can farm them.
So now let's get into some clips here.
We get to actually see it in action.
So this is a barbarian.
And the rune of ritual they have is travel five meters.
Very simple.
And they're going to join that to the earthquake, which is a legendary aspect that you've already seen before, which requires 100 offering.
So you see, we'll put them together in this item.
And then all they have to do is just run around.
Boom, earthquakes dropping.
It's going to be insane with the Paragon legendary glyph we just talked about.
Yeah.
The earthquake train is leaving the station.
What I love about this is it doesn't just count your normal walking, right?
If you're leaping, if you're charging, that's all counting towards the distance that you're moving, right?
Oh, whoa.
And you can see it here in the whirlwind, for instance.
Like it's obviously spawning earthquakes.
Was that a druid petrify ultimate?
This is supposed to be the wrong clip.
All right. Sorry guys.
You know, we're doing it live.
Let's just move on to the next one.
Okay.
So we have a necromancer here with the rune of ritual cast a non channeled core skill getting 25 each.
And then this is a classic from D2, gain plus three to all skills.
So you'll get to see this necro's got five skill ranks for reap and sever.
And they're going to go out and catch the four skill.
Casual, socketable harlequin crest.
Pretty good.
So a little pew pew, just doing your basic core skill usage, filling up the offering needed.
Yeah.
I really like the little tracking buff that fills up as you as you're getting it.
So you don't need to really micromanage this.
You can just add a glance, see that, hey, I just filled it up and now I get plus three ranks of sever.
Yep.
So now you're a plus three.
There you go.
What was that?
So yeah, this necro is just cooking and, um, oh, what is this another broken clip?
Did they just cast teleport?
What?
Okay.
I, I, I think, I think you guys.
Teleporting necros.
What are you cooking over there, Jeevan?
Yeah, I'll stop making jokes mostly.
Um, yeah.
So what we really wanted to lean into with D2 runewords, among other things, was the ability to cast other classes skills and use their power and how to cast it.
into your build.
So with runewords, you're going to get to do that.
Each class is going to share two skills and one legendary aspect like the, uh, the earthquake one that you saw.
Um, and some of them are even going to get, get to cast improved versions.
So for instance, you know, instead of, um, the standard decrepify from the necromancer, you get to cast horrid decrepify, which is the upgraded version.
And that's kind of, we did that for a lot of reasons.
You know, we wanted to make some of them feel a little better and a little more powerful.
And a lot of it is about balance.
But one important thing that I always want to, um, highlight here is that you always cast the best version of the skill if you have upgrades as the sort of home owner of the class.
Right?
So what that means is let's say you're a spirit born and you equip the cry rune, which is the vortex spell.
If you have points into the upgrade, um, then you'll cast the upgraded vortex when the rune goes off.
So I don't think there'll be any class envy.
You know, like everyone will get the best version of their own skills and then they'll get to use other classes skills.
And, um, we're really excited to see how people can construct new builds and new archetypes and what they can do with using the power of the classes.
And that says enhanced war cry.
So that means necros can become berserk, right?
That indeed does mean that.
And, uh, and, and that enhanced war cry is a winner.
I gotta say that one's real strong.
We've already seen people just chopping up the pit with that one.
Yeah, absolutely.
Uh, absolutely.
Really looking forward to what kind of interesting new combinations and builds you can come up with by, by dipping into other class skills, uh, in, in unique ways.
Uh, it really just like multiplies the possibilities of, of what you can do with any given class.
Yeah, exactly.
And not only do we want you to augment your builds with other classes skills, but, you know, runes will scale with gear.
So when you get more interesting runes of rituals, you'll find ways to optimize them as well and get more output.
So we really feel like people will have a lot of theory crafting that they can build off of the runeword system.
And I'm very excited to see how you break the game.
By the way, that's what she's doing.
She's doing PTR for me.
Just break, break the game.
See every build you can find that totally destroys everything.
Um, so now we have the crafting element.
Um, so using three of the same rune, you can use them to roll a new rune.
Uh, you go to the jeweler or it might not be the jeweler, but we'll see.
Um, and you will combine three of the same exact rune and you'll get a new rune out that is guaranteed to be different than the rune you put in.
And there's a chance to uproll it to the next highest rarity.
So if you put three magic runes in, there's a chance that it'll be a rare rune.
Same with, same with rare.
There's a chance that it'll be a legendary rune.
Um, and then on top of that, we'll have the ability to craft mythic uniques.
So you can use runes.
Um, each route, each mythic unique can be crafted with a specific set of runes.
Um, you'll need a legendary rare and magic runes of a certain quantity and one resplendent spark.
And this is in addition to the existing mythic unique crafting flow.
So, um, yeah, uh, oh, I was just gonna say this really harkens back to the sort of crafting that was so core and deep.
Um, with the ruins of being able to match three and get the next upgrade, but in a way that's a little bit more flexible and gives you more progression out of it.
And this is all tradable, right?
So that match three, those crafting mythic uniques, what do you think that's gonna do with trading?
Yeah.
I mean, I, I think it's gonna really build a sort of player community around how to acquire the runes you need, whether it's because you want to combine, you know, you have two and you want to find that third one to combine.
You're hunting for a new one or you're hunting for a specific mythic unique.
I think we're gonna have a lot of player interaction and well, someone's gonna win the capitalism game there.
So we'll see how that goes.
I really like how, how the, uh, the, the rune crafting system makes it.
So you're kind of always progressing, right?
If you're getting room drops, then, then you're, you're, you're getting materials that you know, can use to progress towards higher rarity runes and potentially towards these mythic unique items.
Unlike, uh, you know, some of the other loot drops, you know, if you don't find a good piece of gear, it just ends up being salvage.
Here with runes, you're kind of constantly getting some of that progression, even if it's not always the perfect rune right now.
Yeah, I think that's something that we, we did talk to a lot of sort of D2 diehards when we, we built rune words.
And one of the things that most of them tend to mention consistently was like every rune drop is progress, right?
You're always moving up that ladder.
And so we wanted to make sure that even if you didn't get the exact thing you wanted, it still meant something to you one way or another.
Well, I know, uh, we have, we've talked a lot about a lot of stuff today.
We, we had a progression itemization.
Uh, we talked about quality of life.
We talked about class, uh, changes.
And of course the newest thing, which is rune words, which will be in vessel of hatred.
Um, but the one thing we did want to quickly talk about was PTR.
PTR is coming up.
Uh, and we want to give a little bit, or at least some specifics on what that PTR test is going to be.
And also hear from the team on exactly like what they're looking for, uh, from you guys out there that are playing like for feedback, uh, as you guys play through the systems, everything that we've actually talked about today is going to be present in this PTR.
So, uh, all the, uh, class balance changes, the progression changes, uh, rune words will also be part of, uh, the PTR.
So we actually do want players jumping in, uh, and checking it out.
So, uh, let's jump right into some of the PTR items.
So, uh, as everyone knows, uh, PTR, uh, from even the last PTR that we had, uh, will carry over content from your main account.
So if you've already done all your renown, cleared your fog of war, your altar of Lola status, uh, uh, status will carry over onto your PTR account.
Uh, we did do a character copy as well.
It was a while back though.
So, uh, there, there, you may find that it might be a little dated from like the character copy that you have on live, but, uh, that will exist later.
So, uh, that will exist for players to actually use.
Um, one thing I will note is that we are planning on having two different testing phases for PTR specifically.
Uh, the first testing phase will actually begin next Wednesday.
Uh, and we'll run through Friday, uh, about midday where we're gonna actually give players the opportunity of kind of just starting characters from fresh, uh, because we really need people to try out the new progression systems that, uh, Colin and Hazelyn were talking about specifically in the beginning of the stream.
So Wednesday through midday Friday, we really need players to jump in, check that out, give us feedback specifically, uh, regarding anything tied to the new progression systems.
So, uh, around midday on Friday though, we will be turning on the rest of the PTR, which will include things like rune words and, and all the other, uh, features that we were kind of talking about, uh, are, well.
All the other features will be part of it, but rune words and things like that will be turning in on Friday.
One thing that we've heard from feedback from players specifically, especially as we have addressed this in the past is that there is going to be a boost vendor available for this PTR.
So in Kyovishad players will be able to go and visit this specific vendor. This is the best video that I was talking about because this Fallen is dancing and it looks, it looks absolutely amazing.
Uh, this vendor will be available and you'll be able to interact with it. And this vendor will actually then be able to provide you a ton of, uh, uh, enhancements to your character, uh, which we do have a list of here.
Uh, so you will be able to boost your character up to level 50 level 60, of course, which is the new level cap after vessel of hatred actually ships.
Uh, we will end up clearing out your whole map, your waypoints, uh, fog of war. Uh, we will do your class mechanic stuff and have that already unlocked.
All torment tears will be unlocked. Your potions will be, uh, upgraded completely. And then I know based off of feedback that we got from like the last PTR was, uh, hey, it'd be great if we could generate like, like,
legendary items, if we can get all the unique items, all the runes, or, well, that's new now, but all the, the runes and everything like that, including master working materials that will actually be available in this vendor.
So this is a way for players to be more efficient while testing and being able to give us, uh, more feedback, especially around end game related items.
Uh, so we really need players to jump in for PTR. One, one last caveat I do want to mention is, um,
Um, Infernal Hordes will not be available in this specific PTR. Uh, we are still doing some work on that right now, uh, before we actually get it ready, but, uh, all the other features within the game will be available.
Infernal Hordes, as I mentioned, will be, it's a permanent feature, so it's coming back to the game no matter what. Uh, and then separately, um, I, I do want to remind everyone that PTR right now is still just PC Battle.net only.
This does give us the flexibility of being able to upload, change things on the fly.
Like things like turning, turning Rune words on, on Friday, for instance, is, uh, gives us, we have the flexibility of being able to do that on, on, uh, our own platform.
So it's just easier for us to be able to have that, uh, additional, uh, work from our side to, to be able to make things like that happen when we can do testing specifically from that end.
Um, but Colin, Aislinn, uh, I'd be really curious to hear like what you guys are looking for specifically in this PTR from feedback from players, uh, that they can focus in on and provide feedback on, uh, as they go into the test.
Yeah.
So I think we really want to see people focusing on the new journey.
So starting from level one and feeling out what difficulty tier is right for you.
Um, and if that feels like it's the difficulty tier that you would expect to be on based on, uh, how powerful you've managed to make your character and how many of the progression systems you've engaged with.
Like if you engage with tempering and you go all out and you, you know, like, you're like, I'm going to make my character a blaster, even though they're only level 30, like how far can you go with that?
And are you going as far as you expected you would be able to go?
Yeah, those are great points.
It really is about, you know, are we hitting that expectation that we've sort of created, right?
Which is, we really loved how the mind cage was functioning.
We loved how tormented bosses felt in terms of having hard mode versions of things.
Um, are these difficulty tiers sort of meeting those expectations of all the things that we have had in the previous game now mapped to a more streamlined system, um, that should be much, much easier to navigate.
Awesome.
And I know on the class side, like Charles, what are you kind of looking for?
What's the team looking for on that front?
Yeah, I think we're really looking at the new system.
We're looking at the new skills and the new key passives for each class and, and how they're usable at, at all points in your character journey, right?
They should feel good to press when you just first learn these new skills.
Um, but they should also feel really good when you're in the late game and you're trying to, you know, make, you make a build all around them, right?
Around your, your stone burst.
Like, does it feel like that has enough support and that you can, you know, make a stone burst build or, or dance of knives and, um, or all the other different skills.
Like, do they fit in?
What's their appropriate power level?
And, and we really want to make sure that the new skills and the new key passives, uh, enable new ways of playing our classes and that, and they feel satisfying to build that way.
Awesome.
And Jeevan, I know you mentioned to everyone, break the game with RuneWords.
So, is there any, maybe any more extra items you're looking for in terms of feedback?
Yeah, I mean, it's, it's definitely mostly about that.
I want to see what people come up with.
I want to see, you know, what you can cook in terms of build and you can do something fun or cool or unexpected.
And, um, also, you know, I'm, I'm highly interested in the sort of balanced feedback.
I think we'll get it from all of you, but, um, we've had a lot of people on the team work very hard on conceptualizing how to make sure this stuff is right on the edge of broken without actually being broken.
And you'll get to, you'll get to prove me wrong if that isn't the case.
Um, yep.
Awesome.
Well, I know, um, we do want to jump into a little bit of Q and A before we kind of wrap up.
I know we've been here for a little while, so we'll try to grab some questions specifically from Twitch chat.
I know, uh, the, probably the most, uh, popular question right now, uh, from, from the community is about Armory.
And I do want to start off with that specifically.
And I do also want to just confirm that we are working on an Armory.
It is, it, the, the team is cooking on it right now.
Uh, we just don't have it ready immediately, but soon as we have an update, um, we will be providing that, uh, to the community.
There is work for an Armory happening.
We're not purposely ignoring it.
I promise you.
Uh, and it, it, it is in the work specifically from that end.
So, um, I know, uh, we, we have questions from Twitch chat.
So this is where I actually like butcher everyone's name.
So, uh, in standard fashion, I will continue to do that.
It's just a little different now because I actually like have a, a screen in front of me, which is actually really, really beneficial.
Um, but I guess we'll start off with a question regarding, uh, the different difficulty tiers.
So this is from double DHZ, which is, uh, since we now have eight difficulties, does this mean with power increase in later seasons, more difficulties will be added?
Wouldn't, uh, would, are we planning on adding, uh, like 20 difficulties like in Diablo three?
Like what, what's the plans around that?
Yeah, we want to be really measured in terms of when we add difficulty tiers.
Um, I think it sets us up for adding them when we feel like it's an inappropriate time.
We don't want to get to a spot where we have 20 different difficulty tiers.
We want to have just enough granularity to support the amount of power that we're adding.
And what we don't want to do is sort of say, okay, we're going to add things like rune words or add things like seasonal powers and then nerf all of you by making the monsters 100% tankier to compensate for the power.
We'd actually rather create a system that when you get that new power, we're going to add another band of difficulty to get even more efficiency out of that power.
Um, so that's been the sort of guiding light is we don't want to continue to sort of nerf players into a spot where they can sort of use all this new power to push.
Um, a great example of that is previously in seasons, we would actually increase monster health to compensate for some of the seasonal powers.
Now, if you get seasonal powers, if you're blasting Penitent and leveling to 60 faster, good for you.
Like that's something that we think is actually really important to the system.
Awesome. Um, I know next question that we have, this is a question I've seen a decent amount.
This is from explosive cat. Hopefully your cat is not exploding.
Uh, what's the purpose of nightmare dungeons now that glyphs have moved out of pit?
Yeah. So nightmare dungeons are going to be where you receive your master working materials.
Um, and because nightmare dungeons are going to be following the, um, difficulty tier, uh, system now,
you're going to be able to go into higher torment tiers or rather higher difficulty tier, uh, nightmare dungeons and get more, uh, masterwork materials out of that.
So just like, you know, all other kinds of content in the game.
Now being able to go into a higher difficulty of that activity is going to ultimately be better for you.
Yeah. The grind sort of putting a grind currency actually fits much better in a nightmare dungeon compared to the pit,
because it means that every sort of elite you kill every chest you open or every corner you go into and you find an elite pack.
Those are going to be master working materials as opposed to today where it's like, well,
the instant I make a turn that is not in the direction of finishing this dungeon has been a waste of my time.
Cause I want that cliff that can play completely changes when everything in the dungeon is dropping master working materials.
And we think that feels so much better for that type of content.
Um, conversely, you know, with the pit, uh, you know, again, we're going to reward you for pushing to the pit.
We're going to reward you for pushing difficulty.
And we do want you to sort of get there quickly and get that reward and get out.
So we think that'll feel a lot better.
Yeah. So just, just for people, cause I think when they immediately heard like, well,
now it's just moved to nightmare dungeons and it's just at the end, it's actually part of, of the, the, the, the whole nightmare dungeon.
It's not just the end goal, getting to the end and do it and getting, you know, master working materials there.
Just want to clarify for chat.
Cause I know immediately there's a good amount.
There's a good amount at the end when you kill the boss, right?
Of course the boss has to have good shit, but like, what's really going to feel great is like when you run into a massive elite pack,
like you just randomly run into, you know, we, we spawned maybe too many.
Those are all going to represent, you know, little loot bags of master working materials, which is going to be huge.
Awesome.
Um, this question is from RxU 105.
Um, are runes reusable?
Um, yeah.
So, um, by the way, I just want to say chat, I've, I've been reading, I've been reading Twitch chat and what you've said has, uh, struck a chord.
Anyway, um, yes, they will be reusable.
Oh, gee, man.
Can't take you anywhere.
Um, you could unsocket runes and you can, uh, move them into different items.
Yes, absolutely.
Um, I saw a few related questions to that.
Uh, they, they don't get to exist in the same, um, item as gems.
You do have to pick between gems and, uh, runes on any individual item.
Awesome.
Um, I know there was a question related to, um, another, well, at least, I don't know.
I don't know if Charles, you want to answer this or if you have additional details.
There's a lot of questions related to one of the mythic uniques and it's, uh, additive damage to demons and angels specifically.
Um, I don't know if you want to talk about it.
I will confirm that is the wording on the effect.
Plus damage to angels and demons.
There you go, guys.
We'll just leave it at that.
Um, and no further.
I know.
Yeah.
No further comment on that.
Um, additional question that we have related to, uh, Paragon is why cap the amount of boards and instead of just capping maybe the amount of lifts we can use.
This is from hot air.
Yeah, that's a really good point.
Um, something that I think we can take back and really think about.
We had discussed and we felt like the cleanest solution from just sort of the, um, flow perspective was that we wanted to just make it really sort of compact and make those choices about which glyphs and which legendary nodes.
And eventually what rare and magic nodes matter to you.
Um, but that's really good feedback and something we can continue to monitor as we go into PTR.
And as people get their hands on it again, it's really about making those boards more punchy and the connections between those boards is something that you navigate during your journey.
But the sort of end point is about making those really chunky choices on what glyphs you want and what legendary nodes you want.
Um, and we think that ultimately, especially now that Paragon is realm wide and all your alts.
I think we touched on that earlier.
All your alts get to benefit from this.
Um, it's really going to streamline that process of getting your points locked in quickly on those alt characters and get them into the end game really quickly.
Um, so, but that's a really good point of feedback.
Um, a question from.
WTF I, I, I, I, I, I, I, I lack a lot of whatever.
I see.
This is, this is bad.
Yeah.
You get the point.
Will everyone need to be in Kyovashad to change difficulty like it is currently?
That's a good question.
We've added, actually, yeah.
So you could imagine how obnoxious it would be to do the pit in Karagar
and then have to go to Kyovashad to then unlock the new Torment tier that you just got.
So we actually added difficulty tier selectors in Karagar
as well as Kyovashad in addition to Kyovashad.
And then we also have one in Karast and there's also another one,
I think, near the dark citadel entrance.
We've added them in a few locations across the game
just to make that a little bit of a better experience.
A question from a few people.
There's like Korinter.
There's another question from Nine Tons of Pain.
Are lists kind of shared between all characters in the realm
or do they have to be leveled up separately?
So those are still leveled up separately,
but that's something like going forward,
we definitely want an emphasis on like making alts more seamless to play into.
And we definitely, there's some underlying feedback there,
which is, wouldn't it be great if the Paragon lists for account wide?
And it's like, yeah, that's something we can take back to the team.
And philosophically, you know,
we really want to start moving towards a direction
where making alts is really easy to get into and feel powerful.
So that's something we can definitely take note of.
And I'll also highlight that, right,
because the Paragon points are shared account wide
or realm wide, as it were,
if you make a new character,
you're going to get a ton of Paragon points right away,
which increases your player power level,
which maybe means you take on a higher pit tier
and then you get the catch-up mechanic on leveling up those glifts.
So it is a little bit easier for your alts to level up those glifts as well,
even if it's not 100% shared.
Yeah, that's very true.
You can level them up really fast in the pit if you're pushing deep.
There is a question regarding Eternal Realm characters,
and what happens to them when 2.0 kind of launches?
What's the, like, do,
I'm assuming because they already have, like, 925 gear,
if they're at max level,
they'll be brought down to that new eye level that we had mentioned.
Is there, like, any specific changes or anything,
or is it kind of laid out exactly kind of how we presented?
Oh, I can answer this.
Yeah.
So we are doing some adjustments for those Eternal players
who really like to play the game on one character.
We wanted to make sure that there was new loot to chase.
We also just needed to make sure that with the new character level adjustments,
you know, we sort of had to adjust the eye power of items
now that the fact that the max character level is 60.
In addition to our goals of really sort of creating more grounded numbers,
it does mean level 50 is getting an eye power adjustment
as well as the affixes are being adjusted.
But we are going to max roll every single affix that we adjusted power-wise.
So, for example, if you get a 5,
we're going to take those items and adjust them.
We aren't going to re-roll those affix bands.
Like, if you had perfect affixes,
we're just going to essentially max roll all of them within that band
so there's no feels bad about, you know, I had this perfect item
and you ruined it by readjusting it.
But the sort of main takeaway there is
we wanted to make sure in patch 2.0 that there was new loot to chase.
You know, we wanted to make sure that the new uniques had a place to sing
and that's all sort of in service to that
for that type of Eternal player who really likes that sort of long-form progression.
Awesome.
A question from Ice Panther.
Rumors, are they applicable to all items and weapons
or are they restricted to specific types of equipment?
Additionally, can gems be inserted into equipment with runes?
Yeah, they can be inserted into all types of equipment
so they're not restricted from being in uniques
as long as, you know, you have two sockets for that unique.
And to restate the slots that are available with two sockets,
on base game it's three.
It's chest, pants, and two-hander.
We're also adding a second socket to helm so you'll have four slots.
And you cannot mix runes with gems in any item.
And you wouldn't want to.
You'd basically be losing the benefit of them.
Awesome.
I know we have some questions related to, like, some co-op bugs.
I will say that I've gone on, I know, like, forums and Reddit
and addressed, at least addressed them that we are working on them.
I can tell you the team is most definitely working on them right now.
Excuse me as I call.
Still getting over my sickness.
And then I know this is actually a pretty,
I'm going to ask this because it's a funny question.
Are there runes for G and then Bun?
Oh, I mean, my narcissism certainly would have let me do that.
But I think we can't do that sort of stuff, unfortunately.
I would have loved to.
But I will say, there are, you know,
the runes have these sort of phrases that they unlock
when you actually compose the spells.
And we have some, I think, fun references and Easter eggs
to, you know, the great Diablo games of the past.
And so hopefully that'll kind of make you smile when you see them.
Awesome.
And then runes, are they stackable?
Yeah, they are stackable.
And we have added a new tab for them as well.
We have a socketable tab.
So all your runes and gems will go there.
There we go.
It would be pretty good for your inventory.
Yeah, that would have been really messing with inventory
if runes did not stack.
And now they have their own tab.
Yeah, and now they have their own tab,
which is really, really good.
So cool.
I know we are very over on time.
So I do want to make sure that we let everyone go here
so that they can eat,
because we've now gone well past lunch over here in California.
Just a reminder for everyone that PTR is actually going to be starting next Wednesday.
We will have patch notes in the blog up immediately after the stream, specifically here.
So you guys can check it out.
Check out the patch notes.
It's 17,000 words.
A lot of words.
So I apologize.
I will say that for other locales, it might be until early next week before those patch notes will be available.
It just takes a while for us to localize on some of those, and it kind of came in a little hot.
So we do plan on actually having that available in all languages.
Just for now, they will be English only and immediately up after this specific stream.
Again, PTR starts next Wednesday.
We'll have two different phases.
Wednesday through Friday will be that first initial phase where we need players jumping in,
checking out the progression changes, and testing all that out.
And then starting on Friday for the rest of the week specifically,
we'll end up having the boost vendor available where players can actually jump in
and test out everything that they need to regarding rune words and all other things that are tied to Endgame.
I do want to give a huge thanks to everyone on this panel here.
Colin, Aislinn, Charles, Jeevan, thank you so much for going through a ton of information.
I do want to also call out the rest of the Diablo team because they have been doing a ton of work towards Vessel of Hatred
and, of course, Patch 2.0 and Season 6.
One thing we will say is that you guys actually haven't heard about Season 6 yet.
We still have information to tell you about Season 6.
We'll be sharing that more here in the coming weeks as we head towards launch.
So there is still a seasonal theme and mechanic with Season 6 that we'll be sharing here soon.
So thank you guys, everyone, and thank you Diablo community for tuning in.
Check out Diablo4.com immediately after the stream, and we'll see you guys in Sanctuary.
Thanks again.
Thanks, everyone.
Oh, we're ending with this.
Best.
I love it.
We can't forget the most important member of the team.
But we'll just be reducing our 2018elt.
This is a long number of people who have become part of the team.
We're ending with this.
We can see that it may be far from various Sortingsitesites who have decided by ele.
But we will be, multiplayer in  Freddy alien, which is including the highest type of Mental film.
Here are the more competitive culture related where they can't get low on your constructs.
There is a