And I wonder if I can show...
Hey, what's going on, man?
What is up?
All right, can you...
We're doing it.
It's happening.
Can you guys hear him fine?
Is he fine up or down?
How is it sounding, guys?
Can you talk for a second, Joe?
Testing the ups and downs.
What's up?
How do I sound, chat?
I can see it's way too low.
I'm going to turn you way higher.
Let's try again.
I could just start screaming,
hey, how do I sound right now?
Okay, is that better, guys?
Up more, up more.
Okay, we're going...
I have you at 100.
Okay, this is dangerous.
This is going to get dangerous
when I get excited about something.
So we got to watch out for that.
Apologizing in advance.
Hey, thanks so much for coming on here, man.
I'm really excited.
Yeah, this is going to be a blast.
I'm looking forward to the conversation.
Hell yeah.
Where's my partner in crime?
Where's Adam Z. Jackson?
You want to know what?
He's faking all of these technical issues
and he's just like,
you want to know what?
I'm going to call in sick
and I'm just going to have Joe solo this.
Yeah, it's fine.
Let's do it.
Let's just sign him up
for a whole bunch of stuff.
Okay, so what I'm going to do here,
tried my best to be as prepared as possible.
Cool.
But of course,
I'm probably not prepared at all.
So that's just the way life goes.
No, no, no, no.
It's all good.
Hey, and one thing up front,
right off the top here is like,
I have a lot of things I want to say,
but it's okay if you want to interject.
So it's not rude.
I'm not going to take it as being rude.
So if there's the things you want to chat through
or things you want clarification on,
like, please, please, please interrupt me.
It's all good.
I feel like I feel like
I want to give that preface
to everybody I talk to now on stream, right?
I would never interrupt
that sweet, angelic, mellow fluous voice.
Speaking of that, Adam Jackson is here.
Let's take four questions.
Can people hear me okay?
I've spent the last 45 minutes
troubleshooting my mic
and it's been the worst.
It's okay?
Dude, is that a paper towel roller by your bed?
How do I get one of those?
I have kids.
They're very messy.
It's part of the life.
Dude, that is,
that's the most ingenious thing I've ever seen.
We're pretty creative over here.
You can hear me okay, though.
I'm very concerned about this.
It's fine.
Okay.
Thank God.
I mean, I can hear you.
Chat, can you hear them?
Sounds perfect for me.
How is it for you guys?
All right, cool.
Because I changed,
I fucked with all my computer settings
and now everything's terrible.
But as long as it works, I'm happy.
All right.
Okay.
I'm starting a 40 minute timer.
Then we'll do rapid fire at the end
to try to hit as many as possible.
That sounds good?
Sounds good to me.
Thank you so much for being here, guys.
All right.
Yesterday, CJ Riker did an interview with them.
So he asked a bunch of great questions.
I want to do some follow-ups
to some of the questions
that you guys talked about.
So one thing,
the topic that I think you guys
probably covered the most
in the interview yesterday
at different parts
was about aspirational
and pinnacle content.
Some of the things that you said
that was uber Lilith
at the start of the Diablo 4
was all mechanical mastery.
If you don't dodge the waves,
you're dead.
There's pretty much nothing
you can do about that.
And a lot of players
didn't have fun
just, you know,
getting crushed by her waves.
It's talked about
there's different lovers
to pull on the difficulty.
You can make players weaker
like Nightmare Dungeon Sigils.
You can make monsters hit harder.
You can give them more health,
more crowd control.
And I heard you say
that the decisions
that you make
before you go into the encounter
should matter more
because it's an ARPG.
It's about hunting loot.
It's about getting powerful.
And then you go in
and you have a big advantage
and you finally overcome
the difficulty.
And another thing
that I heard you guys say
is when you guys introduce
very difficult events
like the Avatar of Zier,
for example,
when you properly advertise it
as something that's
very difficult,
you didn't get any
negative backlash
or too much negative backlash
for the difficulty of it
because it was properly labeled.
So with that huge preface in mind,
my question is,
is do you guys have plans
in the future of Diablo 4
to build in these very,
very difficult encounters
that do require skill,
that do require you
to go in with an event
or with a boss,
learn their mechanics,
and that is going to be
another supplement
besides getting gear
to winning?
Thoughts on that?
Yeah, sure.
So I can just kind of,
I'll start off.
So the,
so yeah,
everything we talked about yesterday,
you just did a good job
of covering again.
I appreciate that.
But when we think about
what the future
of aspirational content
needs to look like in the game,
we do want to leave opportunities
for this kind of
like a mechanically complex content
for players to engage with.
And we experiment with it
a few different ways.
So I don't think that
like the Echo Lulith encounter,
it's a really good example
of like,
you know,
us like diving really,
really hard into mechanical mastery
where we expect players
to really have to be
very,
very active in terms
of their dodges
in order to survive.
But we,
we do want to continue
to experiment with these ideas
and try more things,
particularly when they are advertised
in the appropriate place.
Adam,
do you have,
do you have thoughts on this?
Yeah.
Originally I did
and it was like
a very long-winded answer,
but I don't want to
take up too much time on this.
I guess what I'll say is,
you know,
everything kind of exists
on a spectrum
when we're talking about
things like difficulty
or a lot of game design
topics and ideas.
Like in this spectrum,
in my mind,
it's like,
you know,
how hard should the thing be
versus how,
how much should your gear
going into it matter?
Right.
I think we're still
trying to find out
what the best answer is
for the things
that are really,
really hard,
like Uber Lilith
or these crazy,
difficult fights.
One of the things
that we're doing
in season four
that we started doing
in Beyond
that one of our
encounter designers
came up with a great idea
was adding this,
I think you've probably
seen our Ray Racks,
but that second debuff idea
where,
you know,
you can screw up
getting hit by a wave
a couple times,
but then after that
you're probably just
going to get one shot
and die.
And so that gives us
this kind of happy medium
between pure one shot mechanics
and things where you have
to be perfect
in your dexterity
versus,
you know,
the other way
where you can just
like outgear everything.
There's some other things
that can go into
of like,
you know,
the difference of
the most powerful
and least power
or mid powerful builds
and how we do difficulty.
Maybe we'll give that
a different answer,
but that's the TLDR.
I think we're still
trying to figure out
what is best for our game
and what our players like.
You know,
in my heart of hearts,
I'm more like you, Racks.
I love the very,
very crazy hard things.
I don't mind one shots
personally.
In my games,
but I don't think
it's best for this game.
Yeah.
It's not millennia.
We have play it.
Yeah.
I don't think that
it's best long term,
but having a little bit
of that kind of stuff
sometimes I think is okay.
I think it's more
how much and how we introduce
it and how we frame it
to people.
That's the simple answer.
Okay.
So kind of like
one thing that you guys
are liking is kind of
like the soft enrageous
where over time
eventually it gets
to get so difficult
that you're eventually
going to lose.
Yeah.
Fancy 14 does a good job
with this as well.
Like they have this idea
like, you know,
if you mess up a mechanic,
you're going to get
stacking deep off
and it can escalate
and get worse and worse
as the fight goes on.
It's an interesting way
to allow for some mistakes
to occur for some learning
to happen,
but really like
and to punish you,
but not immediately
spike you
and end the encounter.
Awesome.
So one thing that
see some other games
doing is they release
roadmaps of kind of
like in the same talk
of Endgame of things
that,
Callie,
stop it.
Sit down.
Sorry about that.
So for Diablo 4,
will we ever see
roadmaps come out
kind of showing
like detailing
what might be coming
in the next six months
to a year?
I know that there's
some challenges
with that.
Like if you guys
change your mind,
then like the community
gets really mad at you.
What are your thoughts
on that?
I think it's important
that community knows
that we are identifying
problems,
you know,
and that we are listening,
as I've said before.
And I think that a roadmap
does a good job
of expressing
some of this information,
but it does,
to your point,
does lock us
into a schedule.
So I think that we're
kind of like thinking
about how we want
to approach like explaining
these sorts of things.
Like you'll recall
back in like season two,
I mentioned at the very end
of actually between
when we were wrapping up
season two and AOZ was out
and we were getting ready
to begin talking
about season three,
I mentioned that we had
identified a lot
of itemization issues
and things we wanted
to make like upgrades to
and make updates,
which turned into
the season of Loot Reborn
and season four.
You know,
I wanted to make it clear
that we identified
a lot of the issues
that the players
have been talking
to us about for a while,
but we weren't able
to like immediately resolve
those sorts of things.
So I don't want,
one thing I,
when I occasionally see
from players
when they see a long roadmap
is they'll see something
that they care deeply
about it,
like really,
really towards the end
of a year
and they'll ask them like,
well,
do they not think
this is important?
Do they not care about this?
And I,
I think that there's a way
for us to talk
about these things
that players feel
that they have confidence
like that we are
looking at these problems
and we do have plans.
So I just think
we're just working
through exactly the way
that we want
to approach this.
Yeah,
I think I'll chime
in a little bit.
One of the things
that you're going to hear
is a constant theme
from me
and other designers
say this with different words.
But there's this idea
that there's,
there's rarely
really perfect solutions.
There's really only
trade-offs in the world.
And this actually comes
from an economic term
that says that there's
never solutions,
only trade-offs.
But, you know,
when you ask us things like,
you know,
why don't you do X or Y
or why don't you provide roadmaps?
The way that our brains
immediately go is,
well,
there's pros and cons
and which decision is best
trying to get the most pros
that we can
with the least cons
that we can, right?
A simple example
with roadmaps
is the pro of roadmap
is everybody's on the same page.
We show that,
hey,
we care about these things
and the community
knows what to expect, right?
Obviously,
that is a desirable thing to do.
But there's big cons
that maybe we have
that you don't see.
And this is where
most design discussions
end up of people asking us,
well,
what do you think
as developers?
is that we try to explain
the cons to you
so that you understand
the full picture.
You know,
the cons of a roadmap
is we're locked in now.
We've promised things to you
that we may not be able to do
for whatever reason
when things end up
changing down the road, right?
Life has a way
of screwing with your plans,
especially when you try
to plan things more long-term.
This isn't just true
with game design,
but anything.
So we try to keep,
make promises
and keep promises.
Like,
one of my things
I'm really passionate about
as a designer is
when it comes to interacting
with the community,
making promises
and then keeping them.
So I'm extremely careful
of the promises.
I mean,
this is just my strategy
of how to build trust
with people
and the community
and just life in general
is I'm very careful
of what promises I make
and then I make damn sure
when I do
that I keep them.
And so to do that,
the longer our roadmap
goes out,
the higher chance
we're not going to keep
those promises.
Some things,
for example,
that we've seeded in the past,
I remember it was either
our season one
or season two
campfire chat.
I made a list of things
that our team
wants to do longer term.
One of those things
on those lists
was making scaling mechanics
for legendaries
that kind of suck.
And we finally were doing
that in season four,
right?
You know,
your earthquake,
legendaries,
all of those,
we finally made them scale
with your weapon
to make the damage go up.
I also talked about
at the time,
and we haven't delivered
on this yet in my opinion,
but making ultimates
meaningful and scale
in a similar way.
It's on our radar,
something I want to do.
Haven't done it yet.
I didn't give a date
because I don't know
when the date is
because our timelines
and schedules
and priorities
changed quite a bit
based on community feedback.
You know,
if I had made the promise
like,
hey,
we're definitely
fixing ultimates,
then Loot Reborn
wouldn't have happened
because I have to spend
my team's time
on doing that other thing.
But this other thing
came up that I think
is way more important
for the game.
And that's just kind of
how the nature
of our job goes.
Thank you for the
super detailed answer.
And that is a perfect
segue into my next question.
It's kind of like
an edition of Mythbusters,
kind of.
So a lot of people
in the community,
a lot of the people
that are angry
in the community
about, you know,
whatever it is
they're angry about
at the time,
they say that...
They're passionate
about something.
Passionate.
Very passionate.
That's the word
we're looking for.
Constructively passionate, yeah.
Yeah, constructively passionate.
So one thing that I...
They have like the meme video
of you guys saying
feedback, feedback, feedback.
And then on the internet
from a bunch of different angles
they say,
Blizzard doesn't listen
to feedback.
They don't do anything.
They don't even test their game.
We're their beta testers.
Da-da-da-da.
So I wanted to ask you guys,
could you give us
some insights
into how your team
actually processes
and internalizes feedback?
Is it like concatenated
for you and you guys
have a meeting
and you discuss it like that?
How do you guys
go about testing things
internally
to kind of debunk
all of these myths
that you guys are just
working by yourselves
and never listening
to anything
which we know is not true?
You want to go first, Joe?
Yeah, I think we both
probably have different things
you want to say about this.
So I think that...
The point on feedback
that I think you're...
That's being brought up,
there's like kind of two things.
Like one,
are the designers in a corner
entirely by themselves
like just making decisions
with no information
being good to them.
And the other version
is like,
is the team listening
to the community, right?
And then how do we process
these sorts of things, right?
So the...
Starting from the
does the team
listen to the community
like side of this thing,
you know,
we are always reading
everything on...
It's getting posted on Reddit.
We're getting everything
that's posted on the forums.
We're going through
our socials
on a regular basis.
We have teams
and people like Adam Fletcher,
you know,
the community director.
He's going through
and like kind of gathering
a lot of this information
for us.
And in places where we don't...
Like I personally can't read
every thread
in every social media site, right?
You can't?
I can't.
Because there's other things
I also do as part of my job.
But I do read a lot of stuff, right?
And a lot of things
get sent to me.
So a lot of that stuff
can get like kind of
pulled together
for like reporting purposes
and brought to us, right?
And I think that's
really, really useful.
We also have a lot
of internal feedback
that we get from the team.
Like, so when we start
working on something,
we were able to like
kind of give a presentation
to the overall dev team
to get an idea
of what we're trying to do.
We have regular play tests
where like a large group of people
all get a chance
to kind of give us feedback
on a regular basis.
And we can keep checking in
with them as time goes on.
So that's...
I think that's a starting point
for these things.
But it's really important to us
that we are like hearing things
from the community
because that's kind of telling us
like are the changes
that we're making right now,
are they effective?
Like are people having
a good time with these things?
Because we can look
at all kinds of data
to determine things.
But like hearing
when people talk about it
is also really, really important.
When they have...
When players have needs
that aren't met,
you know, it's our job
to find ways to kind of
like bridge the gap there
and make sure that they're being heard
and the game is going to be
more fun for them.
But what do you want to talk about?
Yeah.
So firstly, I would say
different game companies,
different teams,
and even different teams
within a bigger team
have different cultures
and ideas and ways
that they process feedback.
So I'll tell you
what I do on my team
and kind of what D4
kind of does
as a larger team, right?
So on the live team,
we are probably
the most interactive
with feedback
because we're doing
the live changes.
We have to be very connected
to the game
to make good decisions.
So I give this speech
a lot to the people
in my group
of your job
as a designer
is to go and find
the problems
with the game
and then you are
the filter
when the community
comes in
and brings up things,
whether it's a streamer
giving things.
I post things all the time
from streamers.
from Reddit threads.
I post things all the time
from our forums.
Anywhere that you can go out
and go.
And also,
personal play experience.
Nothing replaces that as well.
So we actually dedicate
every day
at least some amount of time
that everybody in my group
is either playing
an internal build
of future things
coming out in the game,
which I'm playing
through season five right now
and I'm really far in it,
or they're playing
their live character
in the live game
because you need
to understand the game
and understand the problems.
And the way that I do things
and what I've been trying
to tell my team
and I think we're pretty good at
is while you are parsing
all this feedback
and playing the game yourself,
you keep a running list
of notes
of crap that sucks
that you want to make better
or ideas that other people had
that you think are good ideas
that you want to make better.
Now, of course,
not every idea is equal, right?
You don't copy
every Reddit thread
and every single thing
that someone says.
We are the filter
of trying to figure out,
remember I talked about
those no perfect solutions
only trade-offs?
This is where we're like,
hey, they brought up an idea
and we think it's good.
Now we need to explore
if that can actually work
in the game.
And this is where we come up
with our list of things
and priorities
that we're going to do.
That's a starting point.
That's one of a few starting points.
The first starting point
is community feedback,
our own play experience.
Another one is telemetry.
That's just a fancy word for data.
We have the ability
to see data all over the game
of how many people
are equipping
different legendary aspects,
how many people
are engaging
with certain types of content.
We can see what's working,
what's not working,
what people are actually doing
versus what they say.
Usually what they say
will match
with what people are doing,
but there's a mismatch
that we have to have
a discussion of like,
hey, how important
is this actually?
And then another way
is internal testing tools.
Again, we have groups
that give us presentations
and people who their job
is to look through data
and do focus sessions
and all kinds
of other fancy tricks
to come up with stories
and understanding
the different types
of players we have
and what they're doing
and how they work.
And they give us presentations
on different topics
that we're interested in
or they find their own topics
of things that maybe
we didn't think of
that we may have missed.
And then last but not least,
we have internal people.
You know, we have a big team
of people working on this game
and we have certain feedback avenues
via emails or channels
that we give feedback
to each other
because on new stuff,
we can't rely on telemetry
or the community
or all those other things.
And that's where things
are a lot harder.
I think Joe went into this yesterday
a little more deeper,
so I'll just gloss over it.
But this idea that Diablo
is a freaking huge game
that takes forever to play
and really truly understands
because our systems
are so interconnected.
So there is no substitute
for actually going through
that 80 plus hour experience
and playing everything.
The part that makes that really hard
and where I think the community
gives us a hard time sometimes,
I think a little bit of it
is warranted,
but it's a cursed problem
is what I call it,
which is another concept
I'll go into later,
is that to really test our game,
you need to spend your life
playing our game in many ways
or a lot of time,
more times,
more hours
than what you normally
would expect someone
to work at a job, right?
So we can't tell people,
hey, you must spend
all your life playing this game,
but also, by the way,
you have to design
and create the new things too, right?
So that means that internally,
it is really hard to playtest
the full amount of our game
as a designer.
We have to rely on,
we have people in QA
and other playtesters
that do play this content.
We either direct them
of things we want to test and play
or they just find things
on their own
that they think,
hey, they bring it up to us,
like, hey, we think
this is a problem
and we have to parse that.
But there isn't enough time
for a single designer
or every designer
to play the game fully
all the time,
but we do still play it
a good amount
and we use those
internal feedback mechanisms
to make things the best
that they can.
And this is where I think
there is that little
disconnect sometimes
with the community
where, yeah,
we would love to polish things
and play it.
Now, I would love to play
season five 200 hours
before it comes out.
I only get it for,
you know, 50 hours, right?
And we have to use our guts
and existing ideas
and telemetry
to figure out
if the decisions
we make are right.
And then we use
after we launch the game
to really fine tune
and make it perfect, right?
And that's kind of
the overall process
of how things work.
Yeah, one last thing
I want to add here too
is that even,
we're just thinking about
like a feature,
like we're talking
about adding one thing,
like something like the pit,
for example.
Good example,
because it's going to be new
coming out in season four.
If you sit down
and you play the pit
for an hour one day,
you're going to feel
a certain way
about your experience
playing the pit.
You're going to feel
differently if you play
that for two hours a day,
five days straight,
you know,
and you experience it
through that entire process.
You're going to have
a different relationship
with the content
at that point.
And players are going to go,
you know,
10, 20x that number
by the time they're done
playing in season potentially.
So like it's really,
really important
that we get the reps
in on these features
to make sure
that they're really resonating
and they're saying
they're doing everything
that they need to do, right?
So I think if there's a,
there's a lot of truth
to everything that Adam's
talking about.
Everything is a lot of trade-offs.
There's a lot of things
we need to do.
And this kind of links
now suddenly we're able
to like take,
take what we already know
about the season
and then multiply that
like 10, 20, 50 fold
as we get tons of players
going in,
checking things out,
not just from the telemetry,
but also just in the feedback
we're getting from content creators,
from players themselves.
Like we've got a lot
of really good data for that.
So it's been,
it's been very useful
for the same reasons
that Adam talks about.
Yeah.
I mean,
go ahead.
Sorry.
No, go ahead.
One last real quick thing
is this is where you get things
that seem obvious to players
that were bad ideas,
but sounded like really good ideas
when we're sitting in a room
talking about it.
That simple example
I'll give in season four
is when you temper
your items or things
and there's like a really nice thing
that plays
and you can see it,
it's visual,
but you can't skip it easily,
right?
That kind of stuff
is where sometimes
things fall through the cracks
of, hey,
doing this 2,000 times
is actually terrible
because you've got to wait forever
versus, well,
we want to have a moment
of celebration
and for the cool thing
to be cool.
Balancing these things
is what can be harder
to do internally
where obviously
we've messed up enough times
and this is true
for every game company,
so I'm not afraid to admit it,
but we've made that mistake
enough times
that now we're very cognizant of it,
like we make a new feature
or a new activity,
like, hey,
how does this feel
if you're doing it for 200 hours?
Is this still going to be something
that people want to go through,
right?
That's a question now
that we ask all the time,
but even then,
there are times
where we have to kill
otherwise good ideas
or we have to flex a little bit
because we do need
some presentation
or some tutorialization
or some other thing
to balance that
even if it makes
the 2,000 times experience
a little bit worse,
right?
The answer's not always
so obvious,
I guess,
but we are receptive
to like when the community
tells us clearly,
hey, no,
we want it to be this way,
we're going to do it that way.
I mean,
it was a lot of great points.
I'm very glad
that I asked that question
because the thing
that is refreshing to me,
the thing that I wanted
to hear more than anything
is that you guys
have a chance
to actually play
through the game
and not only to hear
that you guys play the game
as almost part
of the job description,
but it sounds like
you actually put
a big effort into that.
I mean,
that makes me feel,
that makes me feel great,
honestly.
That's so great to hear.
I'm so glad
that's part of the process.
Talking about
some of the current
modes in the game,
let's talk about,
you talked about yesterday
the State of Nightmare Dungeons,
and CJ did a ton
of iteration on it.
Now we can teleport to them.
You just buffed Glyph XP.
You said that you'd like
to add more fun things
to do to them
in the future.
You guys made events
better now.
I saw Goblin Pax,
I think,
on the PTR
when you put
the Vampire Ambushers.
That was good.
You reduced the cast time
down to 0.75 seconds,
so we're going to have
new things coming out
for it.
My question is,
is going forward,
it looks like you guys
made a ton of
qualitative changes to it.
You just make it
a little bit easier
to access
all of these different things
rather than riding around
on your pony
to every single thing
and everything takes forever.
When you are designing
future things,
is that kind of
at the front of your mind
with things like,
oh,
maybe at Nightmare Dungeons
we can carry
multiple objects?
Because if there's
two rocks and two pedestals,
if you go rock, rock,
you're guaranteed
to backtrack.
I mean,
I have two hands.
And then,
have you thought about
reducing the cast time
even further?
I know that one comment
was,
if the cast time
is so low,
then people may not
even see that they
interacted with something.
But maybe that could be
updated via like a
little quest thing.
Oh, quest,
pick up two rocks.
Oh, it highlights.
Oh, now pick up one rock.
And another part of it was,
it's not just that
I have a problem
freeing prisoners.
going to Dead Man's Dredge,
and the quest objective
is I have to free
seven prisoners.
Like,
how many people
got caught here?
Is qualitative stuff
still at the front
of your mind
when you're iterating
on these things
and in the future
events that you're
going to make?
So I think that there's
a couple different pieces
to pick apart here,
right?
So with Nightmare Dungeons,
they're building upon
the dungeons we had
in Diablo 4,
right?
And these were supposed
to be these really
kind of interesting
little content things
you could find
all over the world.
They all had a little bit
of environmental
storytelling,
objective-based storytelling,
some side quest points
to these dungeons as well.
And we want players
to feel like they're
going on a little bit
of an adventure
when they go into these.
We didn't initially
make the content
in these spaces
to feel like
they were just
blast corridors,
if that makes sense,
right?
So I think that
as we think about
what different players
are looking for
and what we can do
to improve the experience
for everybody,
we don't want to lose
the kind of like
the contextual
and like fantasy
underpinnings
of what players
are doing
when they go
into these spaces.
To your point,
like, you know,
it's not that you hate
freeing prisoners,
no, but you don't like
that it might take,
you know,
0.75 seconds to do it
is one question,
maybe.
And then there's
another one where it's
like, we don't want
to free seven.
So you kind of want
to be like a faster,
more punchy experience,
but it's not that you
don't like having to
click those objects
as part of your experience
going through a dungeon.
I think that like
there's, I think
there's an expectation
when players are like
doing some of these
actions that there is
a response.
So having just a,
like a quest tick
for some things,
I'm not saying that
this is where we would
only ever make this
decision,
and a quest tick for
things like freeing a
prisoner, it is,
it is feedback.
Is it as impactful
as having the moment
where you get to see
your character on
the binds?
I'm not so sure,
you know, but in the
end, is that value,
it's to Adam's point
earlier, but like,
you know, it's about
making trade-offs.
Is the, is the idea
for the player who
does care, does care
about like kind of
going slowly through
the space and trying
to find the collectibles
and trying to do
all these things,
for that player,
is it, is it going
to be a big miss
for them if they
click on stuff and
just kind of like
has a quick update,
doesn't feel like
anything really changed.
So it's sort of like
where we want to
optimize things.
I think when you
look at content
like the, like the
pit, you know,
and a lot of things
we did in Helltide
as well, you know,
we've made a lot
of attempts to try
to make sure that
the content feels like
there is less friction,
you know, as you're
going through.
So like when you
get into a flow state
that you're happy with,
that you can kind of
maintain that pace.
So, and we made a
number of changes
we already called out
to Nightmare Dungeons
to also kind of
support this.
So I think it's a
question of like how
much further do we
want to go within
Nightmare Dungeons
specifically, right?
Because I think we've
already said that we're
looking at this for
other pieces of content.
I don't know where
we're going to fall
necessarily for the
channel time for
clicking on objects
and freeing them.
It could be that it
comes out a little
bit lower.
It could be that we
decide we want to
make changes to make
it more instant
instantaneous.
We haven't really
made a decision.
You know, we'll
continue to be looking
at feedback as we
play and also from
like different players
like players who are
just playing Diablo 4
for the first time.
I want to kind of
hear what their
experience is like as
well.
Awesome.
So here's kind of
like a, here's kind
of like maybe a huge
question, but it
asks very directly.
So what is kind of
the future of the
overworld in Diablo 4?
When we first released,
it was kind of the
main thing you used
to do everything and
kind of the first
experience was that
50 to 100 grind.
Now 1 to 100 is much
easier and the focus
is probably, you know,
having, enjoying that
journey, going to the
pit and anything in the
future that you're going
to release.
A lot of the things that
seem to come out though,
the abattoir and the
challenge riff thing and
the pit, they're all
instanced things.
Are there big plans for
the overworld?
Is that still like the
defining characteristic of
Diablo 4 or are we
moving away from that?
So we, you know, Diablo
4 and the fact that we
have this like big
contiguous sanctuary is
still a really big part
of Diablo 4.
Now, I think that we
want to continue to
expand the landmass and
the areas where players
can explore.
That's still an important
part of things.
But in terms of how
players are engaging with
the experience overall,
we do expect that one of
the downsides of the
open world is that it's a
fixed layout, right?
So if we think about
like the sorts of things
that players like to play
in a, in a, in a, in a
like a playable content
fashion, right?
It's not normally in place
where you like really want
to keep running through
exactly the same glade in
the fracture piece or
exactly the same area, you
know, of Kerstan.
It's, it's, it's usually
you're trying to like find
like different things to
kind of go engage with.
And like our dungeon
systems are places where
you can really do a lot
more of that.
I think we push it really
well within Helltides.
You know, there's lots of
things happening in
Helltides.
They're pretty
procedural in terms of
how things respond in and
like what sorts of events
you might find as you're
kind of wandering around.
But in terms of like
having a lot more like
flexibility to create
different experiences, we
have that really more in
other systems.
But I think for, this is
like going back to some
things I talked about the
other day, there's sort of
like the experience that
a player has.
Diablo is a, is a, is a
big game, right?
And, and I don't say that
to suggest that any, any,
anyone's needs are less
important, just that there
are a lot of different
needs.
Different players have
different expectations.
So when some players come
into Diablo, like they're
here because they want to
go through like this epic
story.
They want to play their,
they really want to play
a sorceress and they want
to like see what happens
to little, if they want to
go explore all, they want
to find all the things in
all the zones and they
want to get really, really
powerful.
And then they're going to,
they're going to take a
break until the expansion
comes out.
That's just the way that
they sort of play these
games.
That's how they, that's
how they play, right?
For those players, these
moments as they explore the
world, it's really, really
important because that's
their experience with Diablo.
It's like their exploration
of the overworld, them
going and finding all
these side quests, talking
to all these characters
and that's their
relationship with the game.
For players who play
seasonally, you know, they
it's, it's once you've
kind of like uncovered all
the applications and you
found all these things and
done this stuff, you don't,
there's not usually a lot
of reasons why you want to
go and have that same
moment of discovery again.
You can't really recreate
it.
We talked for a while about
like moving little statues
around season to season.
So you'd have to collect
them again.
It's, it's, it's another,
another one of my
brilliant ideas.
Yeah.
So we didn't, we didn't do
it of course.
Right.
But like we had the idea of
like every season we'd
move where the little
statues could be found.
So players have to go
find them again.
But then the next
conversation is immediately
like, well, okay, so
people are going to go
onto Maxwell or whatever
and they're going to go
immediately see where the
node map is for the next
set of ultra little.
Then that's now their new
homework they have to do
at the beginning of every
season.
They have to run around
on their horse and go
collect every single one
of these.
And it's like, is that fun?
No, clearly not for that
for that player.
But it wasn't, it was
necessarily horrible the
first time players do this.
Like that's, that's part of
the fun of like almost
like an open world game
anyway.
It's kind of like
exploration and finding
things.
So I know that I'm, I'm
getting to go long, but
so I think that the, the,
the underpinning point
here is that the, the
overworld of Diablo 4 is
so really, really important
as we think about how to
make the best use of it
for like replayable content.
You know, Helltide's a
good example of this.
Blood Harvest is really,
really, really, really
helpful for kind of
giving us some like ideas
of what players are really
excited about things that
we could do better.
Like the like kind of
light social gameplay
of summoning creatures and
things.
And I think we have other
ideas we continue to
explore in that
direction.
I think Legion events
and boss events are
things we continue to
like kind of iterate on
and think more about,
you know, but I think
that in terms of creating
like, like really
compelling replayable
content, I think it's
going to end up being in
more of the space where
you have like more
procedural control over
how like the dungeon is
formulated or like what
players can expect to
encounter as opposed to
these, these more fixed
outdoor locations.
Does that answer your
question?
Yeah.
So I guess laughing at
me.
I didn't answer the
question.
No, no.
These are such in-depth
answers.
I'm, I'm just scared.
I'm looking over at my
questions.
I'm, I'm never going to,
I'm trying to figure out
how to skip around for
all of them.
So I guess I'm so sorry.
No, no, no.
So the main takeaway that
I'm getting there is the
overworld is a super
important part of it, like
a first player's experience
discovering everything.
But then it's hard to
recreate that magic for the
people that come season to
season to season.
And that's why it goes
more to instance stuff is
kind of, I guess the
summary of, yeah, that's
reasonable.
Yeah.
I think we're also on a
regular basis looking for
new ways to engage with
the, uh, with the open
world in ways that are
going to be fun for
seasonal players as well.
Like, so we're, we're
continuing to find like
just experimenting with
things, see what makes it
like fun and new for
players.
Okay.
I promised I would ask
this.
So there, uh, maybe there
might be a player out there
that you guys have heard
of and have maybe added, I
don't know, hundreds of
hours of overtime to the
team, Rob and Rob, you
familiar.
That's a little familiar.
Yeah.
So he got a Rob love
Rob.
He is a good guy.
He had a two questions
about the pit.
These are probably a
little bit more
straightforward, but, um,
I guess for, for end
game activities is, do
you guys ever think about
or worry about, I guess
fishing?
So like it gets to a
point in the pit where,
Oh, you're fishing for
the right mob type or
you're fishing for the
right boss or, and then
you just leave kind of
like what happened in
Diablo three or, Oh,
I'm going to go get a
very on.
And hopefully that it
procs the amazing shrine
for me.
So then I can finally win.
And do you guys off the
top of your head know
about how much the health
in the pit was buffed
by?
And I, I'm guessing
that the main idea for
there is not only to add
difficulty, but to
actually, because the,
when you were going
through the pit, the
bills are so strong that
you delete the, the
rift part of it in two
minutes, like clockwork
every time.
And the monsters don't
even get to do
anything.
So I assume like the
part of the reason for
buffing it is to actually
even let them get a hit
on you and see what they
even do.
Yeah.
I can take the first
part of the question at
least.
I mean, I can take both
too.
Joe wants to take the
other part.
So talk about
fishing.
Yes.
Fishing for stuff keeps
me up at night and I
hate the problem.
And it's a really hard
problem to solve.
Remember that no salute,
you know, rarely perfect
solutions, only trade
offs thing.
Right.
So this very much
applies to this type of
problem.
Right.
A core thing that we
want in our game is,
and when it comes to
combat and effects and
legendary powers and
unique powers and
whatever, is we want to
push the envelope, make
cool shit.
Right.
So on one end of the
spectrum, you need to
make cool stuff.
Right.
And that involves doing
things that aren't
necessarily completely
deterministic because I
think completely
deterministic things after
a while get kind of
boring.
Right.
When you know that you're
going to get this effect
or it's up all the time
or you do this and get
this, like we do it a lot,
by the way.
So I'm not saying that's not
a good design, but just
you need to have some
spiciness, some really
cool, crazy things.
Right.
And that that unique
uber unique power is one
of those.
On the flip side, though,
it means that when you
make really hard content,
doing things like wanting
to make cool stuff,
fishing gets in the way of
that a lot of times,
especially in randomly
generated content, which is
what, you know, the pit is
in many ways.
So that is why we have to
do things that we that by
the way, we as designers
don't like, like removing
the fun shrines or the
things that are going to
break because then you
just find the shrines that,
you know, break the game
in whatever way.
And that's all that you're
doing.
And that becomes the game.
This is a core thing about
ARPGs that I, in my
opinion, after working on
it now for years, and I've
been involved in pretty
much every game genre
extensively as a player
and many as a designer.
I think ARPGs are one of
the hardest, if not the
hardest genre to design
for.
MMOs are really high up
there, too.
There's a lot of other
genres I think are very
difficult, but ARPGs are
a special slice of
awfulness when it comes
to trying to make things
fun and also make them
interesting.
And this is one of the
reasons why.
So as far as, like, this
exact design of the
spear, we're keeping it in
for now.
I would be very sad if we
had to redesign it because
it's the only way to get
through high pit tiers.
That would make me
personally sad, but
because that is the most
difficult thing to do, we
may have to make a tweak to
it.
But we're not doing it yet.
We're going to see how it
plays out.
But I think that the
conversation is more
interesting conceptually,
like, you know, is this a
problem?
Yes, absolutely.
Does it mean that we can't
do things that would
otherwise be cool and
awesome for your average
player?
Yes, absolutely.
But we also think it's
best for the game because
I think fishing for the
right tile set, the right
mob, like restarting a
thing over and over to be
able to progress is not
fun.
And therefore, we have to
design the rest of our
game knowing that that is
a thing.
Yeah, just adding to that,
too.
Like, I think that, you
know, we definitely see
fishing as a problem, so
much so that we built the
gauntlet, you know, for the
trials feature with
fishing specifically as the
thing we're trying to
account for.
Or we said, all right, if
we have a competitive
content feature players are
going to engage with and
it's randomized, then
players aren't really
competing until they find
exactly the right seed that
they manage to roll to
compete against because
that's the actual optimal
seed that they need to
compete on.
It's only against this
monster family or only with
this dungeon tile layout or
only with this, like, these
set of shrines or whatever
it is.
So instead, what we did is
we made a highly
deterministic content type that
changed it every week.
And players went to it
and said, like, well, why
is it so fixed?
Like, this is boring.
Like, I want something
that's different and
changes every time.
But then you kind of fall
back to that same point that
I have brought up about,
like, these trade-offs for
all the problems that we
have.
Then we have to decide,
like, all right, so we're
okay with the idea that,
like, players are going to go
into, like, a gauntlet run
and they're going to have a
wildly disparate experience
potentially between person A
and person B.
And they're just
continually running the
content over and over again
in the hopes they
eventually get a good seed
and that might be the way
that they're able to
place because the difference
could potentially be vast
between one thing and the
next.
So it's a, you know,
it's a complicated space.
It's something we
definitely think about.
The other part of your
question was, what did we
do about the, what did we
do about, like, health
scaling in the pit?
The HP, yeah.
How much did it go up by?
Yeah.
So we did make some big
changes there.
So basically what was
happening in the PTR is
that monster scaling,
monster health scaling was
pretty mild in the pit
going through the first
hundred levels.
It was basically virtually
nil, you know, from
level 100 on.
More or less.
Right.
So we ended up putting it
in a place where, uh,
like the tier 200 pit is
like, okay.
So like, like around tier
150 pit is like close to
where AOZ was, you know,
for like tier 25, uh, uh,
AOZ runs and tier 200
goes beyond that.
So it's pretty, it's pretty
considerable.
The scaling has been
increased.
We still want to be
gradual as you're kind of
progressing through, uh,
because we want you to feel
that you have a place to
push.
It's not like, so like
because AOZ was 25 tiers
extremely, extremely chunky
when you went from tier to
tier as you got deeper and
deeper inside.
Here, it's a little more
gradual as you go further
and further.
And we think that that's
going to be good experience
overall.
Um, because it's ultimately
a lot of the materials you
really want from the pit,
you can gain by the time
you're like doing like tier
sixties.
You start to get like little
bits of the deethyron that
you need to kind of start
finishing off your masterwork
items.
And then that gets more
and more efficient as you
go deeper and deeper, you
know, but there's a, but we
do want to have these like
really, really difficult
challenges.
We made a, we made a, a
decision at the launch
period of the game where we
took nightmare dungeons,
uh, difficulty, we kind of
scaled it in a different
way, you know, whereas
like initially they were
extremely challenging going
up to tier 100 and we ended
up making a reduction in
their difficulty, uh, going
into season one, uh, where
we basically rebalanced
things such that like the
tier 75 old nightmare
dungeon was the new tier 100
nightmare dungeon and
players no longer had that,
like that measuring stick,
that really, really difficult
content anymore.
We kind of take it away.
We want that to still be
there in the pit.
I mean, I think if tier
200 is far beyond
abattoir of zero 25,
especially with some of
like the balancing and the
bug fixes to a lot of
different builds, I
actually, I don't know,
maybe I'm wrong, but I
expect that to be pretty
challenging.
I don't think people are
going to do that as a
cakewalk.
Um, okay.
So we have eight minutes
left.
I'm, I already cut off my
timer.
There's no way I can get
to 99% of these
questions.
So, uh, how do we feel
about maybe doing a little
rapid fire?
Let's do it.
Okay.
Sure.
Yeah.
This was talked about
yesterday.
If I remember correctly,
this was the, so these are
the top, top questions from
YouTube.
So I promised I would ask
them.
So here we go.
Um, this was the number one
question by far, and it was
touched on a little bit
yesterday.
Is there an armory coming?
I heard yesterday.
I think you, if I quote you
correctly, you said that
armory is great.
The team, the team likes it,
had to prioritize some
things.
Will an armory be coming to
Diablo four so we can save
our builds?
Uh, it is.
Yeah.
I mean, this is a problem
that I think that, uh, that
players have.
I think I've already
mentioned that we're like,
we're in the business of
trying to like solve, uh,
player problems.
Uh, it's a thing we're
really excited about.
It's a thing we, it's a
thing we would like to do.
And that's all I can say
right now.
They're excited about it
guys.
Okay.
Uh, there's lots of
different ways to expand the
game.
And as, uh, Joe put it
yesterday, different slices
of, of the pizza to give you
power again from YouTube.
It seems like the most
requested way that people
would like to expand power or
change their builds is to
have this skill tree expanded.
Is that something that we can
look forward to at some point
coming to Diablo four is the
team passionate about
expanding the skill tree in
multiple ways.
Maybe you'll even give us an
ultimate button so we can get
another skill.
You never know.
Uh, yeah, I'll, I'll take
this one, I guess, unless
you'll want to say some more.
Uh, I would say I have, we
have nothing to announce
about big updates to the
skill tree.
It is a little bit more of a
complicated problem because we
want the skill tree to remain
as an easy gateway for new
players and returning players
to come back and kind of know
what that is.
And we didn't want the
complexity and have to
the depth of our game to be
there.
So it comes with some nasty
trade-offs that I'm not sure
that we're willing to make, but
we are open to the idea of
adding some more depth to the
skill tree, but we don't want
it to be super complicated.
It's not going to be the POE
encyclopedia.
We don't, we don't want that,
at least not for our game.
We want to be in crafting in
other places.
Yeah.
If I could show like the,
like seeing how different
players, like, again, there's a
lot of people who like this is
their first Diablo game, like
seeing what players did with the
skill tree in testing.
Yeah.
I think it would be very
surprising to you and your
audience.
They take, they take all the
generators and max them to five.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And other things like that.
It's, it's a tougher problem.
I think a lot of people give it
credit for.
And I don't know that the juice
is worth the squeeze if we go
too far, but hearing that people
want more, we've heard that loud
and clear, but nothing to announce
in the near, in the immediate
future.
Okay.
The next one for repeated and
summoning content now and in the
future of the game, are there
plans to let people just resummon
these bosses without resetting the
instance?
Cause that eats up a lot of time
for the people that do want to
farm up a bunch of things and
kill some bosses.
Yeah, this is a really, this is a
really good idea.
There's a lot of things that get
cleaned up when a plate, when
players reset a dungeon that makes
it a lot easier for us to do this
in the first place.
Let me take that back to the
team.
I don't, I don't know that we've
talked deeply about like exactly
when we could deliver something
like this, but we definitely see
it as a, we definitely see it as
a, something that you can
improve.
So yeah, we'll, we'll take that
back.
All right.
Last one from YouTube here.
Will the campaign receive further
attention?
So we'll, well, first of all,
obviously probably the story
continues with the expansion, but
another way is currently when you
start up a new season of Diablo,
you can, you can go through the
campaign again, if you want, or you
can probably now go farm in
Helltide and the Helltide is going
to level you a million times faster
for a million, million more rewards.
It's not close at all.
And some games let you force you to do
the campaign.
Some games in Diablo 4, you don't
have to.
Have you guys thought about maybe
editing the campaign slightly for a
replay, maybe taking out like the
camel escort for, for example, and
maybe benchmarking, oh, how long does
it take to do a campaign just
normally playing?
What is it?
Three hours for us?
I don't know what it would be.
And then benchmarking what it would
be to do it in Helltide and kind of
have them at the same point at the
end of those journeys to allow
players a real choice in how they
want to start out their new season
because the campaign was such a fan
favorite on the launch and it was
very well done.
Sure.
So I think if there is a, like the
quest team has a lot of really cool
ideas of things that you want to do
to allow for players to like replay
the campaign or to make it, to kind
of edit it a little bit in some ways
that you suggest.
I think that it's a thing that we're
thinking about as we go.
But the, we know that we want to
make sure that we are prioritizing
the piece of the game that need
work first, if that makes sense.
Like, I think that the idea of being
able to replay a campaign is very,
very exciting.
And I think there's really neat
things we can do.
And we do have plans in the future
for this stuff as well.
I don't want to like make it sound
like we're not committing to
anything here.
We kind of do want to do something
like this.
It's just that there's a lot of
other like replay features like
Helltide, for example, that we
thought are, we're in a great
position to like lift up and make
feel like more exciting for
players.
So that's been a more of a
priority for us.
But I do think that there's
opportunities there for sure.
Something there I want to point
out, and this would help when the
community is discussing things or
when you even are with us, is this
idea of opportunity cost.
I don't know if you know what,
are you familiar with that term,
Rax?
Yeah, economics.
Maybe not.
Give up something to gain
something else.
Cool.
Then I don't have to explain it.
But yeah, the opportunity cost
comes very heavy into play when we
talk about features and
suggestions and things from
players.
I think a lot of times it can be
frustrating as a member of a
community, because I'm a member of
gaming communities too, so I know
how it is.
I'm like, hey, you know, this
thing, we obviously, it sounds like
a good idea, and we all agree it's
a good idea.
Why don't the devs do it right
away?
And most of the time when that is
true, it's because of opportunity
costs.
It's that the excited opportunity
costs are something that you didn't
realize makes it harder than it
seems.
But opportunity costs, you know,
here it's like, do we do loot
reborn?
Do we redo how all the loot works in
the game and your entire leveling
experience with our updates to
Helltide?
Or do we make the campaign have
parity with not doing campaign to
level up, right?
Now, having campaign have parity to
the non-campaign obviously is a good
thing, but I would argue very
heavily that loot being better in a
loot-based game is more important
and impacts more people in a better
way, in a more long-term way.
And then the list goes long and
long, forever, forever of the
things that you could do versus
what you have to decide to do.
And then the other part, kind of
alluding to your last question about
resummoning bosses, is that I would
say in that one, like, yeah,
obviously good idea, better player
experience.
In there, I would say the reason why
we're not doing it, just knowing how
the game works a little bit more, is
our game wasn't structured that way
and we have to do a lot of things to
make it structured that way.
And to actually do it is harder than
most people would think, and that is
why.
Both of these things are obviously good
ideas that we would want.
There's different reasons why we
haven't done them yet.
Doesn't mean they won't happen, but
it means that it's why they're not
happening now or yet.
And that's a better way to frame it
when people are talking to each other,
because like, hey, what should the
Diablo X4 team do first or now?
Or hey, you know, maybe this is a
little bit harder.
Could you explain why it's harder?
Would be a good question for an
interviewer, for example, right?
Because then you're going to get
actual insight into why rather than
just complaining that it's not
happening.
Are you providing Rack's feedback on
this?
I mean, I might be giving feedback on
feedback.
That's part of my job too.
But I like productive
conversations is why.
And I think the community would
rather have more productive
conversations than their only
avenues to complain and not know why
things aren't working the way that
they want.
I think people want to know how
things work.
I think that makes sense.
I think they want to know how
things work.
I want to educate people so that we
can have better conversations about
games.
I mean, I'm a loser, guys.
I'm always here.
If you guys ever want to talk, which
we're at
we're actually at time.
I have one more.
All right.
I mean, probably probably the the one
that I I'm just going to ask a 15
part question then to to abuse the one
more.
I guess I love it.
Gamer at heart.
Probably probably the the most important
one that's still left on the list is
about social features.
So there I have three main topics of so I
just I can't believe how many questions
I put here.
That was so stupid of me.
I mean, there's no no chance at all.
Anyway, social features.
So the there's three main things
trading, group finder, clans.
So with trading, what are your guys
thoughts on putting an auction house
esque type of thing just to allow
trading and to avoid third party sites?
Obviously not a real money auction
house.
People are begging for a group finder.
I don't know why people have cooties.
I rather play by myself, but I guess
people want it.
And then clans.
I understand.
I understand there's a big difficulty
with clans, not just implementing them
like they were implemented in Diablo
three, but Diablo three clans mean
absolutely nothing.
It's just a second friends list.
There's no achievements to do.
There's nothing to unlock.
There's nothing to work toward.
But then if you put that in the game
opportunity costs, the thing that the
economic principle we keep talking
about, then if you build that in the
game, then people have to belong to a
clan.
Yep.
And otherwise they feel left out, which
then leads me to another one of my
million questions about SSF, but whatever.
So for social features, trading, group
finder, clans.
What are your guys' thoughts on those
three for Diablo four?
Let's get going.
So for trading, okay.
Trading in season four, players can
trade legendaries and uniques.
They're still going to have to like go
and actually meet up to do those
trades.
There's not going to be an automated
trading function.
There are things we're talking about
with regards to like the trade chat
channels, make it a little bit easier
to navigate in terms of like creating
like an actual auction house user
interface.
It's a thing a team has discussed.
It's not a thing we've landed on.
We really want to see what the reaction
is from players in season four and what
the experience is broadly for players in
season four, how many players are
actually trading, you know, because I
imagine there's going to be, it'll be
different for different types of
players, right?
But I think there could potentially be
room for an investment there because
we don't want to just push players
just to like third party sites.
But we were at a point where we're
like, well, do we really want to like
go and make a whole, it would be a
opportunity cost would be a big
investment to go make an auction
house for Diablo four, for example,
without knowing exactly what the desire
for it is going to be.
And we didn't want to like wait to like
let some of these things be tradable
in the meantime.
So that's the HALA version.
We're not opposed to it.
We want to see how things go in season
four for the, with regards to the
like group finder, I think is the way
that you call it.
We do want to make sure that there are
easier systems for players to use to
find parties of players who are doing
things that interest them.
We do have a social team on Diablo four.
They've been thinking about clan stuff,
things like this, things to make
socialization more easy between
players.
I think there'll be exciting stuff to
share in the future.
So there's things we're thinking
about.
And there are, and then with regards to
the last one, clans, of course,
clans.
Uh, we also have ideas of things
we want to do to update parts of the
clan functionality to make it just a
little more engaging to give more
purpose to parts of clans.
You know, this is a thing that we are,
we have designs for and things we're
thinking about.
I can't announce anything today.
Just to say that we recognize there's some
parts of social features in Diablo four
that can be leveled up, made better.
And there's process we see players going
through as part of regular play in
seasons that we want to make easier,
more streamlined for them.
Well, I, I gotta be honest.
It was, it was actually an honor to have
you guys come here.
I really like you guys.
I love the Diablo franchise since I was
a kid.
This actually meant a lot to me.
Um, I have a million more, I have a
million more questions, but I know we're
out of time.
Want to be respectful of that.
Thank you guys.
Thank you guys for coming here and, uh,
speaking so open and honestly, I'm a
loser.
I'm always here.
If you guys want to go again, I mean,
you guys got three, three free hours.
Uh, I, I got a lot more questions, but
I guess who's, is DM going next or I can
just pass along a million more.
I'm sure they're, I believe so.
Yeah.
I'm on with them.
All right.
It's been a blast.
It's been super fun.
Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
Um, I will say we're trying to get in
front of the community a little bit
more and talk about these things.
It's something that I, I really like
doing and I'm pretty passionate about
and I'm looking forward to doing more.
So thank you guys for being here.
Talk to us.
Hell yeah.
Let's do it again.
Thank you guys.
Uh, everybody in chat say goodbye to
the lovely people at blizzard and
we'll, I guess we'll see you in season
four.
Thank you all.
Thanks guys.