Thank you.
Yeah.
Actually you toMe &
And what we've seen is compared to Season 6, which had a lot of positive feedback as part of our rebound progression model,
is that a lot of that has sort of gone down the drain in terms of how fast players are chewing through some of the content.
So we actually have a graph that we could look at. I apologize, this is terrible, but I just pulled it from the stat, our sort of stat page.
It's not the greatest. But this is a picture of Season 6. You can see on the Y axis here,
it was taking roughly people around 15 to 17 hours on average to get to max level.
We felt like that was a pretty good journey, right? Part of Diablo is that sort of zero to hero journey.
And part of what's fun about leveling is you start to sort of form a build and find a lot of different pieces early on
when you're still forming your character where customization is really fun, right?
You're not necessarily locked into a build. So we felt like that was a pretty good clip for hitting max level.
It's on average, right? So you could either go faster or slower depending on sort of how much of a blaster you are.
So we felt like that was a pretty good average, especially with difficulty tiers and your ability to sort of go faster or slower based on your pacing.
And let's go to Season 7 now. And it nearly doubled.
So you can see that it was taking about nine hours on average, which is kind of insane, right? Again, this is the average.
So if you're, you know, if you're like the Wudijo of the world, it's probably more like two hours or like 30 minutes.
And that was something that we definitely feel like has sort of missed the mark in terms of that initial journey.
So we are going to be making some changes just to adjust for a lot of the seasonal power and things like that.
We're not going to necessarily nerf the power of the seasonal power. We still want you to feel powerful.
But we are going to essentially take a look at the 1 to 25 experience and just smooth that out a little bit,
which is going to essentially make the leveling experience a little bit closer to Season 6.
So it is going to be a slower from 1 to 25. But one thing we've done to sort of compensate that is we've taken a look at the itemization.
We don't like that rares and sort of magic items immediately disappear after the first five minutes of the game.
Yeah, I think you kind of get to that point like we were talking about.
If you get to like level 20, you blink and you're level 20.
And then at the same time you blink and you're like, oh, blues and yellows.
Like, I only look at oranges now. Or like, what's this other color?
So I know that we have some changes that you wanted to talk about.
Yeah, and again, like a lot of this is in the spirit of making sure that zero to hero journey is really satisfying, right?
That's what makes it so awesome when playing Diablo is that sort of I start with nothing and become a god, right?
So we are taking a look at the itemization so that it doesn't just feel like a slog from 1 to 25.
What we're going to be doing is, you know what?
I'm going to jump actually into the legendaries really quick because it's really important, a really important part of this.
The other thing that was contributing to this leveling sort of pace was that players are getting a legendary every three to four minutes.
And that's from 1 to 60. That's not just in the end game.
And it just felt like legendary item quality was just too prevalent across the leveling journey.
You didn't have, you sort of hit max level. There was no journey to assembling your build.
You just had everything as part of the Codex of Power.
So we're also reducing the legendary rate from leveling. We're not really touching the end game legendary drop rates, but from leveling we are adjusting that.
And to compensate that, to jump back into the magic and rares.
We're making it so that magics can have up to two affixes.
So sometimes you're going to find, you know, from your 1 to 25 journey a pretty good magic item.
It might actually be better than a rare, for example, because it might have dropped earlier for you.
It might have higher eye power.
And then we're also making it so that rares can sometimes have up to three affixes.
And what that means is, you know, when you get a drop at level 35 from a Whisper Cache,
right now, you know, in Season 7 it feels terrible when you don't get a legendary item,
because you just know that it's just not even worth looking at, right?
But now, now that rare items can have up to three affixes, that means that you might have a really good imprintable base.
It means all the rares that drop across the game from 1 to 60 could actually be pretty great gear for you,
especially with all of our crafting options.
So we think that this helps smooth out the 1 to 60 journey.
I will caveat that the rare quality is not the best at max level still.
It's going to be a lower eye power, so you're not going to have to filter through a bunch of rares at max level.
We're not going to go back to pre-season 4.
So, yeah, we think this is this sort of smoothing out of the leveling curve,
taking a look at the magic rarities or the item qualities,
is just going to make the experience feel a lot more rewarding and satisfying as you go through these levels.
And then I know some of the other items we've been talking about have been like a little bit of that torment progression.
Yeah.
We've seen, you know, drastic differences between like season 6 to season 7,
and it's something I know we're making tweaks to.
Yeah.
Yeah, so the other half of Diablo is obviously the max level endgame, right?
And we've heard a ton of feedback that like, you know, it just feels like a weekend game right now.
You can just blast through all the torment tiers.
There's nothing that's really satisfying about it.
There's nothing to work towards just because you're just getting so much power so frequently and just really crushing this content.
So what we've done here is if we go to the slide, we've actually given,
actually, let me jump into some of the stats here because I think it's really interesting.
A lot of people got to Torment 4 very quickly.
So on average, it was taking players around 15 hours to get to Torment 4.
That's like roughly double how quickly it took in season 6, which is kind of insane.
Again, it's the culmination of Seasonal Powers and all this crazy stuff going on.
So, and the other part of it is that 50% of players were actually hitting Torment 4.
And just from a philosophy standpoint, we really want like whatever the hardest Torment tier is, in this case, Torment 4, to be aspirational.
And to us, that means around 10%.
That means that, you know, if you're really Johnny Badass, you know, you need to be in the top 10% of players to actually get there.
And it's not hitting the mark.
So what we're going to do is make some adjustments.
So Torment 1 is now going to start at Pit Tier 10, which means we've effectively added 10 Pit tiers to the Pit because now Torment 1 starts earlier.
And then we've also increased the Torment Pit Scaling, Health by roughly 20% multiplicative, and then some damage increases.
Yeah, and that Pit Scaling is, every level of a Pit is multiplicative on previous levels.
So it's not just like, oh, whatever Pit I was at, it's now 20% harder.
It's actually like kind of stacking 20% every level.
So the end result is that, you know, a Pit Tier 100 is much harder than it was before.
And that will, that makes it, you know, harder to reach that absolute highest end.
And it gives you a little bit more for those builds and those Blasters who are getting up to that highest Pit Tier.
There's going to be, it's going to be quite a bit harder to get to quite that same level next season.
Yeah, absolutely.
So with that sort of culminates in moving Torment 1 to Pit Tier 10 and effectively adding 10 Pit Tiers and increasing the multiplicative scaling of the Pit Tier scaling is the journey is going to be a lot more sort of satisfying.
There's a lot more sort of peaks to climb.
And it also means Pit Tier 150 is going to be very difficult.
So, so difficult that I don't believe any of you will reach it.
I'll, I don't know, I'll do something silly on the stream.
He says this now.
I'll probably, oh, that's not enough for doing something so extreme.
And then, like, within the first week.
That's a challenge to all of you out there.
Yeah, you all can vote on the silly things that I do.
But conversely, I just want to cover this really quickly, though.
So, Torment 4 isn't going to be insanely harder than it was before.
It's going to be roughly around Pit Tier 76 is on live right now.
So, Season 7.
So, think about the game that you're playing right now.
Torment 4 is going to be about 11 Pit Tiers harder.
So, it's still achievable.
It's just that upper end is also just going to be that much harder to sort of climb through.
Awesome.
So, we've got a lot of changes coming for, like, Torment scaling.
Obviously, some itemization changes.
So, the big thing being as you're leveling up, you're going to see a lot more opportunities to find items.
Especially with the changes to blue and yellow items there.
And then, of course, as you mentioned, the big caveat is, like, at 60, the item power on Legendaries is still going to be the best method and the best items to actually grab.
So, yeah, lots of big changes coming up.
Great to actually walk through all of them.
I know we have a ton more to talk about specifically around the new season.
So, thank you, Colin.
We're going to jump over to Derek because I know we do want to talk about the new season and what players are actually going to be experiencing in this PTR.
Again, just to redefine what PTR is for some people because I got messages from people going, like, well, PTRs are sometimes buggy.
And I'm like, well, it's a PTR.
So, it is like a beta or an alpha, an early look into a game.
So, we expect that.
There will be, like, known issues and we'll actually have those known issues on our forums.
So, people can actually see them.
You can report bugs.
It actually helps when you guys actually jump into a PTR and experience it.
And give us feedback because that helps tweak the start of the season for the better, essentially.
But with season eight, we will be having, of course, a PTR and we'll be talking about it here in a second.
And if you remember with season seven, we kind of had this, like, this overarching theme with, like, big changes in that season.
One was specifically around, well, it was mostly focused around, like, the whispers.
And, of course, with season eight, we have another overarching theme that we're really going to be talking about where we'll be kind of even seeing an old friend.
So, Derek, do you want to chat about it here?
Yeah, absolutely.
So, yeah, as you mentioned, seasons are kind of like our opportunity to shine focus on an existing system and really amplify or celebrate or enhance it within that respective season.
So, we've seen that with, you know, season four with the Helltide revamps and whatnot, as you mentioned.
Season seven was the emphasis on the Tree of Whispers and Bounties.
So, as Colin kind of mapped out the journey to the endgame, we wanted to shine focus on a major endgame feature, namely surrounding our bosses.
And we have a lot of really cool bosses in, you know, the world of Sanctuary.
But more specifically, the Laird Boss System, or as some of us, and we reference it to as the Boss Ladder.
So, season eight focus is on the Laird Boss System.
We're going to be doing a whole mess of new things to it.
So, we're adding new bosses, new mechanics, quality of life, updates, and a revamped materials loop that I'm going to be covering throughout the course of this segment.
So, you know, first I just want to kind of talk about, you know, the new bosses and additions to the roster.
So, when we're talking about the Laird Bosses, these are like the biggest, baddest, you know, bosses of Sanctuary.
So, we're looking at how do we add to the roster in a meaningful way, but also which bosses do we add that are impactful and versatile enough to carry the entire theme of a season.
So, with that in mind, we're just asking ourselves a question of which of the right bosses to bring.
You mentioned an old friend. So, we had to choose something that was versatile. We had to choose something that was big, bad.
So, that's where we go to Belial.
Yes, season eight, Belial's return. Belial's back in Sanctuary.
He is climbing his way to the top of the Laird Boss Ladder.
He is the new, you know, exalted pinnacle challenge within the ladder.
He is the highest challenge, the highest reward, and he also has some very unique reward-related tricks up his sleeve that I'll give you.
I'll cover a little bit later. So, for now, just know that Belial's back.
And he's also just not joining the party alone. He's bringing a couple of friends from our Vessel of Hatred.
So, first up is our buddy Urvar. So, Urvar's joining the roster of the Laird Boss Ladder system.
He's going to be filling out kind of like the lowest rung of the ladder.
So, he's going to be joining the party with the Varshans and the Beast of Nice and whatnot.
So, Urvar's back. And we're also bringing back another Vessel of Hatred character, the Harbinger of Hatred.
I'm so happy for this.
Yeah, no, this one...
Oh, I love this fight.
I'll talk a little bit more of this guy in just a little bit, but the Harbinger of Hatred will be joining kind of the second rung of the ladder with the likes of Durial and Undarial.
And one thing I just do want to stress is that both of these Vessel of Hatred bosses will dip into the shared loot pools of other bosses within their respective tier,
but also have some additional bonuses that is specific to the Vessel of Hatred, like being a great source of tributes and runes.
But Belial, for all intents and purposes, is available to everyone, and he is just the new pinnacle challenge of the Boss Ladder.
So you're saying even harder than Durial and Undarial right now. He's going to be harder, more rewarding than even those.
Absolutely. Yes.
Oh, wonderful.
New top tier.
Belial, Lord of Lies, he does not mess around.
And I'm really excited about this because I think this is going to pair really well with the sort of leveling journey and the Torment progression where we're making things a little bit more aspirational, a little bit more challenging.
It's really like a return to the heart of the Diablo experience, right? Sort of leveling from nothing and taking on these huge big bads to claim their loot.
Yeah, absolutely. I think that's kind of like the inherent cool thing about the Lair Boss Ladder system is that you start with like the initiate level floor, you take those on, you graduate to the next level, and then now you have kind of Belial just always there looming over you.
Yeah.
That's kind of the aspirational, yes, I get to go fight him now.
But for those who know about our buddy Belial, Lord of Lies, you know that he kind of appears in different forms.
So this is what we're kind of referencing as like his supreme form that appears at the top of the Lair Boss Ladder.
But he also has his, I guess, smaller, more agile, compact form. I like to affectionately refer to him as Baby Belial, but this is Belial in his more compact form.
And throughout the course of the season, or I guess just the Lair Boss mechanics, he's going to be popping up all over the place.
But I'm really excited about this version of Belial's new role in the Lair Boss Ladder system in the sense that defeating and looting any of the Lair Bosses has a small percent chance to initiate a surprise ambush from Belial himself.
And this is really cool because this is kind of like a two for the price of one payout.
Let's say I fight Andario, I defeat Andario, I loot Andario, and I get this special ambush triggered.
And if I defeat Belial, I'll get a double payout of Andario's loot.
So I got the loot from Andario, and I get another payout of Andario's loot from defeating Belial himself.
So it's a really exciting kind of just like injection of some fun novel mechanics within the Lair Boss system that we're doing over and over and over again.
So again, really excited about this update.
And again, in the spirit of teasing kind of the rewards relationship and connection that Belial has, this version of Belial has a very special connection to his larger Supreme form in the Lair Boss Ladder that I'll touch upon a little bit later.
A lot of teasing that I'm kind of just sending that there's a lot to go over.
We're gonna lie to everybody.
Yeah.
We're just kidding.
Belial's actually not here. This is a lie.
Yeah, so that was that. That was the, you know, the Belial ambushes.
But I also want to talk about some additional major sweeping updates that's coming in with just the system as a whole.
And I want to talk about the summoning materials.
As we know, the way that the system currently functions is, you know, you go do activities, you get summoning items, you go visit the boss, and you plop them in, you summon the boss, and then, you know, that's kind of just a flow.
So when we're looking at the Lair Boss system, we don't just look about ways that we can add to it.
We also look about, you know, opportunities to, you know, resolve or reduce some frictions, or just areas for improvement that we can have with it.
Since it's a very mature system, we get a lot of feedback that we, you know, diligently ingest and talk about and whatnot on our team.
So when it came to the summoning materials, we identified a couple of key points of, I guess, friction that players are currently having with it.
One is, since you have to ante up your summoning materials just to summon the boss, it's kind of a feels-bad moment when you realize that you just wasted, you know, X number of materials to find out that you can't defeat Durial.
Like, okay, that's wasted materials, back to the loop, maybe I'll fight him another week or two depending on how fast you are.
And it's just generally not a great feeling for myself or for players and whatnot.
Yeah, I definitely have run into this where it's like, I'm only going to fight the boss when I can guarantee win against it.
Right.
Right, so you never actually fight-
And how do you know that too until, like, trial and error?
Like, you never really have that, like, actual fun fight with the boss where you're like, oh, am I going to lose or not?
Because it's like, well, I'm just not going to risk it.
Yeah, I've had the times where I'm like, I don't know if my build's quite ready, so I'll try to fight a boss.
And then I'm like, oh, this is really tough.
Like, I die a couple times and I'm like, do I really want to keep, like, retrying it?
Because, like, well, I've already invested. I'm kind of, like, I'm kind of committed.
So with this new way, you know, I don't need to invest those right up front.
I can just go and fight them right away and see how strong I am without risking the materials.
Yeah, yeah, so we're going to cover, like, the specificities of the new system and how it all works in a little bit.
But the other kind of pain point that we identified with the current system is also just in regards to, like, the party play.
I think my little earpiece is coming out of my ear. There you go.
It's a common theme on this one. The earpiece just pops out all the time.
We do it live here. Yeah, so the other element is, like, just a party play, right?
And as much as we want to kind of, like, entrust in our fellow man and whatnot and engage in the boss rotations and whatnot,
we have seen, you know, some areas of friction where certain players don't engage in the boss rotations
and they don't submit their materials. Like, no one watching the stream would ever be guilty of this, but that does happen.
It's shocking, but it does happen.
Belial is on the other side of the computer. It's like, yeah, I'll definitely pay the next rotation.
And then they leave and they take all their stuff. So that was another kind of area of friction that we experienced with the current summoning materials.
So I think that's kind of enough of a preface just to set the tone for where the system is going now that we're introducing Season 8.
So what are we doing?
What are we? I don't know. Let's find out.
All right. So Lair Keys. So summoning materials are effectively being repurposed in their roles as a new item called Lair Keys.
And what Lair Keys do, well, I'll just start with this, is since there's no more summoning materials, that just means that effectively all Lair bosses are free to summon.
Yeah. So if you're not sure if you're ready to take on a Varshan or a Durial, just go visit them.
You know, kind of use them as a bit of a training dummy to see if you can actually, you know, take them on.
But what Lair Keys now do is they grant access to the defeated bosses' horde or their treasure chests that they drop.
So now I'll just walk you through kind of the new flow. Imagine this with me.
So you enter Durial's Lair. You walk up to his altar and you just click the altar to summon him.
Again, no cost to you. You fight Durial, you defeat him, out pops his horde.
And now the Shards of Agony, which is now the Lair Key, you use that to open his horde and get all the oodles of loot that he went to go visit him to do.
Yeah. And these work like Helltide chests. So you have to pay in order to get the loot. And the only loot comes from the person who pays.
Yeah. That's a very important distinction is that now every member in the party needs to have the appropriate type and quantity of the Lair Keys to access the loot in the horde.
And you can still trade your keys with friends and things like that. If you have 9999, you know, Durial mats, you can split them in half and give them to your buddies to open the chest.
Yeah, absolutely. My sharing is caring in the system here.
And then, of course, if you're really lucky, you'll get a Belial ambush and you can get double loot.
Yeah. Yeah, there you go. So again, a lot of new avenues and ways to kind of, you know, experience the system.
So we also have the Stygian stones. So Stygian stones in season 8 is living a new life now in the sense that we wanted to ensure that every boss in the first rung of the ladder, our initiate Lair bosses, the Varshans, Griggers, Beasts of Nice, Lord Zers and Urvars now, that they're all equally relevant to getting you to climb to the next rung.
So in addition to it, you can take a screenshot of this chart here. I won't try and walk through the entire thing, but now Stygian stones is a drop that can drop from any of the initiate Lair boss tier here.
And you can crush them into your Lair key of choice for the second rung of the Lair bosses.
So let's say I fight Grigger, I get a Stygian stone and I want to go fight Ondariel. I can just crush that into some Ondariel keys.
And again, just giving a little bit more flexibility and how players actually engage and progress through the Lair boss ladder.
Again, as we know, all roads lead to Belial, Lord of Lies, you know, the top of the pinnacle of the ladder at the end.
Ooh, there's a lot. All right. Final thing here is the item bloat reduction.
So again, with this new system, we're consolidating all the Lair keys to one Lair key type per boss.
So no more kind of managing two different materials.
And so I have enough material. I have two of these, five of these. It's just one material per boss.
We're increasing the item stacking of these to 99 again to cut down some of that bloat.
And one of my personal favorites here is that we're also normalizing the counts of required Lair keys per, you know, boss rank.
So all the initiate tiered bosses, they require the same quantity of their respective keys.
So to the graders and whatnot. So again, it's just cutting down on the total mental math and memory that is kind of affecting the, I guess, like on ramping enjoyment of the current system.
Yeah. And Dario only needs one material, for example, as part of this.
Yeah, absolutely. So you can see in this chart here, you have Pincushion Dolls, Shard of Agony, or the Stygian Stone is kind of the wild card that you can crush to any one of them.
So let's say if Dario needed four Pincushion Dolls, you have three of them, but you have one Stygian Stone, you can crush that into a Pincushion Doll and go get Dario's Horde.
So, all right, that was a pretty big overview and a lot of talking in charts, but I want to take the time to, you know, throw it over to Ruben and behind the scenes here and kind of just get into just what this all looks like as part of this in-game flow.
Hey, hello, Derek. How are you doing, man?
I'm doing great. How are you?
Awesome. Yeah, let me open up the menu for you.
All right, cool. So in this walkthrough, I'm just going to show you kind of, or we're going to show you rather, the new flow to access the lair bosses with a little bit of a sneak peek of the Harbinger of Hatred.
So one thing I want to just call out real quick is kind of some of the quality of life updates that we've taken to just the map presentation and the boss dungeon tooltips themselves.
And I'll kind of just go through these kind of itemized order.
So first, all of the boss dungeon map icons have been given a little bit of a beautiful beautification treatment.
So they're a little bit more bold, red, and easier to identify against the sea of other icons on the map.
But now I want to talk about the tooltip and I'll just start from the top and go make my way down.
So the first quality of life update that we added was just simply printing the name of the boss that resides within the dungeon.
You know, one of the kind of ambiguities that we have the previous, you know, version of this system was not knowing specifically which boss lives in which dungeon.
Like, oh, who does live in the gaping crevice or who lives in the malignant tunnels?
So now you can see here that the Harbinger of Hatred lives in the Harbinger's Den.
This is probably not the best example because who else would live in the Harbinger's Den?
Wow.
Yeah, he technically does live in every single one of them.
He's a liar. You don't know where he's at.
But yeah, so you can see here now, you know, we print the name of the lair boss that lives in the dungeon for a little bit easier find.
Inside of the main body description, we also just give a little bit more guidance and information on, you know, what the value of defeating this boss is
and they're directing players to the fact that they are a source of ancestral and mythic unique items.
So, the last two updates here are some of my favorites of this is that we also display now the required items that you need to access the lair boss's horde.
If you recall the previous, you know, iteration, that was not apparent to you.
So, you would kind of like waste the time traveling to the boss just to find out that, oh, I have three or four Abhorrent's Hearts, so I can't fight the boss yet.
So, we wanted to, again, just smoothen out the access and onboarding to the feature.
And I think my absolute favorite update of all this is, you see at the bottom, we now have the ability to travel directly into the dungeon directly from the map.
So, again, no more teleporting to the nearest waypoint.
We just pop directly in and just get into it.
And, you know, we have Ruben loading into here and I think this is a great time to just outline.
I've talked about the new bosses, I've talked about new mechanics, but we have a collection of really great existing lair bosses.
And one thing that we wanted to take as an opportunity within the season was to also enhance every other lair boss that exists within the system.
So, every lair boss is getting a bit of a difficulty spike and new mechanics to, again, freshen up the fights that we've been, you know, knowing and loving.
So, if you fought, you know, the Varshan's or the Durial's or even the Lilith's, you know, over and over and over again, all this is in the PTR.
So, definitely worth checking them out again to see what's changed and, you know, how much different their experience is.
Yeah, Durial has some messed up surprises.
Yeah, Durial eats you.
Why do you spoil it?
It's definitely worth checking out the mechanics.
But again, so this is the Harbinger of Hatred.
And, you know, just as a reminder, one thing that we do when we add a boss to the lair boss system is we don't just take the carbon copy, you know, campaign version of it.
We also take the opportunity to inject some really crazy mechanics.
So, I don't necessarily want to, you know, kind of spoil the surprises of the Harbinger of Hatred's mechanics here.
But he does get pretty wild.
He does.
This is a spectacle and a half of a fight.
And I'm really excited to have players check it out.
So, yeah, I think this is about all we might want to show of this guy.
Yeah, we probably won't go into it.
We don't want to spoil all the mechanics and everything.
Even though we're kind of also spoiling a little bit of, like, a Rogue build.
We might have noticed some interesting things on Rogue, which I'll get to in a bit.
It's spoil or it's teasing to maintain.
Exactly.
It's teasing.
Teasing.
Teasing everyone along here.
But, yeah, so, you know, that was a sneak peek at the Harbinger of Hatred we just talked about again, in case you missed it.
The all-layer bosses are getting a boost in both their performance and just the mechanics that they have.
Yeah.
But let's, you know, we fast-forwarded past, you know, the Harbinger of Hatred's fight.
So let's imagine a world that, you know, we fought through the whole thing, we killed him, and let's show off now what to expect from the Horde loop flow.
So we have some footage here with this very shiny chest.
Very shiny chest.
So we have four of Horan's hearts, and now we can open up the chest.
Again, each one of us needs to have it.
And I mentioned that Belial has a chance to surprise ambush you after opening any Horde.
And here you go.
Look at this.
This is meant to be a relatively rare occurrence.
But, you know, this is the magic of pre-recorded footage.
We can make the impossible happen.
And in this case, again, painting the full picture of the scenario, you defeated the Harbinger of Hatred, you got the Horde, you opened it, you got baby Belial, you killed him, and now you get another proc of...
Double the loot.
Yeah, double the loot, double the fun.
Yeah, double the loot of what you just essentially got.
With the one-time payment of the Lair Keys that you deposited.
So, yeah, it really is, you know, kind of a two-for-one sale that Belial has for you.
And if you noticed, you might have seen, we did keep a bonus for party play.
So, while you do have to pay to get the chest and open up the Horde, we kept a bonus chance for loot.
So, we love that people enjoy fighting the bosses as parties, and we know that that's a fun social experience in Diablo.
So, what we've done is the Hordes themselves will have bonus chances for loot when you are in a party.
And that does scale with party members.
Yep, absolutely.
So, yeah, a lot of loot everywhere to give.
And on the topic at the very top, I teased that Belial had a very special kind of role in the reward structure, different from every other boss.
So, defeating the ambush version of Belial is not just lucrative in the sense that it's a double payout.
He is also the sole source of the Lair Keys that you need to access his Supreme Form at the top of the ladder, the Supreme Form's Horde.
So, I want to show off now the Supreme Belial's very green chest here.
So, you can see here, it doesn't open up right away.
I have some options.
So, the really cool thing about the Supreme Belial's Horde is that you can set it to mimic the reward drops of any other existing Lair Boss.
So, let's say if you are trying to do Durial runs to get the special stuff that he has, and you can set your Belial to drop the Durial loot, and he will do so at an enhanced rate.
So, it's even better than if you just went to go fight Durial specifically.
Yeah, so if you are really targeting Farming in those specific Uniques, you get, you know, this version of Belial just gives you a much better chance of doing that as well.
Yeah, absolutely. And, not just that in terms of like his value, he also guarantees one Ancestral unique drop per kill, and he's also a really great source of the Infernal compasses.
So, you know, if you want to, you know, empower your Infernal Horde runs and whatnot, it's never a waste of time to go visit the Belial Supreme at the top of the ladder here.
Yeah, and this is in Torment 2, and it all scales with Torment.
Exactly.
So, the higher the Torment, the more you go.
Yeah, what we're seeing in this footage is just Torment 2, so obviously, like Torment 4, you would get more loot out of it.
Because you're, it's a much more difficult challenge.
It is much more.
For sure.
It scales with the Torment tiers, and also if we were in a party in this example here, we'd get even, you know, more chances of great stuff out of it as well.
Yep, exactly right.
Alright, cool. Well, that is the Lair Key and the Lair Boss. I just have a lot of things to cover here.
Yeah, you have, I know we want to talk a little bit about kind of the, it's funny because people saw it as Ruben was on the map, because they probably saw a term like with apparitions and everything.
Right, yeah, there's a lot of teasing in this.
I know, a lot of teasing. This happens when you use a live build and everything's fun.
Yeah, it's exciting.
But one thing, before we hop into the next thing, I do want to reestablish so that everything that we just talked about as far as what we're introducing to the Lair Boss system and all the mechanics, new bosses and whatnot, that is permanent.
That is just how the system works now. So everything is getting introduced in Season 8, but it's not leaving beyond Season 8. It is just there.
It'll be an Eternal, so.
It will, yeah, it'll be an Eternal. That's just how the system works.
What the next segment though is, is all the Seasonal specific stuff.
So again, as Adam mentioned, you might have seen some Apparition and Incursion things pop up.
So let's get into the first kind of seasonal related content here.
Oh, the top says Lair Boss. Okay.
Anyways, we do it live.
Apparition and Incursions.
Apparition and Incursions is a new open world seasonal event to empower your leveling journeys
and also kind of just spread the narrative and dramas of Belial is back on Sanctuary
and he's spreading his own sense of, you know, twisted realities across the land.
He's always in his efforts to try and plunge, you know, the world is Sanctuary into his Realm of Lies
and he's doing it through this fast-paced boss rush style event that kind of takes the spirit of, you know, the open world social boss play of the Blood Maiden
and making a really cool kind of just really fast-paced, you know, bam, bam, bam, boss rush style event.
So I think we have some footage here just to put some, yeah, some visuals to it.
So, you know, this is an area of the world that Belial's apparitions are kind of overtaking
and throughout the course players are going to be defeating these apparitions to draw out up to two of his apparition bosses.
This is pulled from a total of ten potential apparition bosses.
So each time you go through this you'll fight, you know, two of them kind of randomized.
So each time should be a little bit different.
And all of this is leading up to a showdown against Belial himself.
So again, it's celebrating bosses. It's three bosses per event.
And the idea for this is that they're up pretty much 24-7.
So we want to just encourage that, you know, hop on the boss train, ride it to the end, find the next one,
and just, you know, go to your heart's content.
And, you know, celebration of bosses this season, really.
Absolutely. And what do you get for killing those bosses?
Oh, you're going to get some cool stuff, Colin. Let's go to the next slide.
That kind of leads us into the collectible boss powers, seasonal powers.
Oh, spoiled it right there.
Man, it's already on the slide.
Yeah, we're fine.
So the theme for the powers theme for Season 8 is boss powers.
So Belial being kind of like the illusionary character he is, mimicry and whatnot,
in Season 8, players will be acquiring the ability to steal and mimic the powers of up to 24 targeted bosses across Sanctuary.
So we have 24 collectible powers that are gathered from the first time kill of targeted bosses across the full content from level 1 till the very top.
So you asked about, you know, what do the apparition bosses give you?
They're, aside from the loot and all that stuff, they're also your first source of your first 10 boss powers that make up the magic tier,
as you can kind of see in this little chart here.
Graduating from the apparition bosses, you now go into the world bosses.
So each one of our three world bosses have a power associated with them, and then so too do each of our lair bosses capped off with Lilith with her own boss power that you can acquire.
It's like a ladder in the boss power.
Yeah, it's definitely celebrating the progression journey of bosses from, you know, the moment you log in to the moment that you're powerful enough to take down Lilith.
Yeah.
Bilal, you know, Bilal being kind of like the star of the season, he's special, he gets two powers, because that's just how he rolls.
Yeah, cheating.
Yeah, and I think, you know, one of the cool things about this kind of structure, it's a very structured power climb, so little ambiguity of like, how do I get the Wandering Deaths power?
Well, go fight and kill him.
It's just that nice little structured journey that kind of is a nice little stamp collection just to reward each kind of a tier progression that you make across your, you know, leveling and endgame journeys.
But that's not just the coolest part of it, in my opinion here, is that it's also just how the powers work this season.
So you can see that we have four slots, the top slot and three little kind of like supporting slots.
So the really cool thing is that each one of these powers have two sides to them that activate depending on which power slot you put them in.
So you can have up to one main, one power, you can have up to one power slot into your main power slots, or you can have up to three power slot into your modifier slots.
And I just want to dive into this Wandering Deaths chest beam example here.
So if I were to slot the Wandering Deaths power into the main power slot, I would actually unlock the full representation of his iconic chest beam power.
So the main powers is activating and unlocking the actual iconic power that is representative of the boss.
We're going to show kind of a little bit of a showcase after this, but that's how that respective area of the power system works.
The modifier slots though are super, are cool and powerful in their own right though.
So let's say I don't necessarily need the Wandering Deaths, you know, main power for whatever utility purposes.
I can still get value out of the fact that I own it by slotting it into the modifier slots, which activates kind of like the side B of it, which is more of a supporting thing.
So in this case, it's your main power. Now it empowers your main power to instantly execute non-boss enemies, you know, when they're within a certain threshold of life.
So it's not just, you know, 24 ways to kind of express your sense of power this season.
It's 48 because each of these powers have, you know, kind of like two sides to them.
Yeah, it's really like build your own boss power.
Essentially, yeah. It's a lot of fun just kind of like mix-match slot around and see, you know, what kind of a concoction you come up with.
And that's something that I'm particularly interested in going to the PTR is like, what are some of the favorite combinations or ideally, what are the favorite combinations based off of the circumstance that you're going into?
Definitely. Oh, go ahead, Charles.
One thing I wanted to, that I'm really excited about the system is in previous seasonal power systems, we sometimes found as you got really high, you know, Paragon levels, your build is like super powerful.
The relative impact of some of the seasonal powers was a little lower. They didn't really scale with you as well as we really wanted to.
We've done an update in this season where these boss powers are going to scale with your Paragon level as you're leveling up.
And so they actually are going to get more powerful as you get more powerful.
Right. So the exact number that you, as soon as you unlock it, it, you know, maybe is not the most powerful thing, but as you're powering up, it's still going to be relevant to your build at every stage of your progression.
That's really good. I like the fact that the powers don't kind of just live on their own little island. Like they get in degrade into the other systems that we're engaging with.
Yeah. So that's a high level of the, of the boss powers for season eight. And I want to toss it back to Ruben for just kind of a little bit of a live showcase of them.
Hey, Derek. Thanks for all that. That was great, man. Yeah, I'm excited. What do you got for us?
Well, I get the fun job of showcasing all these powers today, but I must confess, I got my smoothie. So I'm a little jacked up today.
I'm so happy you got your smoothie. So happy for you. I'm thrilled. I'm thrilled.
Let's go ahead and open up our inventory here. And you'll notice on the left side, a familiar tab is our seasonal tab, which is boss powers.
So from this tab is where you'll be kind of interacting with your powers throughout the season. Like Derek mentioned, you can drag and drop them, equip them on the fly.
There's no penalty. I think the team and everybody wants you to experiment and have fun with the builds.
You can also upgrade them by hovering over them. There's a corresponding button here on PC. It's F. So you go ahead and push that to upgrade them.
And yeah, so the top slot is your main slot, like Derek mentioned. This is where your main powers go. And all the bottom ones are your modifier slots.
So right here, you know, Derek's favorite was the Wandering Death's chest beam. So as a modifier, right, you can execute enemies.
But as soon as you drag it over here, boom, now it's a channeled ability. And you'll notice right away, it's a prominent beam.
Yeah, it works well with channeled abilities. It only works with channeled abilities, actually.
And it's kind of cool with Densive Knives because you can adjust and do these micro adjustments to kind of maximize the effect on your target just to keep it on them a little bit longer.
Yeah, and as you can kind of tell, we're not necessarily going for subtlety in terms of the expression of these powers this season.
I'm dying. Someone in chat is like, Goku?
Oh, my God.
I got some wonders. We'll call it real quick. Just one thing I absolutely love is just the animations of the UI itself.
And, you know, you slot these little like eyeball socket, eyeball powers into the little eye sockets and it blinks.
And it just is kind of just fun across the board just engaging with this.
Well, true.
It is and it pops.
Yeah.
So what do we got next?
The next one I want to showcase is Lilith's Wind of Hate just because probably most of us have died to this before.
Her spike ability from the ground.
And it works on almost every skill.
So you can definitely you can see as soon as I dash here, I get the spikes with barrage.
You get the spikes so you can slot in almost every build and have fun with it.
Even dance of knives.
Really cool ability there.
Let's see what else we got.
Another fun one.
There's a transformative ability is Joriel's Burrow.
So it completely changes your evade skill and you burrow underground.
You deal damage when you go in to the ground and when you exit.
But the real cool thing is you become immune while underground and you can control the direction.
Oh, that's awesome.
It is awesome.
Yeah, that's one of my absolute favorite.
I love that one.
You can stand still if you like or whatever.
And it scales as you get more evade charges, you get more burrows.
So I'm sure there's a lot of especially adding three new bosses with all kinds of crazy effects.
You know, you can now dodge them a little bit easier, which is great.
I'm sure there's some good use cases for that.
Yeah.
Even just right there, I want to just chime in and just say that, you know, we showed off a power that procs off of the evade.
We showed one that procs off channeling and one that procs off any skills.
Like one of the goals going into the design of these powers was to just remove any ambiguity about how do I actually proc it.
We wanted to make it as utility focused and straightforward as possible so that players can really easily digest and how they work it into their builds.
Yeah, that's a great point.
Urvar's Bombs is probably my personal favorite as I like making builds and interesting builds.
This definitely supports ultimate builds.
And as you can see on the screen here, it lowers your cooldown by five seconds, which is great, and gives you a nice damage component to kind of top off on it.
So we're playing Rogue and Death Trap is an ultimate ability.
So as soon as I pop it, you'll see Urvar's Bombs kind of shoot out and you get that lower cooldown effect as well.
So it's great.
And you get two Death Traps.
I wonder how you got that.
That's on me.
That's on me, guys.
Yeah.
All the teasing on the stream.
And finally, before they play the walk-off music, I think I could showcase, let's do Gregor's Lightning Square.
So if you noticed, Lilith's skill had like a slight cooldown.
This one scales with your build really well.
So the more you can cast core skills, the more you get these iconic kind of lightning strike panels shoot out from your character.
So you can imagine you can just go full Thunder God here the whole time with your builds.
So yeah, I think that's all I can showcase today.
But I appreciate the time.
No, thank you.
That was awesome.
Yeah, so again, those are just like a kind of a sneak peek at just a handful of the powers.
Again, throughout the course of the PTR, you'll get to, you know, experiment and engage with all of them.
And again, looking forward to the feedback and just, you know, just general notes of how you incorporate into your builds and what really excites you.
So I think that's pretty much the wrap up for all the content coming in Season 8 that persists beyond and within.
Yeah, all the Season 8 stuff that will be available in PTR for players to actually jump into.
We're still going to be talking about a few more things as we get closer to Season 8 with the launch of the actual season itself.
So Derek, thank you so much for walking us through everything.
And of course, with a new Season and a new PTR, we have a lot of changes that are coming into classes, specifically like the Rogue.
We saw someone doing those, yeah.
We can just skip the Rogue.
We'll just skip the Rogue.
There's other classes to talk about.
Yeah, so Charles over here is actually going to go through all the class changes that players will be able to experience and test out during the PTR.
Yeah, of course. I mean, there's tons of new bosses to fight, so how are you going to fight them?
Right, so let's talk about some class updates that are coming.
First, I want to talk about some updates that are going to affect all classes in some way.
These are kind of a bit more generic updates.
So talking about ultimate scaling, this is something that we introduced in Season 7, the current live season,
where as you get to rank 5 of the ultimate skills, some of them had mechanics that allowed you to crank up their damage by building different stats.
Right, so if you got more damage while fortified, then your blood wave is going to do more damage, for instance.
We think that's really cool. It enabled a lot of very powerful builds.
A lot of very powerful builds.
And so we're looking at ensuring that those don't like really eclipse every other option in the game.
We still love that those are powerful builds. We love that you're playing them.
We don't want them to be the only option.
And so with that in mind, we're looking at putting a cap on that scaling.
You can scale them up to 200% bonus damage, which is still a lot.
You're still doing, you know, like triple damage.
But we just want to make sure it doesn't get completely out of control with all the new stats and some of the scaling coming in from some of the seasonal powers that could potentially lead those to be, you know, crowding out other options of gameplay.
Additionally, we're looking at crowd control.
This is something I talked about on our last campfire chat about how we're really looking at the moment to moment combat of our game.
You know, like, what are you doing like every like one second to the next?
And one thing that came up a lot was sometimes enemies just randomly get crowd controlled.
They randomly are frozen or stunned.
And you a lot of this comes from some of the what we call incidental crowd control as in lucky hit crowd control effects or anything that involves not like, oh, I pressed a button.
Now they're stunned, right?
And we noticed like, hey, we got a lot of these effects across the game in many different places.
And so we looked at really toning those down specifically in the generic spaces.
I know Fist of Fate is one of a very popular unique item right now for many reasons.
One of them was that kind of free crowd control.
But that's something that we think wasn't really promoting the best moment to moment combat and most engaging flow.
So that particular affix has been changed to lucky hit apply vulnerable.
But a lot of the other identity of Fist of Fate is still there as well.
So it still has, you know, wide ranges on things.
It still does random damage and a lot of lucky hit chance as well.
Yeah. And this change really puts the value of Frost Nova and Ground Stomp and it sort of makes those more valuable and satisfying.
Right. Yeah.
So if you really want to get those kind of crowd control effects, like, it's going to be a build choice.
You're going to have to consciously do it and you're going to like know when it's happening.
It's not just, oh, they randomly got stunned.
And, you know, if they didn't get stunned, maybe you got hit.
And that never felt good when it was just kind of purely random.
Yeah. Yeah.
Additionally, this is something that the keen-eyed among you might have spied when we were looking at some other stuff.
We've done a bit of a naming pass on some of the damage over time effects.
This is no functional change.
This is just a naming thing where we have things like physical damage.
And when it's physical damage over time, we call it bleeding.
And when it's poison, we call it poisoning, for instance.
We didn't previously have names for shadow, lightning, or cold damage over time.
We would just call it like from shadow damage over time affected enemies, which was an absolute mouthful.
So we've got new common terms.
Shadow damage over time will be called corrupting damage.
Lightning damage over time is shocking damage.
And cold damage over time, which we saw with the wandering death chest beam, is called frostbite damage.
So that's just a terminology thing.
It still relates to those base damage types, same as always.
It's just a terminology update.
Cleans up the tooltips.
Absolutely, yeah.
Alright, so let's get on to some of the actual class updates.
Starting, oh, we'll just go alphabetically with the Barbarian.
Alright, so our focus on Barbarian this season is primarily about Barbarian's core fantasy of being physical and hitting enemies with a big weapon, right?
In the past couple seasons, a lot of the meta builds around Barbarian have focused around things like earthquakes or dusting.
And they're also focused around the boss devils, which are really cool and fun.
But I think they, we got some feedback that, hey, I don't really feel like I'm hitting enemies with my big weapon.
I'm just making a tornado that hits them.
Which is not maybe fulfilling the fantasy that you want out of a Barbarian.
Your core skill isn't the cool thing. It's the thing that the core skill spawns.
Right.
Yeah.
Right. And that's, it's cool that those exist, but we want to make sure we're also catering to that, you know, heavy hitter kind of fantasy.
And so a lot of the updates this season are focused around that.
Specifically updates to double swing core skill and the twin strikes unique to make that a bit more impactful to actually be hitting.
Whirlwind as well.
That's getting a buff and a rework with Gore's, its unique Gore's devastating grips.
Um, and then the new unique and legendary this season really talked to mighty throw in particular and make that just like the biggest hitting thing.
Let's take a look at those, uh, uniques and, or the unique and legendary here.
So we've got the Bane of Aja Den.
This is a, uh, unique glove item.
And it says that every 12 seconds your next mighty throw is going to detonate all of its pulses instantly.
You know, normally mighty throw like pulses over time.
It's going to do them all at once and deal massively increased damage.
And that's going to pair up very well with the new legendary aspect of delayed extinction,
which causes both mighty throw and steel grasp to gain multiplicative bonus damage rather than cooldown from cooldown reduction.
So if you've got cooldown reduction on your gear or on the Bane of Aja Den, for instance,
that's not going to actually reduce the cooldown.
It's going to be a multiplicative scaler for these skills.
And so that now you've got a new problem to solve, right?
You, you, uh, can't cast these skills quite as often, but when you do, they're going to hit super hard.
And so we've got a video clip of it just deleting a screen.
So you walk up to a ground here and they're all gone.
One hit, that's all it takes.
Because you've got all these multipliers on your one big hit.
But of course, because it doesn't benefit from cooldown reduction,
that cooldown is going to be pretty much locked at that 12 second mark.
And so you're going to have to find some other way to kind of fill the gap in there.
And you've got a new challenge for your build to overcome.
I'm hoping to see, like, Belial get decked by the...
I think it is possible that you're going to melt some bosses with some really big hits.
It's a great finishing move.
Oh, yeah.
All right, let's take a look at the Druid.
So for the Druid, I want to talk a little bit about...
One of the meta builds right now is revolts around Cataclysm.
And kind of snapshotting issues that come up with that.
And so for those of you who don't know what snapshotting basically means is...
For Cataclysm, which is one of their ultimate skills that has a duration.
So you press the button, it summons a storm around you that lasts for some amount of time.
And if you get a lot of that cooldown reduction and you can cast Cataclysm a second time
before the first one expires, currently on the live game, the second cast of Cataclysm
will keep all of the bonuses and, like, bonus damage effects or guaranteed overpowers or whatever
that was affecting the first one.
And that was definitely not intended.
That is not how we wanted that to work.
We didn't want bonuses from one cast kind of instance to carry over to the next cast.
Now this can only happen in situations where you get that lot of cooldown.
But it was kind of promoting this gameplay where it's very feast or famine.
If you successfully kind of snapshot all the buffs, this build is insanely powerful.
And if you mess it up or you don't get the snapshot quite right, you're actually really weak.
And that led to unintuitive gameplay and this really big divide between the best and the optimal
and, like, kind of the average normal case scenario.
So we're addressing that where we don't really want to promote that between two different cast snapshotting.
Yeah, we don't like snapshotting in general.
Right, yeah.
The kind of snapshotting where you are persisting things between different cast instances
or equipping gear and then unequipping it to maintain a bonus.
Those are snapshotting things that we don't think promotes healthy gameplay.
It's unintuitive in a lot of cases.
You need to read a guide and follow an exact checklist to do it.
That's not something that we think is good for the game.
There are some cases where, you know, with Cataclysm, you know, giving the bonus to that whole cast,
that first time you cast it, that it, you might say it's kind of snapshots for the duration of Cataclysm,
but that's intended where it says your next cast does something.
That's what we want, but we don't want that to persist on to multiple casts or through basically infinitely.
So that's one thing that we're adjusting on Druid.
But we're also looking at promoting other play styles as well.
We think that build is fun, but there's other ways to play Druid as well.
Specifically with Stoneburst, that's the Earth Core skill.
It was kind of a channeled skill, which from a lot of our channeled skills, they are not allowed to overpower.
But with Stoneburst particularly, we have reworked one of its legendary items to allow it to overpower when you detonate it at maximum size,
which is really cool and opens up some new build possibilities for Stoneburst.
And finally, I want to talk about the new unique Gathlin's Birthright.
This is a, let's take a look at it on screen here.
It's in a similar vein to Tempest Roar and Vassilius Prayer, where it is a unique helm that is very transformational.
But rather than talking to werewolves or werebear build, it's talking to human form builds.
If you just, you don't want to, you don't want to embrace the wilds quite as much, you want to stay in your human form,
Gathlin's Birthright is going to be the unique helm for you.
It says, while you're in human form, critically striking enemies with your nature magic skills will grant you Anima of the Forest for 10 seconds.
And when you get, whenever you gain Anima of the Forest, you are infused with bonus key passives, Perfect Storm and Earthen Might.
So if you have this and you have another key passive, you can potentially have up to three key passives active at once,
which is not something we've ever done before in Diablo 4.
That's nutty. And I love that it's on the helm. So if you really want to be a human druid, which historically, you know, hasn't been as great as like Werewolf, for example, this is the helm for you.
Yeah, this is exactly, exactly that. It's in a similar spot as like, hey, this is build defining in the way that Tempest Roar is for werewolves.
We want this to be the build defining helm for human form druids.
Additionally, Aspect of Impending Deluge that empowers your Storm Strike, which is probably pretty useful with this human form nature magic build,
which will cause your Storm Strike to deal more and also increase damage that they take from your other skills for a time.
I think we've got a picture of this or a video of this in action where you've got your druid, it's got your, you need 200 stacks of Anima of the Force,
which sounds like a lot, but it triggers on every hit. So in most combat situations, you actually stack it up pretty quick.
And see, once you get this online, you're going to be empowered with Earthen Might and with Perfect Storm and with Nature's Fury.
You have all of this power.
And the idea of three passes going at once is, the key passes is crazy.
Yeah.
And the boss power is slapped on top of that too.
Oh yeah. It is a lot when you get this empowered state.
Alright, moving on to one of my favorite classes, the Necromancer.
So Necromancer was probably the talk of the current season, season 7, with Bloodwave.
I know we've mentioned it a few times on stream. Bloodwave, really good.
We've talked about how we're going to look at ultimate scaling, so maybe it won't scale up with the bonus damage,
at least not to the same level that it had before. We're going to put a cap on that.
We also just think we generally overshot the mark on the unique item, the Kissimmee's Legacy,
which really, like, you get this item and suddenly you're a god.
We just had so much power in one spot. And we like a bit more of that progression that Colin was alluding to before about that zero to hero journey.
And when you have one item that is, you equip it and it's over. Like, you're as powerful as you ever need to be.
That really shortcuts that journey and really makes it feel less satisfying than we want.
So we're taking a look at reducing the power of that unique in particular, as well as some other adjustments to Bloodwave.
We do want Bloodwave builds to still be powerful and still be an option if you like that playstyle.
We just don't want it to be the S++ tier that it was in the past.
Additionally, we're taking a look at Bloodlance. This is a core skill that has historically been very good in multi-target,
kind of clearing out pit runs or dungeon situations. But then you run up into a boss, which, hey, we're fighting a lot of bosses this season.
Yeah, we'll be.
And it suddenly falls really flat because its core mechanic is about, like, arcing damage between enemies.
And if there's only one enemy, what are you doing here, right?
So with this update to Bloodlance, it's going to still maintain some of that fantasy where it arcs the damage between enemies.
But if you're hitting a target who's already lanced, it's going to do a massive amount more damage.
So it's much better in single-target situations and much more viable for bossing.
And finally, the new legendary and unique for this season talks to minions.
So let's take a look at Sanguivar, Blade of Zir, the unique two-handed sword.
So this weapon will empower your summons, so your minions and your army of the dead, to affect enemies with Vampiric Curse.
Now, for those of you who played back in Season 2, Vampiric Curse was a mechanic that we introduced in Season of Blood
where you affect enemies with it, and as you kill them, you kind of collect their soul.
And then you can unleash these souls. They kind of run out from you and explode in this really satisfying moment.
And we put that on a handful of legendary aspects, but now all of your summons will affect enemies with Vampiric Curse.
And you can unleash them with Army of the Dead.
And when you do that, the souls from Vampiric Curse and Army of the Dead itself will deal massively increased damage, scaling with how many souls you've collected.
It's huge. I love Minion Necro. It's like my favorite one.
Oh yeah. Yeah. This is really cool for Army of the Dead and Minion Necro to just really be that impactful moment of summoning an army of skeletons to just eviscerate the enemies.
And additionally, Aspect of Service and Sacrifice, I love playing with this one. This one feels so good to play.
Your skeleton warriors explode on death, dealing a massive chunk of physical damage to surrounding enemies.
And to help make sure they die, they lose 25% life per second while in combat.
So you're going to be needing to resummon them quite often, but when you do, hey, it's good, because they're going to be detonating for this massive chunk at the end.
And additionally, while you're resummoning all your warriors, your mages are going to be super tanky.
They're going to take 90% less damage and deal massively increased damage.
So you're going to have your mages up pretty much all the time, and you're going to be focusing on resummoning the warriors to run in there and explode and do their damage that way.
That's awesome. It's a really clever way to make it feel like you're constantly summoning and you have your back line of mages just obliterating.
Yeah, it's great. Let's take a look at Sanguevar, Blade of Xeer in action here.
Oh no, sorry, this is actually service and sacrifice.
So you've got your skeleton warriors, the skirmishers, they run up there.
And then here's Blade of Xeer, right?
You get all those skeleton warriors running out when you activate Army of the Dead.
You just get the normal ones that are running around, but then they all...
You unleash a stream of them straight from you with the Sanguevar.
Really impactful ultimate skill there.
Yeah, Army of the Dead is just so underutilized, so I'm so happy to see it come back into the fold.
It's great.
Alright, next up we've got the one we've been teasing for a bit.
Thank you, Ruben.
The Rogue.
Let's take a look at the idea with Rogue.
So, as you probably guessed, the theme of Rogue this season is looking at trap builds.
Right? With both death trap and poison trap in a way.
Historically, poison trap has been kind of underrepresented.
Death trap builds have been quite popular, pretty powerful, and a lot of fun to play.
Poison trap kind of fell by the wayside a little bit.
It had a number of issues that we're looking to address this season to really promote poison trap as a viable standalone build.
And what we're seeing from Ruben was the Scoundrel's Leather rework.
Now, this is a unique chest item that's been in the game for a while.
It was about traps in the past.
We've done a rework this season where when you cast a trap, or rather every 10 seconds when you cast the trap,
you're going to get a bonus death trap.
So, you could cast poison trap, or caltrops, or death trap itself, and then you get a second death trap.
And when you actually cast the death trap active button, you're going to kind of jump or teleport to that position.
So, you can just instantly get into the fray there.
Oh, that's cool.
Yeah, so, you know, Rogues are all about mobility and jumping around the battlefield and doing that kind of thing.
This is just another tool in their arsenal to really jump in, put the death trap down, which groups up some enemies,
and then they're ready for you to slaughter there.
But let's take a look at the new items that talk to poison trap specifically.
The bands of Icarus Rose, these are unique gloves that says your poison trap, which normally has a 9 second duration,
it's always going to do its full damage over 3 seconds instead.
So, it's much shorter duration, but higher DPS.
And it's always going to benefit from all of its upgrades.
You know, that enhancement and those modifications, you just get all of them.
You don't need to put skill points in.
And normally, the two choices are mutually exclusive.
You get both with these.
And they're going to be even more powerful.
Additionally, poison trap will now also benefit from your combo points if you're using those.
It's going to have no cooldown during the inner sight if you're using inner sight.
And if you're using preparation, its cooldown is going to be reduced by the preparation trigger.
So previously, poison trap didn't really interact with any of these three mechanics very well.
And now, it benefits from whichever one you want.
That's so cool.
So it really makes it more like a core skill, something that can work into my rotation.
Oh yeah.
Yeah, you're going to be wanting to use this very often with this unique.
And then, the aspect of contamination.
As many builds that focus around poison on Rogue often want to build critical strike damage,
because that's really good with the poison imbuement,
poison trap now also can scale up with some critical strike chance.
So with aspect of contamination, it unleashes a poison burst when it detonates,
like kind of an initial upfront hit.
And then, if that burst critically strikes, which, you know, if you build in a lot of crit chance, it probably will,
or if you hit a lot of enemies, then you're going to deal increased poison damage for a duration.
Which will, of course, increase the rest of the duration of the poison trap.
And this is probably my favorite clip here. Let's get a clip of this one.
Right? So you apply poison trap, which it's going to throw two of them out, and one of its upgrades knocks down enemies,
and because it's increased, it knocks them down for quite a while, and so they just take a little nap in your poison traps.
I don't recommend it, but hey, if they do, they take a ton of poison damage.
I love the knockdown animation of this guy.
Yeah. So good.
This guy just falls right down.
Just sit down.
Lay down, I guess.
His face is in it too.
His face plants and then succumbs to the poison.
It's awesome.
All right. Moving on, we've got our Sorceress.
So the Sorceress class definitely is one of the ones currently on Season 7 that I think didn't have any of these real big outlier builds
that we had kind of talked about. Some of the highest highs come from like the Blood Necro or the Druid with the snapshotting Cataclysm.
And I think I definitely want to acknowledge that, you know, Sorceress maybe didn't have some of those real outliers this season,
and they were maybe felt like they were a bit behind of those.
So as we talked about with other classes, we're definitely looking at bringing those outlier builds down a notch
to bring them kind of back to the norm of some of the other builds so they're not so far ahead.
But for Sorceress, we're looking at improving some of the quality of life and some of the interactions between some of their mechanics,
like Crackling Energy, Meteors and Meteorites, and making sure they scale well with the build.
Like Crackling Energy will now have the Shock skill tag, so if you're building up damage for Shock skills or some of the other synergies there,
those now interact with your Crackling Energy.
And additionally with Meteor and Meteorites, they're not going to be able to scale with each other's damage,
which helps builds just be a bit more cohesive and feel more robustly supported.
That being said, I think where Sorceress has been in Season 7 is in terms of its power progression
and the relative strength of its builds amongst each other is closer to the ideal state of where we envision all classes ending up.
We recognize that they are kind of a bit lower than other classes in Season 7,
but we're looking at bringing them up a little bit with improved quality of life and build options
and making sure that some of the outlier builds that's really skewing that perception are being brought to be...
to...
Bring them close together and create some more harmony between the classes.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Yeah, and I think this is something that we're actively looking at again to the point of early in the season.
If things aren't really performing to the level of our expectation and it doesn't feel good,
then those are things that we're going to buff and Sorceress is a great example of what we're going to be really looking at.
Yeah.
Yeah, and we want to do that in ways that make...
We don't just want to slap on a 50x scaler on Sorceress.
We want to make sure that the builds feel cohesive and coherent in a way that makes a lot of sense.
And so that's what all the bulk of our focus is for Sorc this season.
Specifically, I want to talk a little bit about Ice Shards.
That's what the new Unique is going to be working with here.
Let's take a look at the Unique, the Hail of Virglass.
This is a Unique Helm that's going to empower your Ice Shards to spread out rather than shoot in kind of a straight line, that kind of rapid fire.
It's now going to be a spread pattern.
You can hit more enemies with it and you get bonus shards and you're going to be dealing increased damage for every time an Ice Shard's damage is an enemy and it's going to stack up.
So it takes a lot of stacks.
You need to be spamming Ice Shards.
You need to be hitting a lot.
But once you do, it unleashes a lot of bonus damage.
And also, it just makes the skill, in my opinion, a lot more usable.
I like the spread pattern a whole lot.
It lets you hit wider screen and you can kind of like shotgun enemies if you get nice and close to them.
That's cool.
And Shivering Aspect, a new Legendary Aspect here.
Enemies are going to take increased damage based on how much they're chilled or staggering.
Now, historically, some of the Frost Sorcs or some of the other builds that were heavy on those crowd control effects,
sometimes they really struggled into bosses, which, hey, bosses are the theme of the season.
It's very appropriate.
So we're making sure that some of these new effects that scale based on the crowd control effects also work against bosses.
So this will kind of take how much stagger you've built up on the boss and also give you a bonus damage based on that.
So we're really being cognizant of, hey, let's make sure this works in the situations you want it to.
And it's not night and day, oh, I'm clearing trash mobs and then I hit the boss and you just feel so different.
We want to make sure that's a bit smoother of an experience between the two ways of playing.
Alright, let's take a look at the Hail of Virglass with these new Ice Shards in action.
Right, so they fire out pretty quick, they fire out in a nice spread, and you can clear through whole packs of skeletons with a single cast here.
Multi-shot.
Oh yeah.
Multi-shot with Ice Shards.
Alright, and moving on to our final class here, the Spiritborn.
So the Spiritborn was in a pretty good state, I mean, similar to Sorceress where it didn't have those crazy overpowered builds.
But we think it's in a relatively healthy spot and we're just looking at empowering new build options and making tighter synergies between the builds and giving you some new tools to play with.
With that in mind, we took a look at Rushing Claw. It's one of my favorite skills on the Spiritborn, but never really found its way into any of the most popular builds in the past couple seasons since Spiritborn was released.
And we've updated the two upgrade choices to be kind of transformative.
It's kind of a, if you pick one upgrade, the current one, Rushing Claws has four charges, and so when you use a charge you kind of quickly dash through an enemy.
And so you have four charges, you can spam it four times real quick.
The other upgrade now has been reworked where it gains even more charges. It gains 12 charges.
But using it consumes all the charges. So really it has just one, but for every charge that it consumes it deals massively increased damage and it hits a wider area.
So now gaining cooldown reduction or gaining more charges actually just increases your damage output.
And it promotes a very different play style for this. So you get kind of an option. You can choose the original version, which is still very powerful and very cool.
Or you can choose the new upgrade and kind of spend all your charges at once, do a big kind of damage cooldown, and then work on building up those charges again to deal even more.
Additionally, we've looked at Storm Feathers and specifically how they interact with the new unique item, the Sunbird's Gorgett, which I think we've got a picture of right here.
So the Sunbird's Gorgett is a new unique amulet. This really works to synergize with the Eagle and Jaguar builds.
So it says picking up a Storm Feather, which you can create in many different ways, will form a Firestorm around you for eight seconds that deals fire damage.
And every additional Storm Feather that you pick up is going to intensify this Firestorm. It's going to make it grow in size up to a maximum, and then it's going to increase its damage output.
For as many Storm Feathers as you can spawn, this Firestorm is going to get more intense.
But it only lasts for eight seconds, so intensifying it or picking up more Storm Feathers, it's not going to extend the duration.
So it's kind of locked to that eight second duration, and then it'll reset. So you really want to collect as many Storm Feathers as possible in eight seconds, and then it restarts.
And also this Firestorm is considered an Eagle, Jaguar, and Storm Feather skill.
So you've got lots of options for how you want to increase this damage through your other talent choices or your itemization.
You've got lots of options for how to work this into a build in either Eagle or Jaguar or both.
And following up on the theme with Rushing Claw, we've got the new Rip and Tear aspect, where Rushing Claw is going to deal increased damage, and is empowered based on how many charges you had when you cast it.
So if you're taking the upgrade that gives you 12 charges, it's probably always going to be with 4+, and so it's going to strike an additional time.
But if you're choosing the option where you spend each charge as you go, it's going to go through a bit of a cycle here.
You're going to get an additional Strike, then it's going to get a guaranteed Crit, then it's going to get a guaranteed Overpower, and when you just have one charge left, it's going to give you a nice chunky heal to help keep you in the fight.
Nice. There's a ton of versatility in there.
Yeah, yeah. Lots of different ways to play, and it works great with either way that Rushing Claw now works.
Alright, let's take a look at the Sunbird's Gorget in action here, right? So you're moving along, you're picking up tons of these feathers, and the Firestorm around you just grows in intensity.
You've got lots of different ways to scale it up, and it provides a nice kind of passive AoE around you as you're picking them up, and you're really going to want to make sure you're kind of thinking about exactly how your character's moving to make sure you're picking up as many of these Storm Feathers as possible to maximize your damage output.
Alright, that's a lot. We got a lot of new class content coming for every class. We did get through all of them.
But yeah, I'm really looking forward to seeing all the new builds that these empower, how they modify old existing builds, and all the interesting combinations that I'm sure all of you will test out on the PTR and find out the most absolutely broken thing and let me know about it.
Yes, please let us know if you find something absolutely broken, which I'm sure you will.
So thank you again, Charles, for walking us through all the different class changes.
Again, this is, we do plan on having patch notes along with the blog related to everything tied to PTR.
So there's other changes that we didn't actually cover often here.
That will be on the Diablo4.com immediately after the stream.
So everyone can actually check it out, inspect it, you know, do their theory crafting and everything related to that.
Of course, with PTR, we kind of want to know when PTR actually begins.
PTR is starting next Tuesday.
And this is, of course, PTR on PC Battle.net.
So players will be able to jump in starting on the 11th and it'll run for a week there.
I will note that players actually will be able to also pre-download the PTR the day prior.
So around Monday afternoon here in California, translate that using some sort of time tool.
That will be when players will be able to pre-download.
So it'll be about a day beforehand.
One thing to note is, of course, the boost vendor, MRAC, will be available, which will be dancing in town for everyone.
But one thing we did want to note is that the boost themselves will be available probably two days after the PTR actually begins.
The reason behind this is actually a little bit tied to how Season 7 performed.
One thing we allowed players to do was immediately boost the second they got into PTR.
And we really didn't get that whole entire flow as we were kind of going through.
Yeah, the headhunt and things like that.
So we also just want to hear your feedback on the leveling process, right?
This is why we run the PTR.
We really want to hear your thoughts on how the sort of more uniform leveling feels, how the legendary drop rates feel.
So that is really valuable to us for launching a really awesome Season 8 Return of the Wild.
Yeah, and so after a couple days, MRAC will be more than happy to take your Paragon levels to insane numbers.
So PTR boost will be available just a couple days after that.
One other thing I do want to note is we will of course have our forums available and online for PTR.
That is the best place to actually provide feedback.
Of course we do look in other places such as Reddit, Discord, etc.
But I will say like the forums is kind of we turn them on specifically like a PTR section.
So please put feedback in there because we are constantly checking in there for any notes, feedback from players on that end.
One other note is within the PTR.
You guys may see a term called the Reliquary that may just kind of pop up here and there and we haven't talked about the Reliquary.
Nor will the blog later today actually be talking about the Reliquary.
I will say that you guys will hear more about the Reliquary before the start of Season 8 in itself.
But for right now, ignore it.
Turn a blind eye. I don't know.
But it is a rework of our Battle Pass system that we're doing.
We've heard a lot of comments from players related to the Battle Pass.
We're trying to make it a little bit more customizable for people, especially for rewards that they're looking for.
So we'll have a detailed breakdown of what the Reliquary is before Season 8.
So looking forward to kind of sharing that before we actually kick off this season.
And I know I have a lot.
I'm trying to get through all my stuff.
I'm hungry.
The last thing we do want to talk about is I've gotten asked a million times about this and I've even seen it in chat.
And it's related to a roadmap for Diablo 4.
And I will say that we are actively working on a roadmap that we can share with you all, which is great because it gives you and everyone an opportunity to kind of see more of like the future vision of what's coming for Diablo 4.
We do plan on actually having this roadmap out before Season 8.
So we're really excited to share it.
So as soon as we actually do have that available, we of course, you'll hear it everywhere.
We will be on every single microphone and megaphone out there showcasing what the roadmap is.
And you've probably seen roadmap.
If you're curious, like what does a roadmap entail?
You've probably seen some of our fellow teams here at Blizzard, such as like Diablo Immortal or like World of Warcraft.
They've actually posted these more public facing roadmaps.
And that's something that we want to do here so that you guys have that ability of being able to see what's coming up for Diablo 4 and more exciting news related to it.
So I know we have Q&A.
We want to jump into Q&A here really quickly.
So if you guys do have any questions or anything, of course, we have our chat available on the Twitch link for Diablo.
So feel free to jump in and ask any questions.
I know we always queue it up with one question specifically.
And do we have a question slide here?
There we go.
How does party play work with lair bosses?
We kind of covered this a little bit, but I don't know if you guys want to go into specifically more details on this.
Yeah, I can jump into that.
So when you are fighting the lair bosses in a party and the horde spawns, when you open the horde, we essentially do a bonus chance for an extra drop based on the amount of party play.
So if you're in a party of four and you open up that horde, it's going to guarantee an extra unique item.
So it scales with the amount of parties or party members you have and it's always a good time, you know, when you get together with people.
Awesome.
I'm like, I'm so unprepared.
All right, let me look through the questions here as people are dropping in questions.
I have a team of people dropping questions to it.
If you ever want to know how we do this, we just have a Google Doc and we're copying and pasting questions from chat into there.
Very high tech.
Very high tech, like super high tech.
Let's see.
This is from Skulm TV.
Any plans to place a blacksmith or vendor near the boss rooms to help people quickly salvage slash clear inventory without having to go into town?
I think this is something that we can definitely take away and consider, especially with the revamp flow.
That's definitely something that's interesting.
One thing that the revamp flow does, I will touch on, is the amount of chain bossing really requires you to have a lot of power.
If anything, you know, sort of some philosophy here is that we've heard a lot of feedback that it feels mandatory to play some of these bosses in a party just because chain bossing is so lucrative.
And we do expect some amount of the chain bossing to come down a little bit because a lot more of the resources are being consumed when opening those chests.
So it's not a direct answer to your question.
I think it's an interesting idea.
But I do think the amount of chain bossing and required trips and flow breaks to go back to town from some of this bossing is going to come down a little bit, especially if you've been playing a ton of partying.
Awesome.
Question from Fan27.
Q&A, or sorry, he wrote Diablo Q&A and I just read that out loud.
Any chance we will have to redo strongholds and waypoints on every character every single season?
I can answer that one too.
Yeah, this is something I definitely experience.
It's always a big pain in the ass where it's like, oh, there's some cool bounty or apparition incursion, but I have to go get the waypoint.
It's something the team has been talking about.
There's no concrete plans today, which I know is disappointing, but it's something we know is a problem and something we 100% want to tackle in the near future.
Awesome.
Jokems says, this is actually a question that we were talking about that might actually come up, but would you consider adding the frog from Witch Powers in Season 7 as a permanent companion skill for druids?
And at the moment I can say we're not for that specifically, but it is a thing that I think we didn't really clarify in regards to what from Season 7 is kind of like for sure staying over.
I will say like the Witch Powers are most definitely like something that aren't carrying over completely over to the future seasons.
But one thing in regards to at least the Tree of Whispers is that like we have a bunch of new NPCs there.
We redid the layout there.
That is made that as a hub that doesn't feel like I'm just going for the tree and I have to like immediately leave.
It's made it as like an all-encompassing place that you can most definitely tap into from that end.
Yeah.
Oh, go ahead, Charles.
I can speak a bit to, you know, the Seasonal Powers.
As we said, a lot of those Witchcraft Powers are specific to Season 7.
That is true.
They are not necessarily coming back in Season 8.
But we do hear that feedback, right?
I think they got a really positive reception.
Yep.
A lot of like the Poison Frog, one of my favorites, you know, the Fire Bats and all kinds of the other things that are very visually flashy and just a lot of fun to play with.
We hear that and that definitely helps us to inform like making future content in the past.
We've done that where we've taken some favorite Seasonal Mechanics, put them on items to return.
I can't speak to any particular plans, but just know that we do hear this feedback and it'll definitely help us to help craft content in the future.
We got a lot of questions related to PTR because I know, as I mentioned, this is a PC Battle.net PTR and there's a few people like Kim from Canada.
And I can't read this because the text color is so just jarring.
But we've gotten a lot of questions related to PTR being on PC Battle.net asking like, hey, is there any plans of bringing it to console, maybe Steam?
I'll say the reason why PC Battle.net works best for us is that Battle.net is a platform that is housed here at Blizzard and is the processes of getting builds up there, making like any type of change, especially for PTR where we're in a smaller window and we may need to change something really quickly.
Just it gives us more flexibility and allows us to be able to change those things really, really smoothly.
I know with other platforms and everything, there's more processes involved for good reason because they have more checks and balances and everything.
So it makes it a little bit more difficult on our end to do some of those fast iterations that we may need with PTR.
So in the foreseeable future right now, we see PC Battle.net as being kind of the home for PTRs when we do end up testing anything.
Question from...
My computer is telling me to update. It's been telling me for weeks.
Don't hate me, IT.
ChrisMate says, will the lair bosses have resilience slash damage reduction that the world bosses have to ensure that they just don't get one shot too fast with some classes or builds triv... triv... triv...
I can't talk today. Triv... I can't talk today. Triv... Triv... Yeah.
Triv... Triv... Yeah.
I can't even talk.
I think this is a great question. It's something we actually talk about on the team a bunch.
And from our perspective, adding something like resilience would sort of devalue that power progression.
Like we feel like it sort of disservices that sort of zero to hero. Once Belial was really hard, but now I've gotten so strong I can just crush him.
That said, we do think that the level of one-shotting bosses that has been happening is a little bit too much.
There isn't enough of a journey to get to a point where I can just stomp on Varshawn or I can stomp on the Penant to Knight.
So what we have done is, like Derek mentioned earlier in the stream, we've massively buffed a lot of these bosses.
Like so much so that we're kind of like, try it on the PTR and see.
But a lot of these bosses should present more of a journey to getting to a place where you can really stomp on them throughout the Torment tiers.
Even Uberlilith herself has been, or I don't remember what we actually call her.
Uberlilith.
We just keep calling her Uberlilith.
It's fine.
Has seen quite a buff.
And that should mean that that journey to getting to a place where you're really farming some of these bosses is a lot more fulfilling, but it's longer also.
You're not just like walking into Torment 1 and one-shotting Varshawn.
Yeah, and that kind of ties into what I talked about with some of the outlier builds that were just like Bloodwave Necro prime example of being something where you get one item and then suddenly you can one-shot everything.
It's really not, it doesn't promote the best gameplay.
It's just, it's fun for a little bit to go in and one-shot everything, but that's something we think it's much more engaging to have a little bit of back and forth and you're not just going in and stomping them.
But you are, you do feel powerful, feel some power progression.
Yeah.
And as you get more powerful and more gear and more Paragon levels, you do get more powerful and it becomes easier to overcome these challenges.
And then you start feeling that real powerful stuff as you really complete your build.
Yeah, and I'll also say like, I think part of how we originally set up the boss ladder, it really did encourage the one-shotting behavior, right?
Like if you have to pay materials to fight this boss, why would you ever fight the boss when it's actually a challenge, right?
You would only fight it when it's really difficult.
But the changes that we've made have really sort of, you know, in a fun way I'm hoping this plays out that you can sort of maybe get a cheeky run in on Varshan when maybe he's really hard, but you get a really powerful, unique, because you don't have to risk anything anymore when to actually summon him.
Yeah, I think it also kind of speaks to just the approach of injecting challenge across the lair bosses.
Like we discussed, you know, we could just do straight stat boosts and that would definitely resolve it.
But within Season 8, the team took the extra opportunity to also just inject new mechanics and updated mechanics to the lair bosses across the board to introduce that hiked challenge, but in an interesting way that's just more fun, I guess, really for us to enjoy.
We have a question related to, I'm going to speed through a few last questions here. Lilith, will Lilith ever make an entry into maybe the boss lair system or anything? This is from Ganon North.
Yeah, I think that's something that we've been thinking about and like what's the right place and what's the right time for something like that.
She's in an interesting spot now where she's kind of like the pinnacle of the season's journey a lot of times and that's something we can definitely think about, especially with this revamped.
flow of being able to summon the bosses. So we can definitely take that into consideration. That'd be a lot of fun.
Quick question related to the Spiritborn. This is from The Schwab.
Does the new Russian Claw aspect power give you all the previous bonuses at 4 plus charges or just the extra cast?
It's just the extra one. So if you're casting it at 4 or more charges, it only hits an extra time. It does not get guaranteed crit or overpower or heal you.
It's you kind of either progress through one benefit at a time or you just get the 4 plus if you're using the new upgrade.
I'm gonna do two quick last questions. I will end on the one that everyone's asking. I see it in chat. Don't worry.
In regards to... I lost it. There it is. From mid-central vowel, at what point will you start maybe potentially removing uniques that have proven to be not that useful?
Or do you guys feel like uniques are feeling bloated in the current setup?
I think... I actually feel like we don't necessarily have enough uniques in terms of speaking to every skill.
Like I think that's something that you see with the poison trap and you see with ice shards.
That is sort of why we have the boss ladder to give you more deterministic or maybe not deterministic but targeted ways to find some of the uniques you're looking for.
This lets us have a lot of different uniques but things that you actually have to target.
The other thing I'll just say too is like part of the game is random items and figuring out how to assemble a build out of the random items.
So like we don't want to get to a place where I just sort of log into Diablo and I get all the uniques I want and then I'm sort of done with the game.
And it's just sort of this linear deterministic track through getting the pieces that you want.
But that said, like we're always sort of listening to the feedback and if it does start to feel like where I'm just constantly sifting through things I don't care about.
Those are things that we can absolutely take a look at.
Yeah, and I think on the design side when we're looking at unique designs I think there are still some spots in the game like with poison trap this season where there were some skills or some play styles that had, you know, had some threads there.
But it wasn't really a complete and cohesive build and still require a bit more support.
So we're still going to be looking for those opportunities to support builds or play styles that we think are interesting and fun with new uniques every season.
But additionally we are also taking a look at kind of that, you know, the catalog of uniques we have in the game.
So a good example on Rogue again is that the Scoundrel's Leather this season.
That was an item that was sometimes played but not often for its actual unique effect.
For some of its affixes actually it was pretty powerful.
But its unique effect was pretty lackluster.
And so we've done just a whole rework on it.
We said, hey, what's the identity of this?
Well, it's talking to death trap builds in a way, but in a way that wasn't super compelling.
And so we said, well, let's kind of scrap that existing effect and how can we better support that?
Let's take another try at this.
So that's one way that we're going to look to find those underused uniques that really maybe don't find a home.
We're going to constantly be reevaluating them and seeing how we can kind of plus them up and make them achieve the potential
and fulfill that build niche that they were intended to do in the first place.
Alright, I mean, I ended with the last question because everyone's asking this related to aspirational content.
Is there going to be are there more plans for that?
Things like whether it's a potential leaderboards to more like endgame type of features and stuff.
Do we where are we in regards to some of that?
Yeah, I'll say the team absolutely.
This is top of mind and something that we absolutely want to improve in terms of adding more milestones for you to reach more satisfied.
more satisfying and more rewarding milestones and celebrating those milestones.
So the team is actively sort of looking at what are ways that we can level up some of the aspirational feel of the game.
I'll also say just in season eight, again, a lot of the torment tiers and bosses have really been leveled up.
And I'll say again, the pit has been pretty massively buff.
So there are some tuning changes we've made just to make the game the pieces that we have today a little bit more aspirational and challenging and satisfying to overcome.
We really think season seven was a fun candy rush.
And it was a it was a sugar rush, sort of like the smoothie smoothies.
Everyone's been shrinking behind.
Everyone not everyone.
Not everyone.
Yeah, I got it.
There's a note now that says that it got delivered midstream.
Oh, okay.
Well, yeah, Marcus redeemed.
Yeah, but like season seven was really fast.
And we do think when the game reaches that state of where just nothing really you have to work for it and it's just really fast and it's over in a weekend.
Totally.
There's not enough things to work towards.
So we are sort of taking an approach again with some of the balance changes to make some of the game feel a little bit more aspirational.
And it's a focus for our team going forward.
Yeah, and I will say we've had conversations about this.
I feel like almost weekly Colin and I talk about it a whole lot.
I know there's a there's a lot of discussions happening and a lot of people thinking about that specifically from that end.
So a huge shout out and thanks to you guys for jumping in and to Ruben, of course, for jumping into the build and running through everything.
Again, PTR is going to be starting next Tuesday.
You can early download on PC Battle.net starting Monday afternoon, California time.
And we will have a blog and patch notes and everything available for people to check out immediately after this stream.
Really looking forward to everyone jumping in, testing out the new boss layer system.
Of course, the new powers that are associated with it, all the class changes and all the quality of life stuff that we talked about with in terms of like the leveling journey as you're going up within this new season.
So really looking forward to everyone jumping in.
Please make sure to take advantage of giving us your feedback on the forums or Reddit or Discord, other places.
We're going to be most definitely checking out starting all next week.
So thank you guys again.
We have March of the Goblins, which is currently going on in Diablo 4.
And we have a D2R ladder reset tonight.
So if you're a big D2R person, feel free to jump in.
It's always a fun time.
We will see you guys in the PTR next week and really appreciate it.
Thanks all.
Thanks, everyone.
Thanks.