this stuff. Herodric spells, all new this season, and the team has put so much love, so much energy
into designing all of this. We're so excited. I can't wait to tell you about it, which I'm going
to do right now in this overview section, starting with these bullet points. So several spell
components. That doesn't do it justice. We have 30 different components you're going to be able to
combine together. That's a lot of choice. And you're going to basically be building your own
spell. What does that mean? We're going to get into it. And the last bullet point, unique utility.
Again, what does that mean? It means a lot. This is a pretty intricate system. These spells are not
just like, oh, what one does the most damage, right? It's a lot about like, what kind of functionality
do I want with these skills? And you can really customize it exactly how you want. Yeah, the
possibilities are endless. Go ahead. Yeah. Yeah. In previous seasons, like in season eight, you get
the power from the boss. And that is the one thing that you have. And that's the visual component.
But like you said, you build these Herodic spells. Like you get to pick the different things you want
to put together, which is really cool. Exactly. Yeah. It's so cool. With that said, let's just hop
into it. Let's start digging into what these are. All right. So right here, what we are looking at
is a catalyst. And a catalyst, for those that don't know, which probably most of you don't know,
is the foundation of your spell. This is what gives it its form and its function. And as you can see,
there is already so much depth here. It has a lucky hit chance. It has its own cooldown. It has a rank 10
bonus. And it does a really cool effect that isn't just damage. Each one of these, they do something
unique that you're going to love to play around with. And there are multiple of these.
So how do we trigger the catalysts in the first place? How do we get those going?
That is a good question. There's even a lot of depth when it comes to that system.
And I think the next slide is actually going to be the best thing to convey that.
All right. So what we are looking at right here is the seasonal interface for Herodic spellcraft.
And if you look, you will see that there is actually a bar right there on the UI that kind
of mimics your action bar interface. And if you notice, when the catalyst got placed into the slot,
the action bar skill now has a purple blinking border around it. What does that mean? It means
that your catalyst is now bound to that action bar skill. And that's where the cooldown comes in,
right? Yep. That's where the cooldown comes in. The cooldown is the limiter. So you're not just
going to always be able to press that button and make your catalyst fire off. Right. It's beholden
to its cooldown. But thankfully, ranking up does lower the cooldown. So you're going to get more and
more frequent use out of these catalysts as you rank them up and make them more powerful.
Excellent. Yeah. So that's what's going on in this interface. Let's see what happens when this rogue
presses the button with Celestial Surge equipped.
Okay. Yeah, that's awesome. You see, that does most of the talking for itself.
So basically what just happened is that the rogue threw the smoke bomb and the smoke bomb was the
guiding factor for the catalyst. And the catalyst created that arcanic horadric rune on the ground
right where the smoke bomb landed. It did its pull in effect. And then that barrage of stars just
started doing their work randomly all over that area. What do you guys think? Is that pretty cool?
That's pretty neat. And that's only like one of the possible combinations, right? Because like
you have one catalyst there and you assigned it to a specific skill, but you could pick any of the
catalysts and you could assign it to any of the skills that your class has available to it.
And the way that the catalyst interacts changes based on the kind of skill you're using, right?
Exactly. So think of it like an extension of your skills. You know, it's going to feel very natural
and organic as you're, what's the term, invoking these into combat. So yeah, go ahead.
I really like how you get to choose like when you deploy this in combat, right? If you want it on
smoke bomb, it's like, okay, I want to be CCing an enemies or like, I know there's a clump of enemies
there so I can deploy this at a key time. Or if I like don't want to think about it too much, like I just,
I just want it to happen as much as possible, right? I'll just put it on my core skill that I'm
pressing all the time and it'll happen like as often as it can. And like you get that choice
in how you want to deploy these. Exactly. And like I said, it's going to feel natural.
If you're a Sorc and you put it on flame shield, it's going to summon on your character.
If you're using a ranged ability, it's going to go where the ranged ability lands.
If you're using a melee skill, it's going to be in melee range on the character you hit.
It's just going to feel like what you would expect it to be.
So the catalyst just really flows around however you want to integrate it into your
play style effectively. Exactly. We don't want to spoil all of the catalysts. We want you to
experience them on the PTR, but we do have one more for you to look at right now that's really
cool. So let's go to that tooltip. So this is the Cosmic Anomaly. This is a summons type. We know
players love summons. It's going to scale off summon damage bonuses naturally because it has the tag.
It has a passive and an active component. For those of you familiar with Druid Companions,
this is going to feel really natural to you. It's that same kind of setup.
And I'm not even going to mention the rank 10, but it's pretty insane. Like just if you read it,
that's a powerful effect. So when you reach that threshold, you are unlocking a whole new realm of
power for your catalyst. And yeah, let's go see what this looks like. What does it look like in game?
Oh, shiny. So shiny. Look at that. Very lightning-y. Very lightning-y. Yeah, that's a...
There it goes. That's a real word, right? Yeah, yeah. Absolutely. I'm going to say this.
Oh, I love this clip. Oh, that's so satisfying. Okay. That's also a little heartless. I can't
believe the necromancer would do that. Those are your friends and you just send them to go explode?
Unbelievable. But good news, they come back. Your friends come back. So you can go send them over
to explode. They do their thing. And then they always return to you. Yeah. So the thing I really
love about this clip in particular is that the necromancers chosen this catalyst and assigned
it to Bone Prison, which is very clever because they also have a pull-in with corpse tendrils.
And so what they do is they pull everything in with corpse tendrils and then cast Bone Prison,
which invokes the cosmic anomalies and kills all of them while they're stuck all together inside the
Bone Prison. Exactly. Well said. There's so many satisfying combinations for you to discover.
However, we're going to leave it there, but let me tell you the amount of depth in this system
is so fun. We've had so much fun playtesting this internally. Oh, yeah, yeah. I've been playing
it quite a bit in the last couple of minutes or however long. And apparently I lose track of
time while I'm doing it. No, it's great. I love it. This is just such an awesome addition to the game.
Yeah. Like, honestly, I've got to say, I did write the 230 PTR blog. I hope you all like it.
But this is definitely a system like going in and testing it out before to then help write the blog.
I was like, the blog is not going to cut it in terms of listing on all the different tools.
Like the way all the different aspects of the Horadix Spellcraft interface together,
it's really something that you need to go in and playtest yourself because of all the different
combinations, all the way the different powers interface with each other. It's very hard to get
on paper. So it's really something you got to go in and test for yourselves. It's a ton of fun.
You can. Right. Yeah. And you get that opportunity. How about that? Exactly. Going forward,
we have something cool to show you. So we've talked a lot about catalysts. Now let's talk about
infusions. This is another thing you can socket into your Horadric interface. And this is going to
change the damage type, the elemental damage that your catalyst deals. And it doesn't just stop there.
The damage type has mechanics attached to it that change its function too. So what would you expect
fire to do? Like fire is destructive. It's really, you know, it's, it's all consuming. So naturally it's
going to destroy enemy structures. What does that mean? I'm not going to tell you, but you're going to,
well, you're, maybe you're going to see it in just a moment actually, but I'm not going to tell you for
this time right now. And fire also creates burning areas on the ground that will damage enemies that you
keep in that area. And it doesn't stop there. I'm sorry. There's so much depth on these items and
there are five of them, right? So you have so much choice, but also while it's equipped,
your fire damage bonus is equal to that of your highest damage type bonus. What does that mean?
Yeah. So even if you're like playing like a frost sorcerer who just has like a lot of frost
damage or cold damage, right? You can still use this and it kind of benefits from all of your,
your cold damage because all of the, um, the elemental damage types kind of get,
get equalized here. So I could be, for example, a frost sorc and I just have copious amounts of
frost damage bonus, right? It's just, it's, it's flowing everywhere. I have too much of it.
I swap in the poison infusion and then suddenly I have an equal amount of poison damage bonus.
That's really cool because my poison catalyst is going to be hitting like a truck and players love
dealing lots of damage, right? I love it. But also, and tell me if this is cool when you guys get in,
get to play test with it, the possibilities expand even more because now I'm a sorc that has a lot
of poison damage and a real visage. Like, do I want to throw that on my helmet now? I don't know.
I've never really had that, that kind of build crafting opportunity, that kind of build crafting
opportunity. So there's so much there. Uh, just can't wait to see everyone's reaction when you'll
play with it. And so just to make sure I get this right. Um, I have my catalyst. That's what we see
visually in these clips here, like those cosmic anomalies. And we just talked about infusions
and infusions change the elemental damage type specifically of my catalyst, right?
Correct. Yep. Okay. So as you're seeing right here, he's swapping out the lightning gem with a fire
gem. And now look at them. They're all fiery. They have smoldering flames and watch this when they
combust, look at it. There's a burning patch on the ground and you can get multiple of those.
It isn't just always going to be one. Uh, this is destruction incarnate, right? This is,
this is cool. Oh yeah. Yeah. And each infusion has like their own secondary, uh, damaging or,
or just not necessarily damaging, but just a fact that they apply as well. And in fire's case,
it's the burning. Yeah. It is layers on top of layers, right? Um, so again, we're so excited,
uh, for people that were closely reading that tool tip on the infusion page, you might've seen
a rank five bonus, um, even more depth. We keep talking about depth that rank, that rank five bonus.
We're going to get into it right now. Uh, basically it allows you to deactivate monster affixes
depending on the damage type you are using. So what would you expect fire to deactivate? Well,
it makes sense that thematically it would deactivate chilling winds. Those are those like icy winds that
monsters can summon in. They like slow your projectiles. Yeah. So annoying. No one likes being slow.
I was just playing a, yeah, I was playing a blood spear necromancer season eight and the chilling winds
were so annoying. Oh yeah. So let's look at a clip and see, uh, chilling winds being deactivated.
So this is a different catalyst than we've seen before, right? This one draws like a damaging beam.
Yeah. So this is disintegrate. It is another catalyst. We're not going to show you the tool tip about all
its possibilities and what it does, but yeah, you'll see that the moment he deactivates the monster,
those chilling winds just disappear and they will stay disappeared as long as they are, you know,
consistently deactivated. Uh, so as you know, this is going to be very satisfying to use. Like you're going
to be able to swap these in and if certain, uh, monster affixes just ruin your day and you really
dislike them, well, they're just gone like that. Uh, and we have one more clip to show you.
Yep. So, oh, okay. There we go. The waller wall is just gone. Uh, this is also fire because I talked
about structures. Um, that's waller walls. That is lightning totems. Those like things that arc lightning
damage, the red lightning damage all around the arena, that is tether points. Those things that
like chain you to the ground fire destroys all of those. Uh, so we're going to leave it at that.
We hope you really have fun playing around with that. Yeah. No more wallers. Yeah. Yeah. If you hate wallers,
your problems have, your prayers have been answered. That's great. Yeah. I mean, that's super handy because
now if you're going into a nightmare dungeon, there's particular monster ethics, you can just slap in
whichever, uh, whichever infusion you need and then you're, you won't have to deal with it.
Exactly. Exactly. Um, so yeah, there's going to be so much choice here to like swap things on the fly
and react to things to kind of suit your play style. And that's really cool. That's really exciting.
Uh, but wait, there is more. We have more in this system for you. Actually, we have three more socket
spaces of things you have to think about while you are designing your spell. So let's get into that.
So we have arcana arcana are going to be dropping in seasonal content randomly in the released version
of this season, but on PTR, we're just going to be giving it to you. So you'll be able to play around
with all of them, but arcana are like, think of them like the tuning knobs for your powers. Uh, these are
small, subtle effects that when you add three of them, they really kind of tailor the power, uh, the catalyst
to your play style. Yeah. So we have, okay, so let's recap again, really quick. Yeah. We have
the catalyst, which is the visual effect. We have the infusion, which determines the catalyst's
elemental type and gives it fancy bells and whistles. And then we have the arcana, which even modifies it
further. And like we saw there, like you could make it bigger or you could give yourself a buff when
you use your catalyst and that kind of stuff. Exactly. So like, let me just walk you through
these three arcana right here. So, uh, I picked these three because, uh, they're kind of, they kind of
show off different reasons you might use an arcana. So starting on the left side with gleaming conduit,
it increases the effect size of your catalyst. Uh, what does that mean? Let's go back to the first
catalyst we showed off. It was the celestial surge where you had the stars raining from the sky.
Uh, that's a randomized pattern, right? That's a bit of a downside, but with this placed into the socket,
suddenly those stars are creating bigger impacts when they land on the ground. Right. Meaning by swapping
in this, uh, arcana, you are overcoming a bit of that downside and you are making that damage more
consistent and just more overall impactful. Yep. And that's just going to apply differently to each
catalyst. Yeah. Uh, for tranquil stone, I'm actually just going to throw this over the Charles.
Charles, what class might be happy about this arcana? I mean, you know, I've heard some classes,
necromancer, talking about how they don't have too many options for unstoppable. Well, now you have
many, many options, uh, five different catalyst options and tons of different ways to invoke
it, um, to gain that unstoppable. So, you know, necromancers, uh, look out for that tranquil stone.
Exactly. Yeah. So this, again, this kind of goes to that philosophy of these will kind of fill in holes.
Oh my gosh. One sec. Okay. Technical difficulty aside, I can hear again, uh, tranquil stone will
basically, uh, overcome some downsides of your class. It will, you know, fill in the holes and allow you to
come certain, overcome things you lack. And that's really cool. And then potent alloy. Alloy?
Alloy. Alloy. Alloy. Okay. I pronounced it correctly. Potent alloy. Uh, we talked about how infusions
interact with monster affixes. You're even going to find some arcana in the mix that will also
additionally interact with even more monster affixes. Right. So if that really suits your play style,
feel free to, uh, place those in, but wait, there's a little bit more we're getting there,
but there's a little bit more, uh, there are also legendary arcana. And when we think about
legendary arcana, we're not really thinking about pure player power. We're thinking about the,
how hard they are to understand the depth of them, right? There's just a lot going on. And what do I
mean by that? So there are five legendary arcana that you can discover out there. And as you see
in this slide right here, we have nightmare orb, but if you look at it, it changes what's going on.
So let's start on the left side. So on the left side, your nightmare orb is speaking to the cosmic
anomaly, uh, catalyst from before. Oh, yeah. And it adjusts its effect to match it. So when you put this
on your pet summons catalyst, suddenly they're going to have this little aura around them where
when, as they run into enemies, they're going to fear and slow them. Uh, but if we go to the right
side, the nightmare orb is talking to celestial surge and this does a completely different effect. It's
going to fear unaffected enemies. But once the fear ends, you have a chance to create even more stars.
So these legendary arcanas care about each individual catalyst then? Yep. Exactly. So the same
legendary arcana has five different variations, uh, to wrap your head around. And there are five of
these. So five times five, I'm going to say the keyword one more time. I'm sorry. That's a lot of depth.
So I feel like you've just presented to me and us a unfathomable amount of combinatorics, Liam.
Yes. Yes, I did. Okay. Uh, my earpiece has fallen out now like five times. So the funny thing is,
if you guys remember from last stream, Adam's earpiece was falling out all the time. Yeah.
We actually changed that and I got the souped up earpiece. So this, this baby that's locked in,
we're going to be getting those for the rest of the stream. So as Liam struggles, I benefit.
I'm good for like a minute and then it's probably going to fall out again. Actually, I already feel
falling out. Don't worry about it. Instead, we have some really cool video content to show you. While the
rest of us just talk broadly about this system and why we're so excited. So, uh, everybody,
the floor is open. What is your favorite combination? What are you the most excited about
when it comes to these, uh, spells? Yeah, I really think that, um, I love, uh, finding ways to get my
ultimate cool down really low so that I can trigger it on my ultimate, uh, constantly. Uh, it kinds of
mixes really, really well. Just playing like an ultimate build in general. It's really fun.
Yeah, I've got a soft spot for summons. I really love the cosmic anomaly. I love, uh, just having a
bunch of guys out there, even if they're floaty, glowy orbs of elemental destruction, um, and love
commanding them and having them go and explode. That's, that's just really fun for me.
Yeah, I've been a big fan of playing barb lately, but I find when I get into the higher torment tiers,
you're just like so up and close and taking damage that it, it, the survivability does get a bit more
difficult. So like having the ability to use some more like ranged abilities to then throw, uh, my spellcraft out and then kind of
do some CC while I am like an up close and personal player. And like, I'll probably play a rogue next
season too. So in a similar vein, like being able to kind of like still have those, uh, damaging abilities
that are, you know, will do damage over distance while being able to like, you know, go heel in the corner.
It's nice to just like influence those play styles.
Yeah, definitely. So again, so much content here. We are unbelievably excited for you guys to get into the
PTR and try these out. Yeah. Uh, again, we've had so much fun play testing them and we can't wait to
see what everyone thinks about it. I feel like I got into a state where like I was play testing
Herodric spellcraft and I was like, the time just started slipping away. Cause like, I just started
being like, well, what if I like did this kind of list with this infusion and then apply it to this skill?
Oh, and now this Arcana matters and that just have happened again and again and again. It's just so much
fun to play with. Yeah. Yeah. It's a, it's a really, really intricate system. Um, I just want to
throw it to Aislinn and I get to say one more thing. Do it. There's more.
There's more. There's already enough, Liam. Yeah. You think we need more?
Yeah. You want to throw a whole another layer on top of this, Liam? You crazy man.
Well, yes, uh, you are correct. There is more. There are, uh, Herodric jewels. Uh, Herodric jewels are what you
might be reminded by, uh, well, you might be reminded, um, excuse me, I can speak English.
Uh, occult gems from season seven. Uh, they are very similar to occult gems from season seven.
We have a lot of similar effects on Herodric jewels that you might have seen from season seven
occult gems, but we've added lots of new shiny layers of paint and, and glorious effects, uh, to
these Herodric jewels. And we've also really brought them in and, um, both aesthetically and mechanically
unified them with Herodric spellcraft. Uh, so what you're going to be doing is you're going to be
finding these Herodric jewels through tomes starting in Torment one. Um, so once you actually
get to the end game, you'll start finding the ability to, uh, craft these Herodric jewels. You can
then, once you've found the tome, uh, take it to a crafting station and actually craft it with the
seasonal currency Herodric files and gem fragments. And don't worry, it's not as many gem fragments as
occult gems. If, if you have a PTSD from that, like I do, it was a lot. Um, and yeah, you can
then just socket them into your jewelry sockets and just pump up your build even further. And what our
first example here is liminal echo, which you might actually recognize, uh, as an occult gem, uh, in
terms of a cheat death, but we have reflavored it and rethemed it and changed its mechanics to actually
invoke propulsion, which is a different one of the catalysts that we didn't actually show here, but you
will, you will see that in the PTR. Uh, and it makes you invulnerable and then it has an ICD.
Um, but yeah, we have way more, uh, Herodric jewels than just that. There are 15 total. They all do
lots of crazy different stuff. So we're going to go over some of our favorite here is just to give
you guys a sneak peek. Uh, so the first one is Tyrant Bane. You can look over that text there and you
might think to yourself, is this Bane of the Stricken? And the answer would be, yes, it is. If you are a D3
enjoyer, it is Bane of the Stricken for dot builds. I'm very personally excited about that one. Uh, the
second one we have is the Starflux. This one is fantastic. Uh, it's just punch you in the teeth,
straight value, double your catalyst damage. That's a lot of damage though. So if you do want to do that,
you're probably going to lose control of your Herodric spellcraft to some degree, which causes your
catalysts to inherit their infusions randomly. So you don't actually get to determine or decide rather,
how that's going to happen. And then finally we have idle from below. You may also recognize this
effect from occult gems, but with a twist. Uh, and you, I mean the twist is, it's, it's probably fine.
I, yeah, and jeweled guardians, I bet they're pushovers, but don't worry about it. No, no, no,
don't worry about it. No, yeah, no. Focus on the first line for that one. That's the important part.
Right, Mary, of course, that max life, unhindered. Great stuff. Absolutely. Nothing else to worry about.
For sure. For sure. All right. And, uh, I think we have a video of the Starflux to kind of give you a sense of what that is
like. So this is the cosmic anomaly, uh, catalyst with the Starflux equipped. And you might notice
that they have different infusions applied to them because it's determined randomly each time
a new cosmic anomaly comes out. Uh, and this can be really actually interesting because Liam, to your
point before, uh, different infusions deal with different enemy of fixes. So if you have the Starflux
equipped and cosmic anomalies, you might actually be able to deal with a bunch of different enemy
effects simultaneously, which is pretty cool. Exactly. And just look at that kaleidoscopic
explosion, right? Yeah. So satisfying. It's so beautiful. Absolutely. And we have, uh, like I
said, we have 15 Horadric jewels and all of them do various wacky, amazing, cool stuff. Uh, so while
you're experimenting with Horadric spellcraft and trying out all of the new things in season nine,
slot some of those in and see what kind of madness you can accomplish. Yeah. Not gonna lie,
Chad was pretty excited about the, uh, the Horadric jewels. And like the Starflux, it looks absolutely
not yet. I'm really, really pumped to test it out. Uh, a few call-outs for everyone, uh, uh,
watching as well. We will have a Q and A towards the end of the stream. So if you do have any
questions for our development team, any questions for Dan, like what's the best way to make poutine
gravy from scratch, you know, he's your guy for it. Um, so we will have that towards the end of
the stream. So drop your questions in chat. We do have community members, um, pulling those. And again,
like we want your feedback. This, that was a ton of information, a ton of systems. And we actually do
have specific things that we're looking for in terms of what we're seeking for each,
uh, for each bit, uh, bit and component going in the two through PTR. Yeah, that's true. Like,
you know, uh, I guess I'll speak specifically to Horadric, uh, jewels. Got to make sure I get the
terms right. Um, yeah. So we want to hear what you guys think about all the different Horadric jewels.
We want to know, like, do these effects feel correct? This is the perfect time, uh, to give feedback on
just straight up bouncing. Does this give you enough bonus damage? Does this give you too much bonus
damage? Does this feel good? Does it not feel good? Uh, are the jewel guardians, uh,
I don't worry about them. Yeah. Don't give us feedback on that part.
Maybe you should worry about them, you know? Maybe they need to get a little too stuck.
Yeah, yeah. But yeah, just, yeah, let us know about, uh, Horadric jewels. And of course,
I'm sure you'd love to hear your thoughts about it. Definitely. For Horadric spells,
please just let us know how it feels both in early and late game. I know, uh, it's PTR. A lot of people
are going to be mainly jumping into the late game, but early game is also really helpful. We want them to feel
really cool and satisfying to use in all realms of content. Uh, we also just want to know about
the effects themselves. Are they satisfying? Does anything feel off? Uh, do we need to like tighten
up cooldowns or things like that? Just get into the weeds with it. We will definitely be reading
through as much as we can and making these spells the best they can be for launch.
Yep. Now's the time to get that feedback. Tune those knobs. It's the, it's the best time to do it.
And for everyone, uh, watching from home, we also will have the D4 patch notes and the blog
hitting after the stream. So if there's anything you missed on the stream, um, that will be available
for you to read in depth and disseminate over the weekend before you jump into the PTR.
Um, but I know one of the biggest parts of the patch notes, uh, has to do with class balance.
And we do have some, Charles, you got a lot to talk about today.
I got some notes here. We got lots to talk about, you know, kind of teed it up at the start of the stream,
how we kind of think about class balance currently. Um, but of course it's, it's an ever changing
process and we always want to be giving, you know, new things to play with new ways to play Diablo 4.
And, uh, so there's lots of updates, uh, this season, um, with that in mind.
Yeah. Uh, so let's get into, uh, some of the, the changes that affect all classes in some way
before getting into each individual class and talk about some of the new stuff coming for them.
These are kind of, uh, changes that are, are global or, or affect everybody. Uh, so first up, you know,
Overpower has been overpowered for a while. We should have seen that coming, uh, with the name. Oops.
Oops. Um, yeah, it has been, uh, really like just one of the strongest things you can be doing across
any class for the past, um, handful of seasons now. And, uh, so we're, we're definitely taking a big swing
at it here in season nine. Um, so Overpower's initial design philosophy was, it was supposed to be, um, a, a,
a stat that tankier kind of builds, uh, things that have like, um, that strong defensive fantasy,
things like Werebear, Barbarians, Blood Necro, could, could build these defensive stats like max
health and fortify and convert that into offensive power. Uh, that's the initial design conception of
it. And which is why whenever you did Overpower, you got bonus damage in a, um, based on the amount
of maximum life and fortify that your character had. This ended up being a lot because it was kind
of tied to the, uh, like ratio of how much you, of health you already had. Uh, I don't want to get
too deep into the, the math here, but basically, uh, it was a lot of additive damage. Uh, so it would
be the equivalent of you having like plus a thousand or more percent damage on your gear when you
overpowered. And that led to Overpower's being extremely strong, far more than say Critical Strike,
for instance. And even dominating builds that originally weren't intended to like benefit
from that so much. Yeah, we, we saw just every class was trying to Overpower because it was so
valuable. Yeah. Um, probably also didn't help that it's already so good to just stack max life,
right? So it was like, you're doing a ton of damage and you're doing the right thing by stacking
Max life because it's so potent, right? So yeah, it was very dominant for that reason. Right. And so in
this season, in season nine, we're going to be making an update to that additive portion, the additive
damage that you get from the overpower, that messy behind the scenes formula that you would get,
essentially reducing it by 80%. So if you used to get, you know, a thousand percent bonus damage
there, it's only going to be 200, um, here in the PTR. Uh, the, uh, it still gives a multiplicative
bonus just like Critical Strikes because it's still rare. It's still, you need to work to get your
overpowers online just like Critical Strikes. Um, so it's still going to be powerful. Overpowering is
still going to be better than not doing it. Um, but it won't be so infinitely far ahead like we've
seen it. Uh, we definitely want a lot of feedback on this because we know it's been, uh, you know,
the real big talking point of a lot of different, uh, meta builds right now feels like you need to,
uh, work on overpower. Um, that's not the intent. We don't want everybody to feel like you have to do it
all the time in order to optimize your damage. So we definitely want to make sure that we open up
the possibilities to other, uh, classes. Um, kind of tied in with that, the additive damage rebalance.
So, uh, that's, that's the base power of overpower we talked about. Um, another contributing factor
was that whenever you got overpowered damage on your items, it was just overstatted. You know,
we, we balanced those initially when, um, earlier on in the game's lifetime when we had a different
estimate of how often players would be overpowering or doing any of these kinds of conditional effects,
like critical strike or dot damage or, or what have you. Um, so we've done kind of a comprehensive
pass on items, uh, the base affixes that, that show up, uh, this, this season and said, okay,
critical strike damage. We're going to give you an equivalent amount of critical strike damage
and overpower damage if it appears in the same spot. Uh, previously it was something like you would
get a one handed weapon and it would literally have almost 200% overpower damage and ancestral,
and it would give like 55% critical strike damage. And that's just way too different,
right? Like that was one reason like, well, why would I build crit damage when I can build
overpower and get four times the benefit? Uh, so we're, we're looking to re-normalize that and kind
of, uh, establish a better baseline of comparison of these stats against each other. Um, this affects
everybody in some way as you're building, um, your items, you're going to be looking for different
stats. There's just the, the numerical values will be different there, but we think it, it gets into a much
better state for allowing you to go, you know, for vulnerable damage, for crit damage, for summons
damage and not feel like you're doing it wrong because it wasn't overpower, right? Um, next we've
got a basic skill buff. Um, there's, there's a lot of things that affect every class this season.
Yeah. Um, so talking about basic skills, um, this is kind of an initiative where we are starting here to,
to really comprehensively look at all of the skills in the game and look at their relative balance,
against each other. And, um, you know, sometimes we've had some basic skills which just, you know,
do negative damage. You think like you're healing the enemies by attacking because it's so weak.
Yeah. And other ones that you can actually like really build, um, a full kind of basic skill build
around because it has a lot of support, has good base damage, has whatever effects. Um, we've done a
comprehensive pass on every single basic skill in the game and, and retuned them. And when I say retuned,
I say double or triple their damage output for the most part. Um, literally skills that used to do
like 20% of your weapon damage now do like 60 or 80%, uh, just, just massive increases on every single
basic skill in the game. Now, um, that's to help them kind of compete kind of right out of the box.
You get a basic skill, you press the button, it feels impactful. That's the goal. Um, we do want still
basic skill, um, oriented builds in the late game to, to exist. But of course, if we just tripled or,
um, their damage output, uh, that would cause some of them to be kind of way too good on, on some ends.
Yes. So we have, uh, adjusted some of the, uh, the scalers that you see on some of the legendary
and unique items that talk to, uh, basic skills in particular, brought them down a little bit.
We still want them to be, uh, competitive and probably better this season than they have been in the past.
Uh, but we're just, um, you know, we're not trying to triple every single basic skill. We want to make
sure that it, it, uh, smooths out that progression. Right. Um, I will say that this is, uh, you know,
we, we looked at basic skills here in this season. It's, uh, an initiative where we're going to be
looking at other categories of skills and in future seasons. So definitely keep an eye on, uh, similar
kinds of, uh, comprehensive balance passes, uh, for, for future seasons as they come down. So your feedback
on exactly how we landed on this basic skill pass, uh, is really helpful to help inform like,
hey, is our, is our methodology or comparison, uh, right. Uh, and we're, we're the tuning on these,
um, accurate. Uh, next up maximum resistance. This is a, a, a relatively quicker point. Um, so right now on,
uh, on live, if you, uh, your maximum resistance for every element is capped at 70%. Now on the PTR,
it'll be capped at 75% baseline. So everyone can get a little bit more resistance. Um, the absolute cap
is still 85 if you get some maximum resistance effects. Uh, but the baseline you'll get 75 resist
in order to be resistance capped. Um, in exchange, there were some unique items that were, uh, that had
just a whole bunch of, um, all resistance on them. Like Jens Blessing, some, some boots that just gave you
like 50 some percent, um, maximum resistance to all elements. Uh, those ones...
Too much of it, a little by itself. Yeah, exactly. So some of those outliers that really solve your
resistance a little too easily, we're going to tone those down a little bit. Um, but kind of in
exchange, we give everyone, uh, the option to build a little bit more to make sure that,
that building up resistance has a kind of a meaningful journey to it. Uh, and finally on this
slide that affects, um, all characters, the key passives, we've also done a pass much like with basic
skills to look at, um, our various key passives that affect every build, um, and, and kind of look at their
relative power level. And a lot of the outliers that we've seen in class balance, um, historically
have come from a key passive that just scales kind of infinitely, right? You, you build up some critical
strike damage, which increases your other damage and that just scales infinitely. And that causes
builds that can use that key passive to be far more powerful than builds that use other key passives,
which maybe don't scale that infinitely. Um, so with that in mind, we looked at every key passive
and we've set a bar of about 75%, um, multiplicative damage, um, a bonus. So if it, if it just said do
increase damage, it would say 75% increase. Now some will have more conditions, you know,
it only affects certain types of damage. And so we budget those at a little bit higher and so on.
Um, but we, anything that had like a previous uncapped scaler, we're going to put a cap on it to
make sure that it kind of hits that 75% mark and even a handful of some key passives that were
underperforming that mark that were, were not quite that good, uh, have gotten buff up to, to try
to let them compete. And so builds that, um, got some of those buffed key passives. We'll be really
happy to see that too. Absolutely. I guess I'll just make a comment. We're not the fun police, right?
We're not coming here to ruin your day, but what we are doing is we want to make a more consistent
experience for our players and we want the pieces to fit together naturally. Your progression is smooth.
There's all these puzzle pieces. They just make sense as you stack them up. And we just,
we want to move away from having such extreme outliers. Yeah. The, the extreme balance outliers
are really what kind of, um, can kill the fun of the game. If you're like, Hey, I want to play,
you know, whatever kind of, uh, build you want, but then you see somebody else doing something
different and you're like, Oh, they are a hundred times better than me. It actually does affect how much
fun you're having because you feel like you're playing suboptimally. And, uh, by, by kind of bringing
some of these, uh, more in line to, to, uh, uh, kind of a budget of power that we want from certain
sources, we help to, to eliminate those outliers that are like miles ahead of everybody else.
Um, with that in mind, you know, we, we think that this is, uh, going to promote better build
diversity, of course, as, as you can play more options and it won't feel as bad that you aren't,
um, uh, you aren't being left behind in such a way. All right. So let's, uh, move on to the
individual class changes. Those affect everybody, but of course, every class has some new stuff to
talk about here. On first up, uh, we've got barbarians. Uh, so for the barbarian, um, the big
talk of them for a while has been earthquakes in particular. Barbarians, uh, love to, uh, you know,
stomp on the ground and they stomp so hard that they make some earthquakes. Um, those have been extremely
powerful for a handful of seasons and we know that, you know, there's other fantasies to explore
in barbarian other than just earthquakes. And so we have done, um, some updates to kind of bring down
some of the power level of earthquakes specifically on its legendary paragon node, uh, the force of
nature that gave it a ton of multiplicative damage on the earthquakes that has been brought down quite
a bit. Um, to the second bullet point here, a lot of the legendary paragon nodes in, in barbarian
paragon and across every other class has been kind of simplified. Some of them used to have
effects which is like do a thing to get a buff to give you some damage and it stacks up to five
times, right? It would be like kind of a multi-step thing for a paragon node, which, uh, we thought
that's maybe a little bit more complex. It's asking you a little bit too much. Um, so we've simplified
them and often it's just like, hey, do a thing, get a bonus and that's it. Right. Uh, and specifically
on barbarian, uh, I think they got some of the bigger updates in that, in that regard. And in a lot of
cases the, the paragon become even more powerful because you don't need to stack it up five times
or whatever it might be. You just get the bonus right out of the gate. So they are slightly more
powerful. Could you say barbarians are getting a seismic shakeup? I'm so sorry. A little bit,
a little bit. On some of these, it may, may feel that way. Yes. Um, additionally, we've, uh, we've got a new
unique item this season. Uh, we know that, uh, players love playing with, uh, Bash Cleave, uh, from a while back. And now, uh, what if every other one of their
basic skills could cleave? Well, have I got the unique for you? And, uh, it's my favorite named unique in this
season, which is saying something. It's true. Um, it is the hooves of the mountain god. So good.
So, uh, hooves of the mountain guard, god, whenever you, um, attack with a basic skill while you're at
maximum fury, you kind of enter the state where your fury is going to be draining and you're in, you're kind
of empowered here. And during that time, your basic skills will cleave and deal increased damage.
All of your basic skills will do that while you're empowered here. And of course, uh, your,
your fury is draining. So you're going to want to keep spamming those basic skills to rebuild it back
up and kind of maintain that state as long as possible. Yeah. So at this point with this unique,
you really care about generating a tremendous amount of fury, but it's not actually to cast a
core. It's just to keep going. Yeah. Yeah. Keep going and keep hitting with your, your basic skills that
are just hitting hard and cleave in all around you. It's pretty awesome. Uh, we've got a video clip here
of this in action. Of course, we've seen, uh, Bash cleave before, uh, through some of the tempering, um, affixes.
Uh, that temporary affix is going to be updated to give, uh, another multiplicative, uh, bonus to,
to bash here, but, um, because now it can cleave through this, this unique. And of course you can,
uh, mow through a whole, uh, uh, uh, set of skeletons here, uh, with your bash while your,
your fury is draining. Yeah. I love that. The parts coming up where, yep. One hit,
they're just all to the side. Oh yeah. Oh my goodness.
All right. We've got, uh, next class. We've got the druid to talk about. All right. So the, uh,
druid this season, uh, the, um, talk of the druid has been cataclysm for a while. Um, a couple
points on that. So, uh, a lot of cataclysm, it's this long lasting ultimate, right? You, you,
you press cataclysm, you get the storm around you. It lasts a while. And, um, it, it suffered from,
uh, some like we call snapshotting, um, where you get a buff or some effect that says, hey,
your next skill cast does increase damage or, or it has some effect. And when you, uh, when you press
cataclysm, it's obviously a very long effect and it benefits from that effect from the, the, the bonus
damage to your next cast. Uh, that's absolutely intended, right? When we say your next cast,
we mean the whole cast cataclysm is a great thing to do that on. Uh, that being said, we, we do find that
cataclysm being the only way to play druid, or at least the only kind of competitive way to play
druid is not really healthy because we know that is a kind of mechanically intensive play style that
you need to think about buffs. You need to set it up kind of precisely. And for players who like that,
uh, play style, we, we would love to encourage that. But when it becomes the only way or the
absolute best way, the kind of mandatory way to play a class, uh, that's kind of unhealthy. And so we've
done some, uh, numerical nerfs to bring cataclysm and some of the modifiers to it, uh, down to earth
a little bit. So it, it will, um, allow for other opportunities, uh, other ways to play druid in a
competitive way. Um, so some of those are grizzly rage. Um, we've got, uh, updates to, uh, a lot of
legendaries that used to talk to grizzly rage. And that does also remind me, um, about, uh, what we're
doing with legendaries this season, as we talk about this, um, in previous seasons, we've always
had a new unique item and a new legendary aspect for every class, uh, here for season nine, we're
just going to be doing a brand new unique item. And we're instead of doing reworks to a lot of
existing legendaries. Uh, so a handful of legendaries on each class have been, uh, rather
substantially reworked where we, we looked at them and said, Hey, we have a legendary that already talks
to grizzly rage, but it kind of sucked. Right. And we said, well, rather than make a brand new one,
let's take this existing one that really wasn't hitting that mark. And then just like functionally
change a lot of things to it. Um, it may still have, you know, the same kind of theme, same kind
of niche probably keeps the same name in a lot of cases. Um, but instead of like adding a brand new
legendary aspect to that kind of dilutes the drop pool, right? It, every, every legendary we add
makes it harder to find any in particular legendary. You also don't want a situation where
like if we leave that, uh, aspect not desirable, but then we make a new one that is you're like,
Oh man, I really hope I find the good one and not the bad one. So that's another positive for this.
Exactly. So we've done a lot of updates on every class, uh, to take their, their, uh, poor, the,
the bad legendaries and, and look to update them to support some of the new play styles that we're
interested in encouraging this season. And so for Druid, uh, several of the ones talking to grizzly rage
and poison in particular are going to be updated. So benevolent of us finding homes for all these
legendaries, you know, it's great. You know, like now they have a home to go to. They actually
hopefully find a new niche to fit into and they won't be so sad off to the side and people pick
them up and they're like, no in the gutter. Yeah. Yeah. That's absolutely the hope is, is that we're
able to, to look at every legendary and unique item in the game and say, Hey, there's you pick it up and
you read it and you're like, Oh, I see where this would be useful. And you would feel excited about it.
It might not be the build you're currently playing, but you, you see that it does have a home and a
niche. That's our goal. And we know that a lot of legendaries in the game right now aren't hitting
that mark. And that's why we're, we're focusing on, on reworks, uh, at least for this season, right?
Uh, with that in mind with, uh, grizzly rage and some poison updates, let's talk about, um,
probably one of my favorite visual uniques of the season. Uh, I call it splashing poison puddles,
right? Because, um, you know, we're getting, we're coming up on summer here. Everyone loves splashing in the sun,
you know, playing in the water, but we're in Diablo in the world of sanctuary and nothing's ever that wholesome.
It's, it's, it's poison bottles. Let's take a look at the rotting lightbringer.
So the rotting lightbringer, um, every 10 seconds, when you cast pulverize, it'll form a poison puddle
where you pulverize. And if you pulverize that puddle again, then it'll splash, uh, additional
percent of that damage, uh, to, to enemies, uh, nearby. It'll like throw out some extra little, uh,
little projectiles of poison. Um, and of course you are, um, splashing in the, in the, in the poison
puddle to, to damage everyone around it. Sounds horrifying, Charles. Oh, it is.
It sounds absolutely terrifying. Yeah, it's all your enemies. Yeah, I don't know what you're talking about.
This is fun in the sun. This is, this is great fun in the sun. Uh, I think we had a video clip here
of this in action, right? Of course, we're at the beach. Where else would you be? You splash, make a
poison puddle, and as you do that, you know, little, uh, globs of poison go out and, uh, hit the enemies
around you. And this is also marrying the concept of like poison, the, the, the, the theme in Druida of poison,
mm-hmm, and werebear, which has typically been for specifically, uh, uh, werewolf, but now we're,
we're seeing it here too. Druids are, are the master of kind of this hybridization and mixing and matching,
uh, these things. So, so we always love encouraging, you know, you finding ways to mix, mix these up.
Right. All right, uh, enough on Druid. Let's talk about the Necromancer. So Necromancer has, uh,
had some powerful ultimates as well. This is going to be a common theme. A lot of ultimate skills have been
quite powerful recently, uh, in particular Soul Rift and Blood Wave. Now Soul Rift is, uh, a skill
which does everything, right? It does damage, it gives you increased damage, it applies vulnerable,
it gives you resource, uh, gives you barrier, it, uh, restores your potion charges. Yeah. Oh my goodness.
Why not? So, um, we looked at all these things and said, well, we could like just chop down the numbers
on some of these because like almost everyone is playing Soul Rift if you're not playing Blood Wave.
It's like one of those two as a Necromancer. Um, and we decided that the, the best course of action
for Soul Rift is to just kind of reduce some of its functionality. So it will still do all of those
things except generate a barrier. Uh, the barrier generation was giving a little bit too much
survivability, which we thought felt a bit more at home in like the Bone Storm or Blood Wave kind of world,
um, as like kind of a more survivability, uh, ultimate. Right. Uh, Soul Rift will still give
you lots of resource and still, um, increases your damage by just a little bit instead of, uh, a ton.
Uh, but we think that'll bring it, uh, a bit more down to earth and give some other options, uh, like
Army of the Dead and Bone Storm a bit of chances to compete. So overall you would say like it's kind
of moving towards being, its theme is kind of like it's an engine for you, right? It sustains your potions,
it gives you a sense, uh, and that's its big, you know, gameplay niche. Yeah,
rather than being kind of your, uh, defensive tanky, uh, source. Uh, Blood Wave as well has
been kind of the other ultimate skill that most Necromancers have been building around.
Uh, this one just does a ton of damage and a lot of that has come from some of the unique items
that interact with it. Uh, they give, uh, kind of a disproportionate amount of damage output,
uh, an increase to your Blood Wave. Uh, specifically Endira's Memory, which works on your, um, your pants,
your leg armor. Uh, that's a slot which for most characters that don't have a unique item,
uh, is not really an offensive slot. You can't really get a whole lot of bonus damage from that.
And so we're looking to, to say, hey, any unique items that are on, on pants in particular,
we're going to be looking to reduce the, the damage output of there. They'll still have some damage
output, but not quite as much. And so that's where, um, we're looking to reduce the power of Blood Wave
overall is on, on some of those uniques that talk to it. Uh, but of course we've got new things to
play with on the Necromancer. We've got Skeletal Archmages. And so this comes on the new unique,
the Hand of Nas. So the Hand of Nas, uh, new unique gloves, which, uh, if you really want to be playing
a minion build, but you're like, I just want mages, you know, maybe you're really vibing with the,
the Haradric Mage spellcraft theme of the season. Yes.
Um, if you sacrifice both your Warriors and your Golem, and so you are all in on mages,
you get to summon additional mages for every minion that you've sacrificed.
So if you used to have a whole bunch of, you know, bonus, um, Skeletal, uh, uh,
Warriors, you now can get that many more mages. Uh, once mages attack, uh, 25 times,
they get to level up. They can rank up to a Skeletal Archmages. They get a little bit bigger,
they get a little bit of a flashy visual, and the Skeletal Archmages will, uh, deal some bonus
damage. And also whenever they are attacked, they will teleport away to safety because they are,
you know, they got a new skill. When you level up, you learn a new skill. Same thing with Skeletal
Mages. It's just the way it works. Of course. So, um, let's take a look at this in action.
So you've got, um, just four mages here. Of course you're going to be able to have more,
uh, if you really spec into it. And, uh, as enemies come up and attack those mages, uh,
occasionally they will teleport away. Their attacks now can do some, uh, additional burst damage.
And they've got a little, uh, like lightning effect on their hands. And they're a little
bit bigger to show that they are, um, you know, promoted to Archmage status.
So with this unique, I can't actually have my warriors or my golem.
Right.
So now I'm the tank for my mages.
You do need to be tanking for your mages, right? It kind of turns the traditional minion play style
of like, my minions go forward and, and protect me. And it turns it on its head, right?
You have this powerful backline of a lot of mages who do bonus damage. Um, but in, in exchange,
you know, you need to protect them. They can protect themselves a little bit with the, uh,
the teleport away to safety. Uh, but it's going to kind of be on you, the necromancer to,
to be the frontline in this kind of build.
It's pretty awesome.
All right. Next up, we've got the rogue. So the rogue big talk has been, uh, their ultimate skills,
uh, death trap, as, uh, you know, ultimate skills are great. They, they have been, uh,
ultimate and very powerful for quite a while. Uh, rogues, no exception. They've got death trap
has been one of the most powerful builds for kind of two seasons in a row here.
Uh, similar to soul rift in a lot of ways that kind of did a lot of everything.
Um, we, and we also know that it did a ton, ton of damage on its own, right?
Uh, so, and it also had a, uh, unique pants item, the eyes in the dark that really talked to it and
increased its damage output, uh, dramatically. Uh, so much in the line of our philosophy of,
hey, pants armor shouldn't be so ridiculous amount of damage output, even if it is unique.
Uh, we've done some tuning on the eyes in the dark to make sure that death trap is not, uh,
uh, quite as, as explosively damaging as it, as it has been in the past.
Uh, we are looking to buff up, uh, the infiltrators and bursting venoms.
Um, legendary items that talk to poison trap and poison builds and saying,
hey, you know, there's other traps out there. You can play poison trap.
Um, so giving a little bit more support here with those, um, legendary reworks.
And we also have some updates to, um, uh, Eagle Horn.
This is the, the penetrating shot unique, uh, bow.
Uh, just, just some numerical buffs there to make sure it's actually hitting harder
and penetrating shot has a bit more of a, of a reason to use it.
Uh, we know that, uh, kind of ranged rogues have fallen out of favor for a while.
It's been a lot more about melee and I mean, death trap is even a melee kind of skill.
Yeah.
Um, and we know that, uh, players love to play ranged rogue as well.
So we want to make sure that we give a little bit more support to that to enable it.
Um, for those who do like melee play styles, but maybe not trap, uh, you might like flurry.
And if so, we have got a, uh, great unique, uh, coming next season.
The death mask of Nirmatruk.
I definitely pronounced that correct.
Um, so you can now over exert yourself while casting flurry.
Well, that's a weird thing to say.
What does that mean?
It does mean that you spend your life total if you don't have enough energy.
Mm.
So energy, that's not a problem anymore.
You have your whole life total to work with.
Yeah.
Uh, so you can keep on casting flurry, but when it does cost you your life total,
when you're kind of overexerted in this state, it's going to stack up above.
It's going to increase the, the attack speed of flurry,
and it's going to increase its damage output for five seconds.
So you really want to be in this kind of overexerted state.
It doesn't actually do anything if you're not overexerting.
Yeah.
So you really want to make sure that you're getting to the state.
I love how this kind of, um, changes up some of your,
like how you think about your build.
You don't necessarily want a lot of resource regeneration.
Right.
You want more health regen.
Uh, cause if you have too much resource,
then maybe you're not even getting into the state as often as you'd like.
Let's take a look at this in action.
I actually really love this clip of the, uh, the rogue just going super fast, right?
So they sneak in and as they're stacking up, you can see they've got like no resource.
They go hyper fast.
This is, is such a, a fast attacking skill when it's all stacked up.
Oh my goodness.
But of course, the faster you attack, the faster your life total drains.
Yep.
And you know, if you're really low, it's not going to kill you by doing this.
You just won't be able to cast it there, but it does mean you're on very low life
and any stray attack might take you out if you're not super careful with it.
I will raise a flag for those of you curious about trying this out.
It's called a death mask for a reason.
Yeah.
It might not necessarily be their death.
It might be yours.
So be a little careful.
But on the positive side,
you do get a look like an anime character zooming around like crazy.
Like, look at that.
Absolutely.
Definitely.
Uh, definitely, uh, hardcore players beware with this one.
Yep.
Um, you know, might be a little risky for you.
All right.
Uh, we've got the Sorceress next.
So the Sorceress has been, um, definitely one of our top builds this season, I would say,
in Lightning Spear.
And, uh, I think one of the, the, the big talking points around Sorceress for a while has been
Lightning Spear.
Uh, a lot of players have felt like that is the only or best way to play Sorc.
For a number of seasons now.
And it's not just been just one season here.
And one of the reasons for that, I'd say the main reason is that Lightning Spear baseline is
pretty bad.
Like if you just get the skill on its own with nothing else, it doesn't really do a whole lot
of damage.
Uh, but then you get a Splintering Energy Legendary and suddenly it goes from one to a hundred real
quick.
Oh, yes.
That, that Legendary aspect is, is like one of the most powerful in terms of like how much
percentage gain does it give the skill in question.
Splintering Energy is like way far above, uh, really where we want Legendary aspects to be.
And that kind of speaks to this, this outlier concept we've been talking about where when
you have one particular source of power that is disproportionately valuable, like a key passive
that scales crazy or a Splintering Energy Legendary that that's the only thing that matters,
right?
Yeah.
Is, is that maximizing the damage of this one thing is the only thing that matters.
We find that that leads to some of these outlier situations and it's also just not as fun.
Right.
Like nothing else in your build mattered.
It's just about that one, uh, effect, whether it be a Legendary or a key passive.
And you find that there's better build variety and healthier class balance when that power is
spread out among as many different sources that you might want as possible rather than concentrated
so intensely in one.
Right.
And so this was definitely one of the most egregious examples, I'd say, of, of, uh, concentrating the power in a
single spot in that Splintering Energy, uh, aspect.
So, uh, with that in mind, we've taken, uh, the baseline Lightning Spear and buffed up its damage
rather substantially.
Uh, but of course the Splintering Energy has, uh, dramatically been reduced in effectiveness.
So overall we still think the Lightning Spear builds are going to be, uh, brought down quite a
bit because they were quite far above everyone else.
Uh, they also definitely relied on some of the overpower changes, uh, or they relied on overpower to
really, uh, get into the highest levels of pit pushing.
And so that's, um, overpower is obviously a little bit weaker in this season.
So we think that'll bring it down a bit.
Um, in an exchange, we're looking at, at buffing up some of the other builds available to, to Sork.
Uh, specifically with Burning, uh, as we, one of the, the Burning, uh, key passive,
the Combustion key passive was one of those that was kind of uncapped scaling.
It wasn't necessarily problematic, but maybe that was really just because Lightning Spear crowded
it all out. Um, same with like Enlightenment, kind of crowding up those options.
Uh, we have put a cap on that, like we, we've said with the philosophy of, of making sure that
no individual power source eclipses all others. Uh, but with that in mind, we did look and say,
well, hey, this might be a little bit of a nerf to some other Burning builds like Firewall
or Incinerate. And so we've just done like a 25-ish percent, uh, baseline buff to those, uh,
Burning skills just to make sure they can, uh, kind of, uh, be compensated for that.
Uh, similar with Enlightenment, that was another one of the key passives that kind of blew past our
power budget. So we've done a bit of rebalancing there. Um, but also we've got, um, a new unique,
uh, one of my favorites, uh, huge Hydras.
Yes. So this is the...
Chad has been very excited for this.
Oh, really?
They saw huge Hydras on the front.
Huge Hydras.
I'm just like, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's this? What's this?
Yes. So we've got the Ophidian Iris. This is a, an ancestral unique amulet. Uh, and here,
uh, Hydra gets the core skill tag. So, um, it'll benefit from a lot of your core skill bonuses.
And it'll always summon a three-headed Hydra on, rather than, um, even if you had more heads,
if you had like plus Hydra heads, uh, you're still only going to get three. That's the kind
of the baseline number. But for each head that you would have had above three, the Hydra goes larger
and deals, uh, like 100% more damage per additional head. And so these big heads will also, uh,
do splash damage rather than just a single target and, and hitting one enemy. They kind of explode
on impact just like they're shooting fireballs. Yes.
Um, and so this is going to turn, um, you know, your Hydra from like a lot of spammy little tiny
hits into individual bigger hits with big Hydra heads. So it's no longer about how many heads can
get on my Hydra. It's about how big can I make my baby Hydra. Yes. Excellent. Um, so it'll, it'll scale
up with its damage for every additional head that you got. And of course this has, uh, an inherent
affects that casted Hydras do have plus two heads, which, um, so you already have a bit of built-in
multiplier on the, on the emulate itself. Uh, so we've got a side-by-side comparison here, right? So on the
left here, we've got the kind of baseline. You've got four Hydra heads. They're, you know, they're, they're
fine. They're there. But after, if you really build up lots of bonus Hydra heads, you're only going to get
three, but they're going to, they're going to be much bigger than, than you, the character and,
uh, you know, can, can be as big as some of those big elites running around the screen. And of course
with, uh, splashing and exploding, uh, fire attacks, uh, it should be, um, a lot more appealing. Um,
we've also taken a look at, at updating some, some other things on Hydra. We removed its baseline
mana cost, um, increased its lucky hit chance, and also done some other modifications to Conjuration
and Hydra legendaries, uh, just to make sure that like kind of a Hydra build really makes a lot of
sense and, and is able to be competitive. So really love to hear feedback on, in the, the PTR about,
um, how these kind of, uh, builds land. And last but not least, uh, we've got the Spiritborn.
So the Spiritborn, uh, has been probably one of the classes that's been furthest behind,
I'd say, in terms of, uh, on the current live season. And so we're definitely looking at,
um, I think they're going to be one of the biggest beneficiaries of the basic skill rebalancing work
that we did where we looked at every basic skill and, and doubled or tripled the baseline values of
a lot of them. Um, but in exchange, some of the scalers on legendaries and uniques, um, we, we adjust
those downward a little bit. Um, the net result is still that basic skill builds will be better than
before. And I think Spiritborn is going to be one of the biggest beneficiaries of that. Additionally,
we've also got an update to the deflection aspect with, uh, Razor Wings build. Uh, previously,
this was one of those legendaries that didn't really have a home. It dealt like a percentage
of counterattacks damage and counterattack does not do damage. So a percent of zero is zero.
Yeah. Um, so now it's going to increase the Razor Wings itself damage when you reflect them with this
deflection kind of gameplay. And so, uh, just a little bit more kind of multiplicative damage support
for Razor Wings build. Um, following with the theme of ultimate skills, uh, on all classes, as well
being kind of a little, um, too strong, the hunter ultimate, the jaguar ultimate, has been the, the
ultimate on Spiritborn, uh, since its launch that really every Spiritborn player has used. I think like
something like 90 plus percent of Spiritborn players are using the hunter, uh, currently. And, uh,
that's great that you're having a lot of fun with it, but it's also means that there's other options
that aren't really being explored. It's kind of taking up all the space in the, the, the build
variety. And so one of the reasons for that is that, uh, the hunter, uh, allows, it resets itself.
If you cast it and then kill an enemy, it's going to reset itself and it can kind of chain reset. Um,
and, uh, the chance of chain resetting reduces every time it does. And so it just kind of like
feels bad whenever you're like, oh, I guess I ran out of luck and now I have to wait. Yeah. Um,
we found that to be like one ex kind of degenerately powerful for anything that triggers on when you
cast an ultimate. Uh, but also it was just not fun when you kind of failed to, to, to get that reset.
Yeah. And so we're looking at reworking the exact mechanics of the way the hunter reset works. So
it'll still have that like kind of cooldown reduction theme, uh, but it won't be quite as feast or famine as
it was in the past. Uh, we've also got a new unique item. Uh, this one is the, uh, Balaton's, uh, Maxiltal.
I might've mispronounced that. Uh, Maxiltal. I literally looked up how to pronounce this this morning and
I, I, I tried. It's a tricky one, Charles. It's a very tricky one. Uh, so this, uh, works with, uh, poison and
thorns built kind of hybridizing those two together. So, uh, attacks against close enemies. When you're,
when you're attacking close up, uh, you're, you're up close and personal, you're going to do bonus a percent of
your thorns damage, but as poisoning over three seconds. So you get a kind of a free way to apply poisoning here.
But if you've also been hit recently and you've retaliated with your thorns, then that poisoning
damage is going to be increased even further. So it really allows you to convert your thorns damage
into offense. Um, and it does even reward you for, for actually getting hit with that thorns. Uh,
but a lot of this is going to come in that poisoning damage when you're, when you're hitting the enemies
up close and personal. Yeah. I love how this unique really takes the core concept of thorns,
which is you must be hit, but still it like empowers you very intensely in terms of your
offense by leaning into that, which is pretty cool. Yeah. It definitely solves that problem where
previous thorns builds were kind of, we were hesitant to make pure thorns of like just build
thorns and nothing else to be too powerful because then you just walk in and you AFK and everything
dies and that's not necessarily fun gameplay. And so I think this does a really good job of, of, um,
straddling the line of active and passive gameplay that, that thorns players, uh, would really want.
Totally.
Totally. So that's a lot. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. There's a lot of class changes coming in the PTR. And so
we'd love to hear all the feedback you have around, you know, do these unique items and the legendary
reworks and the other balance changes, are these builds good, right? Can you play that, that Hydra
Sork, um, is it, you know, is it reasonable to play in Torment 4, uh, at the highest levels when you
have like the really maxed out stuff and every point along the progression, um, and not just that build,
every build that we're, that I talked about here. Uh, we're also really looking to make sure that we
get feedback on the basic skill, uh, update. Like I said, we touched every single basic skill in the
game. There might be some outliers still, some things that are a little too strong, a little too weak.
Um, and as we're going to be doing similar passes and looking at other, ask other kind of categories
of skills on the skill tree, we'd love any kind of feedback on, um, kind of exactly where they land so
that we can help and inform future balancing as well. Uh, and finally, uh, just wanted to, uh,
make sure that, uh, we really are focusing on, on kind of shifting up that very top of the meta.
I talked a lot about some nerfs to the, the really over-performing builds, uh, specifically
overpower, uh, because we do want to make sure that season nine, you don't feel like, oh, it's all
the same builds all again at the top of the meta, uh, for the third season in a row. We, we really don't
want that to be the case. We want to make sure there's new options for, for players, uh, who really want
to push the limit of their character and it's not just the same thing over and over again.
Totally. Wow. Well, Charles, take a bow. That was, uh, incredible section. I mean,
players are going to have a ton to chew on in the PTR. That is, uh, an absolute smattering of content.
Are you surprised he pronounced everything correctly? I mean, you nailed it.
Yeah, I was ready to razz me on the spear for an unique, and I'm like, oh, man's, man's been practicing.
That's fantastic. Uh, so yeah, patch notes and the blog do hit following the stream. So if you missed
anything in any of the sections, we will have those available following the streams. You can get in
and really get into the nitty gritties of all those changes. Um, but we do have some more changes
still coming that are going to affect, uh, the entire game. So Aislinn, I know we've got some
systems. We kind of teased it. Dan sort of touched it at the start of the stream, but, uh, we can finally
get into it. What do you have for us? Yeah. Let's talk about systems, guys. So the first one I want to
talk about is the night, uh, or excuse me, the seasonal activity variety. That's the next one.
Um, so something we saw in season eight was we added, um, seasonal currency to the layer bosses,
and it was for the season of the boss, uh, which we really ended up liking. Uh, the reason we like it
a ton is because it touches all parts of the game. Like you need to go to a bunch of different places to
actually get layer keys. And so if layer bosses in the end game are a thing that provide access,
access to seasonal progression, that kind of naturally disseminates out to the entire game
experience, which we really, really liked. So we actually want to keep that going forward. Uh,
and we'd like to use that, uh, on top of any other ways that the player can earn, uh, seasonal reputation
or seasonal currency in a given season. Um, and, uh, the same is true, uh, not just in Torment, but across
the entire game through elites and bosses granting seasonal reputation. Whenever you kill any elites or any boss
in the game in season nine, uh, you are going to earn seasonal reputation. And this is tying directly
into that problem we were having where, you know, we felt really pressured to go to Apparition Incursion.
Um, we, we love the seasonal content and, uh, we love the Horadric strong rooms and we love all the new
amazing nightmare dungeon updates, but we want to also want to make sure that if you end up finding yourself
in Helltide or in a stronghold, because you felt like it, you're actually earning progress and the game's rewarding you for
playing it basically. This makes me so happy because I'm a very scatterbrained player. I'm always, you know,
I'm going to do this activity, then this one, then this one, but now I get to feel good all the time.
Yeah, that's, that's the hope. So thank you for that. That's awesome.
Of course. Um, yeah, so that's the, that's the hope with this update. And I just want to reiterate,
um, there are still going to be really powerful and good ways to earn seasonal reputation and currency
specifically through interacting with the season. These are on top of all of that other stuff so
that you can just go do a bunch of cool stuff. So yeah, that's that. And let's talk about,
let's talk more about, uh, the, uh, the nightmare sigils, uh, and what's coming with that. So we talked
a little bit about it when Dan was talking about this and I actually want to preface this section with
something that's not listed here, but I think you guys might want to know. Uh, you can now teleport to
nightmare dungeons from inside a nightmare dungeon. Uh, we wanted to make that update.
It's just a quality of life change because this was season of the nightmare dungeon. So there you go.
It's going to be a lot smoother to go from nightmare dungeon to nightmare dungeon, uh, in season nine and
going forward in Diablo four, very happy about that. Cause it was kind of annoying to like have to
leave the dungeon and then go to the next one, but that's no longer a thing. Uh, okay. That out of the way,
let's talk about these new affixes and what's so cool about them. So, uh, in live right now,
there were only, uh, two positive affixes in the game. There was like an experience affix and a gold
affix and that ended up getting pared down over time. And we kind of wanted to take a step back
and be like, how can we inject a lot more depth and ways for you to like find what you're actually
looking for in a nightmare dungeon. And so what we decided and landed on was we wanted to make a lot
more positive affixes and we wanted to assign a rarity system to them so that sometimes when you
crafted or found a nightmare dungeon sigil, you'd get really rare ones that were really powerful.
And other times you'd get, uh, you know, normal ones, but, uh, ones that might give you like a specific
kind of reward, which can be really useful. Um, and so here, for example, we have the horagric materials
reserve. Uh, this one gives you a smattering of, uh, different resources that you might need. So if you
find yourself low on forgotten souls or other kinds of resources, you can specifically go to
this nightmare dungeon and stock up on that stuff. And we have some other affixes like that,
for example, specifically gems or different kinds of gems, which also helps you stock up on,
uh, whichever kinds of gems you might be needing. Um, and then there are, of course,
still like the experience one and the gold one and a lot of other, uh, miscellaneous affixes,
uh, that will just, you know, hopefully be really fun to just go in and poke around and pick one,
which ones are the best for you. Um, and another thing I really wanted to call out is that we've
specifically wanted to avoid penalizing specific elements or builds in negative nightmare dungeon
affixes. So something we saw, uh, earlier in Diablo's development or excuse me, Diablo 4 being live,
um, was there were negative affixes that would say, uh, you know, you deal less, uh, shadow damage or
whatever. And if your build was a shadow build, that kind of didn't feel great. Um, and so we wanted
to make sure that all of these negative affixes were more agnostic of speaking directly to your build,
but still provided the challenge. Um, and so with, with these two changes together, we're really hoping
that we're going to see a lot more variety and depth in actually, uh, engaging with nightmare dungeons,
and that they're not going to feel too frictioned or you're not going to find a nightmare dungeon that
just doesn't, that feels like it's telling you, no, you're not allowed to play me. Like we don't
want that happening. Um, and again, this is a permanent update to the game. We've done this because it is,
uh, you know, a season very heavily focused on nightmare dungeons, but which was like the perfect
time to do this. And now we're super stoked that it's going to be going forward. Um, and we want to hear
what you have to say about it. You know that, like I said, there's a lot of different affixes. Uh, let
us know how they feel, run through these dungeons, let us know how interacting with the mechanics in
them works, and if you like it or not. Uh, and we'll be able to take that feedback and make the system
even better for season nine's launch. Yeah, that was actually a question that Addiction had, uh, in
Twitch chat, which is, are these dungeon changes permanent? And so for this section, all these changes
that Azen speak to are permanent and the same thing with Escalating Nightmares and Horagic Strongrooms,
those are going to persist, uh, beyond the 2-3-0 PTR in season nine. So, uh, and then everything
Azen's getting to now, that's all going to affect, uh, the, the Eternal and Seasonal and will be
permanent. So, yeah, super nice, super good changes. Yes, super excited about it. All right, cool. Yeah,
I think we have an asset here, uh, kind of showing off what you might be able to find in a nightmare
dungeon. So that nifty little purpley mirror thingy is a Horagic artifact, which is, uh, a part of one of
the new affixes that you'll actually find when, uh, venturing into nightmare dungeons. And of course,
our rogue is getting rid of this pesky blood blister. Uh, so, yeah, can't wait for you to try it all out.
It's going to be fun. Next up, we have, uh, oh, drum roll, please. Thank you. I'm so excited. I'm very,
very happy and excited and proud to be able to say we are increasing the quality of items per torment
tier. And what this means is when you go into torment two or then further into three or four,
you are going to find more ancestral items. You are going to find more ancestral items from all sources.
This includes layer boss drops. When you go and fight a layer boss in a higher torment tier,
you are going to have a better chance at finding, uh, ancestrals when you climb those torments.
This is true throughout the world when things are just dropping randomly. This is true in the pit.
This is, this is true everywhere. Um, we really like this change. Uh, we think that it rewards you for,
uh, ascending the torment tier in a very impactful, you know, like we say, punch you in the face kind of
way. Um, and it's not so intense that it feels required though to go to higher torments. And that's
something we, uh, also really want to make sure we get right because we want to ensure that we're
enriching the progression journey for all players, regardless of where you are in the game right now.
Um, and so again, you know, we keep saying this, but this is a, uh, going to be a test realm. So please go on,
try this out, see if you can feel the difference and, you know, can you feel the difference? Can you not feel
the difference? Do you like the difference between these different torment tiers, uh, and the, the loot quality changes that are occurring between them?
Uh, and that's just another topic that we'd love to hear your feedback on.
All right. And with that said, let's just talk about a bit of more miscellaneous reward economy stuff.
Uh, so here there's some, uh, more miscellaneous feedback that we got from season eight that we
want to just improve on for the game so that everyone just has more fun. Um, we hear you guys about
legendary rune drop rates. We know that those were too low. Uh, so we've just increased the chance
across the whole game, uh, to get that back to a point where it feels like if you are playing a lot
and you really are trying to make progress towards like crafting a mythic, that's feasible. Um, another
thing where, again, the big reward moments, uh, we want to make sure that when you actually run a
tribute of harmony, harmony, it feels like a big burst. Like it's like, oh yes, okay, cool. This is a lot of runes.
This is fantastic. Um, and so now if you really do want to find a lot of those runes, tributes of
harmony are going to be a really good bet. We also kind of just want to inject identity into under city
tributes in general that they now all just drop a rune always. So now just in general going to the
under city, you're going to find more runes than you certainly would have before. Um, and that just
applies to all different kinds of tributes. Um, the whisper cache resource increase one is actually
split among three different whisper caches. So we were finding that the gold whisper cache,
the materials whisper cache, and the, uh, gem fragment whisper cache just weren't really giving
you enough, uh, for the opportunity cost against the other kinds. So we just bumped up how much those
are giving you of their respective thing pretty substantially. You can also now actually find
whole gems inside gem fragment, uh, uh, whisper caches. Uh, and it's only a chance for some of the, uh,
good ones. Like for example, I think there's actually a very small chance to find a grand
gem now in a, uh, gem cache, which is a lot of gem fragments. So it's not a very high chance.
You gotta stop making my day. That sounds so cool. Oh my gosh.
Yeah, let's go. Um, and oh yes, this is one of my personal favorites. So we saw that the, uh, jewelers of
sanctuary had adopted some wanderer unfriendly practices and their caches were perhaps a bit too expensive.
Uh, and we have decided to, you know, crack down on that and, uh, make sure that they are,
they are being more friendly to our wanderers. Uh, so now here we have, uh, these different
jewelry cache types, their cost has been significantly reduced. Uh, and on top of that,
not only has their cost been significantly reduced, but they're going to give you, uh, quite a bit more,
uh, actual jewelry. So with the gem fragments increases, uh, or rather like different sources of,
uh, getting more gem fragments and the reduced cost and the increased stuff from the caches,
they should be more lucrative. Uh, and finally talking about gems, we have, uh, increased the
amount of gems you're going to be getting from infernal hordes as well. You know, again, punch you
in the face at this point. I'm sorry if I've given you a bloody nose, but you know, that's lots of face
punching today. There's a through line in the stream. Yeah. Poison puddles are rated M for excitement.
There you go. Um, yeah, but, uh, thank you guys for listening to the systems updates. Uh, there's a
lot to unpack here and these kinds of updates are sometimes a little challenging to test within a PTR
environment because you're getting like all these boosts, uh, and it only lasts a short period of time.
But if this kind of stuff interests you, please, by all means, test it out, let us know what you think,
give us all the feedback, uh, on it you want because everything is just super valuable for us
to tweak it to make it even more awesome. Yeah. Like as Dan said, uh, or sorry, Dan, as I'm citing Dan,
uh, one of the things he said is like, now's the time that we can turn the knobs and really juice
things up. So definitely go in and like, take your time with a lot of these changes. Some of them might
not feel, you know, impactful at first, but like really get a feel for how things have shifted because
there are so many different components in this PTR that it's gonna, you know, there's a ton of different,
uh, influences from all the different areas of the game. So that's really exciting, Aislinn. I'm
super excited to check those things out, get some more jeweler caches. Yeah, that'll be great. Yeah.
Um, but yeah, so the 2-3-0 PTR, so some just general reminders for everyone watching.
It's gonna be exclusively on PC Battle.net and it'll be available from May 27th until June 3rd.
So get in, test it out, please give us your feedback. Uh, the PTR forums, uh, the Diablo 4 PTR forums will be open.
Those will be the, that'll be the best place for you to drop your feedback. Of course, we will be monitoring
our socials as usual, um, but we will be definitely looking into the, to the forums to get most of the
feedback there. Uh, the PTR boost will be available right outside of Kyovishad. Uh, Merak, our favorite
dancing demons there. Merak, he's kind of been getting fit for the summer. His, his offerings are
so diversified this time around. Like you can really segment out between seasonal currency, into the
different like item caches. Like there's a ton, a lot of great custom, uh, boosts that you can get from
Merak. So he is there, he's in Kyovishad. He's happy to see you as always. And, uh, yeah, give us
your feedback on the PTR forums. Uh, we're really looking forward to it, uh, but definitely get in
there and test and give us all your feedback. And with that, that brings us to our Q and A portion
of the stream. So hopefully you've been dropping your questions in Twitch chat. We're really excited
to get into it. But first off, we do want to take a moment, uh, to address our first question,
which is what are we potentially doing about Reliquary? So this is our first stream since season eight
Reliquary. It was our team's first big swing at changing the battle passes in a big way,
you know, bringing in different rewards, more enhanced rewards, giving some more choice to
the players. We have heard your overwhelming feedback. We know that this is a, is a system
with some mixed feelings. And so we are looking, the team is working very hard in the background.
We are looking to bring some more things into the Reliquary, um, to really give you some of that value.
And, you know, that's something we've been talking about a lot. Thank you all for the feedback on it.
Uh, we've been reading that, you know, across forums, the socials ever since the season launched.
Um, and do note, we do have an event Reliquary that is coming up around the corner. So in a couple
weeks, oh, and pretty soon, you'll get another event Reliquary to dig your teeth into. But it is
something that the team has noted. Uh, we don't have a timeline on it, but it is something that we will,
uh, implement in the future. So thank you again for that. Uh, additionally with season eight, we also had
the Berserk collaboration, which like Aislinn, I know you've got the, the brand of sacrifice on right now.
Like you're a huge Berserk fan. I became a fan once we started the IP collab. It's been really fun
seeing all the like guts and Griffiths running around in game. Uh, but again, we have heard
your feedback on, uh, on that IP collaboration. Um, and we've taken that into account. And for those
of you that know the roadmap, we do have another IP collab, uh, coming down the pipe in the future. So
we want to take that feedback from the Berserk collab and really integrate that into the future
offerings so that we can, you know, better diversify and change up some of the ways that you access
those, um, those, um, pieces of content from the IP collab. So again, thank you very much for your
feedback. We do really appreciate it. You know, ongoing game dev is an iterative process and the
community is a very big part of that. So we very much appreciate it. Yeah. Thank you for that. Um,
and yeah, with that, let's get into Q and A. Okay. So thank you. Shout out to the community team for
grabbing all these questions. What are we going to start off with? All right. Renata Cain, this one
may be, I might send this one to Dan first. Uh, will you be able to find Horadric strongholds inside
Escalating Nightmares? Yeah, uh, you absolutely will. Uh, Escalating Nightmares are nightmare dungeons. Uh,
and so any feature that you could find in a nightmare dungeon, including the affixes we talked about,
uh, and also including Horadric strongrooms will, will appear in that flow. Awesome. Love that.
Uh, the rudder, these new dungeon changes will be available, uh, in the eternal realm at the start
of next season? Uh, yes. The, uh, nightmare dungeon affix changes. Um, I think I, I might need to throw
it to Dan. I know they're permanent additions to the game. So yeah, they should be available in internal.
They should all be available in internal. Fantastic. Yeah. Fantastic. Uh, one other question. I didn't
have this, uh, it didn't catch the name as it was flying past, but people were asking, where is mouse and
keyboard on console? That is still coming with season nine. However, because the 2.3L PTR is exclusive to
PC, we're not going to test console changes. However, that is still coming. So fear, fear not. Uh, wow.
Okay. I have to read this question just cause of the username. BigDaddyDen76. Uh, this one's for you,
Charles. Okay. With Soul Rift not generating barrier, how is Necromancer going to gain defense?
Uh, there's lots of different options for Necromancer to gain defense. Um, you've got,
um, some, some new options in the, uh, you know, the seasonal Horadric, um, uh, spellcraft. Uh, you've got
Fortify through some of the blood magic. Um, you've got other ways of generating barrier, but not just
on Soul Rift. They've got, um, some passive and some other ways of generating barrier from legendaries.
And you may just need to, you know, access some of the, the, uh, defensive legendary options that are
out there, which, uh, typically been very underutilized just because you had other ways of, of solving that
defense. Uh, we still think Soul Rift will be pretty appealing because it has, um, you know, like a lot of
energy, uh, resource gain. Um, but if you really want pure defense, then maybe look at some of the blood
skills, maybe look at bone storm instead, which still has a large damage reduction component
attached to it as well. Right. Fantastic. Uh, Mippy, are there any updates on tempering and masterworking?
Hmm. Yeah. So tempering and masterworking is something that we have been talking about internally.
Uh, you know, we don't have anything to share exactly yet about how we would want to tweak the system.
Um, so hang tight, but I can say in terms of a quality of life update, uh, in 2-2-2,
so the patch coming out in season 8, uh, we are actually going to be updating the amount of non-gold,
non-obdiscite resource and materials that it costs to masterwork, uh, from rank 1 to 4 and on the reset.
And the reason why is because we were seeing that people that were getting pretty far into the end game
would end up, like, effectively, um, deprecating the need for the gold and even potentially the
obdiscite and then getting blocked by those other resources. But that was never actually the intent
of the system. It was there. Those resource costs were there to like, uh, slow you down basically,
or just rather friction you in other ways, um, and, and tax those resources never to be like the
primary thing that blocks you. And so we don't want that to happen. So we've pulled back pretty
significantly on how much that actually costs. Yeah. Uh, but beyond that, stay tuned as we keep
filtering through feedback and please, please keep giving us feedback. Uh, that's really great.
And like, I know we've all been masterwork blocked at a specific point, so anything to reduce friction
in that system is, uh, is pretty great. Uh, Liam, this one's for you. Scroll of Wisdom. With a system like
Horadric Spells being this awesome, are you looking to maybe make it a permanent part of the game? I already
feel sad knowing it's going to leave the game for the next season's power. So I can't specifically speak
on that, but what I will say is nothing is ever truly gone because we are developers. We have access
to everything, right? So as we, and this is a game that will continue to evolve and evolve. So the team
hasn't talked about it. I can't say anything definitive, but you know, we love all the seasonal stuff we
create and yeah, who knows for the future. Yeah. That's something we've seen in previous seasons where like,
uh, back way back in season two, when we first did the vampiric powers, we
brought some of them back as, um, some of the more popular ones back as unique items.
Um, once again, we're not committing to any particular bringing back, but, uh, it's always
on our radar and that's why we love hearing feedback about the things that really resonate
with players and then that can help us to design future systems, whether it be future seasonal or
future, um, kind of those permanent systems as well. Uh, we're always listening to that and, and it's
always on the table to bring them back, the ones that really resonate with players. Nice.
Uh, party cannon, 1990, very fun name. Uh, will there be, will there in the future be a possibility
that the nightmare sigils can have active whispers shown on them?
Mm. Yeah. That's another thing that we've seen a lot of folks talk about.
Uh, it's, it's something we would, we're interested in exploring that space, uh, because it's a really
fun and kind of a natural connection. Uh, right now for season nine, that's not something that's going to be,
uh, directly in the season, but we do look to, you know, make these kinds of changes going forward
pretty consistently. So, and if that's something you feel strongly about, please keep letting us
know and, and we will, uh, we'll see what we can do. Absolutely. Uh, this one, Charles, I feel like
I already know what you're going to say to this. Uh, cop Mando, will there, will there be any more
balance changes for the current season? Uh, for season eight, uh, the current season that is live.
Oh, actually. Yeah. Yeah. Uh, currently the, no, there's no plans for any more balance changes on
season eight. Um, the, the season of bosses that's currently live on the game. Uh, we've updated our
seasonal, uh, balance cadence a little bit. Um, so now starting in season eight and going forward, even
into season nine, we're going to have, you know, the PTR before the season. That's when we do kind of
our initial batch, like, Hey, these are the balance changes we're looking at. We take in a lot of the
feedback from the PTR and then we iterate on it. And we, we, when it goes live, the season goes live,
we, we say, Hey, here's the live season. Uh, we'll take the immediate feedback from that. If there's
any kind of progression, uh, breakers, things that are really outlier things that we kind of missed or,
you know, an interaction that, oops, that wasn't intended. And we'll try to make a rapid reaction
within the first week or two of a season to, to bring it, um, you know, bring it down to earth or, or
to, to bring some of those builds that were really underperforming our mark and bring those up a
little bit. Uh, but after that point, we're, our intention is to really let the season ride, right?
Once, once you're about two weeks into the season, you've, you've already committed some time into
your build. You've invested in your character and we really want to respect that time investment.
And we don't want to come in and say, Oh, just kidding. We're going to dramatically change the meta
on you right after you've already done all that investment. We just know that's going to feel bad for
everyone involved. And so we've really committed to making fast, rapid reactions right after that
season launch within a week or two, and then letting it ride from there, um, until the end of
the season, until the next season when we kind of repeat the cycle again. Yeah. Honestly, it's like,
I'm really glad of the way we do it too, because like even for season eight, having it be a bit of
a shorter season, it would be so rough to, you know, you're like, okay, I've got these two months with,
you know, with my build and with these boss powers. So then to have, you know, almost like the rug pulled,
um, halfway through and being able to, uh, you know, really get into the nitty gritties of it
and stick with that build. So, yeah. And that gives us, uh, as developers, uh, and like designers
looking at this data and thinking about these balance changes, it allows us to kind of take
our focus off season eight and focus more on season nine. And so, you know, we're going to be putting
out higher quality balance changes and higher quality releases, um, by kind of moving on from a season to
focus on the next one earlier. That just gives us more time to look at that data and really deliver high
quality releases season over season. So the little plug I'm going to put, please play the PTR because
we're all a bunch of nerds. And I promise you when you're playing the PTR, we are watching and we are
just reading all the things being said. And it is so fun and meaningful to us to see people reacting
and giving us new ways to improve the things we've made. Oh, absolutely. 100 percent. 110 percent.
100, 150. We will be reading your feedback. Do not worry about that. Uh, Kuroi Nekamata. Uh, I think Liam,
this will be, uh, it could be one for you, but maybe for the whole team. Uh, would you consider
the possibility that one can disable the effects of other players or at least dim them down so that
one is not always flashed when IE Sorcs, like four Sorcs are running around? And I could see that with
the, uh, the, uh, the powers coming in this season, they are so bright and visual that, uh,
yeah, it's gonna be a busy screen. It's probably a bit, the Herodric spells are pretty insane. And I know,
like we've had earthquake barbarians running around covering the ground with, well, broken ground.
Don't do. Yeah. So, uh, this is definitely things we're considering. Like we all, you know, play the
game and we play in parties. So we know what it's like when everything is just cluttered and insane.
Uh, I can't speak to broadly everything. I've heard bits and pieces. You could talk about that,
Charles or Aislinn, but I know with the Herodric spells, we are making use of some tech to do that
on some of the powers, such as with the pets, the cosmic anomalies. You're not going to see a hundred cosmic
anomalies floating and going everywhere. They're going to be kind of dimmed out very similar to
like the, uh, necromancer minions. We'll be using that kind of thing for them. Yeah. This is a kind of
overarching pain point that, uh, I think surfaces from time to time, which is very reasonable and fair.
And it's something that the team considers, especially with every new release, uh, the Herodric
spellcraft. I'm glad we're doing that. Um, and it's, it's, uh, you know, it's something that they,
they take into with a lot of consideration and they want to protect the visual clarity of the game.
Uh, but they also want to make sure that people can see the things they want to see. Uh, so if there
are certain things that crop up that you find particularly egregious in that way, especially
during the PTR, please play the PTR, uh, let us know and we can get that information to the team
and we can, we can talk about it. Oh yeah. I got a question here from Airsoft Daniel, uh,
at Diablo, what changes will be made to reliquaries in season nine to provide more value to paying
players? Uh, so kind of similar to what I addressed at the start of the stream, we do have some changes
coming in to get some more content into reliquaries. Um, it's unclear as to whether or not that's going
to be hitting in season nine. It will be in the future. So season nine is probably too soon for
those changes to hit. Um, however, we are looking to inject more of that content into the reliquaries
moving forward. So it's definitely something to look out, to look out for probably not season nine,
but definitely in the future. And I think we've got time for one last question. Let's see.
Um, ice panther, uh, this one's for you, Charles. Are you bringing out any more new items,
ancestral or mythics into the new season? Uh, so for the new season, we're going to be releasing one
new unique item per class. The ones we highlighted on stream here. Uh, no more, um, uh, there's no
additional items, uh, unique or legendaries that we didn't talk about. Um, but there will be some new,
uh, relatively new legendary effects because we did some substantial reworks of, you know,
we basically said, Hey, this was something that talked to grizzly rage was my main example. And we
just kind of completely changed its effect. So in, in some way, though, those are kind of new,
um, but they don't, uh, they're not brand new in terms of, um, like, uh, a brand new legendary to
collect. And we didn't go over those reworked legendaries explicitly on the stream, but they
are going to be testable in the PTR. They'll be testable in PTR. They'll be in the patch notes
blog once, uh, this is done. There just was like a handful and because they were kind of reworks,
um, we're naturally limited on time. This stream is already going quite a while.
So we wanted to make sure that, that we, you know, there are more class balance changes and more
content, um, than we even talked about here. So make sure you check out the blog afterwards for
all those details. Absolutely. And that brings us to the end of our, the Q and A portion of the
stream, which brings us to the end of the stream. So yeah, if you're still watching, thank you for
sticking with us. This one has been a beefy stream for sure. Uh, patch notes and the PTR blog are
going to be hitting following this stream. It is a very, very substantial blog. So we will have all
localized languages available early next week. Um, but you can check those out when those do go
live. Uh, the PTR is going to be available from May 27th to June, June 3rd on PC Battle.net. I want
to give a huge thank you to all the developers that have been here today. Dan coming in all the way
from Albany. Thank you for hanging with us this whole time. It's been really great hanging out with
you and getting to chat the new season. Um, and to all of you at home, thank you for tuning in. Um,
like Aislinn said to start the stream, we love that you played Diablo 4. We love being a part of this
process and you guys are a very big part of that. Uh, thank you to our production crew.
There's a ton of hands that, uh, that work behind the scenes to make these streams possible. They
work very tirelessly. Um, so thank you to them for helping bring, uh, these streams to life.
And yeah, we will see you all for the 230 PTR. We'll see you in Sanctuary. Hell yes. Oh, and stick
around. Sorry. Stick around following the stream because we will have the Diablo creator. Uh, we're going to be
rating RizzarJ on both, or sorry, RizzarJ on both YouTube and Twitch. So stick around for more great
Diablo 4 content. But yeah, we'll see you in the 230 PTR. See you in Sanctuary. Yep. Bye guys. Thank you.