We've been saying this whole time that hell is coming.
Now, hell is here.
Something that's always present in a Diablo title,
and we wanted to make sure that for Diablo 4,
returning to hell was a special moment.
We referenced the end-game cinematic with Prava and Inarius
taking the fight to hell at the end of the game.
We really wanted to capture that experience,
that sensation of battling throngs of demons in hell.
In the Infernal Quartz, they're going to go into this mode,
battle waves of demons,
and be able to kind of change the shape of the game experience as you play it.
Those of you who have joined us since Base Game and throughout the seasons
will have noticed that we have this phenomenon in the world
that's going on called Helltides.
Some of you might have noticed that Helltides have been getting a lot worse lately.
And now Hell is able to pierce the veil that's holding Hell back from fully invading Sanctuary
and starting to take root in Sanctuary.
And we started by asking ourselves some questions.
What is the state of Sanctuary right before the Vessel of Hatred happens?
How has Hell changed now that Mephisto isn't there anymore?
What are the demons up to?
Where is Mephisto? Does he have anything to do with this?
Or is this just Hell rising of its own accord as the prophecy proclaimed?
And so we thought to ourselves,
how can we make things even worse for the people in Sanctuary?
In this season, you'll very much get to dive into those mysteries
with some unlikely allies and really get to the bottom of what's happening.
So in this season, we play a lot with the notion of the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
How far would you go to save Sanctuary, to save your world?
What price would you pay?
Would you sacrifice your soul for this?
You're going to meet a guy named Loughran,
who at first seems sort of usual,
but you're going to quickly realize that something is off,
that something is a little strange with this guy.
So Loughran and Estelle are your allies,
and they're going to help you return to Hell.
Both of them are experts in demons,
and they're going to use that knowledge to help you return to Hell
and become more powerful to be able to battle the Infernal Hordes.
The Infernal Hordes is a new endgame activity in Diablo 4.
It's primarily a wave-based activity.
You're going to be fighting wave after wave with demon forces in Hell.
So if any of you have ever played wave-based gameplay before,
you'll know that things escalate.
We've got meteor strikes and all sorts of things
that try to keep you on your toes.
One thing the Infernal Hordes does differently
is the notion of Infernal Offers.
In between each wave, you'll make a choice.
You'll be granted an Infernal Offer,
and by choosing one of three of these offers,
you're going to change the game mode in some way,
a positive and a negative.
You can imagine, from the depths of Hell,
these hands rise out and offer you both a boon and a bane,
a kiss and a curse.
And this is a temptation that the Foul Council is making to you.
And in this temptation, you're offered more power,
but that power comes at a cost.
And so you get to choose, you know,
which temptations you're going to pursue during your Infernal Run
and then customize your experience from there.
One of the guiding principles of this game mode is replay.
It's an in-game mode that we want to make sure
you're playing over and over again.
So we really wanted to create a broad set of enemies
for you to fight during this mode.
We've got many demons to choose from
in the lexicon of Diablo's monster families,
but we're also going to see some other foes you might not expect.
There are going to be certain types of enemies,
like goat men who have been banished to Hell,
that have now rallied to Mephisto and fight by his side.
And even some unlucky souls that marched on Hell
from the Cathedral of Light have now been revived in Hell.
and fight against you alongside the demons.
Basically everything that Hell has to throw at you,
we're throwing it at you this season.
The Infernal Hordes has been built with multiplayer in mind,
but multiplayer is not required.
We want to make sure that solo players
still have a very fun experience in the Infernal Hordes.
Now that said, if you roll in with a party,
you're going to have a lot of fun.
This game mode is going to appear in the Eternal
and in the Seasonal Realm,
and that means that once the season is over,
it's here to stay.
The Infernal Hordes is unlocked at World Tier 3,
so really what you need to do to access it
is earn your way up to World Tier 3
and then complete an Eternal questline
that takes you back to Hell
and then unlocks the Infernal Hordes.
For World Tier 1 and 2 players,
we've built out a seasonal progression
that will help them become more powerful
in order to be able to confront the Infernal Hordes.
First is you can earn reputation,
and that reputation applies to a reputation track
that earns lots of really cool rewards
that will make you more powerful
as you progress on to World Tier 3.
The other thing we've built are micro dungeons
called Hell Breaches
that offer a glimpse at the Infernal Hordes mechanics,
and they give you a chance to learn the mechanics
before you confront the Infernal Hordes at World Tier 3.
The final boss in this season is the Fel Council.
And the Fel Council is some familiar faces
that you might recognize from Diablo 2.
These were priests of the Zacaroon,
holy men who were corrupted
and basically became vessels of hatred in their own right.
The council members in Diablo 2 tried to help contain Mephisto
in his Soul Stone,
and of course, Mephisto being Mephisto,
he was a very strong leader in the world.
He was a very strong leader in the world.
And of course, Mephisto being Mephisto,
slowly but surely corrupted them.
And eventually they had Soul Stones pierced
into their hands and became super powerful.
But eventually you overcame them and sent them to Hell.
Through the course of the story, resummon them.
They'd been reborn, slightly new powers,
but the same animosity toward you.
What's interesting about this boss encounter
is there are five council members,
but you're only going to fight three of them at once.
This allows us to then create many different flavors
of the boss fight for the fellow council.
In fact, it's about ten variations in all.
And so every time you go into that council fight,
there's a very good chance you're going to have a different fight
than the last time you played it.
We think it's going to offer a lot of replay for players.
What we also introduce during these waves
are opportunities for you to earn ether.
Burning ether is the resource that you gather during the infernal hordes
that you can then spend at the end of the activity.
There's going to be a fixed number of waves that you have to defeat.
And once you've completed all those waves,
then you'll face the fell council, defeat them, and collect your treasure.
So upon defeating the fell council, the spoils of Hell will spawn,
and then you consume your burning ether and opening those chests.
Now the trick is when you are playing through these waves,
that's your opportunity to earn as much ether as you can.
Different events are going to spawn all throughout the waves,
around the periphery of the arena,
and it's your job to try and defeat as many of those events as possible
to try and gather up all the ether you can.
Really skilled players are going to be able to really maximize that ether
so they get the biggest payout possible at the end
after defeating the fell council.
So with this burning ether you'll be able to get new uniques,
you'll be able to get new legendaries,
you'll be able to get rare materials,
things you might have scoured the whole of Sanctuary for
in previous seasons or in the base game,
but now we offer it to you here down in the depths of Hell.
A lot of these new uniques and legendaries really build on top of this idea
that they've been forged in Hell.
And so they're going to have unique looks that you can then make into cosmetics
to apply wherever you like.
They can also have unique VFX and sound effects
to really create the sense that they were forged in Hell.
One particular one that I enjoy using a lot are boots.
Boots, you say?
Well, these boots not only have been forged in Hell,
whenever you use a power with a cooldown,
they shoot out a ring of fire that hits everyone around you.
That's just one sample of the types of powers we're exploring.
So death in the Infernal Hordes is quite a big deal.
You're returning to the Realm of Hatred where Mephisto was born.
Like, this has to be a big deal.
In the Infernal Hordes, it's a lot like Nightmare Dungeons.
You only get a fixed number of revives in order to be able to get to the end of your run.
So at lower difficulties of the Infernal Hordes,
you'll get a number of revives shared between your party.
But at higher difficulty levels, the game is going to start taking away those revives.
And that increases the stakes that you have.
If you die too much, you'll be ejected from the mode.
In the Infernal Hordes, we've created a lot of new ways for monsters to ambush the players.
And so I'm pretty stoked to see how our players respond to these.
The seasonal quest line and the eternal quest line, they have lots of little surprises and twists and turns in them.
And there's even some surprises we've buried deep within the Infernal Hordes that hopefully players will have a great time with.
The Infernal Hordes developer update stream.
Hello everyone and welcome to our Season of the Infernal Hordes developer update stream.
My name is Marcus Kretz, I'm a community manager here on the Diablo team.
And today I'm joined by some very familiar faces. Adam and Adam, welcome to the stream.
Yeah, we did it. We took it over.
We took it over. It's just Adam and Adam show.
Now I don't even have to host. It feels great.
Yeah, and for everyone curious in chat, Adam is not going anywhere.
As you all know, there's a ton going on in Diablo. Yeah, Adam Fletcher isn't going anywhere.
Adam Jackson and Adam Fletcher.
There's a ton going on in Diablo right now. We've had a ton of live streams. There's been so much going on.
So it's just a lot easier to share the load amongst all the hosting live streams.
We just finished the Spirit Born live stream. So it's been a little crazy.
And you know, Marcus is here to help out. So you guys may see Marcus more here hosting some live streams in the future.
But yeah, I'm not disappearing.
You're acting as Colin today.
Yeah, exactly. Today I get to pretend I'm Colin.
Ooh.
Yeah, I'm pretty excited about that. Some big shoes to fill there. So yeah.
That is absolutely true.
In terms of everything that's been going on in Diablo, we just had our Season of the Infernal Hordes PTR.
We got a lot of learnings.
Yeah, but we also do have one additional person.
Of course we do.
Mr. Dan Dangway from Albany, New York. Dan, welcome to the stream.
Hey, how's everyone doing?
Doing great. Good to see you.
See, Dan's in like the Cathedral of Light. We're in like the Burning Hell.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's perfect.
It's hot over here.
Exactly.
It tracks.
Yeah.
Thanks for joining us today, Dan.
And the Season 5 PTR.
Yeah.
We've got a lot of learnings.
This was our second PTR for Diablo 4.
So we have a ton of feedback to get into, but we also have some notes from the community on the PTR overall and some learning.
So Adam, do you want to walk us through that?
Yeah, most definitely. You know, this is now our second PTR that we had.
We had one for Season 4 and of course one now for Season 5.
And, you know, we've learned a lot from these PTRs.
PTRs are incredibly important.
They're huge.
They're really beneficial for the whole entire team here.
And one thing we heard a lot of feedback, at least from the Season 5 PTR, is obviously as you're playing through a PTR, it's a non-final thing that you're playing.
It's still very early on.
Yeah.
There are going to be more bugs, more issues, just present in the PTR, because we are getting something out there a little bit earlier just so we can get feedback in on it.
But one thing that I think we most definitely heard from the community is, hey, the tools within PTR at times haven't been the best for the most efficient for players that need to actually test the content that we actually do have.
And so one thing that we did want to at least address and highlight and acknowledge is that, you know, we do plan on making the PTR experiences better in the future.
We do plan on equipping more tools for players out there so they're not having to sit there and grind out, you know, maybe like all the new legendaries or uniques or something like that.
Especially in like Season 5, for example, we gave a character copy feature in this one.
And then, of course, we had the boost feature which came back from Season 4.
And when you boosted your character, a new character, you would end up getting some of the new legendaries or uniques within Season 5.
What happened though is that it wasn't all of them and then we had players within Season 5 having to actually go out and spend their time that they probably could be testing other things like trying to find those items.
And obviously that's like not the most efficient thing to do.
So we do want to, we hear everyone, we acknowledge it, we do want to make the PTR experience better.
So I will say that like in future PTRs, and you'll see this gradually over the next couple of PTRs, it won't be all of a sudden like things will be completely different.
But I do expect like, and players should expect like, that we will have better tools for them to properly test as we gradually go through PTRs in the future.
And we appreciate everyone like letting us know.
We must definitely hear you guys and we must definitely want to make that experience better from that.
But PTRs have been great.
Huge thanks to everyone for jumping in and checking it out for sure.
Yeah, definitely.
Yeah, that feedback is so important.
So, you know, increasing how great these PTRs are is really, really important.
And I know for the Season 5 PTR, one of the huge features that we had in there was the Infernal Hordes itself.
So for everyone who didn't get a chance to jump into the PTR, Mr. Dan Tanguay, can you kind of walk us through what the Infernal Hordes is and what players can expect?
Yeah, absolutely. I'll give you all a quick recap.
So, the Infernal Hordes is a wave-based activity with push your luck choices in between each of those waves.
So, imagine waves of monsters coming in. Lots and lots of monsters, in fact.
And you also have some events, many events that you can also participate in.
Now, in between those waves, you're going to be making what's called the Infernal Offer.
And you're going to pick a boon or a bane, and that's going to change your gameplay for the rest of the run.
So, it allows you to customize what your Infernal Run is going to be like.
And so, we probably see right here, yep, we've got an Infernal Offer that comes up.
So, you're going to select one of those, and that will then change, of course, the rest of the run.
Now, when you complete the required number of waves, then you're able to go confront the Fel Council, who you can see here.
And the Fel Council, as you saw from the video that just came on right before this livestream,
are former servants, well, actually current servants of Mephisto, that you defeated in Diablo II,
and have now returned, and you must fight them once more.
And once you beat them, you're going to be able to spawn what's called the Spoils of Hell.
And these are chests that contain a lot of great goodies.
And so, with that Burning Aether you've been collecting all through the course of the mode,
you're able to choose what kind of spoils you want.
You've got spoils of legendaries and uniques,
and there's some absolutely great new uniques and legendaries in Season 5,
and you can probably farm about half of them, over half of them, from the Infernal Horts.
You're also able to spawn spoils of materials and buy into that,
and that will get you gem shards, that will get you Angel's Breath,
and of course that'll get you master working materials,
which you absolutely need to complete your items journey.
You can also cash out and get a bunch of gold,
which, you know, for those folks who are re-rolling their items in order to masterwork them,
or to enchant their items, is going to be hugely beneficial.
And then finally, there's a special bonus chest at higher tiers,
where you can get a guaranteed roll on a greater affects item.
And so, since that's one of the main chases in the final steps of the endgame,
we wanted to make sure there was an opportunity for players to really, you know,
get a little more lucky with it.
So, final thoughts on the Infernal Hordes.
Remember that it unlocks at World Tier 3.
You need an Infernal Compass in order to unlock it.
And there's eight levels of difficulty for it.
And so, yeah, that's a quick recap.
Awesome. Thanks for walking us through, Dan.
Super excited to jump in and try to grab some of those Uniques.
Now, I know, considering the Infernal Hordes was such a big part of PTR,
we did have a lot of community feedback with regards to, you know, getting into the mode,
some of the pacing.
So, can you walk us through some of those learnings we had based off the PTR feedback?
Oh, absolutely.
So, there was a lot of feedback that came in.
And so much so that we weren't able to address it all.
But we did distill down some big trends and feedback that we were able to tackle.
And so, the first off is that we wanted to improve access to the Infernal Hordes.
So, yeah, it was just too hard to get into the mode regularly to test it.
And folks who wanted to get into it very quickly couldn't get into it either.
So, we've pretty much overhauled access to the Infernal Hordes at this point.
Compasses still exist, but the drop rates on those have been boosted quite a bit.
You know, we want you to earn around four or five compasses an hour so that you can do about four or five runs per hour.
So, you know, you've got, you know, 50% chance to get them from item chests and Helltides unless it's one of those item chests that costs, you know, 250 senders, in which case that's 100% chance.
I mean, you put in the time, we'll just give it to you.
And then, you know, Nightmare Dungeon and Whispers, there's about a 75% chance to get one from a dungeon complete there.
You know, compass tiers at really high levels.
We wanted to make sure drop naturally from high tiered activities like Nightmare Dungeons and the Pit.
And we've also given you a path to just crafting these outright with the Occultists, with Sigil Power and Forgotten Souls.
And then finally, you know, it was a bug that the first compass that dropped from the Eternal Quest was actually a world tier three.
And if you were playing world tier four, sorry, world tier four, you had to switch back to actually get in the Infernal Hordes.
And that didn't feel great. So we updated that as well.
Moving along, the next big thing that we focused on was combat.
The pacing of combat wasn't hitting our goals.
And, you know, we had done a lot of internal testing on it.
And, you know, folks who weren't as in-game focused gave us a lot of feedback where, you know, oh, this is super intense.
Could we dial it back a little bit?
So we did.
But then we put it out on PTR and clearly all said, hey, no, we want more.
So we're giving you more.
The first thing that we did, though, is we fixed some bugs that actually happened.
That actually had a really big impact on the experience.
There was a boss health bug.
And that is hard to say.
Boss health bug that caused all the bosses to be super tanky.
And at tier eight, there were some folks who were spending almost an hour's worth of time in the Infernal's Horde.
And that just that's not what we wanted.
So we fixed those bugs and retuned everything.
So, you know, it's a much tighter experience at this point.
Similarly, there was a bug where difficulty wasn't scaling appropriate in multiplayer.
So we fixed that.
And then some tuning things.
So the pace of many events are pretty much rapid fire at high tiers now, you know, and so you're going to be spinning a lot of plates in this mode.
The monster spawn rates have also been increased to, you know, really capture that feeling of being overwhelmed.
And then finally, we reduced the wave timer down to 60 seconds, which, you know, just creates a much punchier experience for players.
And of course, retuned everything.
And then on top of that, we said, you know what, let's just make it easier for players to pick up burning aether to increase that pace.
So the pets now pick up the burning aether as well.
And that's not all.
Now, of course, you know, we're all playing this for the rewards, right?
And so it was really important for us to improve rewards across the board.
You spend time with the mode, you want to be rewarded appropriately.
And we weren't hitting that mark in the PTR.
So we raised the minimum amount of burning aether earned from any single run.
First off, every single source of aether got boosted by one aether.
And then we added aether drops to the Fel Council so that you're also getting, you know, a lot of bang for your buck just by defeating the boss as well.
And that actually scales per tier as well.
Next up, we retuned all the costs of the Spoils of Hell.
So, you know, the greater equipment, that one with the greater affects in it, used to cost 250.
Now it only costs 60.
Similarly, we retuned the spoils of equipment and the spoils of materials.
So now they only cost 20 aether apiece.
And then finally, we retuned all the rewards that were inside, you know, the the chest as well.
So, you know, at your bare minimum level, when you first start playing the Infernal Hordes and you're not sure exactly how it works, we still want you to feel rewarded just for the time that you invested.
And so the rewards at that bare minimum feel pretty good now.
But, you know, if you are spending a lot of time with it, you know how to optimize this mode.
We wanted to make sure that, you know, the rewards reflected that, too.
So that that higher, you know, ceiling of rewards has been raised as well.
So you're playing at tier eight.
You are going to get significantly more rewards than you would at tier one.
Awesome.
Yeah, that's quite a bit.
That's a lot of stuff to change.
Yeah, that's a lot of stuff to change.
I just want to call out.
Dan, your shirt is amazing.
I was going to interrupt, but I didn't want to while he was talking.
I'm like, now I just want that shirt.
And I'm very jealous that I don't actually own that shirt.
So I will message you after the stream.
You'll let me know where I can get this shirt.
Yeah, I think someone on the team made it.
So I was like, yeah, I needed a new shirt for the live stream.
That is her art.
100%.
Yeah.
Yes.
Now we know.
Okay, now I know.
And it is totally awesome.
I had to wear it.
It is Aaron.
I totally know.
Aaron, we will be touching base after the stream.
Yes.
Dan, that's awesome.
I'm going to be a little bit more.
Yeah, I'm going to be a little bit more.
I had to wear it.
So it is Aaron.
I totally know.
Aaron, we will be touching base after the stream.
Yes.
Yeah, Dan, that's a ton of changes.
Yeah.
It sounds like we're really cranking up the intensity for the Infernal Hordes.
Really, really cool to see.
Super excited to jump into it.
So I know for the Infernal Hordes, that's one part of the season that's coming,
but there was a lot that players didn't get to experience in the PTR that will be coming with the season.
So can you kind of share what's going to be new for players coming into Season 5?
Yeah, absolutely.
So the PTR was really focused on features that were on both the Eternal Realm and the Seasonal Realm.
And we have a number of Seasonal exclusive features that you all haven't had a chance to play with yet.
So we're going to tell you about them now.
First up, we've got the Seasonal Progression.
So you're going to see what we call the Reputation System in some footage here in just a second.
And the Reputation System is something that we had in Season 4 and actually earlier in some events.
And we've brought it back here because it serves as a great backbone for the season.
And we've evolved it in some significant ways.
So first off, how you earn Reputation is a bit different now.
But it was really important for us in Season 5 to give you more of a play,
give you more choice in how you wanted to earn your Reputation.
So previously in Season 4 you earned Reputation through just playing Helltides, as you should,
because we made a lot of improvements to Helltides in Season 4.
But here we wanted to broaden it out a bit more.
So you earn Reputation in Season 5 by just defeating powerful servants of Hell.
Elites, Hellborn, champions, bosses, so on and so forth, right?
And so that gives you a lot more choice to say,
Hey, you know, I can earn Reputation in Helltides or I want to earn it in the Infernal Hordes.
Or honestly, I want to take a break and do a stronghold.
You'll get Reputation there too.
Another small tweak that we made that's pretty important is that when you pick up Reputation,
you actually get a small boost in XP as well.
So as you're continually filling out your Reputation track,
you're starting to level up just a little more quickly than you did before.
Now, another thing that you might have seen are these big green tiles in the Reputation system.
And those are Seasonal Quests.
So we made it very clear that hitting certain tiers of your Reputation system now unlock the Seasonal Quests.
And it actually starts to weave the narrative through the progression a bit more,
which we really like the feel of and we hope to build on in the future.
And then finally, you know, again, it's all about the rewards, right?
So there's lots of great returning rewards in the Reputation system.
You're going to be able to earn Uniques, specifically class-based Uniques.
They're going to help you figure out what you want your build to be early on in the season.
You're also going to be able to get other powerful equipment, big drops of crafting materials.
And of course, at the very end of the Reputation track will be a Resplendent Spark that you can use to ultimately craft a Mythic Unique.
Next up, we've got the Seasonal Quest line.
You know, I was teasing it up a little bit with the Reputation system there.
So the Season of the Infernal Hordes has a rather unique narrative flow because we have an Eternal Quest line that introduces, you know, a big new feature that takes you back to Hell, right?
And so we wanted to make sure that was available to everybody, not just Seasonal Players.
And that also starts at World Tier 3.
Now, those of you who played the PTR have already seen it.
That's the one that features Locrin helping you to get back to Hell and confront the Infernal Hordes.
But we've developed an additional secondary, well, not really secondary, an additional seasonal quest line named of Lambs and Wolves, which we're kind of teasing right here.
And new NPC named Estelle is guiding you to become more powerful before you join Locrin to journey back to Hell.
Now, this one's going to be a little closer in tone to the Iron Wolves quest in Season 4, but it's going to be a bit more expansive than that.
And like I said, it weaves in and out of the seasonal progression.
So how do they relate to one another?
Well, the seasonal quest line is exclusive to Season 5.
And so you are able to get a really more complete picture of the story by playing both the seasonal quest line and the eternal quest line.
You can kind of think of the seasonal quest line as almost like a prequel to you unlocking the Infernal Hordes.
And but we also wanted to make sure that our eternal players don't get left out.
This is an eternal mode that we're introducing after all with the Infernal Hordes.
And so, you know, the infernal or rather the eternal quest line here, which is named Eyes of the Enemy, is going to be available for all players and won't go away after the season end.
So it's going to be there forever. So if you decide sometime down the road that you want to check out the Infernal Hordes and say, I don't know, Season 6, you can do that. Right.
And so, yeah, that's where we ended up with the quest lines this season.
And then the final thing I want to introduce are the Hellbreach dungeons, which we've gotten a few teases of before, but we can go into more detail here.
So these are all new micro dungeons to show that Hell has started taking root in Sanctuary.
Now, since the Infernal Hordes is an endgame activity, World Tier 3+, we wanted to make sure we had some content that targeted our World Tier 1 and 2 players.
And so you go into these, it's going to be a great source of reputation.
It's going to be a great place to get some powerful items.
And it's a pretty cool place to just kind of experience what the gameplay is going to be like down the road.
Now, originally we had kind of patterned these off the Donheim tunnels, you know, if you all remember those.
But, you know, with the introduction of Helltide in Season 4, we had to change it up a little bit because I don't think that alone would have sufficed.
And so what we did is we pulled in a lot of elements from the Infernal Hordes, and we're using this as an opportunity to introduce those elements.
So you see right here, we've got a simple Infernal Choice that shows, you know, that basically says, OK, do I want my boss to be a little simpler or a little more difficult?
And you get to choose. Hopefully the person playing chose the more difficult one I didn't see.
But you're going to be rewarded a lot more for taking that risk of making the boss more difficult.
And you're going to be earning Burning Aether. And at the end, there are going to be some spoils that you can spend on.
And like I said, you'll get some really powerful gear that should help you on your journey toward encountering the Infernal Hordes.
So if you want more details on these, I recommend that you check out our blog that came out two days ago. And yeah, thank you.
Dan, that's awesome. I got to say, chat got pretty excited when you mentioned Domain Tunnels. They kind of blew up there.
Definitely a fan favorite. Everyone remembers the Dopamine Tunnels. Yeah. Right, right.
And it's great that there's now like opportunities for players within like World Tier 1 and 2 to actually be able to have other options of leveling up.
And with these new help reaches, it's a good way to tease in the new content. Exactly.
Yeah. Then you get into those Infernal Hordes in World Tier 3 and off away you go. Yeah. That's awesome.
Dan, thanks so much for joining us. As Dan had mentioned, we did publish the Season of the Infernal Hordes blog a little bit earlier this week.
We are going to have patch notes that we'll publish following the stream.
So for any details we reveal across the stream, you can check those out for more information.
Dan's going to join us towards the end of the stream for our Q&A.
So if you have any questions, please drop those in Twitch chat and we'll be pulling them to get into those towards the end of the stream.
So we just touched on a ton of stuff that's coming in Season of the Infernal Hordes itself.
But based off the PTR, we also have a ton of changes coming across Sanctuary.
Yes. And to walk us through from the other end of the stream, Mr. Adam Fletcher.
Yeah, I get to pretend like I'm the person on the panel.
I'm going to pull out my... You designed and did all of this?
Yeah, exactly. Put in all the changes.
We have a fantastic design team here and I am going to bring in my inner Colin Feiner.
To talk about some stuff. But yes, as Marcus mentioned, there's a lot of changes.
A lot of the stuff that we actually did talk about in the blog and some of the stuff that people heard from PTR.
But there have been changes even since PTR.
Yeah. And we have a few new things in here that we'll also squeak in here as we're talking about it.
But one big topic I know that everyone brought up after PTR and that we even brought up even during our PTR stream was Helltides specifically.
One big topic within Helltides was Baneful Hearts.
If you guys remember back during the PTR stream, we talked about how Season 4 everyone had a plethora of Baneful Hearts.
I mean, it felt like everyone was always carrying about 100 to 150 at any given time and you can deposit as many into your heart's desire and still always have that same amount.
We wanted Baneful Hearts to feel a little bit more special.
And so during the PTR we actually did take the number down in terms of how many you would be able to earn.
We did hear everyone's feedback. People were like, that feels kind of crappy.
So we most definitely readjusted the drop rate of Baneful Hearts to really kind of close that gap in between Season 4 and Season 5 PTR.
We wanted to make sure that was, you know, it feels better.
Like you won't have 150 on you at all times most likely, but you still have plenty now to be able to summon the Maiden as well.
So some of the changes that we have coming up for Baneful Hearts and the rates that will help with this is we're bumping up the drop rates off of chests within Helltide specifically.
Players will also be able to get a guaranteed heart drop off of Helltide Commanders now.
And then one big thing is within world bosses, yeah, we actually have an image of like where you'll be able to now get your heart drop rates guaranteed, is world bosses.
Sometimes world bosses actually do spawn within a Helltide zone.
And we thought it would be kind of cool that, you know, hey, you killed the world boss there and a Helltide happened to be present in that specific zone where the world boss is.
Now you'll just get a guaranteed 3 within that world boss kill, which is kind of nice.
Sounds super cool.
We're also bumping up the drop chance to like local events, mastery chests within Helltide, and of course Harbingers within it as well.
And then one big change that we're doing within this as well is the blood maiden within world tier 1 and 2 in season 4 and even season 5 PTR, you would have to deposit 3 hearts just like world tier 3 and world tier 4.
We're actually tweaking that down to just 2 for world tier 1 and 2.
So there'll be one less like altar pedestal for you to deposit a heart for to summon the blood maiden within world tier 1 and 2, which should help out with, you know.
It just makes your farming a little bit quicker in the early levels.
Exactly, exactly.
And it doesn't feel like you're needing to put in that many for those earlier levels.
That much easier to chain a ton of blood maidens back to back to back.
Exactly, yeah.
So next thing we did want to talk about is within Helltides as tortured gifts, another change for world tier 1 and 2.
There'll be less cinders required to open up the tortured gift chest within world tier 1 and 2.
So it's dropping from 100 to 75 specifically.
And then this is something we talked about in the last stream where it was like really difficult for players to actually kind of go through a Helltide and complete, you know, a full on like, you know, tree of whispers like progression line within Helltide.
So now you'll actually be able to earn all 10 Grim Favors within a Helltide for sure when it's in one subzone.
And actually deposit that within the tree of whispers and get the whisper cash out of it.
I know sometimes it would take like sometimes two Helltides to actually do it.
Or you would have to leave the Helltide and go to a non-Helltide zone to kind of finish it off and stuff.
And so we wanted to make sure that was more efficient specifically within Helltides.
And then this was a big thing.
Big one.
So, you know, we talked about during the season 5 PTR stream that we were, that Profane Mindcages were a season 4 mechanic.
It was only within that.
Well, they were technically.
Yeah.
And so it was, it was removed from season 5.
Heard the feedback.
And people were like, wow, we really missed Mindcages.
Bring them back.
What's going on?
So we did bring them back and we brought them back in like a cooler form.
So now you can actually stack up.
So one, Profane Mindcages are coming back for season 5.
You can actually stack these now up to 3x in season 5.
This is seasonal only.
So this is only on the seasonal realm specifically.
But now stacking up to 3x does actually boost up monster levels for the...
Better rewards.
Better execute.
Better huge.
Yeah.
So you'll end up, you could knock monster levels up, you know, 30 levels if you wanted to.
And you will benefit or maybe suffer.
Or suffer quite a lot, yeah.
But it does give players the option now to use that.
And so Profane Mindcages are back and in a kind of a cooler form for season 5.
Yeah, amazing.
Which is really cool.
And we really appreciate the feedback we heard from players regarding Helltides on that.
So, next overall just general game updates that we do have.
One big thing that we're doing is we are boosting legendary drop rates off of really pretty much almost like all most content like Helltides, Nightmare Dungeons, Infernal Hordes for any monster that is level 100 or higher.
So you'll be able to see and just obtain more legendaries that way, less rares, things like that.
Separately, enchanting.
One big thing we heard is, you know, people were somewhat, you know, blocked a little bit with Angel's Breath.
And so we did remove Angel's Breath as a cost towards enchanting.
It's no longer required.
We've actually now kind of just swapped this over to the respective legendary salvage.
So for instance, armor would be coiling wards, weapons, baleful fragments, and then jewelry, abstruse sigils.
Yeah, tongue twister there.
Abstruse sigils.
But you now have the ability of being able to do enchanting.
Just note that, of course, gold costs are still associated with enchanting.
But now it's a little bit, removing a little bit of that friction with the Angel's Breath requirement.
And then this is something that we had talked about beforehand, which is just crowd control.
Overall, within Season 5 is going to be a lot better.
I know crowd control can be sometimes painful or either knock down or you're stuck.
Yeah, here, knock down and frozen for a million years and crying and then dying horribly.
And so CC duration has been essentially just pretty much reduced, like, across the board to, like, 1.5 seconds max.
And then one cool feature is you can also spam potions now while you're CC'd.
Really good for, like, you know, people in hardcore or, like, maybe it's, like, it creates more desperate moments of, like, I'm still dying.
No matter what.
But you now have the ability of being able to spam potions specifically if you are CC'd, which is really nice.
Yeah.
You know, we were talking about, like, charging, like, somebody for ban-
Bloated Corpse Fiends when they, like, all stun you and they do the Poisoning AOE?
Exactly.
As a keyboard slammer myself, thank you for that.
Yes, exactly.
For this change.
Next update we have is World Bosses.
So, funny enough, this actually fell into Season 5 PTR, but then we forgot to actually put it in Season 5 PTR notes.
And we actually forgot to actually mention it.
And we got a lot of reports of people going, like, hey, why are World Bosses, like, tankier and harder to kill?
Yeah, to fight back now.
Wait, what?
I'm not used to this.
So they actually had a feature called Resilience on there.
Essentially, Resilience normalizes damage across, like, all World content.
So it's like, if you- shared World content.
So, like, if a bunch of people are all coming into a World Boss, you should expect to find that the World Bosses will be a little bit more tankier,
a little bit longer in terms of the experience that you're having as you're fighting against them.
Yeah.
And less, you know, like, hey, I blinked and it's gone.
Oh, sweet. The boss was here for three seconds. Nice.
Yeah, exactly.
Three.
They barely even spawn in.
It was actually present in PTR.
And we actually got a lot of people that were going, like, hey, I think this is a bug.
And it actually wasn't a bug.
It was just something we forgot to actually mention in the patch notes.
So that is our bad.
But we do want to make sure that everyone's aware that World Bosses now have a feature called Resilience.
And that will end up helping out with those encounters specifically.
Separately for bosses, Pit Boss damage has been reduced pretty much across the board.
And then one big thing that we did want to call out is we got a lot of feedback within, you know, Season 4 and, of course, the PTR for Season 5.
Well, we saw some people address the changes that we were having there.
But Pit Bosses had this tendency within Season 4 to have, like, very sharp damage.
Yeah.
Where it would scale up really hard and there were times where you would run into a specific Pit Boss and you could potentially just get one shot based off of, like, those, the shadow boss, like, that would appear.
The extra ones coming in.
The extra ones that would come in.
Even when you went to War and all of that.
You could go and laugh as they left and you died.
Yeah.
So, now there is a feature within Season 5 where those shadow pit boss, like, affixes will appear.
And they will actually leave kind of a stacking debuff onto players now.
So and it can go up to three times.
And then, obviously, when it gets to the max, you have a very good chance of getting, like, heavily, like
Punished.
Yeah.
punished for for taking up to three debuffs from that end.
This is really to allow a little bit more flexibility for players, you know, based off of the feedback we heard regarding a lot of the one shots and things like that.
You now have the ability of being able to, you know, take a couple of these debuffs and maybe not like completely get punished from that.
It's less about like the perfection kind of involved, but more so being a little bit more forgiving in some of those opportunities.
Now, if you are a person that just like face tanks things and goes in and immediately takes three debuffs, you're probably still going to learn that, you know, that damage is still going to be very sharp with the three debuffs.
But it is something to help out in regards to that.
To be clear how that debuff works is every time that you get hit with one of those shadow boss mechanics, you'll take the debuff and it increases all of your damage taken.
So the regular boss is going to hit you harder and the shadow bosses are going to hit you harder too.
Exactly.
So, you know, you just don't want that to ramp up too much because then everything is going to be more punishing.
Yeah.
Exactly.
There's a few people already asking about those debuffs in chat.
Yeah.
It just increases all your damage taken.
So basically, you know, you get some freebies of getting hit by them.
You really don't want to, but then after that, you got to watch out because then it's about as hard as Season 4 was.
Exactly.
So, and then another big thing.
So this was something that was actually not present in the PTR, but it's something that we've heard a lot of feedback about and actually a ton of feedback about.
And this is group play in pits.
In Season 4, the way that it worked was if you were in the pit and you were the party leader and you had three friends that joined along, you would essentially get through the pit.
You would get all the master working materials for yourself, 100% of them.
And then everyone else that joined you would only get about like 50%.
And it felt pretty punishing for people to really kind of join up with friends and run through pits.
And we heard a lot of feedback of like, hey, it'd be great if I'm just joining my friend, we can all just get, you know, 100% of the pit material rewards.
And so that is being tweaked for Season 5.
Now the whole entire party itself will end up receiving 100% of the materials that you end up receiving at the end of the pit.
But so we appreciate the feedback.
Thank you guys for letting us know.
And this is something that wasn't in PTR but will be for Season 5.
Next up, we have endgame bosses.
So this is something, of course, we talked about during the PTR.
And we do want to highlight again because I think this is amazing and will save a whole lot of time.
So nice.
You can now resummon endgame bosses immediately after you end up killing them.
So as you're going through the different boss ladders and stuff, you can just resummon.
The altar will reappear as you can see in the footage.
And throw in the mats and bam.
Again, you're fighting Durial which is really nice.
No more exiting the dungeon, resetting the dungeon, running back and then having to do it over again.
This should save up a whole lot of time.
This should help a whole lot with farming as well, specifically for gear.
And you'll be hearing a lot about all this new gear from Adam here in a second.
But there were some additional changes as well to some of the endgame bosses that we do have.
Like, for instance, the first one we're going to talk about is the Beast and Ice.
The Beast and Ice, of course, required a sigil to actually summon.
Or to actually create the dungeon to go in to fight the Beast and Ice.
There's no longer a sigil that will be required.
And also the Beast and Ice is now way closer to the dungeon.
And it's going to be a short dungeon crawl similar to the other endgame bosses.
So you're not having to, you know, go through a lengthy dungeon just for that.
Yeah, a whole dungeon just to get to the boss.
Yeah.
Likewise, no more sigil dust will be required for summoning the Beast and Ice.
And then, of course, we thought about internal players in this situation.
Because some of them have actually crafted a bunch of sigils.
And now since sigils are no longer required, you can still use those leftover sigils to immediately resummon the Beast and Ice without needing the mats that are still required for the Beast and Ice.
So it's kind of a nice benefit to them.
And then, of course, Varshan also got some updates.
Varshan required a bunch of different body parts.
And now Varshan just requires malignant hearts.
And, of course, we thought about eternal players in this specific instance.
Eternal players can convert their old body parts to hearts by going to the Alchemist.
That's a magical Alchemist.
I get it.
Wow.
But if you ever need a spare heart, you just go to an Alchemist.
That's just how it works.
Swap it out.
Yeah, that's just how it works.
But, yeah, some changes coming to that.
And then, separately, endgame bosses, for endgame bosses, the Boss Ladder bosses, they won't be dropping rare items anymore.
They're actually just going to drop additional gold.
And, of course, you'll have your opportunity of getting legendaries and uniques and mythic uniques from them.
But now we just remove the rare item drops from them.
So it takes up, like, less of the drop chances that you could get in terms of their specific tables.
And then on tormented bosses, tormented bosses now drop five times as many boss mats as before.
And, of course, all tormented bosses have a better chance of dropping a mythic uniques.
So we are boosting up the mythic uniques drop.
There's actually specifics on all this stuff in the patch notes that people can read afterwards.
And we've also reduced the Stygian stone cost for the tormented bosses.
Before it was two, and now it's dropping to one.
So it should help out with players wanting to experiment or try out some of the more difficult endgame bosses that are available,
which are their tormented versions.
And then one big thing that is happening, and this is something that was kind of mentioned in the blog,
and people will see more specifics in the patch notes, experience is changing in terms of, like, the XP bonus from killing higher level monsters.
It's no longer capped in, I believe it's now, well, it's...
I think it used to be ten levels higher.
You didn't get more?
It's so capped, shall I say.
It's capped to 30 levels.
That's actually incorrect on the slide.
But it used to be ten levels.
It's now 30 levels.
And that's across all world tiers.
So if you have...
For example, if you are a level 50 character,
and you kill a level 80 monster in Season 4,
you would only get a level 60 experience.
Up to level 60 credit.
Now you'll get up to that level 80 experience.
So it should help out a lot.
If you are willing to go through more challenging content,
man, you get more XP for it, which is really cool.
And it's also really nice because it plays really well into stacking profane mine cages,
which are not available within Helltide because that can actually also increase monster level by 30 levels as well.
So it's kind of a cool little add-on, you could say, from this.
So yeah.
Pretty sweet.
Yeah.
I think that's it for general game updates.
Holy smokes.
Oh my God.
That's it.
Holy moly.
Yeah.
As I talked about a bunch.
It's all on the patch notes.
You guys will see the patch notes afterwards.
But yeah.
Yeah.
Really amazing to have all those changes.
Chat was absolutely lighting up.
Cool.
Good.
With regards to all the changes to the pit.
And of course, even though we've shown the boss summoning reset again,
they got just as excited.
Awesome to see.
And we really appreciate everyone's feedback during PTR
and hearing especially about the Helltide stuff.
And we totally hear you guys.
And we want to make sure that people have to experience,
still enjoy Helltide to the fullest.
You know what I mean.
Exactly.
No, it's really cool to see those.
I talked too much.
Yeah, those profane mind cages coming back.
But yeah, Adam, thank you so much for that.
Yeah.
And now, everyone, I hope you're comfortable
because we've got a ton to go over with regards to updates,
uniques, some bugs fixes, a ton of class balance changes.
Who better to walk us through, Mr. Adam Jackson?
Yeah, let's do it.
So we've got a lot to talk about today.
I'll try and go as quickly as possible.
So yeah, firstly, thank you all for your feedback and comments.
You know, we got a lot of class-related feedback on the PTR,
a lot of balance feedback, a lot of just how it feels to play things.
And we actually reacted pretty heavily and did a lot of changes between PTR and Season 5 launch,
some of which I think some people know,
and some things are going to be new for you today.
Okay.
So really, yeah, we have a lot of things that changed.
In many ways, honestly, it's going to feel like almost from a balanced perspective
and kind of what your class can do in your journey,
it's going to feel almost like a very different game
compared to what you experienced on the PTR.
I'm going to go through a lot of like the systemic reasons why
and then some specific things that we did to every class
as well as, of course, updating all of our uniques
and kind of the impact that you can expect from that.
So lots to talk about.
So first, we're going to be talking about bug fixes.
We've got quite a few to go through that I think are pretty notable.
Again, we're going to be doing the class balance updates after that
and then the unique changes.
So those will be the three things I'm going to be covering today.
So firstly, as usual, you know,
we're going to be publishing the patch notes right after this
so you can read all of them.
I'm not going to cover everything today,
but just some of the more notable ones.
So first is one on the Necromancer that we've heard about for a while now.
It's Shielding Storm.
This is legendary that when your Bone Storm damages enemies,
you get a barrier equal to your max life.
It used to be based on your base life instead of your max life,
and now we finally fixed that.
To be clear, this is a pretty huge buff.
We may have to reevaluate the power of this a little later,
but we're going to see how it goes.
But now that barrier is going to be very significant
as you're hitting enemies with this aspect.
Next, we've got a couple on the Barbarian.
The first one is the Twister Glyph.
This is a Paragon Node Glyph.
It wasn't properly giving you bonus multiplicative damage
when casting dust doubles,
so dust double builds will be a little bit stronger.
We also fixed an issue with the tempering earthquake duration.
Beforehand, there was a bug
where it was actually lowering the DPS of earthquake
because it would increase the duration,
and then your DPS would go down.
So we fixed that.
So it's now actually just going to make you hit harder.
Next one, I'm going to call out one of our content creators, Woody Joe, here.
This is why we have PTR.
He found a neat little oversight that we had
with a passive called Trick Attacks,
and I'm actually going to go over this in a little bit of detail
because this is going to be coming a little later.
Rank 39 out of 3 seems completely normal.
Yeah, 39 ranks of offensive passive is pretty good.
So a little bit of background to this.
Basically, we changed how this passive Trick Attacks,
what it does.
It went from something that was more utility-based
where it was around CC,
and we turned it into damage.
But we didn't update under the hood for tempering
and where it can appear from a utility to a damage recipe
of where it would show up.
And so it was appearing on utility,
which is a lot more common than damage,
and then you could get it to silly ranks like this.
So to fix this,
right now, or on the PTR, I should say,
it was on this recipe called Alchemist Control
where it was with Chilling Weight and Shadow Crash,
which were also like CC-based passives.
For Season 5 launch,
we're actually going to be disabling this recipe from dropping.
You won't be able to see it for a patch
while we fix this bug.
And what we're going to do is,
once we re-enable the Alchemist Control recipe to drop,
Trick Attacks won't be on here anymore.
What we're actually going to be doing
is we're going to be taking Flurry Size
from another recipe called Rogue Innovation here.
We're going to be moving Flurry Size,
which is more of a utility-based thing,
and moving that over to Alchemist Control,
and then just removing Trick Attacks from Alchemist Control.
So the net effect of this will be that
now both tempering recipes will have three different options
of what you can have there,
and Rogue Innovation will actually have a little bit of a buff here too
because instead of having four things to roll for your tempers,
we're only going to have three.
So it'll be a little bit easier to get what you want.
Next, we're going to be talking about
some generic class balance updates.
So kind of to set you up,
a high-level theme that we're going to see
in our feedback from PTR was
Barbarians are really, really good,
and oh, every other class is kind of a little bit weak,
it feels like, compared to Barbarians.
So we did a lot of things to address this.
So first I want to go into detail a little bit
of how we feel about Barbarians
and where they're at and what we want to do.
We feel like one of the bigger reasons
why Barbarians are so strong
is that they kind of have two class mechanics
compared to other classes, right?
They have the Expertise System,
which is like a normal class mechanic
where, you know, they have this fantasy
of leveling up their weapons,
and then they get bonuses.
But then they also get more item slots
compared to other classes
so they get more access
to more legendary powers.
As far as how we tackle this,
we don't want our only solution
to be the nerf Barbarians, right?
Like a common thing that we hear is like,
hey, they have more item slots,
maybe you should just get rid of the item slots
so that everybody has parity, right?
Like that is a way to make parity,
but, you know, it takes away from their theme
of being a master of weapons,
and it's not very fun.
So that's not the only thing
that we want to do in this situation.
The other thing is that we want to keep
their class identity, right?
Another common suggestion we hear is,
well, just give all the other classes
more item slots so that they're the same
as Barbarian, right?
And similarly, kind of like how
Necromancers have minions,
we don't want to give every class minions
just because, you know,
they don't have access to the cool thing
that Necromancers do.
We don't want to just give every class,
you know, more slots so that they're
exactly the same as Barbarian.
We want to really try and keep
what makes them feel special
as a special thing
and find other ways to kind of bring
parity to the classes.
So here's kind of our strategy
of what we're thinking of with Barbarians.
We have a few different things
that we're going to be doing.
One is we're actually going to be adjusting
how much damage all the classes get
from their core stat,
and this is going to bring other classes
up to the level of Barbarian.
I'm going to be going over that
in a little bit.
We are going to be reducing
the power of Barbarians
as part of our solution,
but again, I want to point out
it's not the only thing
that we want to do.
And then we also want to target
the other class mechanics
and really bring them up
to the level of the Barbarian
effectively having too
and making the other classes
feel cool in the way
that makes them thematic and awesome.
We already actually experimented
with this in Season 4.
This was an intentional thing
that we did,
and we wanted to see how it went
with the Necromancer.
If you remember,
we buffed minions very heavily,
and we also buffed
the Book of the Dead,
their class mechanic,
very heavily.
Not just numbers,
but also in the cool factor, right?
You have mechanics like,
you know, your minions
can throw bone spears,
or, you know,
your golem can do bone spikes
everywhere and make enemies vulnerable.
We want to do this kind of treatment
to the other class mechanics.
Just to be clear,
we're going to be probably doing this
after the Vessel of Hatred expansion launches,
so it'll be a little bit.
So we are doing some things
in the meantime to catch them up,
but you can expect in the future
we're going to be doing
kind of a big overhaul
to the other classes
similarly to the Book of the Dead,
and so their cool factor
and their power level
is going to be going up.
So let's talk about that core stat update
that I talked about previously.
So basically what we're doing here
is we're going to be changing
the amount of damage
that every class gets
from their core stat.
So if you didn't know,
on live right now,
when you log into the game,
you get about 1% more damage
per 10 stat of your class.
So as an example,
you know, the, I don't know,
pick one, the Sorceress,
you know, with Intelligence,
you would have 10 int,
and then you would get 1% more damage.
If you had 100 int,
you'd have 10% more damage,
and so on.
So now it's going to actually
depend on the class
what that ratio is
of how much damage you get
per your core stat.
So the Barbarian is going to be saying
exactly the same,
1% more damage per 10 strength.
The Rogue is going to get
a little bit of a buff here
because they do have
a little bit more slots
compared to other classes,
so they're going to be getting
1% more damage per 9 decks.
And then the other three classes,
the Sorceress, Druid,
and Necromancer,
are going to be getting
1% more damage
per 8 core stat.
So, you know,
without doing a lot of math,
the TLDR here is
Barbarians are staying the same,
Rogues are going to get
a bit of a bump,
a bit of a buff,
and the other three classes
are going to get
even more damage.
So as you get that core stat,
which you get very commonly,
you know,
in Gear and Paragon
and other places,
you're just going to be
doing more damage.
It's just a passive way
that we're going to be
catching up the classes
stat-wise.
So next,
let's move on
to kind of our class updates.
So I'm going to be going
through all the different classes
and talking about
kind of what our updates
are going to be for them,
some of the things
you can expect
that are different
from PTR to launch.
So Barbarian,
you know,
currently Barbarians,
in addition to having
more item slots,
have some of the best
key passives in the game
like in Season 4
and on live.
One of the very main ways
that we're targeting
bringing them down
is reducing the power level
so that really
their key passives
are comparable
to other classes.
We on the team felt like,
you know,
they already have
all these other things
that are really strong
going for them.
They don't need,
like,
overly-statted,
way-powerful key passives
that do, like,
you know,
over 100% multiplicative damage
when the other classes
are doing way less.
So you did see that
on the PTR.
We did see a lot of feedback
on, like,
why are we bringing down
Walking Arsenal
to have parity
when, you know,
it wasn't even really meta
compared to the other
key passives.
And I just kind of wanted
to bring some light
to this of how we think
about it.
The reason why we brought
Walking Arsenal
to be level with the other ones
when we brought them
to be equal to other classes
is that, you know,
we want all the key passes
on Barbarian
to have parity with each other.
If we just brought down
the other key passes
that were way over-performing
and didn't bring
Walking Arsenal down
to be even with them,
then really Walking Arsenal
is just going to be
the best mandatory pick
and every Barbarian build
is going to have to interact
with this system.
And we really wanted them
to be equal with each other
so that, you know,
there's actually a choice
when you get to your key passive
of which one to take.
So I just wanted to clarify that
of, you know,
what our thinking was there.
But, you know,
it's not all doom and gloom
for Barbarians.
You know,
we did hear feedback
of like,
man, it really sucks.
You know,
I understand that they're
being brought down
and it's fair,
but, you know,
we want to have some things
to look forward to.
So we did introduce
a number of buffs
coming in between PTR and live
so that you have some things
to look forward to
and new build paths
or your, you know,
underperforming builds
are not being brought down
as well.
So I'm going to give
a couple of examples here.
One is Hammer of the Ancients.
We increased its damage
baseline by 10%.
And we also adjusted
the Of Ancestral Force legendary.
One of the troubling things
that this build has problems with
is like single target damage
against bosses and things.
You know,
it does really good in AoE
and brings down enemies,
but its single target
is a little bit lacking.
So we're upgrading
this legendary power.
So now it's going to be doing
more damage against bosses.
So it'll kind of help you
with that single target issue.
Another one is Upheaval.
Upheaval builds can rejoice
and also a little bit of a preview
of kind of how we're changing
uniques,
which I'll be going over
a lot more later.
But we're increasing
Upheaval damage by about 15%.
And we also rounded out
Hellhammer now.
It's quite a bit more powerful.
I can point out a bunch of things here
of how it's better.
But you can see
it gives more skill ranks
of upheaval compared to before.
The damage of its burning
on the ground
just baseline went up.
It also has scaling
on the burning damage.
So, you know,
before the burning damage
wasn't really a meaningful
part of the unique.
One of the things
you're going to see
with uniques across the board
is that they're going to be
a lot more about
the thematic
of what the unique is.
And that's where their power
is going to be.
So here,
the burning ground
actually will scale
with your strength
at a pretty significant degree.
So, you know,
it'll actually be doing
meaningful damage, hopefully.
You can also see
its inherent affix now
is damage to burning enemies
instead of overpower damage.
So it's going with that theme
of Hellhammer
burning the ground.
It's also giving you
skill ranks of wall up,
a passive.
So that's more multiplicative damage.
You also get upheaval size.
So now your burning ground
and your upheaval
is going to be bigger.
So there's just all kinds
of new things going on.
It's going to be a lot cooler,
a lot more powerful,
and hopefully a lot more fun.
Yeah, Hellhammer
looks absolutely insane.
Yeah.
300 strength also,
by the way,
no big deal.
300 strength,
360 strength,
no big deal.
No big deal.
It's going to be pretty good.
So next,
the Sorceress.
We got a whole lot of feedback
that, you know,
the Sorceress isn't powerful enough
compared to other classes.
We got so much.
I'm going to stop us right here.
We got so much feedback
about the Sorceress.
Just a little bit.
And the Druid.
And the Necromancer.
I will just note,
like,
we hear you guys.
We absolutely do.
Yeah.
Okay,
now you may continue.
Okay.
So,
for the Sorceress specifically,
we heard feedback
that they're not powerful enough.
So we did quite a few things
to address it.
Firstly,
they've got a lot of large buffs
to their Uniques.
I would say even more
than other classes.
Your Uniques are going to feel
really good,
is the hope,
and I think we've hit it.
And I'll be going over
some of them a little bit later.
We also buffed
all of their Core and Mastery skills
by about 15 to 20%.
So just baseline.
Remember,
this is in addition
to the Core stat buff.
All of your Core and Mastery skills
are also getting buffed baseline
by a pretty significant degree.
So you're just going to hit harder.
We also did multiple defensive buffs.
You know,
we heard a lot of feedback
that they have trouble surviving
in situations
that the other classes
could kind of get away with.
These are some examples.
We did more than this.
But Ice Armor,
your base shield amount
is going up from 40%
to 56% of your max life.
Snow Veiled aspect.
This one was updated
from PTR to launch.
So on PTR,
it was that your Ice Armor
gave you Unstoppable
and gave you Armor.
And on launch,
you're still going to get Unstoppable,
but you're going to get
damage reduction,
which anyone who knows
how the defenses
within this game work
is way more significant
than just getting Armor.
Yeah.
When you hit that Armor cap,
it's kind of like...
Yeah, you just want to
gobble up DR like Pac-Man.
As much as you can get,
the more the better,
and this is going to give you...
Yeah, the DR is going to be huge.
Very big.
Also, we did multiple buffs
to the Paragon board.
Again, this is not covering everything.
But one of the things
is that we put a lot of caps
to make sure that
some Paragon O's
just didn't go out of control
compared to everything else.
But we heard feedback
that those caps
were a little bit too punishing.
So we increased them.
An example here
is Burning Instinct,
where on PTR,
it capped at 40%
more multiplicative damage.
And we increased that
up to 80%.
So now your Burning damage,
that's based on your Crit Strike,
multiplier,
is going to be going up.
Your total amount
is going to go up.
But then also,
the rate that you get it.
It used to be 1% per 50 int.
Now it's 1% per 20 int.
So you'll be getting
more efficient
paying for your buck
for your int
and a total cap
that's much higher.
So Druid,
similar to Sorceress,
surprise, surprise,
got a lot of feedback
that it's not powerful enough
compared to the Barbarian
or other classes.
So we've got
a lot of multiple quality of life
and damage buffs coming in.
Again, these are just some examples.
Also, you've got to remember
the Uniques
are going to be coming in as well.
Boulder damage went up.
We increased the damage
across the board
of their core skills mostly
and we missed Boulder.
So we're increasing
their damage a bit.
We also got a lot of feedback
that we came out
with this really cool
Unique for Cataclysm
that made the Lightning Bolts
smart and target enemies.
And a lot of people
were like,
hey, why does it have to
get a Unique
to make my skill be smart?
And we agreed.
So we just made
the skill smart baseline.
So now those Lightning Bolts
from the ultimate
will just target enemies.
Perfect Storm.
The Storm key passive
is getting its damage
boosted from 30% to 40%.
Seismic Shift.
This was an aspect
that we think is really cool
where your Earth Spike
kind of goes in a line
and does a bunch of Earth Spikes.
Used to have a Kiss Curse mechanic
and it no longer does.
So before it used to
give you this big bonus
of way more resource reduction
and more damage on it.
But it added a cooldown.
And now it just doesn't
add a cooldown
so you can spam it
and cast a bunch
of Earth Spikes everywhere.
Should be a lot more fun.
Also similar to the Sorceress,
we're buffing their
little bonus cap
on their Legendary Paragon nodes.
So an example here,
you know they went
from 40% to 60%.
So you've got Thunderstruck,
Earthen Devastation,
and Survival Instincts.
We've got a little visual there
at the bottom node
but you can see that
that top end of the damage
is now 60%.
So it's going to be
better than PTR.
Also we came out
with that new Unique
I mentioned for Cataclysm.
It used to be on the gloves
on PTR which a lot of people,
which we agreed with,
you know it kind of felt bad
that you've got
the two Storm-related Uniques
on the same slot
and you can't take them together.
It was competing
with Unsun Aesthetics Wraps.
This was the Lightning Storm Unique.
But now it's going to be
on the ring slot
so now you can take them
both together
so they're not competing
with each other anymore.
Next is the Rogue.
So to be frank,
the Rogue is,
we feel like it's
in a pretty good spot
so we didn't do
as many changes
compared to other classes.
We did still do a few
that I'll mention today
but they got the least changes.
The first one is Flurry.
So as you know
if you played the PTR,
Flurry got some
pretty dramatic updates, right?
Both of their enhancement
and both of their choices
that you could pick
on the base skill
got changed
and made a lot better.
We saw that, you know,
a lot of the output of Flurry
was related to doing
the mechanics
that the enhancement
and the advanced Flurry
were requiring you to do
like casting it
a bunch of times in a row
and stuff like that
and we wanted to move
some of that damage
from those enhancements
and things into the base skill.
So the enhancement
and the advanced Flurry
are still going to be
pretty potent
but we lowered their damage
and instead just
used the base skill
even more.
And what this is going to mean
is really just that
you're going to be
more consistently
doing that damage
and you're going to be
less reliant on doing
the stacking mechanics
to get it.
Next, Wind Force.
You know,
this one has had
a troubled history
of just trying to find ways
to make it really good
and useful.
Instead of knocking back enemies
when it procs,
it's going to knock them down now
so you no longer
have to worry about
knocking enemies
out of your CC
or you want them
to be grouped up next to you
and then you're just
knocking one of them
or a few of them away.
Now they're just going
to go in place.
We have a before and after here.
Again, a little preview
of what we're doing
with our uniques.
But yeah,
Wind Force,
you can see some of the things
here as a preview
is going to give you
move speed baseline
which is pretty interesting
as a stat on a bow.
You've got chance
for double projectiles
for your barrage.
You've got a couple
passive upgrades there
and then as you can see
the damage went up
but also now
it knocks down enemies
instead of knocks them back.
Last but not least,
the Necromancer.
We've been hearing
a lot of feedback
that blood Necromancer players
are a little sad.
They just aren't really
catching up to the other
versions of Necromancer
so we've buffed up
a bunch of their
tempering recipes
and the damage on them.
We're also buffing
their legendary paragon nodes.
Here's some here
that we did.
Bloodbath,
this one just makes
your overpower damage go up.
It's being doubled
from 35% to 70%
so that's pretty meaty.
Blood begets blood.
That damage bonus
when you're picking up
blood orbs
is being doubled
and the maximum amount
so you're getting more
per stack
and you need less stacks
to get to your max damage.
So pretty good there.
And then last but not least here,
Lucky Hit.
We've heard a lot of feedback
from Necromancer players
that they kind of rely a lot
on the Miasma corpse explosion
to get their Lucky Hit procs off
and that their other skills
don't really compete
and so they can't really
have fun with Lucky Hit
based builds
more generally.
So we just buffed Lucky Hit
on a bunch of different skills
so you can see there
what all the numbers are.
Again, those will be
on the patch notes
but really they're just
going to be Lucky Hit
more often
and getting cool procs more.
All right.
So next,
let's talk about Uniques
a little bit, right?
We've got a lot to cover.
Yeah, so as we promised
in the PTR stream,
we said that we have
this kind of different philosophy
when it comes to Uniques
and we went into detail there
and we updated our Uniques
coming into Season 5
but we didn't update
all of our existing Uniques
in the game yet.
So we've done that pass now.
We've updated nearly
every Unique in the game
and I'm going to do
a little bit of a recap
of kind of how we thought
and then giving you
some examples of what we did.
So these updates
are fairly dramatic.
They're going to be
showing you three
from each class
as well as three generic ones
to give you a really
meaty idea
of the different categories
and ways that we thought
of updating Uniques
and kind of, you know,
what you can expect
for your builds.
Yeah, and I know
and Marcus is going to remind us
about this at the end as well
but like I know.
You'll be hearing it a lot.
But I will say
we are showing three here
for every class
and three generic ones
but every single Unique
is actually
in the patch notes
and we have a before
and after in the patch notes
so you guys will have
easy access and
you can see.
You can easily compare the two
and see what was the difference.
So after the stream
you'll be able to compare
and so we're just only
covering a small amount here.
We'll see everything.
Just a little sample serving.
The patch notes
are absolutely massive
so you'll have a lot too.
That'll be pretty cool to see.
Lots of snack on there.
So yeah,
so one of the things
is your general power level
of Unique Effects is up
and by Unique Effects
I want to be clear
that is like the thing
at the bottom
that is like your,
you know,
deals 40 to 60%
more multiplicative damage
or whatever.
That number is going to be
up on the higher end.
So instead of 40 to 60
it'll be 40 to 80
or 40 to 90
or 40 to whatever, right?
So that power level
is just going to be
generally up
almost across the board.
And then really
what we targeted
for these updates
is the stats
on the Uniques.
So the stats
are going to pretty much
break every rule
that we had in the game
before when it comes
to being a cool item.
So some things
that you're going to see
and I think I got an example
of most of,
if not all of these.
But you're going to see
Uniques that have
different inherents
compared to other stats.
So, you know,
your boot inherent,
you know,
could be something
that's not even related
to boots or movement anymore.
It could be something else.
Or sometimes we add
more inherent stats.
So something that
didn't exist before,
you know,
some items can have
two inherents
instead of just one,
which is a pretty big difference.
We have a lot more
that have stats
that break normal slot rules.
So, you know,
things like movement speed
on bows
or cooldown reduction
on weapons,
stuff like that.
Uniques also can now
have tempering affixes, right?
None of them really did this
in Season 4,
but now that tempering
is in the game
and Uniques have to compete
with these really great
tempered items,
Uniques can have that too.
They can also have
much higher potential
stat values
compared to normal items.
So, you know,
if a normal item
has 20 to 40% more damage,
a Unique can be like,
you know,
1 to 300% more damage
or whatever, right?
And we even do this
with the tempered affixes.
So, Unique can have
juiced up versions
of tempered affixes
that make them solve
those problems much quicker.
Also, we've introduced
a lot of stats
that really have
powerful effects on them.
Sometimes even a single
stat on a Unique
can have the impact
that a legendary power
normally would on an item
as far as what it does
to a build.
And we'll have a couple
examples of that
where like a stat
on an item
is actually giving you
a new effect
that didn't exist before
that you could do.
Damn, that's awesome.
Yeah, so again,
we're going to be going
through three examples
per class
and three generics
and I'm going to just
try and quickly go through
and kind of point out
some of the key things
that are kind of neat
about the items.
So, we're going to
shotgun this a little bit
and yeah, you're going
to see some cool items.
So, let's get to it.
Woo!
Yeah, so first,
Penitent Greaves.
This is a generic unique
you can see here.
This one now has
two inherents
as opposed to one.
Another thing
that you can notice
is that normally,
you know, the inherent,
the evaded grants
more move speed
is only for one second
and this one is not only
has two inherents
but it's for two seconds.
So, you'll evade
and like, you know,
boost around that crazy
sonic speed
for a couple seconds
which is pretty neat.
And now you can run
through enemies
while you do it.
We've also got
some neat stats there
like crit chance
against chilled enemies
and chilled potency
there that are new
to the game.
Here, Fists of Fate.
This one a lot of people
saw a little bit early
and they were
very happy about.
So, one thing I think
that's kind of cool
is that with our uniques
we're really trying
to like double
and triple down
on the fantasy
of the item.
So, you know,
something's about cold
or something here
like Fists of Fate
is about like RNG
to the max.
So, we're really going
hard on like
what the theme is.
So, here you can see
like your attack speed
can go from 0.1
to 0.7
and everything on it
is like has a huge range
of what you can roll.
So, like a greater affixed
Fists of Fate
could be like a best
in slot item
for a lot of builds.
The lucky hit chance
on this.
Yes, this is the one
that people point out
that we...
It's just crazy.
I talked with one
of the people
on our team.
I want to shout out
Alex on our team
who did a lot
of this work
and we had a choice
here and we're like
are we going to go crazy
or go conservative?
I was like,
you know,
let's just go crazy.
Like, this might be insane.
It might actually be
best in slot
and break stuff
but it's really cool.
So, yeah,
greater affix
Fists of Fate
there is going
to be really cool.
Next, the grandfather.
Mythic unique example here.
You know,
a lot of people
had issues
with the ignored
durability loss.
You know,
where you would like
masterwork hit that
or something
and then you're
not getting anything.
We just moved that
into be a,
you know,
a baseline inherent affix now
so you don't have
to worry about that
and then replaced it
with something useful
with a max resource.
And I will note
like even in season four
because that durability
loss was kind of,
was actually a hidden
stat item.
Sometimes when you found
a greater affixed version
of a grandfather.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It would actually apply
to that.
That is now
donezo.
It's just
inheritance can't be greater
which is something
that we thought of
a lot with this.
Yeah, so now let's go
into the classes.
Barbarian.
This is Battle Trance.
This one exists
already on live.
Probably the two
big things here.
One is, you know,
you have two different
passives now that you get.
A lot of times
we're adding skill ranks
to passives
because that's a way
to add multiplicative damage
or just buffs
to really cool effects
on a unique
via their stats.
The other thing
to point out here
is the actual effect
before it was giving you
increased attack speed
to all of your other skills
when you had frenzy stacks.
Now you're going to be
getting damage
and attack speed.
You know, we heard
a lot of feedback
from players that
they would hit attack speed cap
and then this unique
wasn't really doing
very much for them.
So now you're also
just going to get damage
in addition to making it
easier to hit that cap
for your other skills.
So it's just, you know,
more stats, stronger.
Next, Reign of the Ravenous.
A couple things here.
One is it's giving you
skill ranks of rend
which is pretty significant.
And remember,
that 2 to 3
might not seem so significant
but when you greater affix that
and then masterwork it,
like your potential
of more damage on this
goes up very significantly.
We're also giving you
skill ranks
to brawling skills still.
The thing to point out here
is your rend's duration,
this will also just increase
the throughput damage of it
has been doubled
so that's just more damage
on rend
in addition to the skill ranks.
And then also
at the bottom,
a small little detail
but before,
you could only
apply that special effect
of your brawling skills
applying your rend's bleed
every 4 seconds
and now it's every second.
So now if you're able
to spam brawling skills,
you're just going to be
applying rend bleeds
to enemies
and stronger rend bleeds
like crazy.
So it's a pretty big
power boost.
Next, the fields of crimson.
The thing that we want
to call out here,
I mean there's a lot of things
that are kind of
unique and different
but is that
one kind of rule
that we had
with item stats
that we're now changing
and breaking
is we never really
buffed things
like enhancements
or like the AB,
like the different
choice upgrades
that you could do
for a skill.
This one actually buffs
enhanced ruptures
explosion size.
So you know,
normally when you
rupture an enemy
it does that explosion.
This will make that
explosion be way bigger.
So it's kind of
a neat way
that we can manipulate
player power via stats.
Next, let's move on
to the sorceress.
So the staff
of endless rage,
we actually have
a combo here
that we're going to
show a little video of
before and after
with this.
Fireball builds.
The staff now does
some and the gloves
would be doing
some unique things
to fireballs.
One is butt plus
fireball projectile speed.
So this is actually
going to make your
fireballs fly through
the air faster
or bounce quicker
and so you'll be able
to get through them
and they'll finish
their path faster.
You've got the
tempering recipe now
so it doesn't compete
with your chance
to cast twice
and you can see there
it goes up to 75%
just on that one stat.
So it basically
almost solves it for you
by itself
which is pretty huge.
You've got some
massive skill ranks
to fireball
so now again
way more multiplicative
damage than before
and then you know
you can see at the bottom
that the upper end
of that damage
is going up
the same as most
of our uniques.
And next
it's combos
with the gloves
of the illuminator.
A couple things
to kind of
gloat on here
is the fireball
attack speed
is going up
by a much bigger
amount than other
classes
or than normal
attack speed
sorry on other slots.
Also you get mana
when fireball explodes.
I played with
this build
and I think
it was season 1
and I constantly
ran into mana issues
because you always
want to spam this
as much as you can.
So when you think
of this stat
you know
you can greater this
you can masterwork this
and you kind of
combine this
with the attack speed
here
and then you combine
it with the projectile speed.
Yeah and you get
a lot more fireballs
and remember
it's every time
that it explodes
which when it bounces
it's exploding
and when you're
splitting and getting
more from multiple
projectiles
you're getting
more bounce explosions
so it's giving you
a resource engine
all in its own
essentially a fireball
machine gun
which is pretty great.
So we've got a little
bit of a season 4
to season 5
comparison here
of what it looks like
a little video
so in season 4
you can see
you know
every third cast
gives you 3
but season 5
you're going to
randomly get 3
and then sometimes
even more
when it combines
with the double
projectile bonus
so you can actually
really fill up
your screen
with fireballs
everywhere
and every one
of those bounces
is giving you
mana back
to cast more
that's ludicrous
so it's pretty cool
it's its own
little engine
next we've got
blue rose
probably the cool
thing to point out
here is
there's a chance
for ice spikes
to explode twice
so this is also
something that we
haven't really done
where we have these
we call them
sub powers internally
but you know
these things like
dust doubles
or ice spikes
that are like
powers that generate
when you cast a skill
that are usually
through legendaries
or uniques
we generally don't
manipulate them
too heavily
like this
but we're going
to be experimenting
more with that
in unique
stat affixes
so here you know
your ice spikes
can actually
like double proc
so they get
you know
double explosions
and then any other
things that would
proc off that
would be doubled
which is pretty neat
next let's move
on to the druid
so waxing gibbous
this is the
shred druid unique
so what we did
here that I want
to point out
you know
in addition to the fact
that you're getting
a bunch of skill ranks
to shred
and toxics cause
which is a bunch
more multiplicative damage
so power level
is going up significantly
is blood howl
grants stealth
for a few seconds
so what's really
cool about this
is you know
we basically added
a new mechanic
via a simple item
stat in this unique
and it combines
with the unique effect
right
so before on live
you know
you kill enemies
with shred
you go into stealth
and then you come out
and you guarantee
crit
so as you're
killing enemies
over and over
you're just
critting constantly
as you go in
and out of stealth
but you couldn't
really do that
against bosses
you had no other
ways to get
into stealth
but now we've
created an alternative
way where if you
cast blood howl
or get the blood howl
effect in other ways
you'll go into stealth
and get this proc
and now you can get
this you know
against single bosses
or in situations
you couldn't before
so we've given you
a potential way
to create your own
engine
which is pretty neat
to get those
infinite crits
next great staff
of the crone
I believe we showed
this one earlier
to people
but I just wanted
to point out
what was special
about this
storm strike
chaining to additional
targets
you know
things like this
again it's a single
stat that does
something that
kind of really
changes how the
unique works
right
you're going to
get all the
different procs
and different
effects by chaining
to more enemies
more often
you can also see
here that the
upper end of that
damage that you
could get is going
up from 150%
to 200 so it's
just better
and last but not
least we got
storm's companion
this one I again
wanted to highlight
another new thing
that we're doing
and I want to call
it here is
the lucky hit chance
for the pack leader
spirit boon
so normally we never
really manipulate
class mechanics
but here you
know this pack
leader this isn't
like a passive
or thing in the
skill tree this
isn't the spirit
boon your class
mechanic and this
increases that lucky
hit chance to get a
reset on the
cooldowns of all
your companion
skills so again
this is something
that you know
normally we don't
get to manipulate
and now you'll be
able to do and I
think it'll be
pretty cool
we have also
decided that pack
leader is two
words instead of
one
yeah everything's
getting updated
yeah everything
everything's
changing
all right moving
on to the rogue
eagle horn
let me see what
did I want to I
think just pointing
out here this was
about moving the
the tempered recipe
the penetrating shot
projectiles can cast
twice again another
example of that
and we're also giving
you a bunch of
skill ranks to
penetrating shot
again this is a way
that we're adding
just like raw power
and damage in ways
that aren't in the
unique effect
so these stats on
these things can be
very strong out the
gate and then again
tempering and
master working just
makes these go go
really really high
next word of a con
this one was a
really silly fun one
that we liked
you see there the
one I want to point
out well one is the
ultimate damage
actually ultimate
skill damage for the
rogue is kind of a
premium because they
have that paragon
node that makes it
turn into multiplicative
damage for all your
skills so that's
actually pretty meaty
it's also way higher
value than normal
also the chance for
rain of arrows waves
to cast twice
so normally we
don't do you know
chance to double
cast on ultimates
but again uniques
get to break the
rules so now you've
got you know
juiced up rain of
arrows cooldown
reduction they can
cast twice and they
hit way harder on
the rain of arrows
themed unique so
again really trying
to bring out the
theme and the
fantasy of these
uniques in the
stats in the effects
to really create
something special
and next saboteur
signet I was running
this in season four
I'm a little sad that
I'm going to be doing
something else in season
five but I loved my
stun grenade build
but here you can see
a bunch of grenade
damage obvious theme
for the grenade build
we're also giving you
a lot of your stun
grenade size here
and then again a new
affix that kind of
creates your own
engine you're getting
plus one energy when
a stun grenade
explodes and this is
each individual grenade
right so usually
release a cluster of
these things so now
again I spent a lot
of my time in season
four trying to solve
resource and get ways
to to cast this a lot
to throw out the stun
grenades and now this
kind of helps its own
engine also one thing
to point out here is
that it's no longer
just a flurry unique
it's casting a core
skill throws sling
grenades so it's a
lot more generically
applicable you can use
this with you know all
the different core
skills not just flurry
next necromancer the
big one I wanted to
point out here we're
going to be showing
both of the blood
surge uniques and
how they've been
updated and they
combo with each other
we have a stat here
that blood surge
drains more times from
elites so to be clear
this is the drain not
the explosion but the
drain does feed into
the explosion damage
and there's a lot of
like synergy and
things based on
draining enemies so
now you know one of
the problems that
blood surge has always
had is when you're
fighting a single
target or a boss you
know you only drain
one enemy and then
you're not getting
your like explosion
damage up but now
you're going to be
draining multiple
times from those
elites so you're
getting you know more
life back and other
procs when you drain
but also your explosion
will be more significant
now against them
next death speakers
pendant this is the
other blood surge
unique we also added
another thing that
combines with the
other unique where
you're getting essence
per enemy drained
right and so now as
you drain enemies for
the explosion you're
going to be getting
more essence back to
cast the skill and
spam it more we're
also giving you a
bunch of ranks to
blood surge which you
know just makes sense
so you know 50% you
know before master
working and tempering
multiplicative damage is
already a giant buff to
this but then also you
can see that you know
the numbers also went up
on this as well so it's
just going to be going to
be pretty significant
can't wait and last but
not least uh greaves of
the empty tomb this is
your sever unique lots of
stuff to point out here
one is you have multiple
inherents so you know
normally you can only get
three max of eight
charges you get more
here we also had a fun
little thing where your
evade now leaves behind
desecrated ground because
this is the desecrated
ground unique we also
have chance for sever
projectiles to cast twice
we have sever size here
we also give you ranks to
reaper's pursuit so this is
really about just like
moving and grooving like
going around one thing i
want to point out here as
well is this new aspect of
creeping mist that came in
and you can combine this
with the greaves of the
empty tomb so this new
aspect um you know we
heard that necro players
want mobility and boy did
we give you mobility so
what this does is when you
evade during first of all
you get evade cooldown
reduction so you evade more
but when you evade during
blood mist you travel twice
as far and both when you
enter and exit blood mist it
resets your evade cooldown
and one of the things that
makes this crazy where we
might actually be crazy and
i hope we don't have to
revisit this but we're going
to see is that that reset
of your evade cooldown counts
for all of your charges of
evade so what this means is
and we have a video is that
you can evade five times
then evade in blood mist and
then evade five more times
so see here then you're
evading in blood mist and
you're leaving behind that
desecrated ground everywhere
skating around you know
yeah it's like an ice skating
so every time you cast blood
mist you're going to be
getting 10 evades it's silly
and hilarious but we're
putting it in the game and
i hope we don't regret it
necros are going to be
zooming yeah they're going
to be zooming with this so
wow yeah so that's kind of
our preview of our uniques
and kind of what's coming
into the game again we're
pretty excited about it i
think it's gonna be pretty
cool yeah but yeah
professor adam jackson take
a bow that is that is
incredible and again that's
not even everything there's a
lot of stuff at that level
patch notes after the
stream we will be showing
a comparison of every
single unique and their
changes from season four to
season five so you can go
in there and check out all
those changes but that was
a great great overview of
all those changes that is
really really exciting this
brings us to our q a portion
of the show let's all shift
our legs at the same time
yeah yeah so we've been
following along in twitch chat
and we've picked out a bunch
of questions and we're gonna
kick it off tossing it over
to mr dan tangway how do
reward choices work in
multiplayer parties for
infernal hordes does the
leader choose the reward for
everyone or can each player
choose all right so yeah let's
talk about this um in the
infernal hordes when you're
collecting burning ether each
individual collects their own
burning ether and we did this
for the very reason that
you're you're asking questions
about we wanted players to be
able to go in and choose the
rewards that they want to
choose not necessarily what
somebody else gets to first or
what the party leader wants so
every individual party member
will have their own choice of
rewards
awesome awesome thanks for
letting us know
mark is you got to read the
names oh my goodness yeah did i
did i not say eldrick oh
very hard i won't forget you
thank you adam eldrick thank you
for that question
of course you're going to be a
stickler for that yeah no it's a
great thing to call out because
our ladder behind you because our
next question is from dartless or
actually i think we have a
question here on the the lower
third which is uh um this one
this one i we've gotten a lot of
these questions so i do want to
actually address this one this is
when are we going to hear more
about vessel of hatred because
you know you know we just had the
spirit born reveal we we showed off
the spirit born i will note that uh
we also are going to be at gamescom
there's actually some gamescom
news that came out this morning
uh the spirit born will be
playable at gamescom so if you go
to the xbox booth you'll be able
to play it there so if you're
you're you're attending that show
it'd be really awesome there's
actually gonna be more news coming
out uh uh at that time so of
course tune in and and i will say
like you guys have only heard a
very small now there's a lot
fraction of the tip of the jungle
yeah of uh vessel of hatred so
we're really excited for gamescom so
you guys will hear more uh then so
stay tuned yeah grab your tickets
and come to gamescom because we'll
be there i'll be super soon yes
exactly go to germany go to
germany come to cologne come to
cologne um there was some people
confused in chat uh this is a
question from dartless who was
saying we can temper uniques now
did i mishear that maybe that was a
mistake being said so adam if you
want to speak to us yeah 100%
clear cannot temper uniques we want
them to be different in that they do
not engage with that system at least
for now um but no you're going to
be what we what i wanted to say or
be clarifying is that you can get
tempering affixes on uniques like
they'll just drop with those affixes
or whatever but you can't like go to
the to the blacks with them manipulate
them in that way you can't temper
them gotcha cool cool thanks for
clarifying that
adam
yeah do do do do uh it's dafi has a
question for dan tangway are there any
plans to continue iterating on the
infernal hordes in the future since
it's a permanent addition are there
going to be more boons and banes coming
yeah that's a a great question and
yeah just to reiterate what you had
pointed out there uh this is an
eternal realm feature that's going to
appear in the game forevermore and so
this is just the first version of it i
mean you think back to what helltide
was in the base game and how we've
iterated on that over time to get it to
where it is we're going to continue
investing similar levels of effort into
the infernal hordes too and so boons and
banes is something we heard a lot about
uh feedback during the ptr and so we
absolutely want to make more
improvements to the the boons and
banes and so stay tuned um that's not
going to hit in season five uh but we'll
we'll figure out where we can get it in
in future seasons awesome great to hear
that we're going to continue uh tinkering
on that feature in the in the seasons to
come uh i've got a really interesting
question from mano underscore imp with
regards to those mano imp we know mano
with regards to the damage increase per
class resource sure they're asking is the
spirit boring getting one percent damage at
seven points if it's their main stat uh
just because they have a lower amount of
weapons yeah uh tbd tbd i don't want to
go into math on spirit born yet but uh
they'll be getting similar treatment to
all the other stuff all this is kind of
evergreen so awesome awesome uh lukey we
lukey when will we see the overhaul of
the paragon system uh would you consider
removing the paragon limit uh there are
going to be changes to paragon but we uh
aren't talking about uh those changes
yeah awesome yeah awesome tbd tbd tbd
stay tuned uh love this name chicken wing
929 love uh can the reputation rewards for
season season of the infernal hordes be
earned on only one character or all your
seasonal characters um i believe it's uh
uh all characters similar to like what we
have for season four uh so you can
actually go back in and just play like
hey go through the reputation board and
then uh get another resplendent spark
that's really the question really that's
truly the question yes you can you can
get yeah yeah nice
um systematic 5k adam jackson will our
existing uniques be updated with these
new unique changes yeah we we get this
every round that we update them it's the
same rules as always which is the unique
power when we update that is your your
existing uniques will get that right so
when we increase your damage range or
whatever that's going to get but the
stats those are going to be legacy on
any items that exist so you're going to
have to reform your unique to get the
new stats that are on them and now
that's kind of the way that they're
going to work going forward yeah say
otherwise yeah it's it's it's just how
things work under the hood yeah from
when when we do changes on them so yeah
nice
um pudge pudge underscore bp are there
any plans for clan rework slash
improvements
um there are i know there are some uh
changes coming for uh some social
features we're just not ready to talk
about them now but but you'll you guys
will hear about them soon awesome awesome
uh this one's kind of a design
philosophy question for adam jackson
sure evans423 wants to know how
future-proof is the system of static
uniques when adding new slash better
tempering effects and new content how
future-proof are static uniques when
adding new tempers um let me think
semi right because like i think it is
something where if we add like new
tempers or new affixes or whatever we
will probably need to go back and update
uniques that that we wanted to apply
to and make it you know work again
um our hope is that these uniques are
going to be pretty like future-proof
and that they're going to be very
meaty in the amount of power that they
give you um they're also extremely
thematic but i think we do reserve the
right like if we find a new idea for
uh existing passive or existing
tempering that that is introduced to
the game and we want to put it on we
can do that i will say also one thing
that we want to do more is like just
come up with really crazy new ones that
aren't even really tempering recipes
but just like crazy effects right like
blood howl grant stealth or you drain
more with your you know blood search
stuff like that so i would expect we'll
probably be updating them as we go
forward not probably as dramatically as
this all at once but i i foresee this
probably likely yeah nice yeah always
tinkering always updating uh yeah
speaking of which about tempering one
thing that we forgot to mention and i
know we mentioned it the ptr stream last
time i'm sorry my earpiece just keeps
falling off uh it's like i'm like
scratching my ear but i'm not uh the uh
greater af i know there was a lot of
like feedback after season four
regarding um uh tempering and
potentially bricking items and one
update that we talked about during the
ptr stream and i want to mention it
wasn't in ptr but is in uh season five
specifically is uh greater affixes will
actually get additional temporary
rolls on them based on the greater
affix you know quality of of what they
are so uh for for um like like greater
affix one star ones you'll end up getting
one additional temporary roll um and
then it grows by how many stars that
there are so that is going in season
five so and i we mentioned it last
stream i just wanted to reiterate it
because i actually forgot we should have
mentioned it yeah great great to mention
that adam that's awesome uh we've got a
uh easy one here from z weapons uh what is a
mythic unique there was a purple item
yeah you can tune into our last stream
for it but yeah um basically what was
uber uniques is what people call them
um it's basically like you know the
really best items in the game that have
like perfect stats and everything we
rebranded them to mythic uniques they
now have their own special color special
beam when they drop they just got a
whole treatment to really make them
feel like the the penultimate items
that that's super juicy yeah yeah
that's awesome uh sophie0257 uh are
they going to make it so that we can
pre-download the update or will it be
available only on the sixth that's a
great question that's a good based off
uh feedback from season four's launch
the patch will be available to download
roughly an hour before season of the
infernal hordes launches so that season
goes live at 10 a.m and roughly an hour
before you'll be able to pre-download the
patch to get into the game and get ready
for the season yeah i know a lot of
people are probably going like why not
multiple days and things like that we're
getting there we're trying but now it's
it's it's uh we we got a lot of feedback
about you know how things started
immediately on the like you could
download and actually start the season
of course we want to make sure that
people can be as prepared as possible so
uh one hour before the actual uh season
starts like you should be able to
actually download and get that all
prepared so like soon as um uh the season
the the time for the season begin which is
roughly like 10 a.m pacific on on the day of uh
you you can just jump in without needing
to download so yeah yeah uh skull mtv hey
great job thanks uh any plans to rework
master working in brackets higher cost but
you know you can choose upgrades and
tempering to make these systems have less
rng um nothing to announce at this time
we definitely have heard the feedback we
are starting with the first step of like
you know one of the things that we know
feels really bad for players like i got a
uh how do i say the more greater
affixes you have on an item the higher
stress and investment you have to like
make it work the way that you want so we
are relaxing that make it a little bit
easier um another thing that we're
thinking about that's a little lighter is
like the tempering recipes making them
have like three on average instead of
four or more um something that we're
talking about moving towards but nothing
like of overhauling the system and doing
a major change at this time that we have
to announce cool thanks adam uh dan tangway
from holy smokes uh their name isn't for
holy smokes their name is i thought it was
dan tangway asking a question and i was
like wait what no no no uh their name is
frodo bolson frodo bolson but all the
o's are zeros all right uh how does the
infernal hordes work in groups uh do you
need one only one compass per group
um so the infernal hordes you only need
one compass per group in order to be able
to get in yeah sweet just like uh
nightmare dungeon sigils awesome all right
revask any news on reworked nightmare
dungeons
nothing nothing for today yeah nothing to
announce today and nothing to announce
yeah sweet uh green zombie studios can we
expect cool new transmogs in season five
from salvaging items
um i am not sure i know like the the season
five does have over has a lot of new
legendary aspects and uniques like there's
like 50 new legendary aspects and uniques
being added into season five so there's a
lot of of like uh more the the back end type
of stuff that that affects a lot more so on
the gameplay but i'm not exactly sure if
there's a ton coming yeah so we can
actually uh there are a couple of um
new uniques and hell uh that you can earn that
will have all new looks to them that you
can sell the jerry got cosmetic yep bam
there you go dan the savior from albany
there you go froto bolson uh hot pancakes
are there still plans for rare and magic
items i guess in terms of like a rework or
changing their functionality in any way
yeah i'd say nothing to announce today for
that yeah cool nice
all right uh checking through mac and d's
uh can we expect skill trees or support
gems to change the way skills work
can we expect skill trees or support
gems to change the way the skill works i
mean we're not doing any skill tree
overhaul right now in season five um i do
think we have talked a bit on the team
about having the desire of the the
upgrades for skills being like more
impactful and really impactful um nothing
to announce today but it is something that
is on our radar and i think is cool i think
one example that that we talk about a lot
on the team is like the kick upgrade for
the barbarian where normally you know when
we originally designing kick it was this
idea that you have this like skill where
you hit an enemy and you care about the
geometry of the place around you and you
want to hit them into the wall and then
they get knocked down take a bunch of
damage and all this stuff
um that part hasn't really played i think as
well because the pace of our game is so
fast but one of the upgrades for kick um
especially i remember in the early beta like
way before maybe it was alpha even um kick you
know it converts kick from this cooldown based
geometry skill into just a powerhouse where it
just spends all your resource and does a buttload of damage to an
enemy um and it was like one-shotting world
bosses and stuff back then like it was it was hilarious i think i remember that but the the the skill still has that upgrade but i reference that upgrade a lot a lot
because i think it's really cool when you can convert a skill to like used to be
cooldown and now isn't or used to be about this utility and now it's just damage or
vice versa where it like really changes what a skill does um we think it's really cool it
definitely would be a lot of work to like do that to every skill but i think it's
something that's worth talking about and pursuing so it is on our radar of
something to do but nothing to announce today for it awesome that's really cool
thanks adam yeah uh and that brings us to the end of our q a so i want to give a
huge thank you to adam and adam and dan uh for answering all those questions adam
squared adam squared back in action hey just like the ptr stream yeah there you
go screw those joes got them yeah
and that brings us to the end of our season the infernal hordes developer update stream just
a few notes before we close out the stream i just want to take a moment to thank everyone
for tuning into our spirit born showcase a few weeks back yeah it was really cool to show off
that new class it was such a huge moment for the team uh so really want to thank you all for uh
coming to check that out and if you want to play the spirit born in person as adam mentioned earlier
we are going to be a gamescom so get your tickets come to gamescom in cologne germany and
uh just went up through the roof um but speaking of the spirit born uh you can pre-purchase vessel of
hatred today and instantly oh can they hear audio oh can everybody hear us twitch chat where did the
sound go okay we're good yeah we're good okay we're good awesome all right thank you chat for for
keeping us up to date uh speaking of the spirit born you can pre-purchase vessel of hatred today
to get instant access to some items in game before the expansion goes live this october for season
the infernal hordes this season goes live on august 6th at 10 a.m the patch will be available for pre
download roughly an hour before and 10 a.m is in pacific time uh for anyone wondering patch will be
available for pre pre-download about an hour before the season goes live so you can get in and get
ready for the season to start uh the 150 patch notes are going to go live after this stream
yeah for season five so for anything we talked about uh across the stream today that'll be available
and see all the uniques and everything yeah check out those gifts they're pretty they're pretty spiffy
teamwork pretty hard on those we also had the season the infertile hordes deep dive blog go live
earlier this week so a ton of information there as well uh stick around after the stream because we're
going to be rating uh some diablo content creators so go and check them out for adam and
adam and mr dan tangway and albany thank you guys so much for joining us uh for this developer
update stream today yeah thank you so much really awesome to go through all the changes and uh from
all of us here thank you so much uh to everyone at home for watching and checking out the stream
and we will see you all in sanctuary yeah yeah nix woo