Okay, ladies and gentlemen, we are here with the boy Adam Jackson.
Thank you for coming on, Adam.
How are you doing today?
Hey, I'm doing great.
How are you guys doing?
Doing pretty good.
Fantastic.
Excited.
The interview questions are going to start because I know we're a little early.
We're about four minutes and it's early, so we're just going to have a couple minute intro
while the people row in here.
It will be starting at exactly 1 p.m. PST.
But outside of that, how has the day been for you?
Very easy icebreaker, so we would waste the three minutes before we get going.
Yeah, totally.
It's been wild.
We've got so much stuff going on between working on season four, more seasons and things coming
up in the future.
Lots of planning, lots of talks.
The season's going to be coming out soon.
I expect a whole lot of feedback and reaction to that, so it's a busy time over here, but
pretty exciting as well.
Nice, man.
It sounds like you guys are going to have a pretty interesting launch because season four
is coming out here very shortly, and I think itemization is going to be the big talk.
We do have some questions related to both itemization, what's going to be next, etc.,
for you to go through here on the list.
Before we get started, we have to do a quick thing and make sure everyone here can hear
the audio just fine.
Can you hear Ghazi?
So, Ghazi, can you say a sentence?
I can say a sentence.
Absolutely.
Super excited for the release.
Minions.
That's all I'm saying.
And Adam, literally anything at all you want to say?
Yeah.
Test, test.
I also am a minion enjoyer, it turns out.
So, I've heard.
I'm excited to talk about him.
I don't know.
Don't get Ghazi started on minions when we get going, man.
We've spent like the last few days, so I've told DM, you got to make sure that I don't
go off on a rant here because we're going to spend the next 45 minutes on that topic.
So, we've done our best to make sure we don't get stuck there.
Okay.
I'm trying to keep him on a leash from the whole thing being a necromancer interview,
but we'll do what we have to do.
I get it.
Everyone has their thing.
Some people look like Druid Wolves.
Some people look like Necromanion.
Some people look like Breaking the Game with Barb permanently.
Everybody's got their thing.
All right.
So, with that being said, I think we've stalled enough to let the people roll in.
If you're not here by now, we're just going to get going.
We kind of had just, we're wasting a minute or two because we're a couple minutes early.
But with that being said, thank you, everyone, for joining across the different livestream
platforms for this interview with Blizzard's own Adam Jackson.
Before we get going, you wanted to say who you are, what your job is over there for the
people that, for some reason, don't happen to know.
Yeah, totally.
So, hi, everybody.
My name is Adam Jackson.
I'm the lead class designer, specifically on the live classes team.
So, our group handles a lot of the update, pretty much all the balance updates that you
see going into the game for classes.
We also are heavily involved in systems and the stuff that you see, really, in seasonal
and expansion releases that have to do with the things that you farm and why and the classes
themselves and the new Legendary's uniques going in, that kind of stuff.
And Ghazi, introduce yourself for the people that don't know.
Minion Andy, I guess, is the easiest way to describe it.
I do mostly rethink guys' classes for ARPG games, mostly for Path of Exile Diablo 4,
Lost Epoch, recently. Just a hard minion to enjoy.
I can't get enough of it.
Minion Andy Ghazi. And then, of course, I'm DM.
And with that being said, we're going to get going.
So, thank you, first of all, for joining us for the interview.
It is now 1 p.m. PST.
We're going to start with our first question.
So, right out of the get-go, we have some questions.
Hopefully, we can get to all of them.
If we don't, it's all good.
We're going to start with the first one here, which is,
with the recent focus of gameplay being post-100, the 1 to 50 process,
a little faster than it used to be on launch, right?
What are the team's thoughts on progressing the Paragon system?
An example being like new Paragon boards, etc.
Yeah.
So, I think there's definitely room, I believe.
And this is, like, my personal opinion talking here.
But I think that there's definitely room to make Paragon more interesting.
Adding new boards and things is always on the table.
That is something that we can do.
And probably is something that we will do.
But the way that we kind of think of Paragon is that it's kind of your one-stop shop
where we try to make stats cool, right?
Like, why you care about strength, why you care about whatever stats you're chasing.
Like, it's one of those places where we try to make it a little bit more interesting and robust.
I think we did a decent job at the launch game with Paragon,
but I think that there's more that we could add to the depth of the system
to make it just more appealing.
You know, we did a little bit of that in Season 2, if you remember.
We started adding scaling mechanics where we turned some of your stats
that are always additive into multiplicative scaling stats,
like usually in Legendary Paragon nodes and other places.
But that's kind of a little bit of experimentation in that regard.
I would expect that we do more in the future.
Of course, nothing to announce, but that's kind of how we're thinking about it right now,
is that it's cool.
We think there's more opportunity to do cool things there.
Something simple like adding new boards, yeah.
I don't think there's really a high risk there,
and it's something that I could totally see us doing.
I'm curious to the idea of the further development of the Paragon system,
because I know in the interview you had with Rax,
the question regarding the skill tree was that the idea was to not further develop that,
at least not too much, for the sake of newer and newer players.
And then after level 50, we see a progression of that part be in the game,
focus for the company.
But how do you see that,
well, how does the team think about the progression of that development
without making it too advanced for those players?
Yeah, good question.
Paragon board sits in a different place than the skill tree, right?
Skill tree is like the very first thing you're introduced to as a player.
So keeping that experience really easy to understand and robust
for someone that's never played an ARPG before
is a much harder task compared to Paragon,
where Paragon, you've already gotten pretty far into the game
or beat the campaign is our expectation.
So we're allowed to add more complexity at that point in the game.
That being said, there are some UX issues
that I think we know about with Paragon.
It can be a pain to reset and fill in all the many little blips that you have to.
I think those are actually more concerning issues
that I would rather see us tackle than only adding new content.
I think we can do both, of course.
But these are kinds of the things of the problems
that we're looking to solve, I guess you could say, with Paragon.
Simplicity is always a factor
because we do want people to understand our game
and ARPGs are notoriously crunchy.
But if there is a place that we can be a little crunchier,
I would say it is in Paragon,
if anywhere in our game, if that makes sense.
That's fair.
We can move on to the next question that we have is
that as many people are planning their builds in Season 4,
we would like to ask for some clarity pre-launch
regarding tempering affixes,
mostly due to the fact that the patch notes stated
that they'd be balanced but lack specific details.
And I guess the same question applies to core modifiers
such as ranks of Golem Mastery
being available on multiple item slots.
Yeah, lots of people like to ask about Golem Mastery.
So I guess what I would say is
when it comes to patch notes
and what we show to players between PTR and live
is that we kind of have rules and guidelines
for how we present patch notes
and what we put in them between releases.
And PTR is kind of a special case
because PTR, we're introducing new content to you
for the first time,
but then the live patch is actually
when we introduce that content for real.
And I'm using air quotes, right?
Because not everybody is expected to play the PTR.
PTR is also notoriously not balanced
because it's way earlier in development
than when we would normally release something.
And so managing expectations
and how we present patch notes
is something that we're still figuring out.
And what that really means is
when we introduce whole new systems to the game,
we don't specify every single little detail of them.
As an example, in the PTR,
when we introduce the recipes,
we don't list every single tempering recipe
and what the numbers are right now in the PTR notes
because our notes are already huge.
It would blow them out and make them way bigger, right?
And then if we don't put them in PTR,
but then we put them in live,
then we blow out those notes.
And then it's like, well, why didn't you put them in PTR?
And then if we only show the difference,
like only show the things that we change,
then people are wondering,
well, why did you only show
like half the tempering recipes?
Those are the ones that you change,
but you're not showing the rest.
And then it can get confusing of like,
well, where are the rest of the recipes, right?
Like, why don't you just show it all?
And so like, it's an easy kind of thing
to get caught up in what we show.
So in the future, I think we can show more.
It just means that we would have to like commit
to showing that in the PTR,
which then means there's more pressure on the PTR release
to have those things in a better state
and actually quantify out the bigger list of changes, right?
So it depends.
But as far as like specifics,
if you want to know some of the things
like that are changing with tempering,
there's a whole lot of number changes.
Most of them are minor
and aren't really that big of a deal.
We did shift around where a few of the recipes
or not, yeah, like what stats are
and what recipes and that kind of stuff
to make more sense based on feedback.
And then we did adjust some things
that were just the typical,
this is early in development
and wasn't intended at all,
but it's PTR.
So, you know, this is when you get to see it.
The ranks of Golem Mastery is in that category.
I think people were getting crazy,
like 25 plus or something ranks.
No, it's supposed to be just like
every single other passive that you get.
It's only in, you know, very few slots
and it's very special when you get it.
So, you know, if you were planning on making a Golem build
where they slam for 2 billion damage,
you're not going to do it via mastery ranks.
But I'm sure there's other ways
to still make things crazy.
Guys, he got his minion.
He got his minion question
and he got an answer there nice and early.
Got it out of the way.
So, since we're talking about the PTR,
I just want to slip an additional follow-up to that.
Did you guys get out of the PTR
what you were hoping to get?
I know the players were excited
to actually get their hands on the PTR
and test it out, etc.
But I'm curious if you guys got
what you were hoping to get out of launching a PTR.
Oh, absolutely.
Absolutely.
In spades.
When we released very large swaths of the game,
like I would say the launch was the closest to this.
Season 2 was moderately close to this.
But I think this is bigger than that
because we updated all of itemization, right?
We gave people stats and powers
that they never had access to.
Not limited to uniques where we can very control.
Like, hey, you get this very specific,
special, powerful thing.
But in items like, you know,
tempering affixes and things
where we let you get bonus projectiles
across the board or area size,
those are very high-risk things
from our point of view.
And by risk, I mean like,
not only are they scary because of balance,
but they're scary because of like PC performance
and breaking servers and stuff.
Because a lot of our game wasn't made in mind
with every projectile could not just have one more,
but be doubled in the amount.
Or, you know, the size of these skills
were handcrafted to be, this is the size.
And, you know, when you have a back alley deal,
like, yep, we're never going to do that again.
Have a handshake.
We're never going to increase it, whatever,
because this is what the size is going to be.
And then we're like, oh, wait,
we want to double it and do more than that.
We did more than double in PTR.
We didn't even have a cap.
And so we have to figure out, like,
how we're going to manage these things
for the long term and be healthy in the game.
PTR was incredibly helpful for that.
We got a ton of balance feedback, which is nice.
But I would say the bigger important one was,
like, how does the game feel?
Like, the playing through the whole experience
of temporary master working and that progression.
You know, we can have an idea of it,
but, you know, when you have, you know,
50, 100, 200, even 1,000 people playing it,
it's not nearly as much information
as you would think compared to, like,
10 million people playing it, right?
Or whatever.
Like, when you throw numbers at something,
you really see the cracks very quickly
and very easily, and they're more clear.
Whereas when we're only testing things internally,
we'll be like, oh, this could be a problem,
or, oh, this doesn't feel great,
but it might be fine, right?
Like, we can have a discussion,
and we're using our brains and figuring it out,
but we don't have the surety that we do
when we throw a ton of people at it,
especially people who are experts on ARPGs,
like you guys and, you know, our other creators
and even just hardcore community members
that really like to crunch these numbers
and figure things out.
They'll find things in five minutes
that might take us five days, right?
So it's just efficient.
So, yeah.
Short answer, yes, incredibly useful.
I appreciate the insight on that one.
So moving on to the next question here.
So one of the major things that are happening
in Season 4 is obviously itemization.
That rework is now being complete with Loot Reborn.
What would you guys like to focus on next
as your next sort of major focus?
Yeah.
That's a really good question.
I can't get super specific details,
but I can give you ideas of how we're thinking
about things right now.
Sure.
Immediate future, I think actually the focus of the team
is on reacting to Season 4
and this big upheaval that we made to the game.
I am very sure that there will be cracks
in tempering and masterworking
and the player journey as far as, you know,
the pit and how all of this feels when put together
of like how good the game actually is.
And those cracks are going to need to be iterated on
and filled a little bit of like,
hey, you know, we need more tempering recipes here
or hey, the progression of the pit
doesn't feel that great there or whatever, right?
Our immediate thing is
because we upheavled so much in our game,
you know, your whole end game way
that you interact with Diablo 4
and your item progression is now a journey
rather than just you hope the perfect item drops
and you're done.
Those are huge foundational things in ARPG.
So making those and refining those to be good
is the immediate largest concern
by a pretty good amount.
Like when you, I think when you look at like
what we're thinking of with updates with Season 5,
right now I'm being a little bit cagey of like,
I need to leave some reaction time for my team
and myself to like really look at Season 4
of what are the things that we need to react to quickly
that would be the most benefit,
you know, the biggest bane for your buck in Season 5,
for example.
But thinking a little bit more long-term,
like things that aren't immediate reactions to Season 4,
I would say, you know,
we're definitely taking a stab at it in Season 4,
but I think that there's still going to be room
to try and make the end game better for longer,
like have that tail feel good
for a longer period of time
and have a little bit more refinement
in that section of the game, so to speak.
So we're thinking and talking a lot about that
because it's been a thing that we've been,
you know, asked about by the community basically
since we launched,
it's like better end game, better end game,
better end game.
And so that's something that's on our mind.
Also on the class side, personally,
one of the things that's on my mind a lot
is trying to catch up other classes to Barbarian
because Barbarians have more weapons.
This has been a big thorn in our side
for a very long time
of that they kind of have two class mechanics
and everybody else has one.
And so our current plan is to kind of juice up
those other classes
so that they're really crazy impactful and good
and feel awesome
so that they kind of make up
for the lack of aspects that Barbarians get.
And itemization makes Barbarians stronger.
Like there's a bunch of things
that having more items
makes difficult to balance, I would say.
And so really having a firm, solid answer to that.
We kind of addressed it a little bit
in season four with the Necromancer
is our first whack at this
where we just juiced the Book of the Dead
and made it crazy, powerful, and good
and tried to do it in a way
that wasn't just numbers,
you know, like make it cool, right?
It's something that I told my people
a lot to focus on.
And so we're going to see how that goes
but I want to do that for the other classes, right?
So that's kind of one of the big things
at the top of our mind on the class side.
So with in-game...
Oh, sorry, go ahead, Ghazi.
I was just curious.
Like we talk about endgame,
that's the focus.
Endgame, endgame, endgame.
I'm curious about the definition.
Like what are we talking about
when we say endgame?
Because that's different from...
It's very subjective, right?
Are we talking about level 50 to 100
or are we talking about post 100?
Yep.
So funny you ask.
I think Joe P mentioned in an earlier interview,
we used to think of endgame
as everything after the campaign
was our original definition
when we launched the game.
And we had to change our definition
because that wasn't what players
were thinking and saying
and the way that just people
talked about our game.
They thought endgame was post 100
or maybe world tier 4, right?
And right now I would say
it's still not exactly perfect
of what we think of when we say endgame.
I think people still have various opinions.
My definition of endgame
is probably something close
to world tier 4
and when that starts
or when you get to level 100
is an obvious benchmark
that people can have.
But in my mind,
it's when you have access
to all of the activities
that you can do in the game,
which to me would now probably be
whenever you go into the pit
because there's no activity after that
that is like a new activity
that you could not access at all.
So that's what I think of
when I think of endgame.
But I think if you ask 10 different people,
you may get like three
or four different answers.
But that's kind of how we think about it
and talk about it mostly on the team.
Either that or level 100,
you know,
if you want to think about it that way.
So how do you deal with the difficulty
of creating endgame
when players are able
to consume the content
quicker than almost any developer
is going to be able
to produce the endgame
while also shrinking
the beginning portion of the game?
You level to 100 faster
than you ever have.
You're able to get into
these endgame activities
faster than ever,
but you're also at a deficit
in terms of endgame content.
So you're developing it
while people are consuming it
faster than you can.
How do you resolve these issues?
Oh, God.
This is a very long answer,
and I could go into it
for a long time,
so I'll try to keep it brief.
It's a very difficult problem,
and it is one that I think
every ARPG has,
and it's one that we all
have to kind of live with
and mitigate,
but there isn't a perfect
forever solution.
Because really,
what you're saying is,
and this is like the two things
that are competing, right,
is players want content,
and our game is a power fantasy.
That's what ARPGs are, right?
We sell you on,
you do things to become
more powerful,
to have a new mountain to climb,
to be more powerful,
to have a new mountain to climb.
Problem is,
there are only so many mountains
that we can make
as a development team, right?
Because the mountains
are usually content.
And so the difficulty
that I think every ARPG runs into
is you can only create
so many mountains.
So the first thing we try to do
is create as many mountains
as we can, right?
Have as many various
endgame activities
and things for you to do
that are interesting and awesome,
and then, you know,
do that for as long as we can.
But like you said,
people are crazy,
and they consume content
really, really quick.
Some of them do,
some of them not so much,
and we have to balance
between those two player types,
which is a whole other conversation.
But then on the other side,
you know,
for the people that can consume
that content quickly,
we want to make sure
that there's things for them to do
that are interesting and meaningful, right?
And so this is why you see
a very common way
that ARPGs are designed
is that we use
random generated dungeons
and random generated content
for the endgame.
And why we do things
like scale things
either pretty hard or infinitely
so that you have a challenge
against your player power, right?
Like player power goes up,
you need something to fight against it
as you're getting better.
If you don't have something
to fight against it,
then really your answers are like,
make another character
and do the journey again,
or you get bored,
leave, come back later, right?
And those are kind of the options
that a player has,
or, you know,
go against infinitely scaling content.
That's kind of like the box
that we're in when we're designing.
And a lot of our work as designers
is how do we make fun content
and resolve these issues
as best we can.
A perfect solution
is what requires
like a paradigm shift,
I think of like,
you have to kind of change
what an ARPG is
and like make your game ARPG,
but also a little bit
of something else
so that you don't have to worry
about this problem.
But in an ARPG space,
I think this is kind of just
what it is
and how people progress through it
is a challenge
that we're forever going to have.
And so you're going to see us,
you know,
kind of bounce back and forth
of like infinitely scaling content,
but also matching that
with milestone content
or aspirational content
is another word
that people like to use
that I like,
of, you know,
like Uber Lilith
or these things
where it's like,
I get this thing,
I see this thing,
it's a fixed difficulty,
I want to get good enough
to beat that
and then I feel good
and I can either stop
or try and go to the next thing
until there's things that run out
and then I'm happy
and I leave happy, right?
Our goal at the higher level
is that you leave happy, right?
And whether that means
you're doing aspirational
or you do forever content
for a while
and then you kind of churn out,
we want to make sure
both of those experiences
feel good.
Sure.
That's fair.
Listening to that answer,
I mean,
do you feel like,
or would it be fair to say
that the team's focus
on effort right now
has gone from the early stage
of focusing on new player acquisition
to more of a returning player focus
and endgame replayability
and longevity of the player base?
Is that where the focus is?
Would that be fair to say?
We're focused on both.
I think my team right now
is focused on the latter part,
but remember Diablo 4
is a large team
with many different sub-teams.
I'm on the live team,
so my focus right now
is kind of endgame
because that's just
what we see as a place
we could do better,
but there are people
on the team
absolutely focused
on new player experience,
new player,
how they interact
with the game,
returning players
that have,
you know,
they played the original campaign
and then left
and they're coming back.
That's a discussion
that we're having as well
of how do we make that experience
the best that we can,
so there's actually
a lot of different classes
of players
and the types of people
that play Diablo 4
because it's such a large game.
You know,
we're trying to appeal
to many different types
of people that play RPGs
and even those
that this is their
introductory game,
so our task
is a little different
than some other games
where, you know,
they have a more specific focus.
We try to grab it all.
We're greedy,
but, you know,
we want to make sure
that our game's good
for both parties
and that does mean
there's some sacrifices sometimes,
but we really are, like,
trying to make it good
for all of them.
That's fair.
It's a hard problem,
but that is actually
what we're trying to do,
like high-level vision.
Let's just move on
to the next question
since we're kind of
limited on time.
Yeah.
Let's talk about
overworld content
since that is literally
the identity defining
for Diablo 4, right?
And the question we have
is what are the team's
thoughts on the potentials
of strongholds and bosses
having a bigger role
to play moving forward?
Oh, strongholds and bosses.
I guess I'll ask you
a question back.
I can give you
a very easy answer,
and that answer will be
we think they're cool
and we can work on them,
or I can give you, like,
something I think
is a lot more interesting
than maybe an in-depth discussion.
I'll leave it up to you guys.
Let's go for the latter.
Yeah.
All right.
Because I find this
very interesting.
Why strongholds,
why we design them
and what we think about them
in Borah bosses.
So I think there's a concept
that's very interesting.
I would advise you
and anyone that any
of your followers
who really want to get
into game design
or want to talk better
about game design,
there was a really great
GDC presentation
made by a guy named
Alex Jaffe.
He's from Riot, actually.
And he gave one of the best
presentations I've ever seen
on game design.
And he gave a presentation
on something called
cursed problems
in game design.
And I promise this
will lead back to strongholds
very directly.
But what a cursed problem
is in game design
is this idea that
when you make a game
of a certain archetype,
you immediately make
a bunch of promises
to the player.
And these promises
come with problems
that we call cursed problems.
They're these things
that are so fundamental
to the foundation
of your game
that you can't get away
from them.
And they're kind of
your partner forever
or weight on your back
that you have to deal with
that you never get rid of.
But you can mitigate.
I'll give an example
of a cursed problem
in another genre and game.
I used to work on
Heroes of the Storm.
It's a MOBA, right?
Like League of Legends.
If you ever played
League of Legends,
you'll hear this complaint
a lot of matchmaking
and playing a team-based game
by having individual progression, right?
The promise that you make
when you play a MOBA
or a team-based game
is that you are playing
with other people.
But one of the big things
that they sell you on
when you play the game
is that you have
a ranking system
that's based on
your personal improvement.
So you're being ranked
individually,
but you go into a team game
with nine other people
and those other people
can interact
and you can have a game
where you couldn't have won
no matter how good you are
because those gay people
impact your performance.
And so you commonly
get the complaint of,
hey, I went into
a team-based game.
I did well,
but my teammates suck
and I'm mad
because I lost ranking points, right?
I played League of Legends.
It's very common.
This is a cursed problem
of matchmaking-based,
team-based games
where your motivation
that we promise you
is individual performance.
How about Diablo?
Let's tie it back to Diablo.
A cursed problem,
I would argue,
in ARPGs like Diablo
and any other game,
you'll probably have seen
this problem,
is that they are games
of efficiency.
We promise you
player power
is a big reason
why you play these games.
If you want to go in,
you start off
as this peon person
that kind of sucks
and isn't very strong
and you grow into
this really crazy
master of magic
or strength or whatever
that can do
incredible things, right?
And the way that we deliver
you on that promise
is we give you power
as you play the game more
and progress through
the activities,
usually in the form of gear
but also in other ways too, right?
Skill points, paragon,
whatever it is.
What that translates to
is that anything
that you are doing
in the game
that isn't progressing
your power
is very hard
to sell a player on
to make them
want to do it.
And it's even harder
to sell them
if it's not
a repeatable activity
that they can keep doing
to get stronger
and stronger.
The way that I describe
curse problems
or think about it
is like when you ask me,
hey Adam,
what do you think
of strongholds
or world bosses
or uber lilith balance
or a whole lot
of other problems,
I would think of
these curse problems
like a tree
and the curse problem
is actually the trunk,
the center of the game,
what the game actually is
and why you come to play it
and you're asking me
about a leaf
at the very edge
of the branch
and so I can give an answer
like yeah,
the leaf,
yeah, it's cool,
we can work on it
but like really
the leaf connecting
to the branch,
connecting to the trunk,
this is what's actually
causing the thing
that you're asking
the question about,
right?
So when it comes
to strongholds,
why are strongholds,
why do you ask me
the question like,
hey, what about strongholds,
can we make them better?
The reason why
it's a question
that people ask,
I think,
is because people,
strongholds are intended
and why they are cool
and why they go against
the rest of our game
and why it's really hard
for us is that
they are meant to be
one-shot,
awesome,
kind of story-based,
really hand-crafted,
curated content,
right?
I would equate this
to Uberlilla statues
where we got this question
the other day,
the campaign experience,
we get a question,
these are all actually
the same question,
which is,
hey,
you people on D4
made this one-shot experience
that we really love
and is cool,
we want to do it more.
The problem is,
the moment you cross that line
from one-shotting
and it being cool
to being a repeatable activity,
now that activity
is competing
with everything else
in the game
that is repeatable content.
Because now,
strongholds has to compete
against Helltide,
Nightmare Dungeons,
The Pit,
Gathering Uniques,
all of that,
or has to fit in there
in some way.
So one question
about that then,
so what makes
strongholds different?
Like,
why can't we do
an Uber version
of a stronghold
since people say
they want to replay it,
but we can do
an Uber version
of bosses
that are already
in the game.
So we can do the level...
We absolutely,
yeah,
I understand your question,
we absolutely can,
is the answer.
But then,
you've changed it,
the fundamental relationship
that you have as a player
with strongholds
is different now.
You've changed it
from one shot,
this is a cool experience,
that's very unique,
and that is what
the fantasy is
of people that like it,
now you've changed that
to repeatable content
that you're going to do
10, 20, 100 times over.
And the thing is,
a lot of content,
and this is where
it's kind of a curse problem
in the RPG,
we think of every content type
that we add this way.
Is it repeatable?
Is it not?
And the way that you design
that content
is very different.
Because if it's repeatable,
that means that you have
to design the content
in such a way
that it is fun
100 or 1000 times.
That puts a lot more
design constraint
and limitations
of what you can make
that content.
As an example,
or many examples
when you launch the game,
you can even think
of some when you
think of your experience
with the game.
When you do something
500 times,
you care about things
that you wouldn't care about
if you did it one time.
This is why,
for example,
I get questions a lot
of why can't,
can you let us reset boss rooms?
Why do you want
to reset boss rooms?
It's because you do it
500 times and it sucks
to do that every single time.
If you had to do it
one or two times ever,
you wouldn't care very much.
Why did you have to
ride your horse
to Nightmare Dungeons
when we launched the game?
It's fair.
It was fun the first time.
World building,
immersion,
really cool.
Doing it 500 times
because that's all
that you're doing
at your end game,
not so fun.
So would you be concerned
about the same issue
with the new 200 bosses
if let's say
you took some of the rewards
and added like an Uber,
just for the sake
of the debate here.
So let's say
we wanted Uber Strongholds
and you say,
well, you know,
DM,
you liked it the first time.
You might not like it
the 100th time
and I say,
fair enough.
But then I come back
with you and say,
okay,
well,
what if we took
some of the rewards
I would either get
from the pit,
like a grab bag.
We take some of the pit rewards,
take some of the Uber
level 200 rewards
and we throw almost
like a world boss
loop pinata
as an option
to be one of these mountains
that you mentioned earlier.
Maybe we don't want
to make it the best thing.
Maybe we want to make it
a breakup of the experience
so that we can get
basically the same resources
we got to get
literally anyway
from something else.
But it gives us variety
in terms of gameplay.
Now I'm not arguing
this is the best way
to go with the game.
I'm just curious
about the thought process
behind that.
I think that's a good question.
The answer is yes,
we can.
Sometimes it works,
sometimes it doesn't.
Usually it doesn't.
But the reason why
in my experience
designing ARPGs
for a while now
is it's really hard
to tell somebody,
hey, you have option A
and option B.
Option A is 100% efficient.
Option B is 70% efficient.
What does 100% of players do?
Maxroll makes guides.
What is the best
nightmare dungeon
you want to do?
Everybody makes guides.
What is the quickest way
to do the thing?
What is the most efficient?
People are going to do the thing
and it's not like
if something is 100% efficient
versus 50%,
that 50% of players
do the 50%
and the other half
do the 100%.
That's not how it works out
in player behavior.
It's 99% of people
do the 100% efficient.
That's a fair counter.
I'm not sure I agree entirely.
I'm a player that
I guess I would qualify
as a blaster
and not a casual player.
But I feel like
what makes an ARPG great
is to make people
distracted from the fact
that they are playing an ARPG.
Because in reality,
an ARPG game
is honestly
the very definition
of insanity.
We are doing the same thing
over and over and over again
with the only goal
of improving our character
to continue doing
the same thing
over and over again
to do the same thing.
And the best ARPG
is the game
that you can play
would be a game
where you are distracted
from the fact
that you're doing
the same thing
over and over again.
So having options
whether or not
they are slightly less rewarding
is another part.
That's another topic.
But the fact
that you have options
to engage with
for the sake of in-game
replayability,
longevity
would allow you
to be distracted
from that fact
and actually enjoy your time.
That's the way I see it.
So I'm not sure
I entirely agree with that.
I completely agree with you.
I want to premise this.
I'm presenting to you
the problem.
I'm not saying that
a cursed problem
has no solutions
and no ways
to make it better.
The bulk of my time
is spent trying to
answer the questions
that you guys just asked
and do it in a way
that does make it better
even though I know
it's a problem
that will never be
completely absolutely solved.
We do do things like this.
Some ways, for example,
that we get you to do
a variety of activities
because we do want you to
is like a common strategy
is we gate certain rewards
behind certain activities
which makes you
you need to go
and do multiple things.
Right?
Like you have glyph XP
and nightmare dungeons.
You have the helltide
the cinders and helltide
that you couldn't really get
very easily.
We have things
that are special to them
to make you go around.
I think a better solution
we've kind of moved
a little bit more
in this is you
you can get things
you get some activities
or materials
or whatever
from many places.
There is one place
that is the most efficient
but you're getting
pseudo-efficiency
somewhere else
and that feels really good.
Example of this
would be doing helltides
with whispers.
Right?
If you're doing helltides
and you want Varshan materials
for whispers
double dipping on that
feels really good
as a player
and we want to do that
and do that more
and that I think
is kind of an answer
for your uber strongholds question
is I'm not saying
by the way
my answer is not
we can't do uber strongholds
because of these problems.
What I'm saying is
I'm trying to teach you
why it's not so easy
as just like
hey make uber strongholds
replayable
and now everybody's
going to level them immediately.
Right?
We were changing
a content type
from a one shot
this is kind of
similar to the campaign idea
of changing the campaign experience
from a one shot
to a feels good
a hundred times
we have to think about
that we think about
that content differently now.
Totally.
And that requires
a little more thought
and care
not just in rewards
but how it feels
to go through it
over and over again
right?
Because it's fixed.
That's fair enough.
We need to add some randomness
to make it feel better
as you're going through it
over and over again.
It makes sense.
There's more problems
that we have to solve.
It's a design consumable
you make it into
something repetitive
it changes the fundamentals
of how you originally
created it.
I can understand the take.
I appreciate that.
I'll move the conversation
on here
so we can get into
some of the other questions
we still have here.
So currently
build variety in the game
is mostly designed
around item modifier.
So like unique items
with this wall
it's been one example.
It just fundamentally
changes the way
its skill works here.
Has there been discussion
from the team
around modifying skills
potentially outside
of unique items
like within Paragon boards
other inventory based items
whatever you want to call it?
Yeah.
Fun fact
when we were originally
designing things
in the game
a lot of the changing
of the skills
was actually in the skill tree
and in the
we called them
maybe choices
but you know
the different upgrades
you could get
for your skill.
the original
thought behind it
was like
you know
you can make your
frozen orb
like option A
is like
way different
than option B
where they're almost
like different use cases
for the skill.
Right?
And we moved
a little bit away
from that.
Some of them
are still a little
transformative.
I think that we can
make them a little bit
more so in the skill tree
as we do in the future.
That's one way
that I think we can
make the skill tree
interesting
without introducing
a bunch of complexity.
My favorite example
I give to people
on my team
is a kick.
You know
kick isn't that
popular of a skill
but the difference
between baseline kick
and power kick
the upgrade
where it changes
into basically
a core skill
where it uses
all your resource
and does a buttload
of damage to a person.
You know
you went from
thinking of
you know
this skill is like
you think of the
geometry of the game
and kicking enemies
into walls
and it was too complex
I think a little bit
for what we launched
with the speed
of our game.
But the idea
was there of like
one way is
you're playing
4D chests
and you're rewarded
and the other way
is you chase a resource
and you just
you know
this is Sparta
somebody
and kill them
for a billion damage
right?
It's completely
different fantasies
and ways that you
interact with a skill.
I think we could
probably do a little
bit more there
with other skills
to kind of make
them transformative
like that.
We ended up
doing more legendaries
and uniques
as the space
that we do that
because we knew
that items
were so important
and being excited
for a late game
item to drop
was a very core
part of the game.
We've kind of
now made that
a lot better
with like greater
affixes for example
and things in season 4.
So I think
there is more room
to make transformative
upgrades in other
places than items
but I also am
very comfortable
with the system
that we have now
and I kind of like it
it gives you obvious
things to chase
with items
and it feels good
to get an item
that is a big upgrade
that changes how you play.
So I guess
I'd be open to feedback
from people
like is there a place
that you think
is superior to items
to get these kinds
of effects?
Like is it cooler
to have it be deterministic
in the Paragon board
versus you're farming
for something
and you see the moment
that it drops
that transforms
your gameplay?
I mean I'd be in the boat
of saying
you know
make the skill tweak
grow into a tree.
That's kind of the boat
that I'm sitting in
but I also understand
from the interview
you had with Rax
how that is
there's reasons
for that
to keep it
that simplistic
so it makes sense
to have it
in the endgame version
of something dropping
or you know
a gem
or whatever
you want to go
for a power
or a unique item.
But how
unless you have
any follow-up questions
at DM
I wanted to ask you
about how that fits
into the philosophy
of a lead class designer
when it comes
to the fantasies
these altering skills
or uniques
whatever you want
to go for
would have an impact
on the class design.
I'm sorry
not quite sure
I'm going to try
to reword that
that was horrible.
Don't worry.
No I was wondering
how these unique items
or skill altering
modifiers
no matter where
you get them
how that would impact
the class design
when it comes
to focusing
on keeping
or maintaining
the specific
fantasies of classes.
Yeah
so when I think
of a build
or a team
thinks of a build
we try and think
of the entire package
and we compare it
to the whole other
package of a class.
I don't think
of a build
like I don't know
Frozen or
let's say
right when I think
of like the total
power and coolness
and strength
and all that
there's a journey
that needs to be made
but I think of it
as you end
with all the things
right you end
with the conjurations
casting Frozen orbs
and you're blowing
up everything
on your screen
it's awesome
right
so when we think
about like
designing a new
class or when
we're first designing
these classes
we have to think
of you know
how do we make
an interesting
and good player
journey from
the beginning
when you first
use a skill
making that
as impactful
and cool
as possible
while at the
same time
balancing against
you need to
leave room
for growth
and making
things crazy
and also
make it better
some skills
are easier
to do
than others
with that
I would say
we definitely
had a lot
of things
before the game
came out
discussions
about like
hey this skill
doesn't
it feels
really crappy
early on
and we're like
yeah it gets
really crazy
later on though
they're like
yeah but
who's gonna
pick it up
if it feels
really shitty
early on
right
like
you have to
balance the
two things
and that one
is like
it's just
a bunch
of discussions
and iteration
even when the
game is live
of people
complain about it
right
and we're like
yeah we agree
and then we
change it
example that
would be like
barbs and jurids
for a while
have been
complaining that
early game
kind of sucks
but then late game
they're powerhouses
and that's kind
of been the identity
and so we've been
like alleviating
over and over again
like basic skills
are a little better
they're a little better
we don't want to go
too far
but we keep
making them better
right
so that's kind
of how we think
of it
we think of the
whole package
and we try to
make sure that
your journey
is enjoyable
and good
and that's true
by the way
with items
and tempering
and stuff
right
we tried to
create that
journey
and itemization
that was
the point
of season 4
because we think
that's what makes
a good ARPG experience
absolutely
so we have
we're approaching
about 10 minutes
or so left
here right around
there so
we do have
some rapid fire
section
which I mean
not all of these
are just yes
and no type things
so you feel free
to talk about
these don't have
to just be
like one word
answers
but we have
about 15-20
of these
I'm going to
try to blast
through that
these are mostly
primary questions
grabbed from
YouTube comments
the chats
etc
the community
just continues
to ask
over and over
again
some of these
may have already
been asked
apologize if they
have but just
because they've
been spammed
quite a bit
one of the ones
we've seen
quite often
is people
are asking
about raids
so we have
overworld bosses
right
pretty cool
people like
them
it's like a
big lube
pinata
every now and
then
is there any
plans of
further
developments
or have
you guys
thought about
potentially of
raids like
8-man
10-man
related to
clans
larger size
basically
yeah
first I would
say this is
just Adam's
personal opinion
not the team
because I know
everybody has
different thoughts
on it but
I think raids
are interesting
and cool
I think that
they would
present quite
a few
hurdles for us
to overcome
that make
things tough
I think they're
probably doable
but as an
example of some
of the things I
think of right
away that are
like oh my
god this is
scary is like
even now we
have a problem
where we're
always competing
against solo
players efficiency
versus group
play efficiency
there's a lot
of people
that play
Diablo
and RPGs
that really
have a strong
identity with
wanting to play
by themselves
and not be
required to go
into a group
and if we put
in this type
of content
where we say
hey you must
go into a
group to play
this then we
you know we
have to reconcile
that of like
hey do we
how do we
either balance
that around
solo players
do it as well
and if they do
then why is it
group content
or yeah too
bad you have to
also be in a
group to engage
with this and
then that puts
a lot of
pressure on the
rewards for that
content because
if we make
the rewards
something that
a solo player
also needs
then we're
making them
go into a
group when
they may not
want to
but if we
make the
rewards for
that type of
content the
other way where
it's not
something you
need then why
do people do
it in the
first place
so there's
like there's
a lot of
questions there
that are
noodley that
are tough to
answer
but I'm
really just
describing the
problem space
I do think
though that
overall the
idea of getting
with a group
of your buddies
or random
strangers and
doing like a
10 man fight
on a huge
like you know
dungeon or
whatever with
a big boss
at the end
that requires
mechanics like
that is really
cool and
appealing so
so then
that's kind of
how I think
of it so I
got two more
quick ones here
and I'll pass
off to Gazi
so in that
case then if
there's issues
related to like
having forcing
group play
basically let's
go the other
way and say
solo self
out mode now
the trading is
more common
here with
legendary items
etc have we
seen the
potential for
maybe adding
an additional
game mode or
other game
modes I think
it'd be cool
nothing to
announce today
fair enough
next one
pvp there is
a small but
very passionate
pvp community
that is curious
about further
plans involving
content specifically
for these groups
of people I
promise them I'd
ask this one for
them what are
your thoughts on
pvp within the
game sure
um don't have
anything to
announce when it
comes to pvp
specific content
I would say we
I think we would
be more interested
for from those
people like what
would they want
to see from
us I would
actually be
curious about
of like what
do you want do
you want like an
arena type system
where we pre
program your
gear for you do
you like open
world do you do
you want some
type of different
progression system
you know kind of
like the group
versus solo play
the pvp versus
pve discussion is
a little similar
of like the more
that we emphasize
it or give unique
rewards to it the
more that we're
saying to everybody
that doesn't want
to do that hey
you must do this
to progress your
character and
that's back to
that you know
cursed problem
trunk theory like
sure you know
everything is about
power progression so
the moment we put
power in an activity
that's a little more
niche then we can
really make people
unhappy if that's if
they have to engage
with that so like
what would they want
to see do they want
to see a better way
of interacting with
pvp is it just that
the balance is crazy
because I think that
people kind of embrace
the crazy balance in
diablo pvp but that's
where I think I would
start the discussion
thanks for the
answer
that's fair
when it comes to
these questions
these rapid fire
requests and we got
them from chat
and from youtube
and one of the
questions that we
wanted us to ask
was how can we see
how long people have
been offline in our
clients
client management
issues currently
yeah yeah yeah
I'm not involved
with that group so
I can't give it I
actually don't know
but I feel like
that's very reasonable
I think we could
bring that back to
the team pretty
easily I will say
we do have a team
that works on like
UX issues user
experience issues
and they are the
ones that kind of
look at stuff like
that like you know
the ideas that we get
over like group
party finder or
armory party finder
this type of support
we have a team
that's looking at it
I know that they're
working on stuff
but I actually don't
have complete insight
into what they're
doing but that seems
very reasonable to me
stuff I like it
the next question is
actually about pets
in game and we're
talking about non
combat pets
ranging from
cosmetics to
maybe loot pets
that might only loot
gold or something
is that something
that's been discussed
if so what can you
share
we have discussed it
I think it'd be cool
don't have anything
to share
all right
next question would
be so sorry
go on I was just
going to read the
next one
all right it's just
DPS meter and
dummies I would love
to see that because
you can't really see
it when you have a
minion army hitting a
dummy I'd like to
have DPS meters
is that something
we're going to see
in the future
yeah I think it's
cool don't have
anything to announce
fair enough
yeah but I'm
actually thinking a
little bit more about
that and maybe
feedback would be
useful of like is it
really only on
dummies that you
want to do it to
test builds or would
you want to see it in
the rest of the game
DPS meters are kind of
notorious and other
game types but I'm not
sure that we have the
same problems sure of
people being upset with
each other for not
doing as much damage and
all that kind of stuff
but fair enough I feel
like it'd probably be
fine or at least for a
personal one I know
this one's probably like
you can't go anywhere
with this but offline
mode is there any
potential for an
offline mode in Diablo
4 at any point I have
not heard any
discussions about it I
would I would doubt
it okay I think that
one I think I'm a
little more sure I
could say but I don't
see it on the horizon
but fair enough so I'm
not in charge of those
kinds of decisions
glyph leveling and
quality of life is there
any potential for glyph
leveling outside of
nightmare dungeons are
we going to add
experience to glyphs
elsewhere in the game
we've talked about it a
bit nothing to announce
I think kind of going
back to the idea with
hell tides and and
whispers I think it is
cool to have a less
efficient way to do
something while you're
being efficient doing
something else that's my
personal opinion though
and kind of what I what I
feel but I'm not on the
systems team and don't
know the nuances of
glyph leveling specifically
and why we keep it in one
place but I I wouldn't be
surprised I guess is what
I would say but I don't
have a guarantee there
how about things like
surprise events like IE
goblin vaults from D3 for
example you get the ring
you go to secondary you
can pop out or you know
pour those to other
types of things any
surprise ambush related
event type of stuff we
have the goblin packs for
instance which is pretty
cool in D4 rare but cool
yeah well as I say we
we've definitely we've
added a couple in season
four kind of mini events
where like you have a
chance when you kill an
elite and it'll spawn into
like a ton of gold or a
ton of materials or things
or give you way more than
normal we like the idea of
surprise events I think
you can expect us to make
more in the future that is
one way kind of like what I
think it was Gazi I think
you said of like like we
want to break up the
monotony and we're trying
to make sure that it feels
different even though you're
doing the same thing and I
think surprise events is one
of the ways that we do
that sometimes it's more
successful than others but
it's definitely something
that we want to continue to
chase because we think
overall it's good it's just
about how exactly to
implement it that's fair
what's the team's position
on support bills like back
in D3 we have CDPS
demon hunters and barb style
bills do they have a place in
D4 moving forward
that's a good question
I think so but we have to
be careful we were a lot
more scared about it when we
launched the game I remember
people kept asking like Adam
can we make more support
builds make more things
like cross synergy is really
cool and I agree it's cool
the the other side of that
is kind of that that issue
we deal with forever of
group versus solo play is
that the better we make a
support build the more we're
saying the best way to play
this game is to go with
four people support your
friends and you get
multiplicative massively
increased amounts of
output right so I think we
do want we do want it we
have it a little bit with
barbarian shouts right and
we've even had added some
legendaries that do it like
there's a druid one that
turns your blood howl into an
AOE buff but I don't think
it's it's one of those you
have to walk the line very
carefully I think because it
can be very detrimental to the
game if we go too far but I'm
not against it as an idea at
all okay I'll jump over to
the next one real quick with
the opening community events
way back like blizzard aq
openings in World of Warcraft
for example community designs
a legendary any sort of that
community events surrounding
those things what are your
thoughts on that I think it'd
be awesome I'm not against it
at all but those are checks
that I can't cash so yeah I
would love to I'm not going to
make it but yes I would love
an aq event like that in in
d4 or something or even
community making the lead
community making a legendary
oh how scared am I of that
or unique I don't know
probably but we can find a
way to balance it I don't
know I think it'd be cool I
think it'd be neat yeah I'm
on board I'm gonna throw you
a quick one with something
that's close to my heart and
that's map overlay and before
you say immersion I'd like to
say that a lot of people will
say let us play the game we
want to what's the thoughts of
map overlay moving forward
this is personal Adam Adam
thoughts not company thoughts
because everybody has different
opinions I think and we've
talked about map overlay
internally quite a bit I think
map overlay it's one of those
where there's there's such
obvious pros and cons and I
think different types of
players really really want to
engage in different ways I I
personally am not completely
against a map overlay being in
the game but I understand why
there there are people that
feel strongly that you know we
really don't want to try and
make a game where you're
looking at your map the whole
time and not all this beautiful
world and art and things that
we've created to try and
immerse the player and then
they're so into the systems and
the efficiency game that we
pull them out of it and I
think it kind of goes back to
kind of what you said of like
you know ARPGs we really want
you to we know it's an
efficiency game but we don't
want it to feel that exposed all
the time that you must feel
pressure to do things
perfectly all the time and a
map overlay pushes that pretty
hard so I see both sides I think
I'm a little bit personally in
favor of just having it because
people want it but I understand
it changes the game pretty
fundamentally for a lot of
people and there's a pressure
there now it's kind of like
DPS meters in many games too I
would equate it to like the
moment you introduce that you
kind of can't go back and you've
changed how people interact with
your game forever and so I even
if people want it I I see why
it it's a tough topic we're
actually doing pretty good on
time we're almost through the
rapid fire we just got a few
more here and then we pretty
much are GG out the way out the
door here so ultimate button
is something that gets brought up
a lot people have asked can we
get a separate button for the
ultimate yeah maybe I'll say I'll
explain the problem space of why
yeah so when we're thinking
about Diablo and why we don't
have more extra buttons or like
an ultimate button or whatever
is that we we we thought heavily
and work long and hard deciding the
number of buttons that you're
going to have total on your bar at
all and those buttons were
determined by thinking of how many
different actions do we want a
player to worry about at any given
time and right now we have you
know you have a Vage you have
potion you have your regular ones
on your bar and then your core
and your basic right if you have a
basic adding another button is
something that we could do I mean
controller issues aside and making
that feel good it's a matter of how
complex do we want to expect every
single player to interact and at the
time at launching the game we we
wrestled back and forth with this a
lot and our at the at the time our
idea was we would rather have
something like an evade button that
really everybody can use and makes
the game feel very different and it's
kind of like this is very different
than other RPGs than a specific
ultimate button there's also would
need to be a lot of rebalancing of
ultimates when we fully expect
people to have one versus that they
can choose whether or not they do
that work we could do I think it's
more of like do I want to balance and
design everything assuming a player
has an ultimate in addition to all
of their other skills and what that
means to how we have to change
ultimates or do other things I think
it's doable but I don't know that I'm
very excited about the prospect unless
there's a very clear win okay can
understand that a couple just fast
ones I have to go in depth on just
some transmog things people are
asking maybe a color wheel for
transmogs as opposed to just like
red green blue any thoughts on
adding like a color wheel yeah it
seems cool it's not my team but yeah
non-horse mounts pretty much all the
mounts are horses can we get like a
maggot or anything spider I think I
think we should and I wouldn't be
surprised if we did it but I'm not
involved in those conversations but I
think I personally feel like it's a
no-brainer yeah same same I agree I'm
glad I agree on okay wings kind of
controversial but a million people
asked me wings are we ever gonna see
wings in the port yeah that's a little
more controversial I would say I
don't know about the future I can
explain a little bit of where we're at
now and I'm not even completely
involved in this is a little bit of
my opinion because I didn't make
these decisions but you know return to
darkness was one of our big guiding
philosophies when we when we were
making d4 up to launch and this idea
that hey this game is is you know going
back to kind of d1 d2 roots of being
scary and and a little more you know
gruesome and dark and dreary and we even
try even with the combat that's why we
have evade is like you have to dodge
attacks and really plan because this
world is dangerous in some ways we've
learned that players you know want to
blast and they don't care as much as we
maybe we like we over indexed a little
bit on it we still but it is still
something that we care about so like
now it's does we like before wings was
kind of in that it's making the game a
little bit it doesn't fit the vibe we're
going for but we've moved a bit but
have we moved enough that wings are
okay now I don't know fair enough I'm
it's like we're I think we're right
there I could I could see it being
either way but that just explains kind
of how we got here so fair enough I
get that we only got like three
questions left here really so the last
transmog related or cosmetic related
question is can we get cosmetics
potentially for minions I know
Ghazi probably would like this one
I think it would be cool it's a lot
harder to do for minions and for
players though or even like wings
because you can have a million
minions on your screen and how loud
that is is a concern but I don't think
it's an impossibility I'd like to see
it I think it'd be cool same with
Jura transform transmogs I think
would be cool but that's just my
opinion all right go for it Ghazi
speaking of being scary what about a
unicorn level cow level is that ever
something that's going to happen
because we've all been hunting for it
a unicorn level that sounds neat I
don't know what you're talking about
with the other one there it is and
shout out to racks uber tomb lord win
I think it'd be cool I'm down I don't
know whatever people want to fight I
mean we could make it all right and we
pretty much are hitting the end of the
time here I want to thank you for your
time I will submit there's a couple
other there like bug reports that I'll
just DM over as well and we skip those
ones and you know we just had our 45
minutes so I appreciate the time thanks
for answering all the questions and we
actually managed to get through pretty
much the entire list including the
rapid fire so you've done good I
appreciate it you know any last words
anything you want to say
um I would say you know first thanks
to both of you for taking the time to
talk to me you know we really enjoy
these conversations I look forward to
doing more um for everybody else you
know one of the things I'm really
passionate about like first you know go
listen to that convert that to that
presentation that I talked about on a
curse problems I really one of my goals
with getting in front of people and
talking with them and I've done this
ever since I started as a developer you
can go look at interviews with me years
ago from heroes but I like having
better discussions with you all and with
players that are a little more
informed so as people get passionate
want to learn about game design you
know it's easy just to be like hey
why don't you add this and we can
answer those questions but I like more
in-depth ones and we do on the team
of like hey why does this work the way
it does and can we find a way to make
it work and get what we want right like
when you counter back at me with like
the strongholds question like can't we
okay Adam I listen to you I understand
your problem space now that I've
thought about it can we do this and
why or why not like that to me is a
better discussion and a better
culture a better a better world really
if I want to get sappy of like you
know be informed when talking about
things and care about it and think
about it and don't just blast like hey
just do this right yeah I mean I
wouldn't want to answer those either
I felt like I would yeah I'm not
saying everyone has to be a game dev I
just mean like if you care enough to
really want to know like you know
think about it and have real
discussions and so I want to be a
force for that I guess in the community
and I think other people on our team
do as well so thanks yeah but I
really enjoyed the time so enjoy
talking with you both I enjoyed it
it was it was actually nice seeing the
thought process behind it and then
like it kind of in real time because
normally it's like you make a video
maybe you get a response about it or
something but it is kind of nice to
see like in real time the feedback
because you're right just during the
very brief conversation about strong
codes like it did actually I'm like
oh you know it makes sense it's a
consumable design thing kind of hard
to turn into a repetitive Xerre so
thank you for opening up about that
guys you got any last comments or
anything you want to say not really I
mean I know you're a minion lover so I
want to get in on a deep dive talk
with you someday about that we do that
on stream on the tavern talk someday as
well maybe we can someday no yeah I my
roots are in RTS where I manage a
million little units and I love minion
stuff and everything so sounds good
but thanks for joining appreciate it all
right yeah thank you both very much
we'll let you we'll let you head on out
the door here we'll wrap up and all
right we're going to cut back to the
other screen and then cut the audio and
I will be back in just a moment
everybody
bye-bye