I have to say it just went way beyond my expectation.
It's like nothing that we had in D4.
Pure hatred, their Mephisto's army.
We wanted them to feel a little bit more different from your typical demon family.
Everyone's quality was top notch.
But at the time, we didn't know if it was going to work.
I think what we landed is going to turn some heads.
This is not your normal thing. It's the living form of hatred.
The new monster class that we get to introduce, they're called hollows.
These hollows have actually been around for like millennia.
Mephisto at some point did go to Nahantu a long, long, long time ago.
And these hollows were a reaction of Mephisto being in Nahantu at the time.
And then they went dormant.
Bringing Mephisto in the Soul Stone seems like the right thing to do for Narell.
But it has a chain reaction that I don't think anybody was prepared for.
The hollows are really rife throughout Nahantu now that Mephisto is back.
And just visually, like horribly disgusting.
And sort of made up of the things that have been consumed by the hollows.
Yeah, they're an extension of evil.
Infecting wildlife and other monsters and people with this thing called ichor.
And they're just sort of going mad.
When we're designing the hollows, the main thing that we wanted to push was just if hatred came to life, what would it look like?
So we're thinking this black goo that's kind of like formless but also have this red anger energy inside of it.
And then with concept, we just want to make, you know, cool monsters.
What if it's three legs? What if it's no legs? What if it has like three arms?
So we pushed a lot of like options and exploration.
And then from then on, like everyone from narrative to design and concept would talk about it.
It's like, okay, we like this one and then we can push it and move it further.
The hollow family is made up of four members.
The swarmer, the spitter, the caster, and the brutes.
A big thing for me was that the family need to be overwhelming without just relying on pure numbers.
So they're going to get stronger over time if you let them fester their hatred after all.
The swarmer can teleport and attack you from behind, from the sides.
The spitter is a slug with legs.
They spew out this vomit stream of who the brute is.
The big hulking slow guy of the family.
He has the shield that's buffing and making the rest of the army stronger.
The caster is responsible for creating new swarmers.
They also will channel onto a specific hollow and view them with an extra feature.
It makes them stronger and more deadly.
The hollow caster's role serve as an elegant, hovering, yet menacing dungeon character in the game.
Really inform many of our design ideas.
When we want to make a new variant, we want to know in which specific area we are going to see that character or creature.
Readability is like the main focus.
We went through several iterations on the design, the texture, the materials, and the camera testing.
The day after she gave me like, what was it, 10 different variations?
Different variations?
Okay.
Now we are talking.
The emission on the spikes really like, did an awesome job to both on the CineVet and also to improve the readability.
And in the end, we have the version that we were both happy with.
And yeah, hand it over to the tech artist.
We had some really strong narrative direction in understanding how big of a role hatred played.
And we knew that we needed one look to tie it all together.
This hatred has one source and it's all about Mephisto.
For the hollows specifically, we identified that we wanted to do some special work with the materials, with the shaders for those characters.
Shaders are the code that runs on the GPU that takes in all sorts of inputs like textures and lighting and position and outputs what the object's surface is supposed to look like.
We wanted a shader that was capable of adding this sludge layer, this hatred layer over top of it, and making it dynamic and animating so that it really looks like it was constantly undulating or writhing.
So once we had this shader function, we were able to apply that in all these different contexts, like the monsters, like the environment, the character armors even.
Most of the shader work was done by Alex, who really took that shader function and made it work in all sorts of different contexts.
And we also have the hatred add-ons to these characters, these tentacles, these writhing hatred growths all over them, which was a procedurally generated process that was largely run by Sky on our team.
The Hollows boss was kind of born of this idea of what does a pinnacle hollows really look like.
We have the Hollows family, and that was pretty well defined by the time that the Hollows boss kind of came up for concepting.
Our artist, Victor, had a lot of cool ideas for horror themes and really wanted to push visuals with contortions and breaking the neck of this monster all over the place.
That's where we had the option to go, like, and we'd push it and really get that idea of what Hatred and the Hollows are all about.
This inky black ichor that latched on to a once powerful spellcaster.
It was such a great source of power that this particular Hollows monster turned into the priestess of Hatred.
I'm Victor Lee, a principal concept artist on the Diablo team.
and I concepted the Priestess of Hatred.
Victor Lee is one of the OGs from Diablo and he's known for creating a lot of dark imagery.
And every time we want to have a monster or boss, he's done all the greats, even Diablo himself.
One of his monitors on the side of his desk is just like a dark black eye staring at him.
And so when we needed something that's pure darkness, like, we had to tap Vic.
I feel like when we're talking about Hatred, I kind of imagine, visualize it as like a black webby-like thing.
So I thought a spider configuration would work for this.
So I did a few variations, some with souls, human souls trapped in the abdomen.
It's like a purgatory because this creature consumes humans.
I have this nagging feeling for a long time that why I felt it's not working.
It's not working.
No matter how interesting the design is, I'm not pushing the boundaries.
So I basically rethought the whole thing.
A lot of our creatures are just like raw aggression.
It's just muscly and just brutal.
Maybe this one is more insidious.
What if the human figure is not controlling the hatred, but it's the other way around?
Like the hatred is actually mocking humanity.
It's like dragging a puppet around.
So what I did is I kept the human figure as a focal point, but the rest of the creature is this moving mass of basically a ball of hatred.
It broke a lot of rules, but I felt, I just felt like this just fits.
So I went ahead with it and rendered it out.
I was looking at the concept for the first time with the designer on the feature, Charles,
and we were kind of in this stunned silence for a little bit because it was this reaction of,
this thing is so cool.
And then we started thinking, how are we even going to make this thing move?
Typically our monsters are bipedal or they're quadrupeds.
How's it going to move?
We can't rely on walk cycles anymore.
How's it going to rotate?
We can't rely on, you know, the built in rotation stuff without looking weird as hell.
It was clear that in order to make this like animate and look natural,
we were going to have to pretty much dive into uncharted territory.
We wanted it to move in a very unique way.
We wanted it to somersault through the air and be super unpredictable and zippy
and just have like ridiculous animations as those tentacles are flying all over the place.
We had that narrative and kind of drive to make it formless and with our conventional rigging that we can do that.
We were doing prototyping before the feature even kicked off.
Like we were already meeting with animation and tech art to say,
Hey, we have this thing. We think it's really cool, but we need help figuring this out.
So we had a lot of early collaboration, which was really what set us up for success.
When the animator came back with it, going from post to post rather than your normal animations,
I was like, yes, that's it. That's what hatred should feel like.
When you first find the priestess of hatred, it's going to look like a lifeless human corpse.
And you're like, this is doesn't look like a boss fight. I'm in a boss arena. What's going on?
But as you approach, you see that the body gets pulled into a giant pool of hatred.
And then out of that pool of hatred comes this giant mass of tentacles. And that is the boss.
So after animation, it gets to come to me and I get to do all of the really cool visual effects at the end.
Show what those tentacles are doing when they impact them out, when they slap something, when they hit the player.
It really brings the entire thing together.
The vomit attack is really gross because there's like this part of the torso of the humanoid that has been kind of hollowed out and now has teeth.
The tentacles come out from the mass and they grab the humanoid and kind of pull the body back so that the slit in the belly opens up and all of the hatred just pours out a straight beam.
It's pretty gross.
The hollows are just such a unique family. From the moment they spawn in on your screen, you can tell that they are different.
They have just such unique behaviors and animations.
We were able to execute on a vision that's really just so different than what we typically do.
The whole process made me feel very proud of our whole team.
Everyone just got it. They understood what the monster was. They got the vision and it just worked.
The eye on the screen has many functions. It keeps me in the right frame of mind.
What we are doing is dark. It should be horrifying. I should feel the fear while I'm doing it.
It's a reminder of that. The eye also serves as a warning.
Like, get moving. Don't dwell too long and wander around. You know? Get this thing moving. Get the work done.
Hello!
to grab something really quickly.
Welcome to another Diablo 4 Campfire Chat.
My name is Adam Fletcher.
Of course, I'm joined by two familiar faces
on our Campfire Chats.
We have Mr. Adam Jackson and Mr. Colin Feiner.
Hello, everyone.
It's been a little while since we've seen everyone.
We obviously have lots of...
has changed since our last stream.
We ended up launching Vessel of Hatred,
which is really awesome to see.
Tons of players online,
checking out all the new features within Diablo 4,
and of course, the Spiritborn as well.
We've been hearing a lot about this here, Warren.
Seems a little obvious.
And, yeah, awesome.
It's too weak, right?
It's too weak.
Yeah, that's what we've heard.
That's apparently what we most definitely heard.
But, no, it is a little strong,
and we've heard that from a lot of people.
We'll be talking about that a little bit today.
But first, before we do jump in,
I do want to talk about some plans,
upcoming plans that we have for streams.
Obviously, we're doing this stream right now
for the midseason update.
The midseason update is actually currently scheduled
to release next week.
We won't have patch notes immediately after this stream.
As you know, we're doing this stream on a Tuesday,
which is a little bit of a different day for us.
We typically end up doing these streams later in the week
when we do release those patch notes.
But you will have patch notes later this week.
We just need to get them through localization,
make sure everyone sees them,
and we get all the final changes in them
before we actually do release them.
But you will have the final patch notes
for midseason update later this week.
And then, again, midseason update next week.
We will be back next week for another stream.
Yeah.
So back-to-back weeks for streams.
Lots of streams coming up.
So this one is going to be a pretty quick one
to go over midseason update.
And then next week,
we're actually going to talk about the Season 7 PTR.
I should actually call it Patch 2.1 PTR
is specifically the name of it.
We're going to be talking about all the changes
that are coming with Patch 2.1.
That stream is also going to be a little earlier
than when PTR is planning on actually starting.
That's only because for those here in the U.S.
that are aware of it,
the Thanksgiving holiday is coming up
towards the end of November,
and we won't have people in the office.
So we want to make sure
that we can do the stream a little early
and talk to everyone about the Patch 2.1 PTR
before the end of the month.
PTR itself is planning on starting
after the holidays,
or after that Thanksgiving holiday in the U.S.,
and then for the notes regarding PTR,
we'll have that before the holidays.
So everyone can get to,
at least in the U.S.,
they can eat turkey, read patch notes,
and then elsewhere,
they can just read patch notes.
And so we have a lot of stuff coming up
and a lot to talk about,
but before we do get towards
some of the other items,
I know, Colin,
you want to talk a little bit
about where we're at with D4 at the moment?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I'll try and keep it short and sweet.
For the midseason,
we actually think,
I just wanted to talk a little bit
about how we think about the game currently.
You know, we've changed a lot over the past year.
We've changed itemization.
We've changed all of the progression.
And generally, I think,
you know, we've seen a ton of positive feedback
around a lot of the progression changes
made in X1, which is fantastic.
We're really excited to make a lot of these changes.
I think it's hit a lot of the goals
in terms of opening up what builds
you can actually play
and experience a lot of the endgame,
which is great.
Of course, there's, you know,
Spiritborn, Kicking Ass,
and Pit Tier 150.
But like, otherwise,
there's a lot of builds
that sort of can cut it in the endgame,
starting in Torment 1.
And I think that's been super,
like, sort of successful for us.
And I also think, like,
a lot of the sort of itemization changes
we've made in terms of ancestral items,
we think that, like,
they're a little bit on the low side.
We'll talk a little bit more
next week in the PTR
in terms of buffing those.
But we think, like,
it's actually pretty cool
that there's those chase items
that people are looking for.
And I think just generally,
we're pretty happy
with how a lot of things landed.
And right now,
we're sort of taking a step back
and seeing, okay,
now that we've made a lot of these changes,
what are the more iterative steps
we're going to take in the next year
in terms of, like,
tightening up a lot of things.
You know, full disclosure,
I think we missed the mark
a little bit on material tuning
and things like that.
Had to do a couple updates
on material tuning.
Just a couple.
Yeah, just a couple.
So we're really looking
at tightening up a lot of those things
and sort of making more iterative changes
to the overall progression of the game.
And we hope that that creates
some more stability
and that sort of lets us, you know,
sort of put more time
and focus on, like, balance
and adding more things
and sort of leveling up the game
in that sort of way.
Yeah, just thinking back a year ago,
like, so much has changed
in our systems, right?
Like, we did all of our combat math
over again.
We changed resistances.
We changed how loot drops
and, you know,
the whole upgrade system there
in Season 4.
Unique's got a big overhaul.
Like, there's been so much change
in things.
I'm looking forward to having a chance
for things to kind of settle down
and we can fine-tune and refine
the existing systems that we have
now that we have so many ways
of progressing your character,
making yourself stronger.
And I think there's a lot of room
for improvement inside of these systems
to make them kind of better,
which I know people
have been requesting a lot.
So we're looking forward to that.
Yeah, yeah.
It's really about refining
what we currently have.
We feel like the structure
is really strong right now.
Yeah, most definitely.
And I know with this mid-season update,
we, of course, the biggest topic
that we've been hearing a lot
is around class balance,
specifically around, like,
Spirit Born right now
and how it is performing very well
compared to some of the other classes.
And so, Mr. Adam Jackson,
I know you wanted to talk a little bit
about some of the class balance.
Yeah, let's talk about classes.
We've got a lot to go over today.
So, first, just to give an overview
of kind of what I'm going to talk about.
First, we're going to talk a little bit
about kind of the state of Season 6
and kind of how we see things
and how things are going.
And then we're going to give you
a preview of some of the changes
that we're going to be doing
for all the classes.
Normal disclaimer here,
you know, we're not going to be covering
everything that we're going to do
here in the past.
There could be a lot more notes
than what I'm showing today.
But just to kind of give you an idea
of what's coming for each class
and kind of what you can look forward to.
So, yeah, the current state of Season 6.
So, you know, a whole lot of people
are enjoying the Spirit Born.
I think this class has been
really successful.
You know, we've been hearing
that it's a lot of fun.
People are really liking
kind of the way that you build,
the way that you play,
and just the class in general,
which is really gratifying for the team.
Just for some stats here,
62% of all players
have played the Spirit Born.
So, you know, when you think
the other six classes in the game now
and 62% of people are playing it,
you know, that's kind of a lot of love
for the class,
which is pretty exciting to see.
And to give you a basis
of comparison here,
the Sorceress in Season 5
was the most played class,
and she was at 32%.
So, you know, I gave you an idea,
and that was, you know,
Lightning Spear meta,
and, you know, this class
was really, really good.
A lot of people had fun.
And so you can kind of compare there
just how many people
kind of logged into the expansion
and enjoyed that.
So that's pretty exciting.
Yeah, just a few, right?
Yeah, so kind of the state of the game.
You know, the Spirit Born
is performing quite a bit better
than other classes,
which we want to dig deep,
you know, do a little bit
of a deep dive into how and why
and how we think about it.
Largely, a big culprit of this
is actually due to unintended interactions
that the class has
with how some things scale
and other issues.
But then there's also
another component
that there are some balance issues
with the class itself.
And so it's pretty easy
to conflate these two
and be like, well,
how much of the power
is due to, like, you know,
bugs or unintended interactions
and how much of it is just
some things have high numbers.
We do think it's a bit of both,
but the unintended interactions,
I think, are the lion's share
of what's going on here.
But on the bright side,
the other classes
are actually performing
fairly well
when compared to one another.
So if you look at, you know,
Barbarian compared to Necromancer
or Druid compared to Sorceress,
they're actually pretty close
and competitive
when we see, like,
Pit Tier clears
and other content,
how they're doing,
which is a really good sign for us.
So when we're thinking of kind of
what we're going to do going forward
and how we balance the game,
there's kind of two really statements
that we need to think about
when it comes to balance.
The first one that's really important
is we want players
to feel strong and powerful
and to kind of feel like
they can break the game
and find these crazy builds
and do awesome things with.
And then on the other side of the coin,
we also want kind of, you know,
class balance and parity
when it comes to a power level
with one another, right?
You know, we don't want a situation
that exists for a really long time
where, you know,
the only answer is to play Barbarian,
for example,
compared to everything else
and that's all that you kind of
be pushed into playing.
So these two things
are kind of at odds
with one another
and we've kind of gone back and forth
on our strategies here.
If you remember back
when we launched Diablo 4,
we really actually prioritized
class parity and harmony
over, you know,
everything else,
over the power fantasy of the game.
And what this resulted in
was every time that someone
found a build
that was really strong and crazy.
We just kind of
would fix the bugs
or nerf the build
and we ended up
kind of playing whack-a-mole
every time that players
found something cool.
And it ended up being
that Blizzard kind of
turned into the fun police,
which players really didn't like.
We got a pretty big reaction
at the end of the launch period
and into season one
when we tried to only think
about class parity
over kind of
the power fantasy of Diablo.
And in season two,
we kind of really
turned things around
in the way that we thought
about the game
and we really prioritized
power fantasy
and this idea
that our players
kind of want to break the game
and be crazy.
The big shining example there
was Ball Lightning
for you Sorcerous Mains
where that skill
had an unintended interaction.
It was really, really good,
but players really liked it
and had a lot of fun.
And so if you remember
a long time ago,
we came on live stream
and we talked about this
and we kind of said
that we were going to
allow players
to kind of break the game
in this way
until the next season, right?
There are some exceptions
that we'll make
where we'll fix things
in the mid-season
if it's impacting
the performance of the game
or the experience
of other players,
like if your build
is causing a bunch of lag
or something,
then we'll fix it right away.
I think in season six
we had this example
with the Evade build
with Spirit Board.
But overall,
players really liked
this strategy
a whole lot more, right?
They got to enjoy
this kind of,
the point of playing
ARPGs and Diablo
in particular,
of really making
a powerful character
and being able
to smash faces with it, right?
Yeah, and the sort
of philosophy here
is sort of
goes even beyond classes, right?
If you remember
in season one,
we were just nerfing
every dungeon
that was to perform in
and like any time
like there was content
that was like a little bit
out of budget,
we'd nerf it.
So it's really about
sort of establishing
a trust with you,
the player,
during that season
and not trying to
sort of force you
to exploit the fun
early and often.
And it's really about
sort of making sure
that when you play a season,
you know that that season
is going to work
the same throughout the season
and we're not going
to change things
midway on you.
Yeah, I think another factor
to think about too
is that now that we've added
a lot of progression
like tempering
and master working,
that there's a lot
of time investment
that goes into
making a build
even if you know
something that might
be unintended,
but it's really,
really good and crazy
and you spend,
you know,
40 plus,
100 hours,
whatever,
making it.
And if we kind of
pull the rug out
from under you,
it's worrisome
to do that to players,
I think,
in the middle of a season.
It's all about
respecting your time,
right?
Yeah.
So in that vein,
we are not planning
to nerf the Spiritborn
in the midseason patch,
which I think is the thing
that's on everybody's mind.
Like, is Blizzard
going to do it?
And we've decided that
we think it's best
for the game
to not do it
in the midseason.
So in Season 7,
and we'll be talking
about this a little more
in the live stream
next week,
we are going to be
fixing all the
unintended interactions
that we found
with Spiritborn.
We'll also be making
balance adjustments
to bring them in line
with the other classes.
So you can expect
a lot of change there.
But until then,
enjoy what you've got now
while it's there.
I think it's worth
digging into
the unintended interactions
part too, right?
Because it's not necessarily
like you picked
one legendary Paragon node
and now your build
is ridiculous, right?
It's like you're sort of,
for lack of a better word,
abusing some of the mechanics,
right?
If we know Viscous Shield
is scaling off of max HP,
players have poured tons
of time and effort
trying to max Masterwork,
their max life
and getting all the
perfect tempers
and item affixes,
we don't want to take
that away from you, right?
That's not something
that we're trying to
necessarily destroy
all the time commitment
you put into your character
by fixing these things.
So it's not as simple
as just fixed
unintended interaction, right?
But just reiterating,
it is that those
unintended interactions
are things that we will
look at when we get
to Season 7
and we start off
with Season 7.
So obviously with
mid-season update,
enjoy it.
Enjoy it through Season 6,
but come Season 7
and you'll see a preview
of some of these changes
with Season 7
in our PTR stream next week.
You'll see some of the
changes that we plan on.
Yeah, there's a lot
coming there,
but this isn't about that.
This isn't about that
in mid-season.
There's a lot coming there
for everybody
that'll be really exciting.
But yeah,
but the caveat
to all of this is
if something does come up
that impacts other players
in regards to the game's performance
or you're causing lag
for the server or whatever,
we will be fixing
those types of interactions
as soon as possible.
Like the evade build
is our example, right?
We will fix those right away
because we want to make sure
that the game is, you know,
performant for everybody.
So in the mid-season though,
we are going to be buffing
all the other classes
in the mid-season patch,
but I want to caveat
this a little bit with
it's not going to be
to the level of Spiritborn
right now
because a lot of that power
is due to bugs
and unintended things.
So we're really going to be
buffing the classes
to have more parity
and harmony with each other,
but then also to kind of
where we plan to bring
the Spiritborn to
after, you know,
the bugs and stuff
has been fixed.
So you will be seeing
number buffs,
but, you know,
I wouldn't expect to be
at the same level
as what Spiritborn is doing
right now in the mid-season,
just to be clear,
because of that,
the bugs are actually
a big part of the power level.
Yeah, and we don't want
to create an arms race, right?
Where it's like,
okay, everyone gets to be
Pit Tier 150,
then the next natural ask
is like, okay,
I guess we're adding
to them in 5, 6, 7, 8, right?
So we don't want to sort of
get to a place where,
you know,
you're cheering through
12 different Torment Tiers,
sort of really being cautious
about the arms race here.
We actually think
the rest of the classes
are in a really good spot.
Yeah, and I think you can
count on that going forward,
too, not even just right now,
but this is kind of the way
that we think of things
in general.
It's like,
if all the classes
are kind of in this realm
kind of close to each other
and then one has
something unintended
that brings, like,
way up here,
everybody is always like,
well, let's just bring
everybody else to this.
Yeah.
But if we do that every time,
like, you start with this difference
and then you're here
and then you do this
level the game
just insanely high
really fast, right?
And that's not our goal, right?
So if there's something
that stands out,
we'll let people do it
for a while,
but then we're going to
bring it back the next season.
Yeah.
And that's kind of the way
that I think you can
mostly count on us
doing balance
and how the choices
that we make and why.
Definitely.
And the same goes
if there's, like,
an underperforming class.
It's, like, 20 pit tiers
behind everyone else, right?
We have no problems
with, like, bringing that up
to where the rest
of the classes are.
Correct.
Yeah, the real goal
is to get everything
in a pretty good realm
of having harmony
with one another
when something's
out of balance,
it's okay for a season,
but then we're going to
try to bring it back, right?
That's kind of always our goal.
So, yeah, let's get into
the class updates
for all the classes.
We're just going to be
going through one by one
and kind of giving you
a preview of what to see.
Again, this is only a preview.
There's more than
what we're going to show
on screen.
Yeah, way more, right?
This is just, like,
a couple examples
within the stream itself.
And, again, just a reminder,
patch notes later this week,
once we get everything
kind of sorted,
we're at normal time
for a stream
on a Tuesday,
normally we do it
on Thursday
and usually have
patch notes then.
So I expect the patch notes
later this week.
Yeah, let's get to it.
So starting off
with Barbarian,
we got some baseline
core skill buffs
for pretty much
all of them, right?
You can see here,
Upheaval,
Hammer of the Ancients,
Double Swing,
and Rend.
Basically, you know,
we always hear it that
they have a little bit
of trouble leveling.
Their late game
is really good,
but just getting there
can be a little bit painful.
So we're just going to be
squeezing up those numbers
a little bit more.
So you'll have a better
time leveling.
You'll also be a little
bit stronger overall,
but all the builds
will get a little bit better.
And then also we have
some buffs to
underperforming
legendaries and uniques.
Here's an example
with an aspect,
Battle Mad.
You can see here
in the before,
kind of what's on live
right now is it's
basically just a way
to give you Berserking,
rewarding you for
weapon swapping.
And now we're adding
a hefty multiplier to it.
So now this is going to be
a real offensive aspect
that's going to give you,
you know,
a bunch of power.
You're going to get
up to a 40% damage buff
when you're doing
the weapon swapping mechanics.
So we're kind of
finding these places
where we can input damage
or, you know,
these underused
legendaries or uniques
and then adding a reason
to make them more compelling.
Next we've got Druid.
So all of the Druid's
key passives are getting buffed.
I've given a couple
of examples here,
but I'm pretty sure
all of them,
the numbers went up.
So Lupine Ferocity,
you've got the crit damage
going from 70 to 100% bonus.
And then the bonus damage
to injured enemies
going from 140
to 200%,
which is pretty meaty.
And then the one
with nature passive
that buffs your companions,
that bonus damage
is going from 60 to 80%,
which is a pretty big amount.
And then also legendary
you need buffs
in the same way
of the Barbarian.
So here this is
an offensive aspect,
even though I'd argue
it's kind of more utility,
but the Storm Chaser's aspect
where it makes
your tornadoes smart,
where they seek enemies.
We're just adding
a pretty good multiplier
to that.
So Tornado Builds Rejoice,
you're going to get
up to 50% more damage now
just from taking this aspect
that you were probably
taking anyways.
So just making you happier
to take the same things.
Next one,
the Basilisk.
This is the Earth Druid
dealing with Petrify.
So before,
it was that first time
that you hit an enemy,
you'll Petrify them,
and then every time
you Petrify them,
it deals a bunch of damage.
We're just making that
a lot more usable,
so that way you can feel
more comfortable taking it.
So now it's going to be
when you hit a healthy enemy,
you'll Petrify them.
And also,
this will work against bosses.
So every five seconds
that you hit a boss,
you'll attempt to Petrify,
and then you'll get
that bonus damage proc.
So basically,
this unique now
will be giving you
a damage proc
every five seconds
against bosses,
which will be a lot better
than now,
where it doesn't really do
much to bosses at all.
Next, we've got
the Necromancer.
So they're getting buffs
for all their basic skills.
I'm showing Decompose
here as an example.
The damage is almost
being doubled.
Your Essence gain
per second is going up
by quite a bit.
And also now,
it'll scale with
Attack Speed bonuses.
So now,
if you build Attack Speed
or you have it,
Decompose is going to be
generating Essence
for you quicker,
which it didn't used to before.
They're also getting
some buffs
and kind of some
simple functionality changes
to some passives.
So an example here
with the Evulsion passive
is before,
you would get
increased Crit damage
to vulnerable enemies.
And now we're just going
to remove that
double requirement there
of focusing on Crit and Vuln.
So now you'll just get
more damage
against vulnerable enemies.
So it's just a lot
more usable.
It's now used,
you can use it
more generally.
You don't have to worry
about critting all the time
to get the bonus.
So it'll just be
more consistent.
And then we've got
some unique buffs here.
These are just number buffs.
Some examples,
we've got Mordecrux,
so the chance to spawn
the Skeletal Simulacrum
is going up.
And Howl from below,
you're just getting,
you know,
more Corpse Explosion
damage out of it.
So just tuning up
these numbers
to make them competitive.
Next,
we've got the Rogue.
So similar to
the Barbarian,
the Rogue is also
getting buffs to the
Core skills.
Penetrate Shot damage
is going up.
Flurry damage is going up
as some examples.
Also,
their Key Passives
are getting a bit better too.
Victimize,
the Damage Scaling
is going up
for your Vulnerable
Damage bonus.
And Precision
is going up
by a pretty hefty amount
from 15% to 20%
of your Crit Damage bonus.
So it'll just be
a lot more potent.
And next,
we've got the Sorceress
kind of keeping on
the theme of
buffing Key Passives.
So this one,
we're actually doing
a bit of a functionality change.
So Combustion before
used to be that,
you know,
you get a big multiplier
to your Burning Damage,
60%.
And then after that,
we kind of wanted
to reward you
for putting different
Burning Sources
on enemies
and you would get
a little bit of a bonus
per source.
Now we're doing away
with that second part.
So you're still getting
the Burning Damage buff
just across the board.
But now we're actually
going to tie it
to itemization.
So now you'll just
be getting an additional
multiplier based on
your Damage to Burning
Enemies bonus.
So now you're going
to be looking for that,
you know,
in your gear,
in your Paragon
and other places.
So you can now just
really buff up
the Burning Damage
and you don't have
to worry about putting
a bunch of sources
on enemies.
Next,
a similar vein,
Avalanche.
This key passive
is just getting better
and is going to be
tuning into a Damage
bonus as well.
So before it was
that your Frost Skills
have a chance,
a Lucky Hit chance
to make your next
cast of a few
different skills
consume Nomada
and be stronger.
And when you hit
Vulnerable Enemies,
it just made the
chance better.
And now we're just
buffing up the chance
baseline going from
10 to 30% to get that
free cast and bonus
damage.
But now the actual
damage that you deal
is going to be
increased by your
Damage Against
Vulnerable Enemies stat.
So now we've added
basically a scaling
multiplier to this
key passive,
so it should be doing
a lot more damage
over time.
Next we've got
Aspect of Piercing
Cold.
This is for you
Ice Shards enjoyers.
This one's getting
a whole lot better.
So before it used to
be that the number
of pierces was part
of the random roll
and then also the
roll made it deal,
your subsequent hits
deal less damage with
Ice Shards.
And now we flip the
script now and now
the amount of enemies
that it's going to
pierce is going to be
static, so you're just
getting more consistent
value.
But instead of
doing less damage,
you're going to deal
more damage per enemy
hit.
So that actual
difference of going
from less to more is
going to amount to a
substantial increase in
the amount of damage
that this legendary is
pumping out for Ice
Shards.
It's a huge spread.
Last but not least,
for the Sorceress,
we introduced a couple
of new legendary
aspects in Vessel of
Hatred.
We've got them,
they're scaling with
Charge Bolts and
Incinerate.
And both of these
aspects were dealing
what we call flat
damage, or it was
like a certain damage
amount.
And it didn't really
scale up as you
scaled the skill up.
And we've changed
that for both of
these.
So the aspect of
Charge Flash and
the aspect of
Overheating will now
both scale.
As you get more
Charge Bolt or more
Incinerate damage,
these ones will be
dealing a lot more
damage as well.
So these ones will
just scale with you
and be a lot better
over time as you get
stronger.
And next, last but
not least, we got
the Spirit Borm.
So we did do some
changes here.
We really mostly did
small buffs to
skills that haven't
really been being
used or seen less
success.
So we got Razor
Wings here.
The damage is going
up a bit.
And also Razor
Wings used to have
actually a set
cooldown between
casts.
And now we remove
that cooldown so
now you can actually
cast Razor Wings
faster as you build
attack speed like all
other skills in the
game.
We also did some
small buffs to
Withering Fist.
The poison damage
went up, the slow
went up, and one of
the upgrades will now
spread to more
targets when you use
it.
And then we also
got some buffs to
Toxic Skin, which
isn't really seen
much play by
players.
We basically just
did some small
buffs to damage
both baseline, the
enhancement, and one
of the upgrades, the
variants of it.
And these are
mostly just on the
skills that people
aren't actually using
right now.
Our goal isn't to
make the Spirit
Borm even stronger.
No, this is tuning
within the builds
of the cluster.
We're most definitely
seeing Chad and
they're like, wait,
Spirit Borm buffs, and
it's like, these are
like skills that
really no one is
using, so we want
to make sure that
I mean, I can
spuff Quill Volley.
There you go,
Quill Volley.
Most definitely
needs buffs,
apparently.
No, but it's for
things that we just
haven't seen a lot
of play within
Spirit Borm players.
And I know a lot
of players are
looking at some
of the numbers,
and they're also,
these are just
like baseline numbers
on some of these
skills.
Obviously, there's
a lot of
interactions that
happen beyond that
from tempering to
the gear that you
have and everything
like that that will
end up obviously
enhancing those
even more.
So we're expecting
to, as Adam
mentioned before,
we're not expecting
to see the other
classes jump up to
the same power as
the Spirit Borm,
because the Spirit
Borm, again, is
using some unintended
interactions right
now, but those
will be addressed
in Season 7.
So with these
classes specifically,
they will get some
additional buffs so
that they can stay
competitive amongst
each other.
They're staying
together as a pack
but being a little
bit stronger here
with the Mid-Season.
Yeah, the idea
with Mid-Season,
this is probably
going to be true
with most Mid-Season
updates, is that
we're trying to
move everything a
little closer together
and also to set up
for the next season
where there will be
a lot more upheaval.
So we're like
prepping everything
to be kind of close.
Ha ha ha, upheaval.
Oh yeah.
I was like, ha ha ha.
But you know, we're
getting ready for Season
7, which will be a
lot more impactful.
Is that an Easter egg?
Cool.
Awesome.
Well, I know we have a,
again, Adam had
mentioned that this is
just a very small
preview.
Yeah, it's a lot more
than just that.
There's a lot more
than just what we
showed here.
That would be the
shortest patch notes
ever.
But we do actually
have a patch notes
coming out later this
week that will have
all the different
class changes and
everything with the
Mid-Season update.
We do have a few
other things that are
actually also hitting
related to Rune words
and a thing that a lot
of people have been
talking about, which is
shrines specifically.
Yes.
So we can shrines.
What's wrong with
shrines?
the Conduit shrine
that I don't
purposely ignore?
Yeah.
You mean the real
cursed shrine?
There you go.
All right.
Jumping into Rune
Words first.
We are doing some
tuning changes to
Rune Words.
I will tease a little
bit that we do have
some more impactful
changes coming in
Season 7, so tune in
next week for them.
But in the meantime,
we did do some
Rune Word buffs to
ones that aren't being
used as much, mostly
by lowering offering
costs.
Some examples here,
we got the Moni
Rune Word, the
offering that you
get is increased
from 25 to 35.
The Ahu Rune Word,
the offering is
being increased a
lot from 10 to 25
when hitting injured
enemies.
And then I'm just
going to butcher it.
I don't know how to
say it, but the
Seh Rune Word.
The Wolf Spirits are
now always going to
be unhindered.
So we often run into
issues where companions
and things like that
have trouble getting
to enemies, but since
they're spirits, so
why would other
things get in the way?
So now they'll always
be moving through
enemies and getting
to their targets a lot
quicker.
And then Shrines,
you know, heard some
feedback that they
don't really scale
too well.
So the Artillery,
Blast Wave, and
Conduit Shrines will
now deal more damage
and they're going to
scale with you based
on your level and
your Paragon level.
So as you level up,
as you get stronger,
the Shrines will be
getting more potent
with you.
We're going to kind of
test it, you know,
let us know how it
goes, see if you
actually enjoy getting
them and want to get
them now.
We do see some room
maybe to do some more
things above them
further if needed, but
we're going to be
trying this as a first
step to see how it
goes.
Yeah, I know we've
heard from a lot of
people about, like,
especially as you get
to later levels and
you're towards, like,
Endgame and Torment
4 and a Conduit
Shrine appears and
it's like, don't touch
it because maybe that
will make things slower,
which it currently
typically does for a
lot of players,
especially Spirit-born
players.
So it's cool to see
updates to these
shrines.
And again, like,
feedback is really
important for us to
know, like, hey, did
we hit the mark?
Do we need to do
additional things or
do we need to tweak
anything?
So let us know after
you guys get a chance
to check out the new
adjustments to the
shrines.
So that'll be really
important for us.
Some other things that
are coming down the
line, we do have some
in-game specific events
and items that we'll be
hitting here in the
coming weeks?
Weeks?
It's a little bit
after mid-season update.
We do actually have
another, we're bringing
back the Red Clock
Horror, which is part of
the Midwinter Blight
event that we had last
year.
And we'll actually have
a blog that details all
the benefits and rewards
out of this.
It's like XP benefits,
of course, that do come
with this specifically,
which is really great to
have on top of another
event that's coming,
which is Mother's
Blessing.
And Mother's Blessing
will also be, we'll have
that in the blog.
That blog is going to be
hitting on Thursday, I
believe.
So keep an eye out.
For Eternal players, we
also have a cool little
thing, kind of like a
welcome back booster type
of event for them, or
maybe it's not an event.
I don't know how to coin
it, but Colin, what does
that entail?
Yeah, so we wanted to
put together just
something to get you
back into the action.
I know part of X1 ended
up sort of marking a bunch
of items as legacy, so we
just wanted to give
everyone a one-time booster
to come back.
We're going to level you
to 50.
We'll give you a build
that we've made.
We've made three different
ones per class.
You'll be able to use it.
I'm sure everyone watching
probably doesn't care,
but you will care about
this if you haven't done
this, is we're going to
unlock all the altars of
Lilith as part of that
boost.
So if you log in and just
use it, and you haven't
got all your altars,
your altars for free,
easy peasy nuts.
Yeah, and if you're a
base game, Diablo 4,
owner, you'll end up
getting, I believe, one
of those boosts, and then
if you're a vessel of
hatred, you'll end up
getting two of those
boosts on eternal
characters, which is kind
of cool.
So if you want to jump
back in or anything,
especially after the
changes with, there goes
my earpiece.
I've been fumbling with
it all day, and now it's
gone.
But I know a lot of
players, specifically with
Season 6 jumping back in,
they notice, as you
mentioned, a lot of the
gear went to legacy gear,
so this kind of gives them
a way of being able to
kind of recover some of
that.
Yeah, refreshes it.
And then I believe we also
have another free trial
coming up for any new
players that want to check
out the Spirit Born.
The Spirit Born will
actually be part of the
free trial, and that will
be coming up here in the
coming weeks.
And so all this will be in a
blog on Thursday, which is
really cool.
And then, of course, as we
mentioned at the start of
the show, we have another
stream next week.
We'll actually have a date
for the stream later this
week for players so that
you guys can keep an eye
out for that.
But that is our Patch 2.1
PTR stream, and that one
will be pretty beefy.
We have a lot to talk about
regarding Patch 2.1 and,
of course, everything that's
going to be coming with
Season 7.
We are super stoked for
that.
The stream, again, will be a
little early because of the
Thanksgiving holiday, so a
little bit earlier than when
PTR is going to start.
We do plan on having those
notes available for players
before the Thanksgiving
holiday, and then I would
expect that PTR to start
after the Thanksgiving
holiday, so when everyone
is back in post-holiday and
is able to monitor and see
how everything is going with
PTR and taking the
feedback.
So we'll have a stream next
week.
You'll see, of course, some
of us back on stream next
week for that.
And I believe we'll be
joined by Mr. Dan Tanguay
again, who will be in
Albany and chiming in on all
the stuff that's coming with
Season 7 and Patch 2.1.
So lots of big changes
coming specifically with
that.
I know we do want to jump
into some Q&A really
quickly.
So if you guys have any
questions, we have chat
enabled on Twitch, so
twitch.tv slash Diablo.
If you're watching on other
channels and stuff like that,
that's where we do take in
specific questions.
But feel free to drop in any
questions.
We'll try to get through as
many as we can here.
Again, this is just kind of an
abbreviated stream for the
mid-season update, and then
we'll be back in a week.
Next week, yeah.
I get it.
We took a little bit of a
break from streaming, so it
kind of makes sense.
So we'll be back pretty
quickly.
But I know our first
question that we have is
related to ancestral items.
We get a lot of questions
about ancestral items.
I've seen a lot of
questions.
Oh, this earpiece is
driving me nuts.
Question number one.
Adam, fix your earpiece.
There's a plant right here,
which you guys can't see, so
I'm having to read the
screen.
Any updates to ancestral
items?
Do you guys have any
updates or news to share
regarding that?
Yeah, I know we saw a lot
of confusion in terms of
maxing out a lot of the
Codex of Power.
In X1, we actually added
roughly what we call ranks,
five ranks, to a lot of the
legendary aspects that were
ancestral only.
And I know that caused a lot
of confusion.
So currently how it works is
ancestral items have a
higher upper bounds on the
rank that you can achieve for
that aspect.
And we have seen quite a
bit of people struggling to
max out their aspects.
Generally, that was the goal
is that we do want to
grind, right?
Like we think it's good that
you can sort of get an
aspect right away.
But we like that once you
have that play style
assembled, we still want
things that you need to
work on.
That being said, we think
it's a little bit too
aggressive right now.
So we are going to be
making some changes, which
we will detail next week, in
terms of how that actually
works.
But just know that
currently ancestral items are
the sort of where you find
the max rank of a lot of
those aspects.
But you can still find them
on anything else that isn't
ancestral, the lower version.
Yeah.
I know, and we'll be talking
more about ancestral items
next week.
Specifically.
The drop rates.
Yeah, a lot of stuff
regarding that.
Is there any plans?
This is, I'm taking a few
questions from the forums
and of course chat because we
did post this on the forums
beforehand.
Urza from the forum says,
can we get boss materials to
stack like runes or maybe
even higher?
Are there any plans for
something like that?
Yeah, we are looking into it.
There's things on our side in
terms of like storage and
duping that we're a little bit
worried about, but we're
looking at making a change
sometime in the longer future.
Question from a couple people
like Archangel890 and Dragonage
says, any chances that you guys
will potentially change like XP
gain, maybe the growth to
Paragon 300?
Is there any plans on maybe
making adjustments or tuning
specifically on that end?
Currently, not at the moment.
I think it's something we're
monitoring though in terms of
the feedback. We do like that
you can get just about
everything within the first
200 Paragon levels and
everything from there has a
pretty steep diminishing
return in terms of power.
So what we don't want to say
to you all is like you need
to grind 200 hours to unlock
your build and do all the
things that are sort of
play style defining, which we
define as like the sort of
glyphs and the legendary
nodes. So we've seen actually
a lot of positive feedback
that like you can get your
build online and that you
still have something to work
towards. The sooner we sort of
short circuit that Paragon
grind, the more we sort of
get back to that pre-expansion
one state where you just
don't get anything from
killing monsters because
you're Paragon 300 in the
first two weekends. So
currently, you know, we're
looking at monitoring it and
we're super open to the
feedback. But so far we've
seen a good amount of
positivity around it.
I think it's kind of in
line with what you're talking
about with the legendary
powers, right? Like those
last five ranks are on
Ancestral Items only. And so
our idea is like we want you
to get your build online and
play the way you want within a
pretty, you know, pretty
quickly or whatever. But then
you have something to work
towards like incrementally to
become stronger and stronger
and that we're okay with
taking a long time. Totally.
As long as it's not like
cutting you off from the
build at all. Yeah. It's
about getting you into the
fun and like making sure
that your build is blasting
but you have things to sort of
use that build to blast for.
Right. That makes sense.
Yeah. And I think there's
like the other thing that
people are probably forgetting
about is like we do have
these events coming up and
stuff which also benefit.
which will be boosting
it all. And everything
like that which will be a
good opportunity for
players to like be able to
you know if they really
want because they're as
we've seen there are there
is a reward to for getting
to Paragon 300 and stuff.
So it allows players that
opportunity to kind of use
those events to be able to
boost that. And we have
obviously Red Pill Core
stuff coming up here. And
of course we have Mother's
Blessing. So there's
opportunities to help with
some of that XP based off
of those events specifically.
So there is a question
regarding like materials
again. You know can we
expect any additional buffs
for drop rates on Rawhide,
Iron, Forgotten Souls,
anything like that?
Yeah. So actually it is in
the midseason but we did
buff Legion events. I know
that was a personal favorite
of a lot of folks for the
midseason. For season seven
we're taking a look at just
sort of buffing the various
sources and also really
drilling down on like what
are the bottlenecks players
are having and iterating
towards that. There's no
major changes coming in
season seven. Like we're
not going to quadruple the
amount of materials across
the game. But it is
something again in the
spirit of like tightening
the things that we have.
We are actively looking at
a lot of the material
inflows and outflows and
we want to give you the
tools to sort of get the
materials that you're
looking for. We're sort of
what we're trying to do is
ensure that there are
things that you still care
about. Right. And you still
want to grind. It's still in
that spirit of like it's
walking that fine line of
there are things to work
towards without it feeling
super tedious. So that's
what we're trying to
tighten and work towards.
There is a question
regarding this from Remster
Ma says do you have any
plans and start bringing in
new midseason mechanics? I
think for that more so I
would expect like larger
mechanics content changes and
stuff like that to happen
around new seasons as
opposed to a midseason
update. I think we look at
taking midseason updates
making tweaks to you know
balance items or anything
that we're hearing feedback
from so that we can spend
most of our you know
concentration and focus on
really putting in some of
these newer type of content
pieces around new seasons
specifically. Yeah I think
you think going forward is
midseason is a time to just
like tweak and iterate and
you know use rework existing
things but we're really
putting all of our books on
like bigger upheavals you
know larger changes lots of
new stuff into the beginning
of the season. So next week
will be pretty exciting we
got a lot of new stuff
coming in but that's where
we're kind of targeting that
to make that kind of a big
moment and exciting time to
come back and play. There is
a question from casual
dragon regarding under city
drops and asking is there any
plans to potentially fix those
make those better specifically
on that end. Yeah so this
sort of leads into there are
some ancestral drop rate
changes that we want to talk
about next week but in
general what that'll mean is
all the loot across the game
will generally get better so
it is something that we're
working on. I'm about to take
this earpiece and throw it
across the room because it
just keeps popping out and
it's driving me insane. That's
a question from PezRadar. The
question from Finamdar says
Diablo any at Diablo any
stability fixes coming and
seeing a whole lot more
crashes since the last couple
patches. I will say that we've
been monitoring we can actually
see whenever a player actually
crashes. We know it we get
logs from it on our end. I know
that the engineering team here
has been doing a ton of work on
working to get the game more
stable. You've probably seen a
bunch of different small
client patches go out. We
actually just re-enabled like
DLSS in a client patch that
went out yesterday. There are
additional changes and more
reviewing that's being done from
our side to ensure that you
know the game is running very
stable so expect to see more of
that as we get through this
season and of course into next
season because our goal is to
make sure you know baseline
everyone can jump in without
any of these types of issues
and everything. And shout out
to our engineering team. I know
they've been working long and
hard on figuring all this stuff
out. They've been that's like
their top priority right now.
They actually behind the scenes
we even collaborate with them a
lot on doing various things
related to game performance
under the hood like making
skills cleaner making
interactions cleaner like we're
constantly doing stuff to make
the game run smoother in the
background pretty much every
patch like we're fixing multiple
things so it's definitely
something that we're always
working on actively.
Why so blue panda bear? Any
chance on tempering schools can
be used more than once?
Investing time to finally get a
rare drop and it bricks kind of
doesn't feel too great.
Any thoughts on tempering
schools how that's been going?
Yeah I think it's definitely
something we hear a lot of
feedback on and it's something
that you know we were sort of
taking incremental approach right
like with the X1 or the expansion
one changes we made it so that a
lot of recipes are three. We also
added of course the scroll of
tempering or restoration in
expansion one to see how that
sort of changes things. So we're
just really taking a measured
approach. If we see still there's
a lot of feedback that it just
still isn't hitting that mark
we're absolutely open to changing
things like potentially letting it
be used more than once and we're
just sort of monitoring at this
point. We are getting questions
about the Armory. Stay tuned. TM.
Soon. TM. We'll have
information on that. As you guys
know that that has been in
development something that we've
already confirmed about. I will be
talking more about it here soon. TM.
So keep your eyes peeled. Is that the
term? Keep your eyes peeled. I don't
know. There's a saying that you know
stay tuned. I don't know. Last question
here that we have before we head off
is Holes Transition says will Dance and
Knives get buffs and any changes to be
more compatible with collecting loot
like opening doors etc. You know when
you're when you're going you're
spinning to win with your knives and
stuff is there any way of or any
plans of potentially having them
seamlessly move around around a
dungeon or something like that from
that. Nothing on my radar right now
but that's a good note to take. It's a
good note to take. It's a good to
note to take. Rogues want to spin to
win. And never stop. Ever. You have to
do all this setup and snapshot and then
you have to like open the door so we do
know it's a thing. Yeah. So we'll see.
Stay tuned. Stay tuned. It's another
thing to stay tuned. So again thanks
again everyone for jumping in providing
questions and everything from our end.
We will have patch notes later this
week so stay tuned for that. The blogs
for Mother's Blessing, the Red Cloak
Horror, our Eternal Boost stuff,
everything will be out on Thursday. So
also check out for that blog. Midseason
update hits next week so patch notes
will be out before the midseason
update and you guys will also hear
about our stream date next week for
the Patch 2.1 PTR. So we'll be talking
a whole bunch. That will be another
beefy stream. Yeah. I know it's a little
bit short. That one's going to be a
little bit more beefy than this one.
But look at this. Two streams in two
weeks. We're about to do it. So we will
see you guys next week. Again huge
thanks to Colin, Adam for joining us.
Our wonderful Mini Cosrote over here.
Super awesome. Super cute. Love you
Aaron. So but thank you guys. We'll see
you guys next week for our Patch 2.1
PTR stream. And yeah. Check out the
blogs and patch notes later this week.
See you guys.