Season 4 is going to be the biggest update we have ever made to Diablo 4 since it has launched.
Our focus on Season 4 is to really make a lot of evergreen updates to the core systems of Diablo 4.
In Season 4, we're ramping the intensity across the Seasonal and Eternal realms through a collection of new activities
aimed at ensuring the moment-to-moment gameplay experience is as exciting and rewarding
when Hal comes to Sanctuary.
Season 4 item changes are some of the biggest changes we've made to Diablo 4 thus far.
We've never done anything like this.
We are fundamentally changing how you engage with items, how you upgrade them,
and along the way, solving a lot of things that we've seen continually from our community
that we agree with are pain points of our existing item system right now.
So in this new itemization system, we're focusing on narrowing down the scope of the base affixes.
They're going to be a lot simpler, they're going to be fewer in number,
so you can much more easily parse whether this item is useful for you,
and if it is, then you can take it and further upgrade it and customize it to your own specific build.
Tempering is a new system that allows you to really customize the gear that you find.
In order to temper, you will need to go to the Blacksmith
and then choose the recipe that you wish to temper from,
and then a random affix from that recipe will be attached onto your gear.
Tempering recipes can be found from almost all of the content throughout Sanctuaries.
So you will actually be looking for tempering recipes that go directly with what you're envisioning.
Maybe you're thinking, I'm going to play a Frost Sorceress.
There are also going to be recipes that are more generic
and maybe are just generally good for the Sorceress,
but you'll be able to choose which one you think is going to be most powerful
with the build you're making for your class.
We're making a pretty radical change to the Codex of Power in this season.
Based again on the feedback that has been coming from our players.
Now, every single Legendary in the game will be entered into your Codex of Power
so that you can continually imprint the best possible version of that Legendary onto your gear.
So going forward, there will no longer be carrying around all of these Aspect Crystals in your inventory.
It's all going to be in the Codex of Power.
So part of the final system that we have is going to be greater affixes.
What's a greater affix?
Well, we want to keep it compelling that there are some drops that are even better than the others
when you're trying to get the perfect build at endgame.
Because of this, in World Tier 4 and only in World Tier 4,
when an Ancestral Legendary item drops,
there's a chance the affixes on it can roll as greater affixes.
These will roll with bigger values that are normally available for that affix.
Greater affixes are fairly rare, but they're not impossible to find.
While leveling up, you're going to be able to find upgrades much more easily with this new system.
Another part of itemization is going to be masterworking.
Now, this is something really intended for that very high endgame, again, World Tier 4.
This is where a player is going to take an item,
already has the affixes that they want on it,
but now they go through a process of upgrading those affixes,
getting even higher values on them.
Masterworking really starts at level 100.
Once you've already completed your build and found some of the best items,
you're going to be able to test your build against the powerful enemies of the pit.
The pit is a new endgame system that has been added in this season
that is going to challenge players that feel that they have largely maximized their build.
By pushing into more difficult tiers of the pit,
you're going to be able to unlock rarer crafting materials
to masterwork your gear even further.
You're going to have to play some of the hardest content in the game,
but once you do, if you're successful,
you can go and make those affixes even stronger.
In Season 4, we're ramping the intensity of the Helltides
through the inclusion of a variety of new activities,
the first of which is a doubling down and rise of the cultists' presence throughout the tide.
You're going to be running through the Helltides,
seeing the cultists just conjuring up swarms and swarms of demons,
adding to that sense of mannequin chaos that they're pretty well known for.
The other archetype that we're adding is the presence of the Doomsayers,
who were unfortunate enough to be caught out in the tide
and basically just lost their minds to all of the mania going on around them.
And lastly, rounding out the new activities are just the inclusion of the Iron Wolves.
They're finally joining the fight.
They could no longer stand in the sidelines,
seeing the Helltides and Hells forces intensify their assault on Sanctuary.
As Season 4 players engage and progress through the Call of the Wolves seasonal activity,
they'll earn honor with the Iron Wolves,
unlocking access to a vast assortment of rewards
to accompany and empower your Season 4 journeys.
In the updated Helltide, for players who are able to stay alive long enough,
they'll be paid a visit by the Hellborn,
former heroes of Sanctuary who have aligned with the forces of Hell
to attack the allies they once aligned with.
Players who are able to take down the Hellborn
will be acquiring the materials they need
to engage with the new premier Helltide activity,
the Accursed Rituals.
Located in the Helltide,
these Accursed Rituals are pretty much just botched rituals from the cultists
that players will be kick-starting for themselves,
drawing the intention of all the nearby Helltide monsters
in this kind of all-out battle.
One of my favorite themes for these ambushes is the Hellworm.
It's literally a giant Hell slug beast
that emerges from the ground
and spews out a whole bunch of mobs at you.
If you're able to survive that,
you'll be paid a visit from the Blood Maiden,
our brand new Helltide mini-boss
and one of the ultimate challenges in the new experience.
So I think I'm actually most excited about this season
because of what you're able to do with your old characters,
how they can integrate with this new item game
and take them to new levels of power with this system.
I think that the best part of this update
is that you're going to be really empowered
to build the character that you want to play.
You're going to be able to pick custom affixes
and enhance your character in a lot of new and interesting ways.
Happy Friday, Diablo community.
Welcome to another Diablo 4 Campfire Chat.
I am Adam Fletcher.
I'm joined here by a very familiar face,
Mr. Adam Jackson.
Hello, hello.
The Adams have invaded.
We did it. We won.
We have taken over.
We actually are joined by one additional person,
and this person is tuning in, patching in?
I don't know what the...
Phoning in? I don't know.
From Albany, Blizzard Albany,
and that's Mr. Dan Tanguay.
Dan, would you like to introduce yourself?
Yeah, sure thing.
Hi, I'm Dan Tanguay,
and I'm one of the lead seasons designers for Diablo 4,
and yeah, we've got a lot of exciting stuff to share with you.
Awesome.
Great to hear from Dan.
Dan is kind of like melting in Albany.
I believe it's very, very warm up there.
It's actually warmer there than California,
which is kind of crazy.
It is, yeah.
Look at this.
Adam and Adam.
Ooh, I love it.
We did it.
No more Joes.
Yeah, no more Joes.
Where's Joe Pipera?
Not here.
He's actually on vacation,
so that's the reason why he's not here.
But we have a lot to talk about today.
We are actually going to be talking about Season 5 in the PTR,
and we do want to, like, you know,
there's been a lot going on with Diablo 4
over the last couple of months.
Obviously, Season 4 has launched.
We had our mid-season update last week.
We introduced pets, which is really cool.
Just random other band pets.
Just no one expected it,
but we did introduce pets within Season 4,
and at the same time,
we also had our release date announcement
for Vessel of Hatred,
which is October 8th.
So lots and lots and lots of cool stuff
that's going on with Diablo 4,
and we have more to share today.
But, of course, with PTR,
we do need to talk, like,
a little bit of the housekeeping stuff
to make sure that players are aware of it
and when it's going to start.
Currently, we have Season 5 PTR
actually starting next Tuesday,
and that is on the 25th.
It will run for one week,
similar to the Season 4 PTR.
It is PC Battle.net only again.
It is just easier for us
to be able to get builds up
and get things out
and get feedback in really quickly
when we have it on PC Battle.net.
So that will be going live next Tuesday.
Everything that we're talking about today
will be in a blog
that will go live after the stream,
as well as patch notes
will be going live after the stream,
and they're pretty beefy in themselves.
It's Friday, you guys.
We haven't done a Friday stream in...
I don't know.
It's been a while.
It's been a long while.
For feedback, though,
we will be opening up our PTR forums
for players to actually be able to submit feedback.
So the Diablo 4 forums
will have a special section for PTR.
And then separately,
if you do want to leave feedback
on other avenues,
such as like Reddit
or the Community Sanctuary Discord,
places like that,
we most definitely end up
combing through
all the different various ways
of players being able to provide feedback
specifically from that end.
For this PTR,
we will note that
this one will be a little different
than Season 4
in regards to how you can start off characters.
There will still be character boosts
like what we had with the Season 4 PTR.
I believe it's actually moved
to a different city.
I can't recall.
I think we had it in Kiovashod before,
and I believe it's in a different city,
and I don't recall
which city it is.
It's in the blog, though.
But all that information
will be there after the stream.
Separately,
we did incorporate
a character copy feature,
but we initiated
this character copy already.
No one knows this,
but as of yesterday,
characters were copied
from your accounts
over to PTR,
so it gives you
a little bit of variety
of being able to take over
some of those characters
that you've already built out.
Or, you know,
if you want to,
you can still use
the character boost.
I will note,
we do want players
to be experiencing it
in a variety of ways,
like whether using
your current characters
that we're copying over,
or if you're using
some of the character boosts,
we do recommend,
or if you want to level up
to level one,
like that's another option
as well.
It allows us to get feedback
from all different aspects,
so we do recommend,
you know,
trying it out
in different ways
and providing feedback
of like how things feel,
how things flow
within the PTR itself.
So that is all
kind of like the general
housekeeping notes
that we do have.
Oh, and I will say that
I believe we actually did,
we did correct that
Codex of Power reset thing
as well.
Oh, okay.
So yeah,
I remember that was
plaguing some people
last season.
We did correct that,
so it won't reset,
I believe,
every single time
you end up like creating
a new character
or boosting a new character,
I believe.
And then separately,
on the forums,
we will have a known issues list
because they're,
you know,
it's PTR,
it's an early build,
so we want to make sure
that people are aware of that.
And with PTR,
you know,
when we take in feedback,
it's great for players
to be able to like provide
all various forms of feedback.
I will say,
by the time Season 5 launches,
we will try our best
to get as much
of that feedback in.
If it's something
that's like a massive,
like, oh,
like a huge overhaul
or something like that,
I wouldn't expect it
in Season 5,
but it is good
to hear that feedback
because it might be something
that we end up incorporating
maybe in the future
for like a future season
from that end.
Yeah,
it's very useful.
So it helps us drive
future decisions
and even,
we did a lot of reaction
to PTR feedback
in Season 4,
if I remember right.
We did like a whole lot
on our team at least
and I expect the same
for Season 5,
so.
Exactly.
Send it in,
it's very useful.
And then one last thing
I do want to note is
because players have probably seen
when Season 4 is ending,
which is currently
in early August,
you can see that kind of like
on your character select screen
when you're jumping
into the game.
I will note that Season 5
is a little bit shorter
of a season
than what we've had beforehand.
Season 5 itself
will run until
that October 8th date
with Vessel of Hatred
because Vessel of Hatred
is actually the start
of Season 6.
So we did want to
at least clarify,
make sure,
because we've heard
a lot of those questions
of like,
hey,
is Vessel of Hatred
hitting in the middle
of Season 5?
Things like that.
So we did want to note
that from that end.
But enough of the
housekeeping notes.
I know a lot of players
want to hear about
Season 5 in itself.
And so Mr. Dan Tanguay
from the sweltering
city limits of Albany
will be walking us
through Season 5.
Yeah, absolutely.
So yeah,
let's dive into the new features
on PTR for Season 5.
Just to give you
a little bit of context,
you know,
we did some early
brainstorming for Season 5
and we knew that,
you know,
we needed to build out
the endgame.
So endgame,
you know,
we've heard y'all
that endgame is very important.
And Season 4,
we added the pit
into the endgame
and some people
have been playing
Helltides into the endgame.
But we still want to expand
the endgame a bit more,
right?
So if it's an endgame activity,
we definitely need something
that's rewarding
and very replayable.
We also wanted to make something
with a lot of monsters.
I mean,
monster density
and just entering
that feeling of flow state
is really important
for players.
We needed something
that had stakes
and we wanted players
to push their luck.
And finally,
we really wanted
to return to Hell.
You know,
previous Diablo games
let you return to Hell
after you defeat
the big boss,
but Diablo 4
hadn't done that yet.
And so with all
those goals in mind,
let me introduce you
to the Infernal Hordes.
Now,
let me give you
a quick summary
of what the Infernal Hordes is.
It's a wave-based
gameplay mode
with survivor-like choices
in between the waves
and it'll culminate
with an all-new
boss encounter
and then the rewards
build on top
of Itemization 2.0
that came in Season 4.
So,
now how do you go about
confronting the Internal Hordes?
How do you get back to Hell?
I think we can queue up
some footage
and then I'll talk you
through some of the ways
you get back to Hell.
All right.
First off,
you're going to unlock,
you know,
the activity for Hell
with a brisk Eternal questline
starting at World Tier 3
in Zarbenzet.
That's where you need
to go in the PTR.
Now,
you need a new type of key
called a compass,
which you can see down
in the inventory below here.
And like Nightmare Dungeons,
the compasses all have
a starting monster difficulty
and a number of revives.
And there are eight levels
of difficulty
with escalating challenge
and rewards.
As you can see,
it's a very Nightmare Dungeon-like
flow here.
And then compasses
can be upgraded
to higher tiers
with all new consumables
called Abyssal Scrolls.
So,
you'll get a chance
to play with all these
new features
when you're in the PTR.
But,
let's really talk about
the gameplay itself.
And I think we've got
some footage
of the wave-based play
that we can show off here.
First off,
going to have a lot of monsters.
Now,
you have one monster here.
This is the start of wave one.
And so,
you defeat this
Aether Fiend
and it's going to drop
something called
Burning Aether,
which is a new currency.
Now,
this new currency
is specific to hell
and you use it
to unlock the spoils
of hell
at the end of a run.
And at the end
of each wave,
there's going to be
what's called
the Infernal Offer.
So,
let's get through this wave
and we'll take a look
at the Infernal Offer.
Now,
you see these hands
reaching out from hell itself
and they're tempting you
with a choice.
You're going to choose
the form of your destructor.
You're going to pick
a boon and a bane
that impacts
the rest of your run.
And so,
now you've chosen
a boon and a bane
and
that's going to modify
the gameplay
that comes up next.
And so,
here,
you're jumping into
one of the new activities
that also unlocks
Aether in this.
And this is a soul spire.
It's pretty similar
to a hell spire
that you'd see
in Helltide.
And you have to kill
a number of enemies
within that ring
in order to be able
to earn an Aether.
And you can upgrade soul spires
from the Infernal Offer
as well,
if you like.
And then,
finally,
what you need to do
is complete the number
of waves
in order to be able
to confront the boss.
And so,
you see,
in this particular run,
you're at five of five waves.
So,
you are just about ready
once you defeat this wave
to go confront
the new bosses
for the Infernal Hordes.
So,
we'll finish collecting
our Aether here,
find our last number
of enemies,
and I think we're good.
I think we're ready to go.
So,
let's take a look
at our new bosses.
I think we've got
some cool art
to share here.
So,
these are the Fel Council.
They're going to be
some familiar faces
for Diablo II players.
They are resurrected versions
of the council members
from Diablo II.
Now,
for those of you
who didn't play Diablo II,
the council members
were former high priests
of the Zacarum,
and they had promised
to basically
take care of Mephisto
after he'd been trapped
in the Soul Stone,
and he'd been hidden down
and caressed
and trabencal.
And,
of course,
as it happens,
Mephisto corrupted them,
both in mind first
and then their bodies,
and they became demons
who are just zealous
and serve him
without question.
And so,
we thought it was
going to be really cool
to be able to resurrect them
and bring them back
for Diablo IV,
and they fit great in hell.
We had to tweak
their power sets
a little bit
to fit the D4 combat system,
so we gave them
new titles
and new looks
to really reflect
their combat specialties.
Yeah,
it's incredibly awesome
to see
these guys come back.
You know,
it's giving
very nostalgic
vibes
of doing
a bunch of,
you know,
endurance of hate runs
for Mephisto
and doing Meph runs
and everything like that.
So, yeah,
it's really awesome
to see him back
in Season 5.
Yeah,
I agree.
Diablo II
is certainly near
and dear to our hearts
here out in New York.
And,
yeah,
we're really glad
to have him back,
and we hope to see
hopefully more returning
new faces
in the future, too.
So,
let's take a look
at that boss encounter now.
So,
I showed you
a number of
members of the
Fel Council here.
We've actually built
five of them in total,
but you're only going
to fight three at a time.
Now,
we keep two
in the hopper,
basically,
and we do that
because we want
to have a whole bunch
of replay associated
with this boss fight.
And because we're only
using three of the five,
there's actually
ten variations
of this boss fight
that you can fight
randomly
as you do
your infernal run.
And so,
we're going to
basically kill them off.
And
once you defeat one,
the fight
will actually escalate.
Actually,
it probably escalates
even if you just
take down
a certain amount
of health,
if I remember correctly.
And
it escalates.
Basically,
their attacks
become more powerful,
and then they start
really getting
even more powerful
kind of room-clearing
attacks towards the end.
But we've defeated
them here,
and this is the reward
moment I actually
wanted to talk through
with you,
because this is something
that really ties
into itemization 2.0.
You've got several
chests here,
and you've got a choice
of the rewards
you get at the end
of your infernal run.
You can choose
from a chest
that contains
all new legendaries
and new uniques.
You can choose
from a chest
that contains
all sorts of
crafting materials,
including
masterworking materials,
so you don't need
to go to the pit
anymore exclusively
to get masterworking
materials.
You've got a chest
that allows you
just to get
a whole bunch of gold.
I know people out there
are really asking for gold,
and this is going to be
a good source of it.
And finally,
even though it wasn't
shown here,
you have a chest
that guarantees
a single item
with a greater
affects on it.
And so we thought
we'd want to try this out
and see how people
respond to it,
and we thought
it would be pretty exciting.
You know,
certainly in Season 4,
I'm really trying
to get some more
greater affectses,
so I'd love
to have this
in Season 5.
So yeah,
let's take a closer look
at some of the uniques
you can farm
from the Infernal Horde
since we're talking
about rewards already.
So we're going to
queue up some footage here.
So first up,
we've got the Basilisk.
And so this is going
to be a new unique
staff for Druids.
And so when you hit
an enemy with a nurse skill,
it'll petrify them
and deal physical damage.
So turning the monsters
to stone,
always cool.
But it's also cool
that you can CC
your target
and boost
your initial attack here.
So this one's
pretty exciting
for you Druid players
out there.
All right,
next up,
we've got the Third Blade.
Now this is a unique sword
for Barbarians.
This one makes
your Weapon Mastery skills
be treated as core skills
that cost Fury.
Even though they deal
a little reduced damage,
this one's pretty exciting
because now you can start
making all sorts
of new builds
that you've never seen before.
So we're really interested
to see what the community
comes up with here.
All right,
next up,
we've got the Mordicrux.
Now the Mordicrux
is a new unique dagger
for Necros.
So when you consume a corpse,
there's a chance
that you'll create
a skeletal simulacrum
that seeks out enemies.
And when it dies,
it explodes.
So essentially,
you're making a skele bomb
when you consume corpses.
And so that's just going
to seek out targets
and explode.
I think that'd be pretty handy
for my Necro this season.
So I'm looking forward
to that one too.
Next up,
we have the Mordicrux.
Now the Mordicrux
is a new unique dagger
for rogues.
So if you use
a Cetrifuge skill,
you'll create a totem.
And if you hit that totem
with an attack,
it replicates any of the damage
it takes to all nearby enemies.
And so it's a great way
for essentially replicating
and doubling down
on the damage
that you're dealing
in a particular area.
All right.
Next up,
we've got the Vox Omnium.
Now the Vox Omnium
is a new unique staff
for Sorx.
And so when you cast
a core skill,
it's going to cast
an additional
two basic projectiles
based on the previous
elements used.
And so this allows you
to really start comboing
your core and basic skills together.
And if you decide
to have different elements
associated with those
core and basic skills,
now you can start
casting fire
and lightning
and cold
all at the same time.
So we're pretty excited
about this one too.
And the final one
we're going to share out here
is actually a new set of boots
that's available
for all classes.
And these are called
Rackinof's Wake.
And so whenever you use
an ability with a cooldown,
you'll trigger
tongue twister,
trigger an explosion
dealing fire damage.
And so really,
it's pretty straightforward.
You're going to bathe
your enemies in flames
whenever you use
a cooldown skill.
So maybe I'm going to
dust off my whirlwind barb
here and slap them on
and see how it does.
So yeah,
these are some
of the uniques
and legendaries
that are going in
to the infernal hordes.
I think there are
10 uniques overall
and over 20 legendaries
that you can farm
from the infernal hordes.
So there's going to be
a lot to chase down in there.
That's awesome.
Thank you, Dan,
for like sharing,
going through all that stuff.
I know with players
jumping in on PTR,
especially for
and trying out
infernal hordes
and everything,
what's kind of like
the top things
that you really want them
to like kind of hone in on,
give feedback on,
check on for PTR?
Yeah, absolutely.
We definitely need feedback
on the PTR.
It's super critical
to ensuring that,
you know,
the infernal hordes
and all the rewards
feel great
for when the season launches.
So here are some
of the topics
that, you know,
we could use some help on.
First off,
you know,
just how is
the infernal hordes gameplay?
How do the boons
and banes feel?
You know,
which ones do you like
the most or the least?
And these are types of things
that will help us
fine tune that experience.
Similarly,
you know,
how is it acquiring compasses?
Do you have too much?
Too few?
How do you feel
about upgrading them?
You know,
that could help us
really dial in
kind of the access
to the infernal hordes.
We're also interested
in learning
how you feel
about the difficulty
and the gameplay length
of the different tiers.
Like I said at the top,
we've got eight different tiers
of difficulty.
And so,
you know,
we have the ability
to dial those in a little bit.
We want to make sure
that players can
really replay this
over and over again
as they push
into the end game.
Much like the pit.
And then finally,
of course,
how are the rewards?
You know,
which do you like
the most or the least?
You know,
we can certainly
make tweaks
on the rewards
to make sure
they're as enticing
as possible.
Awesome.
Yeah,
and I know
with the infernal hordes,
this is kind of a,
this is another alternative
because as you mentioned,
you can jump into it
starting with world tier three.
So,
if you're actually
leveling a new character,
you can actually
jump into infernal hordes
and you're able
to earn,
like,
experience
in here.
So,
you actually have
the opportunity
of,
like,
jumping into hell tides
if you want to.
You can jump into
infernal hordes.
When you get to,
you know,
85 or something like that,
you can jump into pits.
So,
there's now,
like,
more,
or nightmare dungeons,
obviously,
when you're updating,
you're upgrading
your glyphs and everything.
So,
there's a lot of
different variety now
for being able to
kind of level up
a character,
especially as you're
going to that
mid to late game
phase of your
character's journey,
you could say.
Yeah,
something else to bring up
for the rewards
for the infernal horde
as well that I want
to clarify.
So,
Dan mentioned about,
you know,
there's going to be
uniques that are there
that you can target
farm in the infernal hordes.
There's actually going
to be a group of uniques
and legendaries
that you're able to
target farm in that
piece of content
in the infernal hordes.
So,
you're also,
kind of similar
to how the normal game works,
you know,
how you can target farm
a unique from a boss
but you can find it
anywhere else in the world.
It's the same way here
where you can get
these new uniques
and legendaries anywhere
but you have a better chance,
you know,
if you're targeting them
in the infernal hordes.
And this is the first time
that we're doing this
with a group of legendaries
as well.
We have legendary powers
that are actually able
to be target farmed
in the infernal hordes
which is actually
something a little bit
new to the game.
So,
I just wanted to clarify that
and in addition to that
we're also adding
new uniques
and legendaries
to the rest of the game
as well
in addition to this.
So,
there's actually
a very large group
of uniques.
I think it's over 50
or something.
Yeah,
there's over 50
new uniques
and legendaries
coming into season five.
We have a lot coming.
It's pretty extensive.
And a lot more
to talk about there too.
Yeah,
this was just kind of
a small preview
of what people
are looking at here
and they'll be able
to jump in more
and actually check it out
on PTR
because all of them
will be present there.
And I know Adam
is actually going to talk
through a few additional
ones here later.
But,
yeah,
Dan,
this is awesome.
Can't wait for players
to jump in.
I appreciate you
informing
and providing
all the new updates
and everything.
It's exciting.
Yep.
From the sweltering heat
of all,
I'm going to keep
bringing it up.
They canceled school
up there.
It's crazy.
I'm like,
that's absolutely insane.
But,
we will be seeing Dan
again here later
especially when we get
into Q&A at the end.
But,
Dan,
thank you again.
I think we're...
Oh,
you're welcome.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Appreciate it.
And then,
I think we're going
to jump into
a little bit
of some balance
and class updates
with Mr. Adam Jackson.
Yeah,
let's get to it.
We have a lot
to talk about.
I think we have...
Yeah,
so the topics
I'm going to be
covering today,
we've got unique items.
We're going to be
talking quite a bit
about that.
We've got some updates
to mythic uniques
that are very exciting
and near and dear
to my heart.
And then,
we've got your
standard class updates.
A lot of stuff
coming in Season 5.
One thing to clarify here
is that we are going
to be releasing
the patch notes soon,
so I'm not going
to be going over
every single,
you know,
class update
because there's
a ton of them.
Kind of similar
to Season 4.
I'm really only
going to highlight
just like one
major thing
for each class
on the stream today,
but you'll be able
to see all the things
that we're doing
in the patch notes.
There's a lot.
So, first,
uniques.
We have some
quality of life updates
here,
really targeting
how you get uniques
that I'm pretty pumped
about to announce
here today.
So,
you can now target
farm uniques
from three additional sources.
You can target them
from oval vendors,
helltide chests,
and whisper caches.
These places
where you've always
been able to,
you know,
kind of target farm
certain gear slots
and not been able
to get uniques
and you're wondering,
well, why couldn't we do that?
That stinks.
Well, now you can
and it's awesome
and I love it.
So, here,
just to give some
more detail
into how this works
is basically
when you open,
like, I'm just going
to use helltide chests
as an example, right?
If you want
a specific unique weapon,
let's say,
you can just simply
target the weapon
helltide chests
and you'll be able
to have a chance
to get only unique weapons
for your class
from those chests.
So, when you're targeting
a specific thing,
you just go to,
you know,
the place that has
that slot,
whether it's the
oval vendor,
the helltide chest,
or the whisper cache
and you'll have a chance
to get uniques
that are targeted
for that slot.
So, it kind of adds,
you know,
while you're doing
your normal grind
of, you know,
doing the boss ladder,
killing the boss,
you can also be
collecting ovals,
doing the helltides,
doing the whispers
and having a chance
to target and get
that unique as well
from that content.
And, in addition to that,
this is also true
for mythic uniques.
So, I'll just give
an example here
of exactly how this works.
Let's say that you want
to get, you know,
Harlequin crest,
a Shaco,
or Andariel's Visage.
You don't want
to target those helms.
You could be targeting
helms from helltide,
targeting helms,
and, you know,
when you turn in your ovals
to the oval vendor,
and every time,
if you get a mythic unique,
you will get one of those two
from that source.
Now, also to clarify,
let's say that you are,
like, targeting gloves
for some reason.
You know,
we don't have any mythic
unique gloves yet.
Then, if you were to get
a mythic unique,
you still can.
It'll just give you
a random one instead,
since, you know,
you can't target one
in that slot.
So, pretty exciting way
to target kind of
the things that you want
while you're farming
for the things that you want.
It's going to be amazing.
Yeah, I'm really excited.
I know we've heard
a lot of players going like,
hey, you know,
we do the endgame bosses
a whole lot,
and we're trying to,
and you can actually find them
just in the open world as well.
We've actually seen
a lot of cases,
especially with this past season,
where players are jumping
into helltide,
and they're actually
finding them there,
but now it's an additional,
or additional options
for players,
which I think will be
a lot better
for just overall
finding some of the gear
that everyone really wants.
As someone who,
for the last three seasons,
my uniques have always
come from the beast in ice,
I am very selfishly invested
in getting this into the game.
Yes, yes.
So.
All right, let's talk about
other unique updates here.
We're going to be making
a whole lot of updates
to our unique items,
so I'm going to be
covering a lot today.
We've heard your feedback,
and we're going to be
doing some updates here.
To clarify,
before I go into
what the updates are,
you are going to be
seeing these updates
to the way that we think about
and our philosophy
around uniques
and how they work.
You're going to be seeing them
in the PTR
for the new uniques
coming into season five.
Between the PTR
and the launch,
you'll be seeing
in the season five launch
these updates
to all the existing uniques
in the game.
So when season five comes out,
basically all the uniques
will get these updates
that I'm about to talk about,
but in the PTR,
you're only going to really see this
in the new uniques
coming into the game.
Yeah, there.
So now we can go on
to the next part.
All right.
So the team's been talking a lot.
As many of you probably know,
in season four,
we did Ironization 2.0,
we didn't really update
the uniques
almost at all in the game.
We didn't do a big pass
to cover how they exist
in tempering
or anything like that.
So the team's been talking
a lot about
what is the role
of uniques in Diablo 4?
How are they different
from legendary items?
Because they're kind of similar
in that they both give you
a legendary power
that's really strong.
But how are they different?
And what do we want them
to be long-term?
And we've kind of landed
on a few things here
that I'm going to talk about.
The first one is that,
you know,
they're powerful
and exciting items
that kind of direct players
to builds, right?
So imagine you're
a Fireball Sorc.
You know,
we've got two uniques for you.
They really target you.
You're going to feel
a lot better playing
with Fireball
when you take them.
You know,
we want you to take
these things
and kind of level up
your build.
They're moments of like
very large incremental power
where you feel like
you're, you know,
filling in your fantasy
as a class.
The next one is that
they're kind of
pick up and play, right?
They're easy to evaluate.
The moment that you
pick up the unique,
you know,
you know whether
it's a good one
or a bad one.
We want this to be
a little bit different
from Legendary Powers
where, you know,
you pick it up
and you kind of
go on a journey
where, you know,
you make it into something
that's really good.
A unique,
you know when you pick it up
whether or not
it's one that you want to keep
or one that you don't.
And then the last one,
pretty obvious
but was worth saying,
you know,
they're kind of more
rare chase items
that players don't see
very often.
You know,
when you're going
they're going to be
a good one.
You know,
you want to upgrade
your codex.
They are the way
that you can,
you know,
get greater affixes
and temper
and masterwork them.
So there's a reason
why you want to churn
and look through
a lot of them.
Uniques,
you do want to get
a good one obviously
but not nearly as often
as like a Legendary Power.
We don't need that
aspect of their design.
So they are more rare,
they're harder to get
but when you get it
it's kind of like
a more exciting moment
like did I get
the perfect one?
And then if not
you go and try
and get the next one.
So let's talk a little
about our goals
for the update
that we're going
to be doing here.
One of the things
that we come to a lot
that we talk about
on the team
is this idea
I like this quote
of like players
build their Legendaries
and players build
around their Uniques,
right?
Your Legendary Power
is very,
or your Legendary Items
are very malleable.
You know,
the moment you get it
you don't know yet
if it's going to be
the best in slot item
but it has a chance to be
but they're also like
able to fit
in a lot of different ways.
You can manipulate
their stats via,
you know,
enchanting,
via tempering
and masterworking
and so there's a lot
that you can do
with the item
once you've gotten it.
Whereas Uniques
are a lot more static,
right?
The stats on them
can't change,
you can't really
manipulate them very much
and sometimes
they have maybe
qualities to them
or stats that are
a little bit inconvenient
and you've got to figure out
like how do I overcome
this little detriment
or make my build
into where it's a plus
instead of a detriment,
right?
Like it's a fixed thing
that you have to build around
which is very different
than a Legendary.
Also ideally
we want players
to run two to four Uniques
in their build.
You know,
one of the difficult parts
of this
and I think we're going
to be continuing
to work on
with the balance
and design of Uniques
is that,
you know,
we want you to run some
but we don't want you
to run all of them
in your build,
right?
It's very easy
to go one way
or the other.
I can very easily
make you run no Uniques
and I can very easily
make you run like
every slot is a Unique
by making them
really, really crazy,
right?
We want these to fit
in such a way
that you're running
some of them,
the ones that are
applicable to your build
or maybe some spicy ones
here or there
that you try and,
you know,
like making a special way
to work with you
but not all of them.
I would say right now
like on live
in season four
players are running
more like zero to two
in their build
so it's not as much
as we want
which means that
we want to update them
to make them
a little bit more attractive.
And another one
is we kind of want
to move away
from these generic
fits all build
styles of Uniques,
right?
One thing that I know
a lot of players
have talked about
in the past
that we've had
is that some of our Uniques
are just so generically good
and this is particularly
scary for us
when it's like
what we call
generic Unique
which is one
where every class
can use it
and so like
if every class
can use it
and every build
and it's better
than like the build
specific or class
specific stuff
then it just becomes
best in slot
for everybody
and we've taken away
your agency
and your choice
because you're just
going to target
this item
and ignore everything else,
right?
The only items
in the game
that we really want
to fit that role
are like Mythic Uniques
where they're
across all classes
and they're so good
but they're also
extremely rare
so you're very excited
to see them
whenever you see one
but all the other
regular Uniques
we don't want to
fit that design space
so we're going to be
trying to move away
from these ones
and readjust them
and redesign them
a little bit
where they fit
into all kinds of builds
and kind of target
something that they're
really good at
or that's a little bit
more unique about them
and make them
really good at that
and less generically
good at everything.
It's funny because
everyone's in the chat
going like
oh rip Shaco
rip Shaco
but we just
literally
we just said
Mythics is not
they're a different beast
here
I'm talking about
all your regular ones
Yeah, Shaco's still
going to be just as good
if not better
honestly
Alright, so
enough preamble
what are we actually doing?
So we're going to be doing
two big updates
to Uniques
The first one is
we're going to be
increasing the upper power
of the Unique effects
and the role range
we're going to be doing
an increase in the range
from an average of
10 to 20 roles
which I'll explain in a second
and then we're also
going to be increasing
the upper power
of like how much
you can get from the roles
this is really just
buffing pretty much
most Uniques across the board
to compete with the new world
of Legendary Powers
that we live in
since you know
they got extra power
juice to them
now Uniques are catching up
So as an example here
I gave you know
if an older Unique
like one on live
gave you around 40 to 80%
multiplicative damage
that's going to go up
to like 40, 100
maybe 120
maybe even higher
really the mandate is
as high as we can get away with
without breaking things
and then we're also
going to be increasing
the role range
so this is like
the number of possible roles
it can do
from an average of 10 to 20
so it'll be a little bit harder
to get basically
what we're targeting here
is the discrepancy
inside of a Unique
is a little bit wider
where the difference
of like a low role
and a high role
is a little bit bigger
but the high roles
are way better
than they were before
so they're more exciting
when you get them
really good
but it's a little bit
harder to get there
and the next one
is going to be updating
the affixes
the actual stats
on the Uniques
we're doing a pass
on all of them
and this is kind of
what we're doing
the first thing is
we're changing their stats
to fit with the season 4 updates
right
we're doing the things
like we did before
of simplifying stats
you know
getting rid of
super conditional things
making them
just more generically
understood and good
we're also going to be
adding tempering stats
we're open to really adding
whatever we want
that makes the Unique
fit the fantasy
so as an example here
you know
a lot of two-hand weapon Uniques
have a problem
where they're all
basically competing
against bonus projectiles
as an affix
because you can just
temper that onto your weapons
right
so when it comes
to those kind of situations
we'll just slap the bonus projectiles
on that Unique
and now you know
it's no longer competing
in that way
or we have to kind of
dance around it
we can just put it
we're also open to the idea
by the way
of breaking slot restrictions
kind of like we did
in season 2
so you can have bonus projectiles
or other things
on other slots
you know
like Uniques are
where we get to play
a little bit
and just really make
something thematic
and cool
and build defining
and so they have
less restrictions
than everything else
and the other one
is we're updating
the stat power levels
and the effects
so the idea here
that we're thinking
and this is particularly
nuancy when it comes
to generic Uniques
but stats that kind of
fit the theme
or the fantasy
of the Unique
are going to be
like way stronger
than your normal stats
right
so as an example
if you have a Unique
that's targeting
fire damage
maybe it's like a meteor
or a firewall
and the sorcerer
whatever it may be
you know
that plus fire damage
can be juiced up
to be really really high
but stats that are
more like generically good
like you know
I don't know
attack speed
max life
resist all
those ones
aren't going to be juiced
unless it fits
the theme of the Unique
really well
right
so we have an example
here of one
that has been a problem
for us in the past
I kind of want to go
through how we would
think about it
I'm not going to say
exactly what we're
going to do here
to T'Balt's Will
but kind of give you
our thought process
right
so T'Balt's Will
as many of you know
in previous seasons
was kind of a problem
where it just became
best in slot
for almost every build
you know
the famous line we say
is damage on pants
which was impossible
to get almost anywhere
else in the game
and it turned out
damage on pants
was really really good
right
it also gave you
damage reduction
one of the best stats
in the game
and then it also gave you
a bunch of
it also sold resource
in many ways
for you as well
right
it gave you a bunch
of resource
whenever you became
unstoppable
which wasn't too hard
to do
so it was doing
a lot of things
at once
it gave you
a very unique effect
with putting damage
on a slot
that you don't get it
it also gave you
resource
which is something
that every class
wants very heavily
and Adam
it gave you
three extra potions
and three extra potions
yes
now that one
that's alright
but yeah
so you know
the way that we would
tackle this one
to give you an idea
is like
you know
we either would
kind of pick
do we want to focus
this on the damage
aspect
that it's damage
on a non-damage slot
or maybe we focus
on the resource
aspect
and like
double down
on that
and make that
really powerful
and really cool
or we do like
a little bit of both
but if we do both
then it's not going
to give you the defenses
that another
pants slot would give
right
basically in our mind
we'd be like
we want to give
the minimum amount
of defense
where it's not just
like a trash item
because it has nothing
but then after that
not so much
and you're going to
have to solve
your defenses
in other slots
or somewhere else
to justify getting
the damage
on this slot
is how we would
think about it
right
and so we're having
a lot of conversations
now
I don't think
we're going to nail
every single item
perfectly in this
first pass
so we're really
looking for feedback
when you jump
into season 5
and beyond
and we'll be
adjusting them
but I want to
give you an idea
of what we're doing
and kind of
what we're thinking
and targeting
with this
so I think
we can move on
so Mythic Uniques
are getting a facelift
here
so lots of updates
Mythic Uniques
are now going
to be truly Mythic
they're getting
a new color beam
when they drop
on the ground
they're coming out
with an awesome
new sound
that you're going
to hear in a little bit
we've got new
item UI
that you can see
so they have
a different color
they really are
going to look
and feel like
the special items
that they are
and we have a video
here to show you
the sound
and what it looks
like on the ground
so you can see here
this beam looks
very different
than anything else
isn't that sound
that echoey sound
I love it
sounds like
I don't know
it sounds like
you're murdering
a bunch of
church organs
or something like that
it's just like crazy
but yeah
so you know
when this thing drops
you're definitely
going to know
when you got one
no more
like sifting through
your uniques
to see if it's
actually one of the mythics
you'll know right away
so we're really excited
about this
super happy
it was able to get in
alright
and last but not least
let's talk about
class updates
I'm going to cover
some generic things
across all classes
and then go through
a little bit of each one
again this is not
going to be nearly
close to everything
that we're doing
just a little taste
to teaser
for what you can
expect to see
let's start with
things across all classes
one systemic update
we're doing to the game
is invulnerability skills
are now going to
start their cooldown
when the invulnerability
ends instead of
when the skill begins
this is really to
prevent things like
infinite invulnerability
and really to open up
design space for us
on the team
because now we can
be more comfortable
adding things like
invulnerable duration
to skills
or cooldown reduction
more liberally
and things like that
where we don't have
to worry about this
this is very similar
to what our previous
games have done
and some other games
do and we think
it'll be a good fit here
the idea isn't really
to like make it
that you can't be
invulnerable very often
it's just to prevent
like a hundred percent
uptime where you
actually break down
the combat of the game
and you're not
interacting with
enemies anymore
the next one is
we reviewed monster CC
and we generally
reduce the CC duration
and frequency
across the board
so you know
if you were frustrated
by getting frozen
for a million years
and then dying
that'll happen
much less often
and also to help
with this
potions can be used
while CC'd
even while you're stunned
so you know
while you're frozen
standing there
and everybody's around
you trying to kill you
you can at least
spam potion a little bit
and maybe survive
sometimes
next one
we've got some
bug fixes
see there's some
of the notable ones
we do have more
coming in
but these are the ones
I wanted to call out
Rogue Victimized
is no longer
going to be double
dipping on its damage
which was resulting
in a lot more
multiplicative
or a lot more damage
really than it was
supposed to have
damage over time effects
were getting double
the amount of
percent damage
that they were supposed to
and Skeleton Reapers
were getting both
Book of the Dead bonuses
when the second option
was selected
and again this is
you know just a little
bit of a preview
but we have other
bug fixes coming
but these are some
of the bigger ones
we want to call out
all right now
let's get to the classes
so Barbarian
they have a new
unique coming in
this is the Unbroken Chain
this is for you
support Barbarians
or really just more
defensively oriented ones
basically what this is
going to do is create
a connection between
Steel Grasp and Iron Maelstrom
where you'll be able to
cast Iron Maelstrom
a lot more often
is you use Steel Grasp
and also enemies
damaged by Iron Maelstrom
are going to be doing
less damage
for a little while
so the idea here
is you know
you could debuff enemies
debuff those bosses
and make them do less
damage to you
so you can survive better
and next the Rogue
Flurry is going to be
getting a lot of big
updates
we updated the enhancement
and both of their
upgrades
so you'll be able to
see kind of a theme
here going on
before you know
you would damage
a crowd control
or vulnerable enemy
for the enhancement
then you would heal
now when Flurry
hits an enemy
you can just
make them vulnerable
so actually Flurry
becomes a vulnerable
generator here
which is pretty exciting
and it'll also deal
more damage
as you hit vulnerable
enemies
stacks up really high
so the idea here is
with Flurry builds
you want to make
everything vulnerable
and then just keep
whacking them with Flurry
and gain a bunch of damage
and now Improved Flurry
is changing
before it was about
vulnerable spreading
but now Baseline
you can just generate
vulnerable
so we don't need
that anymore
so now Improved Flurry
is going to actually
give you a dash
so now similar to
things like
the Shred on the Druid
you can kind of
dash to your target
and also every time
you cast Flurry
now it's going to
heal you
so it's going to be
a lot more mobile
a lot more awesome
very cool
and then last but not least
to compete with a dash
what could we do
with Advanced Flurry
well we can just add
a stupid amount of damage
and resource cost reduction
so before you know
you had to evade
through an enemy
and then do damage
with one cast
and stun enemies
now as you spam Flurry
it'll basically get
a big damage bonus
and its energy cost
will go down
which will let you
be able to spam it
even more often
so the idea here
is you just want to be
using it over and over
and over again
and it'll get stronger
and stronger
and ramp up
pretty heavily as you go
I'm excited for Flurry Rogues
very excited
they're going to be
like little hummingbirds
around bouncing around
and it's going to be great
ironically I'm playing
Flurry this season
so I'm always off by one
I always play the thing
and then like
oh we're going to
massively make it better
next time
but it's fine
everything's fine
next Druid
Shepard's Aspect
we've gotten feedback
from players for a while
now about how
Shepard's Aspect
kind of dominates
the meta for Druids
because you're basically
both
it's both not great
from a design
and a balanced perspective
on the design side
we're telling you
to put companions
on your bar
and then they're
actually just buffing you
so we make this
companion build fantasy
but it's actually
just making the player
better
and then on the power side
you're basically
just slotting
three skills
on your bar
with your companions
and then not really
caring about buffing
them or using them
because they're just
kind of there
as proxies
to make you better
so we've changed it
now where
basically it's going
to be about the
companions
so your companion
skills are just
going to deal damage
for every companion
that you have
so the bigger your zoo
the better your zoo
is going to perform
and to compensate
players we're doing
some pretty massive
buffs to Druid
skills baseline
to compensate
so your skills
are just going to be
getting that damage
baseline
and in many cases
a little bit more
so you can check that
out when you see
the PTR patch notes
after this
but we basically
just buffed everything
across the board
and made it so that
Shepherds isn't
required anymore
next for the Sorceress
this is Axial Conduit
I'm really excited
about this unique
this is your Chain
Lightning unique
so Chain Lightning builds
you finally have a unique
that really talks to you
and you can see here
kind of our stats
and that new philosophy
I told you about
you have chance
to double cast Chain Lightning
on pants
instead of just a weapon
so that's pretty cool
so basically
the way that this works
we're going to have a video
but I'm going to explain
to you how this works
because it actually changes
your skill pretty significantly
so now when you cast
Chain Lightning
the way it's going to work
is it's going to cast
and bounce on enemies
just like before
but then it's going to
come back to you
and orbit you a little bit
and then it's going to
go out and hit another enemy
and then come back to you
and orbit
and then come out
and then go out
and do another enemy
and come back
and it's going to do that
back and forth a few times
and every time it comes back to you
is going to drain
some of your mana
and after it drains
so much mana
after coming back 10 times
the bolt is actually
going to explode
for a ridiculous amount
of lightning damage
on enemies
so there's a mini game here
where basically
oh and by the way
you can cast
multiple Chain Lightning
when this is out
you're basically going to be
like running a gambit here
and the mini game
is you want to stack
as much resource regeneration
as you can
so that your lightning bolts
can survive
being drained over and over
and bouncing everywhere
so they can last
to their explosion
and do a ton of damage
to enemies
one thing I want to call out
here also
is that because it drains mana
resource cost reduction
won't work on that drain
you're actually going to want
to focus on gaining resource
which is a little bit different
and kind of makes this build
a little special
I think and unique
compared to other resource
builds based around resource
so let's see it in action here
so you'll see what one cast
looks like
and then I think we'll see
what it looks like
when you spam it
so you can see here
it circles you
goes and hits enemies
circles you
and then it does a big explosion
at the end
that we've tuned the damage
to be pretty high
see there
so then it explodes
so oh wait
oh do we have one
where it casts a bunch of times
maybe we don't
oh there we go
there we go
so see here
you can see that
as you go
it will keep going
going going
and then explode
a bunch of times
another thing I want to point out
is if you're hugging enemies
in melee range
as it's circling you
it will also hit enemies
so you now have a way
to really maximize your damage
by hugging bosses and such
the damage goes way up
so next
last but not least
the necromancer
so we got some feedback
we've had this for a while
and felt this on the team
where you know
the golem we really love
you know we love our golem
our golem boys
and you know
but sometimes it can be frustrating
where you tell the golem
to go somewhere
and then it kind of takes a while
to lug his butt over there
and do his slam
or his shout or whatever
and you know
things can get in the way
and so we've kind of
upgraded him a little bit
I'll let the video speak
for himself here
but so now you can see
your golem will Hulk smash
and just jump on enemies
and slam them down
so this will work
with all of your golem types
by the way
not just the iron golem
but now your golem
is going to leap to the area
that you tell him to go
and then cast his ability
so we're really excited
about this
shout out to Charles Dunn
who got this change in
and our animators
who helped us out
but we're really pumped for it
it looks amazing
yeah
so those were the
the class imbalance changes
and I know
we jumped a slide there
how dare you production
no
but we are
as they wave to me
like I'm sorry
we do want to go into
some quality of life updates
we do have a significant
amount of quality of life
updates that we do
want to go through
that will be available
in season 5
and you guys will actually
be able to check this out
in the PTR
so now we can go
to the next slide
where we do want to talk
about some Helltide
and Whisper updates
specifically
so I know
this has been kind of
at least it's been
a pain point for me
and I've heard
it's been a pain point
for others
is that as you guys
are going through Helltide
there are Whisper objectives
within there
to help you with your
progression on your
Whisper bar
but the issue
with the ones
in Helltide
is that it can sometimes
take quite a while
to do
and you know
sometimes players
would have to leave
the Helltide
to go to another area
to complete some
of these Whisper objectives
so we are optimizing
this to ensure
that they don't take
nearly as much time
the ideal goal
is to get a bunch
of value
within those 15 minutes
and to potentially
end up getting
a full entire Whisper
10 point bar
within 15 minutes
in one Helltide
so you can do
a full Whisper
every Helltide
so that would be
it would be a huge help
because I know
at least for me
I've always had to
like kind of
leave a Helltide
and I kind of
try to knock
some of that out
especially help
for players
that are looking
for additional gold
because Whisper caches
have always been
great sources of gold
and now
as Adam mentioned
you can also use
Whisper caches
to target farm
so it's keeping
things more optimized
for players
which we know
will be way
better there
the next thing
we do want to talk
about is also
Baneful Hearts
I know
this may not sound
like a huge
quality of life thing
or a buff
of any sort
but we have noticed
that players
have had a lot
of Baneful Hearts
within their inventory
we do want to make
these a little bit
more valuable
so they won't drop
as frequently
we know that players
will still have
a significant amount
but maybe not
hundreds and hundreds
like some people
have within their
inventory
but players
should not have
any type of issues
regarding having
a ton of these
Baneful Hearts
but we are tweaking
the drop rate
because they were
dropping a little
too much there
tempering
the very
very
I guess like
brought up topic
well
and like
yeah
people like
talking about
tempering
it's pretty popular
yeah
so I want to take a minute
to talk about tempering
and kind of how the
design team sees it
and kind of what we're
happy with
what we think could be
better
and some adjustments
we'll be making
in season 5
so first high level
kind of how we see
tempering
we really think
that it's important
that items have
an end point
where players know
kind of that the item
is done
and that they're not
hoarding lots of them
forever on the chance
that they can all be good
right
one of the big
key goals
of season 4
was that we didn't
want you saving
a million items
in your stash space
and while we know
that you know
bricking an item
never feels great
we do need
that to be something
that's possible
to do in the game
so that you know
when the journey is done
and you're not just
holding on to an item
forever
so that part we actually
think is working
very well
where you know
an item is done
and you try and go
get another one
and so you're always
interested in items
and trying to you know
have that game loop
go in the game
indefinitely
or until you feel
like your character
is maxed on its power
but we do agree
with players
that you know
the RNG right now
is like completely
out of their hands
which doesn't really
feel great
you know you get
so many tries
basically to roll
and then that's kind of it
and you're done
and it doesn't feel great
so we're looking at ways
in the future
for players
to have more control
over that RNG
so that you know
you have more ways
to maybe manipulate
the tempering
or get the odds
in your favor
and do other things
like that
one update
that's going to be
coming in season 5
it won't be in the PTR
but as we're targeting
for launch
is that
you know we've got
a lot of feedback
that it feels so bad
when you know
you get that like
triple greater affix
and it has the same
number of rolls
and then you brick it
and then you have to try
and go get another one
so in season 5
to help with this
you know as your item
gets better basically
that you find
you're going to have
more chances to temper it
so a much better chance
to get the one
that you want
basically what will work
is you're going to
basically get one extra
roll per greater affix
that you have
so you know you have
one greater affix
one roll
three three rolls
and again just to clarify
this is not in the PTR
but it will be in for the
launch of season 5
in itself
and again just to reiterate
we are still looking at
ways to help out
that experience
within tempering
as we've noted
we agree with players
that it doesn't always
feel great
and so you guys
should expect to hear
more updates to tempering
after we get through
season 5 for sure
yeah
alright
next up
weapons
yeah
so I'll talk about
this one a little bit
we took a look at
this chart
yeah this chart
we took a look at
inherent affixes
on weapons
and we found that
you know a lot of
inherent affixes
like damage to distant
or some other ones
were a little too
conditional
and didn't get the
update you know
in season 4
that we wanted
so we went back
and made them
a little bit more
generically useful
and better across
more builds
so we have a little
chart here
but you can see
kind of
this is going to be
the new
inherent affixes
on all the different
weapon types
so we've made
quite a few
adjustments here
you know as an
example
you know vulnerable
damage is on
bows
and dot damage
is on axes
which I believe
vulnerable on bows
is new
but yeah
so we made
quite a few updates
we basically just
looked at the
matrices of everything
and kind of
adjusted it to see
what makes sense
so basically
you're just going to
have you know
things that actually
impact your builds
much more often
on the weapons
that you want
and as another
result of this update
we are also looking
at what weapons
classes can use
and we updated
them a little bit
to try and you know
let more classes
use more weapons
we want players
to be able to
create interesting
builds
play the way
that we want
and so we want
to open up
these things
as much as we can
in our designs
so now druids
are going to be able
to use two hand
pull arms
one hand swords
and daggers
sorceresses
are going to be able
to use one hand
swords and maces
and necromancers
are going to be able
to use
I think it's
maces and axes
actually
despite this
necromancer
picture right here
that is not
using
well it's using
a two handed
sword but you can
already use a
two handed sword
but not using
a
yeah and the
necromancer here
I know it's
supposed to say
all maces
and axes
as opposed to
all swords
so
but yeah
basically
we're going
to be
opening up
these classes
to use
more weapon
types
and then
also some
of the uniques
are going
to be updated
for the classes
as well
so the
butcher's cleaver
can now be
used for
necros
and sorcerers
can use
doom brainer
and azure
wrath
now
yeah
sorcerers
can use
azure wrath
kind of like
d2
yep
fits their
theme very
well too
so
I think
that'll be
pretty cool
some additional
quality of life
updates
now we're going
to talk about
some endgame
bosses
as I have
experienced
as Adam
has experienced
earlier
as he mentioned
in the stream
we are making
changes to the
beast in ice
you guys will
no longer
have to make
a sigil
to summon
the beast in ice
which is a
huge quality of
life update
the beast will
now live
in a standard
dungeon
the crawl
to get to
the beast in ice
is much
much shorter
now
it's going to be
more similar
to what we've
seen with
some of the
other endgame
bosses
and then at the
same time
eternal players
that have
maybe
already built
out some of
these sigils
we made sure
to keep you
in mind
so you can
still use
those sigils
to fight
the boss
you won't
need summoning
materials
you can just
use the
sigil right
there
in the
boss room
in itself
and this
no longer
requires sigil
dust to
actually summon
the beast in
ice
so some
big changes
to the beast
in ice
to help
out that
whole entire
feel
especially
when you're
really target
farming the
beast in
ice
sometimes
it was
kind of
brutal
to have to
go through
the whole
entire dungeon
each and
every time
so many times
next we have
Varshan
the body parts
are pretty much
being reduced
to one
I know it was
eating up a lot
of inventory
space
it was kind of
hard to manage
at times
and everything
so we're
optimizing this
making this
better
so now you'll
just need one
body part
to essentially
summon Varshan
going forward
starting with
season five
and one
big thing
that we're
going to
call out
here
before
and this
is kind
of like
the cherry
on top
we should
let's actually
just play the
clip and see
if people
actually notice
it
and if not
then we'll
call it out
could be
different
this time
poor Durial
yeah
mythic unique
maybe
no that's
not it
oh
good gear
though
but something
that is
interesting here
is the
cauldron
has reappeared
you can just
resummon
him again
there's the
altar right there
you can now
resummon
all the
end game
bosses
without needing
to run
out of the
dungeon
reset
the dungeon
so this will
help a whole
lot
we'll make
things
way better
in terms of
like optimizing
when you're
for time
and everything
especially when
you're a party
and you're like
everyone leave
the dungeon
so I can
reset
and stuff
like that
now you'll
be able to
do that
immediately
for all
the end game
bosses
which is a
huge huge
feature I know
that players
have been
asking for
so that
will be also
incorporated
into season
five
so lots
and lots
of changes
for season
five
one other
thing
I did want
to call out
regarding tempering
because
just to clarify
because we've
got some people
going like
I don't
understand
the greater
affix stuff
in terms of
additional roles
if you have
a one star
greater affix
you'll get
one additional
role
if you have
a three star
or four star
or something
you would get
three or four
depending
the amount
of stars
that you
actually
specifically
have
on your
item
yeah
it goes up
to three
three
sorry
four
unique
yeah
if
thinking
razor plate
or something
like that
but
the other
thing
that I did
want to
call out
is that
this is
actually
going to
be
retroactive
so
for
players
that
still
have
maybe
an item
that
they may
have
potentially
bricked
and it's
sitting
in their
stash
you know
just for
like
memento
purposes
or anything
like that
yeah
when your
character
does move
to eternal
if it
was a
greater
affix
like a
three star
greater
affix
or something
like that
you will
end up
getting those
afterwards
so
that will
appear
after these
changes
actually are
implemented
with the
start of
season 5
it'll just
be on your
internal
character
obviously
because your
seasonal
character
will move
to eternal
as I fix
my earpiece
that's like
falling out
but
one other
thing I did
want to
call out
as well
for season 5
we have some
really big
accessibility
options that
are being
added to
the actual
game
and we
really
need some
testing on
this in
the season 5
PTR
this is
actually called
out in
our blog
we would
really love
if players
can actually
check them
out
test them
provide
feedback
I will
note
we aren't
planning
despite it
being in
the season 5
PTR
we aren't
planning on
these features
actually launching
with season 5
we really want
to take the
feedback
make them
you know
better
for when
they are
ready
and right
now I think
that the plan
would be that
they would be
ready for
season 6
but it's
important for
us to be
able to get
that feedback
so we really
need people
to actually
test out
these specific
features
we have like
an auto pin
feature
we have a
compass feature
and then we
have like
an audio
navigation
assistance feature
that is coming
within some of
these accessibility
features for
season 5
so really
important for
people to
kind of like
jump in
check it out
give us
feedback
and then you'll
see those
in season 6
after the PTR
is kind of over
but that is
kind of like
a huge wrap
up of all
the stuff
that is coming
for the
season 5
PTR
and even
a little bit
more of
even some
of the stuff
for season 5
itself
we do want
to take some
questions
and we still
have Dan
on the line
from the
burning hells
of Albany
to answer
any questions
that we may
have
but I know
we have a
question
specifically
T-Dub
so if you
have questions
please ask
them in
Twitch chat
which is where
we have live
chat going on
right now
and we will
try to get
through as many
as possible
cool
but first
question I
believe we
have is
because I
teed up this
question
are there any
new class buffs
coming to season
specifically
if Adam
can answer
druid and
sorceress
because I know
we hear you
everyone
about druid
and sorceress
I know we
talked a little
bit about it
here but if you
can like
expand on it
yeah
yes
there are new
class buffs coming
to season 5
covered a little
bit
I think one
thing they call
out that people
talk a lot about
right now is
how barbarians
in particular are
pretty strong
and then the
classes that can't
get as far as
they can in the
pit feels kind
of bad
there's a lot to
chew on there
but I think the
short answer is
yes we hear you
and we're going to
be looking to
beef these things
up
we do have some
specific ways that
we want to be
targeting these
things and there's
a lot of history
to it
barbarians in
particular are
tougher to balance
I think I've
talked about this
on stream a little
bit before of
because of their
arsenal system
they have more
items
anytime that we
mess with
and we've
messed with
the underlying
systems of the
game very heavily
in the last year
season 2
we updated all
the combat math
which of course
impacts items
which impacts
character power
we've updated
in season 4
all of itemization
which obviously
directly impacts
the arsenal system
very heavily
so when we do
these large
shakeups
it's a lot more
difficult in a
short amount of
time to get
everything exactly
perfect of how
the combinatorics
of those effects
are going to
impact classes
right
so that's one
end of it
another end is
what we're trying
to do
and we started
with this in
season 4
we're looking at
the other class
mechanics
and we want to
beef them up
and give them
the treatment
that we gave
with the
necromancer
and the book
of the dead
in season 4
we actually wanted
to try this
as an experiment
like hey
the book of the
dead
the minions
the sacrifice
bonuses
they're what
really make
necromancer feel
really cool
and special
and unique
so we're going
to try and
catch that up
so to speak
to the arsenal
system on the
barbarian
and not only
just increase
the numbers
because just
increasing the
numbers is
kind of easy
we even did
that in the
mid-season patch
if you look
at the druid
boons
we increased
them by 50%
doubled them
in many cases
but we think
to really help
solve that
on the fantasy
and even just
design perspective
we want to
overhaul and
really look at
these mechanics
and make them
way better
and more
thematic
to classes
so we don't
have anything
to announce
today for
season 5
but that's
something more
long term
that we're doing
to help that
problem in the
future
in the short
term we are
looking at
fixing the
issues with
these various
classes
buffing them
up in different
ways
making different
builds and
other things
viable and
trying to
keep that
parity
we're also
looking at
bringing down
the outliers
of power
with the
barbarian
in different
ways
to make
sure that they
have more
parity with
other classes
as well
but that's
kind of our
short and
long term vision
of where we
want this to
be
awesome
I know
we have a
question
specifically
and this is
something I've
seen a few
times regarding
season 5
for Dan
because
Infernal
Hordes
people are
seeing this
gameplay
and they're
hearing about
like okay
can I play
this on
eternal
and seasonal
can I play
this
is this like
an ongoing
thing going
forward
what can
players expect
Dan
sure
yeah
so
with season
five
we wanted
to build
out
the end
game
and because
we're building
out the
end game
we wanted
to make
sure that
any of the
end game
things we're
putting in
are on
both seasonal
and eternal
and so
in this
PTR
you'll be able
to test out
the eternal
version of
Infernal
Hordes
and so
any of the
rewards you get
from it
all that's
eternal
so all
players are
going to
benefit from
it
awesome
yeah so
all players
will benefit
from it
and as
Dan mentioned
it's a
new end game
feature so
it's like
something that
will be
continuous
beyond
even season
five is what
we're looking
at so
yeah
players can
expect to
jump in
Infernal
Hordes
going forward
which is
pretty cool
and yeah
the feedback
is going
to be
incredibly
important
during this
PTR
as Dan
mentioned
beforehand
all the
specific
items that
we're really
hoping to
get
feedback on
regarding
how the
boons feel
rewards feel
how the
combat feels
and the
waves and
stuff like
that will
be really
important for
us during
this specific
moment
what is the
this is another
season five
question
hopefully you
might be able
to answer
this Dan
this is from
Lucky Luciano
shout out
Diablo
partner
what is the
equivalent pit
level of the
eighth difficulty
of like the
Infernal
Hordes
pit level
I guess
or nightmare
dungeon
or monster
level
yeah you're
making me do
math here
yeah we just
adjusted pit
levels
yeah so
tier tier
eight tier
eight of the
Infernal
Hordes is
going to be
equivalent to
about monster
level I think
it's 180 to
200 so it
goes up pretty
high that's
pretty late
okay nice
nice so a
difficult challenge
for sure which
is good to
hear we
have a
question from
Zapadas
you all need
easier names I
swear do you
foresee changes in
grouping in the
pit to allow
group play to be
more efficient
there will be
changes it won't
be something
present in PTR
we'll talk more
about it at the
season five launch
but the team is
very aware of it
because we've heard
about like hey
it's kind of not
great to feel like
I'm getting only
50% of you know
the rewards
associated when I'm
in a group within
a pit if I'm not
the party leader
specifically so it's
something that the
team is taking in
and we will have
an update for
players before season
five and it will be
live whatever change
we have live in
season five so a
question from let's
see I don't know
well this one's easy
okay robot Jomo
what's the team's
philosophy on rate
of power gain it
seems that tempering
especially players
gain too much power
too quickly really
removing the tension
from leveling up
experience any chance
to add more friction
to tempering materials
costs etc yeah we
have seen a little
bit of this and heard
this feedback ourselves
it's kind of going in
two different ways
here so the leveling
experience then how
tempering messes with
it right the leveling
experience as people
probably have seen
has been sped up
quite a bit right we
do want people to be
able to kind of level
quickly and get to the
fun of the game as
quickly as possible so
we do want them you
know we don't want
there to be a ton of
friction like you know
when we first launched
the game we had the
idea that like getting
to level 100 alone was
a big accomplishment
right and we've learned
that you know players
really want to like
fulfill their power
fantasies get to the
part where they're
actually like
incrementally increasing
their character's power
and finding things to
use that power against and
so they they enjoy that
end game a lot and we
want to get them there in
a reasonable amount of
time so that's the part
that is like you know
hey you know it's fine
level quicker it's good
right but then the other
part is like tempering and
kind of the tuning of the
affixes we have heard the
feedback and and kind of
agree with it that you
know the early tempering
recipes are really really
strong right that was by
design when we launched
season four one of the
big kind of mandates to
the team that we felt was
important was we wanted you
know before season four we
constantly got the feedback
and and knew it was true
that you know your item
stats weren't interesting
enough and didn't matter
enough and weren't very
impactful and just didn't
feel good right and so we
we very much like juice
them up to be very strong
and in this new tempering
system that manipulates
them we made it very strong
so that out the gate our
goal was that when you
temper an item you can
really feel the damage it
wasn't like this
incremental my damage
goes up in like 10
different places here and
there and now I'm strong
it was like no this one
thing happened and you
felt it and it was good
and so we're gonna you
know try and walk that
line we're gonna probably
go a little more in
between here where you
know we do agree that the
tempering is warping the
early game experience too
much to the point that
it's like you pick up an
item and you don't care
about the stats because
you just temper something
on and it's like way
better right so we don't
want that but we do still
want them to feel and be
really impactful so we
have heard the feedback I
don't remember don't
think we have huge
adjustments in season
five right away but we
are going to be looking
at that leveling process
and and streaming and
lining that quite a bit
we're having time
actually and talks about
that right now with
various members of the
team so it will be
looked at not tons will
change in season five
though awesome a question
from razzle dazzle
dazzle dare is
razzle dazzle dare is
it's a long name to log in
on did you say we can
temper uniques are you
open to letting us
imprint affixes I had this
thought and we can imprint
a unique but only once
yeah going back that was
kind of what I talked
about with the unique
section we right now
know I'm not going to
say never in the future
it's definitely the
obvious thing that we
could do like you know
just add temporary uniques
of course but we we want
them to have an identity
that is very different
from legendaries one of
the concerns with that is
that the more that you
give uniques manipulation
the more that they just
turn into legendaries with
a different item color when
they drop on the ground
right like they're
actually not different in
how they work if we were
able to manipulate stats
add stats all those
things so we do want them
to have a different
identity in the game so
we're not doing it now
but you know in the
future we've talked about
it we're open to the
idea but we do want to
try this first of like
double down you know
what makes a unique unique
and that you build around
it except there's a
little bit of friction
rather than just turning
it into the item that you
want every time yep a
question from Baric is
hey Adam or Adams I have
a question for the Q&A
how is the dev team
feeling about the
reception of season 4
is that making them
rethink any plans for
future seasons I mean I
think one thing that we
can most definitely call
out here is like
obviously season 4 has
been really great like
we've been hearing a lot
of great feedback from
players and you know
we're very well aware of
like you know how
everyone's been enjoying
it I think one huge thing
that's helped with that as
well was like the idea
that we had a PTR for
season 4 and now we're
seeing that again for
season 5 so like we know
like having that moment
where players can actually
jump in provide feedback
give us some notes on
specific things is really
beneficial especially when
we have like new huge
features like what we did
for season 4 which was
you know obviously
tempering master working
the pit all new hell
tides there was a ton of
new features and then of
course with season 5 you
know players are now
going to be able to run
through infernal horde
tons of new gear and
legendary aspects for them
so it's just like a ton of
stuff that we know that we
can most definitely take
feedback on and having
those moments has really
helped us with some of
those decisions
yeah I would say on the
design team side I know
like the people on team
are very happy with how
season 4 went it couldn't
have gotten better really
in our eyes
PTR was a huge deal
helped us a lot especially
on the balance and design
side to you know get
things into a better place
another thing I may call
out with season 4 is that
I don't know how to phrase
it like you know there's
been a lot of disruption
to the game right and so
when there's that much
disruption of like you know
we update all the core
math and all the items and
everything you know it's
very difficult to get
things into a fine-tuned
state right and you know
without giving anything
away we have big updates
coming in the future with
you know expansion and
other things but one of
the things that we're
looking forward to I think
as a team is when we've
kind of settled down a
little bit on the big
disruptions like
overhauling all of
itemization and things
like that because you
know it becomes a lot
more difficult to fine
tune things like balance
or even on the design
side like designs and
making sure that they
work and that we're
like iterating and
upgrading things versus
you know changing things
around in huge ways so
while we think it was
really successful and
we're happy with how
itemization 2.0 turned
out the team is looking
forward to like making
the things as they are
and make them work
better and more do
fine-tuning work and so
I think you can expect
in the future as a
player you know after
we've done some more
disruption and made the
game like in a really
good place we're very
happy with it which we're
really close to now I
think that you're you
know you have tighter
class balance tighter
designs tighter roles for
things and just you know
the one of the things
that excites me and
excited the team about
season four was like the
tons of quality of life
improvements and how
much of an impact that
makes on players which I
think we knew but it hit
home in season four right
like just the codex of
power how that changed
and how that completely
fixed you know the
hoarding of items and
things like that I think
are what really jazz us
a lot because it just
makes that flow experience
better like the boss
ladder you know being
able to reset bosses
stuff like that I think
is actually really
impactful and good for
for the longevity of the
game so we're excited to
do more things like that
all right last question
that we have here is
say it's just Satan's
oh Satan's with a Z and
666 afterwards very very
Diablo yeah very Diablo
theme is specifically
asking what is the
seasonal theme are we
like holding back any
information right now
regarding that and stuff
Dan I don't know if you
want to clarify here or if
you want me to you can
all right so we haven't
announced the name for
the season yet as far as
I know but the the
seasonal theme seems I
guess fairly obvious you
know we're going back to
hell and so the theme is
pretty much returning to
hell and while the
infernal hordes is just
one part of that the
rewards are another part
and when we have our
season five live stream
we'll go into all of the
rest of the things that
we have planned for season
five exactly yeah we
have we have some yeah
we have some we have
some additional stuff to
talk about when we we do
actually have our season
five live stream we're
just right now the
biggest focus for this
stream is for people to
hear about the content
that they're going to be
able to play in PTR and
we want people to really
hone in and focus in on
that so we can actually
get that feedback for the
team here and we can make
any changes that we may
need to so but yeah that
is kind of going to wrap
this up for today for for
Q&A I'm going to lightning
round like a few quick
things because I'm sure
chat will kill me if I
don't call it out sure now
we're getting a lot of
questions about loadouts it
is again still something
that we are very well aware
of and we we still plan on
it's just takes a lot of
time it's a huge huge amount
of overhaul changes and
everything from that end
separately we this isn't
coming up a lot auction
house there are currently
no plans right now for
for something like that but
we we hear you guys we
we feedback things like
that let us know but right
now those are those are the
two big things I've been
seeing a ton in chat I just
want to address them before
people go like you're not
reading chat you're in some
like alternate universe chat or
something like that but PTR
again just to remind everyone
starts next Tuesday it runs
for one week it's on PC
battle net only please
provide feedback on our
forums reddit social media
our community discord things
like that we're always
looking around we really are
we really value the feedback
that we get during these PTR
processes and of course at
the same time we patch notes
on the blog are live
immediately after this stream
so check out Diablo4.com
when those do get up next
time you guys see us next
time we stream is July
18th it's the spirit born
reveal yeah everyone gets to
check out the the the spirit
born so we'll be back live
on stream on July 18th we'll
be revealing the brand new
class coming to Diablo 4 that
will be part of vessel of
hatred so really excited about
that and yeah I think that
wraps it up I want to give a
huge shout out to Dan and
Albany yeah thank you Dan
yeah enjoy the AC cool I'm
at the burning fire under
him yeah I know exactly and
thank you again Adam Jackson
and from everyone on the
Diablo 4 team we wish you a
wonderful weekend and we'll
see you in PTR next week
thank you everybody see you
guys
and
I'll see you next week
for Joel
and
with
a
give