Umm
You
Thank you.
it's the podcast.
or we're in it.
I don't know.
It's Friday, you guys.
We haven't done a Friday stream in,
I don't know, it's been a while.
It's been a long while.
For feedback, though,
we will be opening up our PTR forums
for players to actually be able to submit feedback.
So the Diablo 4 forums will have a special section for PTR.
And then separately,
if you do want to leave feedback on other avenues,
such as like Reddit or the Community Sanctuary Discord,
places like that,
we most definitely end up combing through
all the different various ways
of players being able to provide feedback
specifically from that end.
For this PTR, we will note that
this one will be a little different than Season 4
in regards to how you can start off characters.
There will still be character boosts
like what we had with the Season 4 PTR.
I believe it's actually moved to a different city.
I can't recall.
I think we had it in Kiovashad before,
and I believe it's in a different city,
and I don't recall which city it is.
It's in the blog, though.
But all that information will be there after the stream.
Separately, we did incorporate a character copy feature,
but we initiated this character copy already.
No one knows this, but as of yesterday,
characters were copied from your accounts over to PTR.
So it gives you a little bit of variety
of being able to take over some of those characters
that you've already built out.
Or, you know, if you want to,
you can still use the character boost.
I will note, we do want players to be experiencing it
in a variety of ways,
like whether using your current characters
that we're copying over,
or if you're using some of the character boosts,
we do recommend,
or if you want to level up to level one,
like that's another option as well.
It allows us to get feedback
from all different aspects.
So we do recommend, you know,
trying it out in different ways
and providing feedback of like how things feel,
how things flow within the PTR itself.
So that is all kind of like
the general housekeeping notes that we do have.
Oh, and I will say that I believe we actually did,
we did correct that Codex of Power reset thing as well.
So yeah, I remember that was plaguing some people last season.
We did correct that.
So it won't reset, I believe,
every single time you end up like creating a new character
or boosting a new character, I believe.
And then separately on the forums,
we will have a known issues list
because they're, you know, it's PTR,
it's an early build.
So we want to make sure that people are aware of that.
And with PTR, you know, when we take in feedback,
it's great for players to be able to like
provide all various forms of feedback.
I will say by the time season five launches,
we will try our best to get as much of that feedback in.
If it's something that's like a massive,
like, oh, like a huge overhaul or something like that,
I wouldn't expect it in season five,
but it is good to hear that feedback
because it might be something that we end up incorporating
maybe in the future
for like a future season from that end.
Yeah, it's very useful.
So it helps us drive future decisions.
And even we did a lot of reaction to PTR feedback in season four.
If I remember right,
we did like a whole lot on our team at least.
And I expect the same for season five.
So exactly.
Send it in.
It's very useful.
And then one last thing I do want to note is
because players have probably seen when season four is ending,
which is currently in early August.
You can see that kind of like on your character select screen
when you're jumping into the game.
I will note that season five is a little bit shorter of a season
than what we've had beforehand.
Season five itself will run until that October 8th date
with Vessel of Hatred
because Vessel of Hatred is actually the start of season six.
So we did want to at least clarify,
make sure because we've heard a lot of those questions of like,
hey, is Vessel of Hatred hitting in the middle of season five?
Things like that.
So we did want to note that from that end.
But enough of the housekeeping notes.
I know a lot of players want to hear about season five in itself.
And so Mr. Dan Tanguay from the sweltering city limits of Albany
will be walking us through season five.
Yeah, absolutely.
So yeah, let's dive into the new features on PTR for season five.
Just to give you a little bit of context,
you know, we did some early brainstorming for season five
and we knew that, you know, we needed to build out the end game.
So end game, you know, we've heard y'all that end game is very important.
And season four, we added the pit into the end game
and some people have been playing Helltides into the end game.
But we still want to expand the end game a bit more, right?
So if it's an end game activity,
we definitely need something that's rewarding and very replayable.
We also wanted to make something with a lot of monsters.
I mean, monster density and just entering that feeling of flow state
is really important for players.
We needed something that had stakes and we wanted players to push their luck.
And finally, we really wanted to return to Hell.
You know, previous Diablo games let you return to Hell
after you defeat the big boss,
but Diablo 4 hadn't done that yet.
And so with all those goals in mind,
let me introduce you to the Infernal Hordes.
Now, let me give you a quick summary of what the Infernal Hordes is.
It's a wave-based gameplay mode
with survivor-like choices in between the waves
and it'll culminate with an all-new boss encounter
and then the rewards build on top of itemization 2.0
that came in season four.
So now how do you go about confronting the internal hordes?
How do you get back to Hell?
I think we can queue up some footage
and then I'll talk you through some of the ways you get back to Hell.
All right.
First off, you're going to unlock, you know, the activity for Hell
with a brisk eternal questline starting at World Tier 3 in Zarbenzet.
That's where you need to go in the PTR.
Now, you need a new type of key called a compass,
which you can see down in the inventory below here.
And like Nightmare Dungeons,
the compasses all have a starting monster difficulty
and a number of revives.
And there are eight levels of difficulty
with escalating challenge and rewards.
As you can see, it's a very Nightmare Dungeon-like flow here.
And then compasses can be upgraded to higher tiers
with all new consumables called Abyssal Scrolls.
So you'll get a chance to play with all these new features
when you're in the PTR.
But let's really talk about the gameplay itself.
And I think we've got some footage of the wave-based play
that we could show off here.
First off, going to have a lot of monsters.
Now, you have one monster here.
This is the start of wave one.
And so you defeat this Aether Fiend,
and it's going to drop something called Burning Aether,
which is a new currency.
Now, this new currency is specific to hell,
and you use it to unlock the spoils of hell
at the end of a run.
And at the end of each wave,
there's going to be what's called the Infernal Offer.
So let's get through this wave,
and we'll take a look at the Infernal Offer.
Now, you see these hands reaching out from hell itself,
and they're tempting you with a choice.
You're going to choose the form of your destructor.
You're going to pick a boon and a bane
that impacts the rest of your run.
And so now you've chosen a boon and a bane,
and that's going to modify the gameplay that comes up next.
And so here you're jumping into one of the new activities
that also unlocks Aether in this.
And this is a Soul Spire.
It's pretty similar to a Hell Spire
that you'd see in Helltide.
And you have to kill a number of enemies within that ring
in order to be able to earn an Aether.
And you can upgrade Soul Spires
from the Infernal Offer as well, if you like.
And then finally, what you need to do
is complete the number of waves
in order to be able to confront the boss.
And so you see in this particular run,
you're at five of five waves.
So you are just about ready once you defeat this wave
to go confront the new bosses for the Infernal Hordes.
So we'll finish collecting our Aether here,
find our last number of enemies,
and I think we're good.
I think we're ready to go.
So let's take a look at our new bosses.
I think we've got some cool art to share here.
So these are the Fel Council.
They're going to be some familiar faces for Diablo II players.
They are resurrected versions of the Council members
from Diablo II.
Now for those of you who didn't play Diablo II,
the Council members were former high priests of the Zacarum,
and they had promised to basically take care of Mephisto
after he'd been trapped in the Soul Stone,
and he'd been hidden down and caressed and travencle.
And of course, as it happens,
Mephisto corrupted them,
both in mind first and then their bodies,
and they became demons who are just zealous and serve him without question.
And so we thought it was going to be really cool to be able to resurrect them
and bring them back for Diablo IV,
and they fit great in hell.
We had to tweak their power sets a little bit
to fit the D4 combat system.
So we gave them new titles and new looks
to really reflect their combat specialties.
It's incredibly awesome to see these guys come back.
It's giving very nostalgic vibes
of doing a bunch of endurance of hate runs for Mephisto
and doing Meph runs and everything like that.
So yeah, it's really awesome to see them back in Season 5.
Yeah, I agree.
Diablo II is certainly near and dear to our hearts here out in New York.
And yeah, we're really glad to have them back,
and we hope to see hopefully more returning new faces in the future too.
So let's take a look at that boss encounter now.
So I showed you a number of members of the Fell Council here.
We've actually built five of them in total,
but you're only going to fight three at a time.
Now we keep two in the hopper basically,
and we do that because we want to have a whole bunch of replay
associated with this boss fight.
And because we're only using three of the five,
there's actually 10 variations of this boss fight you can fight
randomly as you do your Infernal Run.
And so we're going to basically kill them off.
And once you defeat one, the fight will actually escalate.
Actually, it probably escalates even if you just take down
a certain amount of health, if I remember correctly.
And it escalates.
Basically, their attacks become more powerful,
and then they start really getting even more powerful
kind of room-clearing attacks towards the end.
But we've defeated them here,
and this is the reward moment I actually wanted to talk through with you
because this is something that really ties into itemization 2.0.
You've got several chests here,
and you've got a choice of the rewards you get
at the end of your Infernal Run.
You can choose from a chest that contains all new legendaries and new uniques.
You can choose from a chest that contains all sorts of crafting materials,
including masterworking materials.
So you don't need to go to the pit anymore exclusively
to get masterworking materials.
You've got a chest that allows you just to get a whole bunch of gold.
I know people out there are really asking for gold,
and this is going to be a good source of it.
And finally, even though it wasn't shown here,
you have a chest that guarantees a single item with a greater affects on it.
And so we thought we'd want to try this out
and see how people respond to it.
And we thought it would be pretty exciting.
You know, certainly in Season 4,
I'm really trying to get some more greater affectses,
so I'd love to have this in Season 5.
So yeah, let's take a closer look at some of the uniques
you can farm from the Infernal Horde
since we're talking about rewards already.
So we're going to queue up some footage here.
So first up, we've got the Basilisk.
And so this is going to be a new unique staff for Druids.
And so when you hit an enemy with a Nerf skill,
it'll petrify them and deal physical damage.
So turning the monsters to stone, always cool.
But it's also cool that you can CC your target
and boost your initial attack here.
So this one's pretty exciting for you Druid players out there.
All right, next up, we've got the Third Blade.
Now this is a unique sword for Barbarians.
This one makes your Weapon Mastery skills
be treated as core skills that cost Fury.
Even though they deal a little reduced damage,
this one's pretty exciting because now you can start making
all sorts of new builds that you've never seen before.
So we're really interested to see what the community comes up with here.
All right, next up, we've got the Mordicrux.
Now the Mordicrux is a new unique dagger for Necros.
So when you consume a corpse,
there's a chance that you'll create a skeletal simulacrum
that seeks out enemies.
And when it dies, it explodes.
So essentially, you're making a Skelly Bomb
when you consume the corpses.
And so that's just going to seek out targets and explode.
I think that'd be pretty handy for my Necro this season.
So I'm looking forward to that one too.
Next up, we have the Mordicrux.
Now the Mordicrux is a new unique dagger for Rogues.
So if you use a Sutterfuge skill, you'll create a Totem.
And if you hit that Totem with an attack,
it replicates any of the damage it takes to all nearby enemies.
And so it's a great way for essentially replicating
and doubling down on the damage that you're dealing in a particular area.
All right, next up, we've got the Vox Omnium.
Now the Vox Omnium is a new unique staff for Sorcs.
And so when you cast a Core skill,
it's going to cast an additional two basic projectiles
based on the previous elements used.
And so this allows you to really start comboing
your Core and Basic skills together.
And if you decide to have different elements
associated with those Core and Basic skills,
now you can start casting Fire and Lightning and Cold
all at the same time.
So we're pretty excited about this one too.
And the final one we're going to share out here
is actually a new set of boots that's available for all classes.
And these are called Rackanoth's Wake.
And so whenever you use an ability with a cooldown,
you'll trigger an explosion dealing fire damage.
And so really, it's pretty straightforward.
You're going to bathe your enemies in flames
whenever you use a cooldown skill.
So maybe I'm going to dust off my Whirlwind Barb here
and slap them on and see how it does.
So yeah, these are some of the Uniques and Legendaries
that are going in to the Infernal Hordes.
I think there are 10 Uniques overall
and over 20 Legendaries that you can farm from the Infernal Hordes.
So there's going to be a lot to chase down in there.
That's awesome.
Thank you, Dan, for sharing and going through all that stuff.
I know with players jumping in on PTR,
especially for and trying out Infernal Hordes and everything,
what's kind of like the top things that you really want them to like kind of hone in on,
give feedback on, check on for PTR?
Yeah, absolutely.
We definitely need feedback on the PTR.
It's super critical to ensuring that the Infernal Hordes
and all the rewards feel great for when the season launches.
So here are some of the topics that we could use some help on.
First off, just how is the Infernal Hordes gameplay?
How do the Boons and Banes feel?
Which ones do you like the most or the least?
And these are types of things that will help us fine-tune that experience.
Similarly, how is it acquiring compasses?
Do you have too much, too few?
How do you feel about upgrading them?
That could help us really dial in kind of the access to the Infernal Hordes.
We're also interested in learning how you feel about the difficulty
and the gameplay length of the different tiers.
Like I said at the top, we've got eight different tiers of difficulty.
And so we have the ability to dial those in a little bit.
We want to make sure that players can really replay this over and over again
as they push into the endgame, much like the pit.
And then finally, of course, how are the rewards?
Which do you like the most or the least?
We can certainly make tweaks on the rewards
to make sure they're as enticing as possible.
Awesome.
Yeah, and I know with Infernal Hordes, this is another alternative
because, as you mentioned, you can jump into it starting with World Tier 3.
So if you're actually leveling a new character,
you can actually jump into Infernal Hordes
and you're able to earn experience in here.
So you actually have the opportunity of jumping into Helltides if you want to.
You can jump into Infernal Hordes.
When you get to 85 or something like that, you can jump into pits.
So there's now more...
Or Nightmare Dungeons, obviously, when you're upgrading your glyphs and everything.
So there's a lot of different variety now for being able to kind of level up a character,
especially as you're going to that mid-to-late game phase of your character's journey, you could say.
Yeah, something else to bring up for the rewards for the Infernal Horde as well
that I want to clarify.
So Dan mentioned about there's going to be uniques that are there
that you can target farm in the Infernal Hordes.
There's actually going to be a group of uniques and legendaries
that you're able to target farm in that piece of content in the Infernal Hordes.
So you're also kind of similar to how the normal game works,
how you can target farm a unique from a boss,
but you can find it anywhere else in the world.
It's the same way here where you can get these new uniques and legendaries anywhere,
but you have a better chance if you're targeting them in the Infernal Hordes.
And this is the first time that we're doing this with a group of legendaries as well.
We have legendary powers that are actually able to be target farmed in the Infernal Hordes,
which is actually something a little bit new to the game.
So I just wanted to clarify that.
And in addition to that, we're also adding new uniques and legendaries
to the rest of the game as well in addition to this.
So there's actually a very large group of uniques.
I think it's over 50 or something.
Yeah, there's over 50 new uniques and legendaries coming into Season 5.
So we have a lot coming.
It's pretty extensive.
More to talk about there too.
Yeah, this was just kind of a small preview of what people are looking at here,
and they'll be able to jump in more and actually check it out on PTR
because all of them will be present there.
And I know Adam is actually going to talk through a few additional ones here later.
But yeah, Dan, this is awesome.
Can't wait for players to jump in.
I appreciate you informing and providing all the new updates and everything.
Yeah, it's exciting.
From the sweltering heat of all...
I'm going to keep bringing it up.
They canceled school up there.
It's crazy.
I'm like, that's absolutely insane.
But we will be seeing Dan again here later,
especially when we get into Q&A at the end.
But Dan, thank you again.
I think we're...
Oh, you're welcome.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Appreciate it.
And then I think we're going to jump into a little bit of some balance and class updates
with Mr. Adam Jackson.
Yeah, let's get to it.
We have a lot to talk about.
I think we have...
Yeah, so the topics I'm going to be covering today,
we've got unique items.
We're going to be talking quite a bit about that.
We've got some updates to mythic uniques that are very exciting
and near and dear to my heart.
And then we've got your standard class updates,
a lot of stuff coming in Season 5.
One thing to clarify here is that we are going to be releasing the patch notes soon,
so I'm not going to be going over every single class update
because there's a ton of them.
Kind of similar to Season 4.
I'm really only going to highlight just one major thing for each class on the stream today.
But you'll be able to see all the things that we're doing in the patch notes.
There's a lot.
So first, uniques.
We have some quality of life updates here,
really targeting how you get uniques
that I'm pretty pumped about to announce here today.
So you can now target farm uniques from three additional sources.
You can target them from Ovalvendors,
Helltide Chess, and Whisper Caches.
These places where you've always been able to, you know,
kind of target farm certain gear slots
and not been able to get uniques.
And you're wondering, well, why couldn't we do that?
That stinks.
Well, now you can.
And it's awesome.
And I love it.
So here, just to give some more detail into how this works,
is basically when you open, like,
I'm just going to use Helltide Chess as an example, right?
If you want a specific unique weapon, let's say,
you can just simply target the weapon Helltide Chess,
and you'll be able to have a chance to get only unique weapons
for your class from those chests.
So when you're targeting a specific thing,
you just go to, you know, the place that has that slot,
whether it's the Ovalvendor, the Helltide Chess,
or the Whisper Cache,
and you'll have a chance to get uniques
that are targeted for that slot.
So it kind of adds, you know,
while you're doing your normal grind of, you know,
doing the boss ladder, killing the boss,
you can also be collecting Obles, doing the Helltides,
doing the Whisperers,
and having a chance to target and get that unique as well
from that content.
And in addition to that,
this is also true for mythic uniques.
So I'll just give an example here of exactly how this works.
Let's say that you want to get, you know,
Harlequin Crest, a Shaco, or an Daryl's Visage.
You don't want to target those helms.
You could be targeting helms from Helltide,
targeting helms when you turn in your obals,
the Ovalvendor.
And every time, if you get a mythic unique,
you will get one of those two from that source.
Now, also to clarify,
let's say that you are targeting gloves for some reason.
You know, we don't have any mythic unique gloves yet.
Then if you were to get a mythic unique,
you still can.
It'll just give you a random one instead,
since, you know, you can't target one in that slot.
So pretty exciting way to target kind of the things that you want
while you're farming.
Yeah, it's going to be amazing.
I know we've heard a lot of players going like,
hey, you know, we do the endgame bosses a whole lot.
And you can actually find them just in the open world as well.
We've actually seen a lot of cases,
especially with this past season,
where players are jumping into Helltide
and they're actually finding them there.
But now it's an additional,
or additional options for players,
which I think will be a lot better
for just overall finding some of the gear
that everyone really wants.
As someone who, for the last three seasons,
my uniques have always come from the Beast and Ice,
I am very selfishly invested in getting this into the game.
Yes, yes.
All right, let's talk about other unique updates here.
We're going to be making a whole lot of updates
to our unique items.
So I'm going to be covering a lot today.
We've heard your feedback,
and we're going to be doing some updates here.
To clarify before I go into what the updates are,
you are going to be seeing these updates
to like the way that we think about
and our philosophy around uniques and how they work.
You're going to be seeing them in the PTR
for the new uniques coming into season five.
Between the PTR and the launch,
you'll be seeing in the season five launch,
these updates to all the existing uniques in the game.
So when season five comes out,
basically all the uniques will get these updates
that I'm about to talk about.
But in the PTR,
you're only going to really see this
in the new uniques coming into the game.
Yeah, there.
So now we can go on to the next part.
All right.
So the team's been talking a lot.
As many of you probably know,
in season four,
we did itemization 2.0.
We didn't really update the uniques
almost at all in the game, right?
We didn't do like a big pass
to like cover how they exist in tempering
or anything like that.
So the team's been talking a lot about,
you know,
what is the role of uniques in Diablo 4?
Like how are they different from legendary items?
Because they're kind of similar
in that they both give you,
you know,
a legendary power that's really strong.
But how are they different?
And what do we want them to be long term?
And we've kind of landed on a few things here
that I'm going to talk about.
The first one is that,
you know,
they're powerful and exciting items
that kind of direct players to builds, right?
So imagine you're a Fireball sort.
You know,
we've got two uniques for you.
They really target you.
You're going to feel a lot better
playing with Fireball when you take them.
You know,
we want you to take these things
and kind of level up your build.
They're moments of like
very large incremental power
where you feel like you're,
you know,
filling in your fantasy as a class.
The next one is that
they're kind of pick up and play, right?
They're easy to evaluate.
The moment that you pick up the unique,
you know,
you know whether it's a good one
or a bad one.
We want this to be a little bit different
from legendary powers
where, you know,
you pick it up
and you kind of go on a journey
where, you know,
you make it into something
that's really good.
A unique,
you know when you pick it up
whether or not
it's one that you want to keep
or one that you don't.
And then the last one,
pretty obvious,
but was worth saying,
you know,
they're kind of more rare chase items
that players don't see very often.
You know,
when you're going through the end game,
you're seeing legendary powers a lot
because, you know,
we have a lot of reasons
to give you a lot of them.
You want to upgrade your codex.
They are the way that you can,
you know,
get greater affixes
and temper and masterwork them.
So there's a reason why
you want to churn
and look through a lot of them.
Uniques,
you do want to get a good one,
obviously,
but not nearly as often
as like a legendary power.
We don't need that,
that aspect of their design.
So they are more rare.
They're harder to get,
but when you get it,
it's kind of like
a more exciting moment.
Like,
did I get the perfect one?
And then if not,
you go and try and get the next one.
So let's talk a little about
our goals for the update
that we're going to be doing here.
One of the things
that we come to a lot
that we talk about on the team
is this idea,
and I like this quote,
of like,
players build their legendaries
and players build around
their uniques, right?
Your legendary power is very,
or your legendary items
are very malleable.
You know,
the moment you get it,
you don't know yet
if it's going to be
the best in slot item,
but it has a chance to be.
But they're also like
able to fit
in a lot of different ways.
You can manipulate
their stats via,
you know,
enchanting,
via tempering,
and masterworking.
And so there's a lot
that you can do
with the item
once you've gotten it.
Whereas uniques,
they're a lot more static, right?
The stats on them
can't change.
You can't really
manipulate them very much.
And sometimes
they have maybe
qualities to them
or stats that are
a little bit inconvenient.
And you've got to figure out,
like,
how do I overcome
this little detriment
or make my build
into where it's a plus
instead of a detriment, right?
Like,
it's a fixed thing
that you have to build around,
which is very different
than a legendary.
Also,
ideally,
we want players
to run two to four uniques
in their build.
You know,
one of the difficult parts
of this,
and I think we're going
to be continuing
to work on with the balance
and design of uniques,
is that,
you know,
we want you to run some,
but we don't want you
to run all of them
in your build, right?
It's very easy
to go one way or the other.
I can very easily
make you run no uniques,
and I can very easily
make you run, like,
every slot is a unique
by making them really,
really crazy, right?
We want these to fit
in such a way
that you're running
some of them,
the ones that are applicable
to your build,
or maybe some spicy ones
here or there
that you try and,
you know,
like,
make in a special way
to work with you,
but not all of them.
I would say right now,
like on live in season four,
players are running more
like zero to two
in their build,
so it's not as much
as we want,
which means that we want
to update them
to make them a little
bit more attractive.
And another one is
we kind of want to move away
from these generic
fits all build styles
of uniques, right?
One thing that I know
a lot of players
have talked about
in the past
that we've had
is that some of our uniques
are just so generically good,
and this is particularly
scary for us
when it's like
what we call generic unique,
which is one where
every class can use it,
and so like if every class
can use it
and every build can use it
and it's better
than like the build specific
or class specific stuff,
then it just becomes
best in slot for everybody,
and we've taken away
your agency and your choice
because you're just
going to target this item
and ignore everything else,
right?
The only items in the game
that we really want
to fit that role
are like mythic uniques
where they're across all classes
and they're so good,
but they're also extremely rare,
so you're very excited
to see them
whenever you see one,
but all the other
regular uniques,
we don't want to fit
that design space,
so we're going to be
trying to move away
from these ones
and readjust them
and redesign them
a little bit
where they fit
into all kinds of builds
and kind of target
something that they're
really good at
or that's a little bit
more unique about them
and make them
really good at that
and less generically
good at everything.
It's funny because
everyone's in the chat
going like,
oh, rip Shaco,
rip Shaco,
but we just literally,
we just said.
Mythics is not,
they're a different beast here.
I'm talking about
all your regular ones.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Shaco's still
going to be just as good,
if not better, honestly.
All right, so,
enough preamble, right?
What are we actually doing?
So, we're going to be doing
two big updates
to uniques.
The first one is
we're going to be
increasing the upper power
of the unique effects
and the roll range.
We're going to be doing
an increase in the range
from an average
of 10 to 20 rolls,
which I'll explain
in a second,
and then we're also
going to be increasing
the upper power
of how much you can get
from the rolls.
This is really just buffing
pretty much most uniques
across the board
to compete with the new world
of legendary powers
that we live in
since, you know,
they got extra power juice
to them.
Now uniques are catching up.
So, as an example here,
I gave, you know,
if an older unique,
like one on live,
gave you around 40 to 80%
multiplicative damage,
that's going to go up
to like 40, 100,
maybe 120,
maybe even higher.
Really, the mandate is
as high as we can get away with
without breaking things.
And then we're also
going to be increasing
the roll range.
This is like the number
of possible rolls it can do
from an average of 10 to 20.
So, it'll be a little bit
harder to get basically,
what we're targeting here
is the discrepancy
inside of a unique
is a little bit wider
where the difference
of like a low roll
and a high roll
is a little bit bigger,
but the high rolls
are way better
than they were before.
So, they're more exciting
when you get them
really good,
but it's a little bit
harder to get there.
And the next one
is going to be updating
the affixes,
the actual stats
on the uniques.
We're doing a pass
on all of them
and this is kind of
what we're doing.
The first thing is
we're changing their stats
to fit with the season 4
updates, right?
We're doing the things
like we did before
of simplifying stats,
you know,
getting rid of
super conditional things,
making them just more
generically understood
and good.
We're also going to be
adding tempering stats.
We're open to really
adding whatever we want
that makes a unique
fit the fantasy.
So, as an example here,
you know,
a lot of two-hand weapon
uniques have a problem
where they're all
basically competing
against bonus projectiles
as an affix
because you can just
temper that onto your
weapons, right?
So, when it comes
to those kind of
situations,
we'll just slap
the bonus projectiles
on that unique
and now, you know,
it's no longer
competing in that way
or we have to kind of
dance around it.
We can just put it.
We're also open
to the idea, by the way,
of breaking slot restrictions
kind of like we did
in Season 2
so you can have
bonus projectiles
or other things
on other slots.
You know, like uniques
are where we get
to play a little bit
and just really make
something thematic
and cool
and build defining
and so they have
less restrictions
than everything else.
And the other one
is we're updating
the stat power levels
and the effects.
So, the idea here
that we're thinking
and this is particularly
nuancy when it comes
to generic uniques
but stats that kind
of fit the theme
or the fantasy
of the unique
are going to be
like way stronger
than your normal stats,
right?
So, as an example,
if you have a unique
that's targeting
fire damage,
maybe it's like a meteor
or a firewall
and the sorcerer
or whatever it may be,
you know, that plus
fire damage can be
juiced up to be
really, really high
but stats that are
more like generically good
like, you know,
I don't know,
attack speed,
max life, resist all,
those ones aren't
going to be juiced
unless it fits
the theme of the unique
really well, right?
So, we have an example
here of one that
has been a problem
for us in the past
and I kind of want
to go through
how we would think
about it.
I'm not going to say
exactly what we're
going to do here
to T'Bolt's Will
but kind of give you
our thought process, right?
So, T'Bolt's Will,
as many of you know
in previous seasons
was kind of a problem
where it just became
best in slot
for almost every build.
You know,
the famous line we say
is there was damage
on pants which was
impossible to get
almost anywhere else
in the game
and it turned out
damage on pants
was really, really good,
right?
It also gave you
damage reduction,
one of the best stats
in the game
and then it also gave you
a bunch of,
it also solved resource
in many ways for you
as well, right?
It gave you a bunch
of resource
whenever you became
unstoppable which wasn't
too hard to do
so it was doing
a lot of things at once.
It gave you
a very unique effect
with putting damage
on a slot that you
don't get it.
It also gave you
resource which is
something that every
class wants very heavily.
And Adam,
it gave you
three extra potions.
And three extra potions!
Yes.
Now that one,
you know,
that's alright.
But yeah,
so, you know,
the way that we would
tackle this one
to give you an idea
is like,
you know,
we either would
kind of pick,
you know,
do we want to focus
this on the damage
aspect that it's
damage on a
non-damage slot
or maybe we focus
on the resource
aspect and like
double down on that
and make that
really powerful
and really cool
or we do like
a little bit of both
but if we do both
then it's not going
to give you the
defenses that another
pants slot would give,
right?
Basically,
in our mind,
we'd be like,
we want to give the
minimum amount of defense
where it's not just
like a trash item
because it has nothing
but then after that
not so much
and you're going to
have to solve your
defenses in other slots
or somewhere else
to justify getting
the damage on this slot
is how we would
think about it,
right?
And so we're having
a lot of conversations
now.
I don't think we're
going to nail
every single item
perfectly in this
first pass
so we're really
looking for feedback
when you,
you know,
jump into season five
and beyond
and we'll be
adjusting them
but I want to
give you an idea
of what we're doing
and kind of what
we're thinking
and targeting with this.
So I think we can
move on.
So Mythic Uniques
are getting a
facelift here.
So lots of updates
here.
Mythic Uniques are
now going to be
truly Mythic.
They're getting a
new color beam
when they drop
on the ground.
They're coming out
with an awesome new
sound that you're
going to hear
in a little bit.
We've got a new
item UI that you
can see so they
have a different color.
They really are
going to look and
feel like the special
items that they are.
And we have a video
here to show you
the sound and what
it looks like on
the ground.
So you can see
here this beam
looks very different
than anything else.
Isn't that sound,
that echoey sound,
I love it.
Sounds like a...
I don't know,
it sounds like
you're murdering
a bunch of
church organs
or something like that.
It's just crazy.
But yeah,
so when this thing
drops,
you're definitely
going to know
when you've got one.
No more sifting
through your Uniques
to see if it's
actually one of the
Mythics.
You'll know right away.
So we're really
excited about this.
Super happy it was
able to get in.
All right,
and last but not least,
let's talk about
class updates.
I'm going to cover
some generic things
across all classes
and then go through
a little bit of each one.
Again,
this is not going to be
nearly close to
everything that we're
doing,
just a little taste
to teaser for what
you can expect to see.
Let's start with
things across all classes.
One systemic update
we're doing to the game
is invulnerability skills
are now going to start
their cooldown
when the invulnerability
ends instead of
when the skill begins.
This is really to
prevent things like
infinite invulnerability
and really to open up
design space for us
on the team
because now we can be
more comfortable
adding things like
invulnerable duration
to skills or
cooldown reduction
more liberally
and things like that
where we don't have
to worry about this.
This is very similar
to what our previous
games have done
and some other games do
and we think it'll be
a good fit here.
The idea isn't really
to make it that you
can't be invulnerable
very often.
It's just to prevent
100% uptime
where you actually
break down the combat
of the game
and you're not interacting
with enemies anymore.
The next one is
we reviewed monster CC
and we generally
reduced the CC duration
and frequency
across the board
so if you were
frustrated by getting
frozen for a million
years and then dying
that'll happen
much less often
and also to help
with this
potions can be used
while CC'd
even while you're
stunned.
So while you're
frozen standing there
and everybody's around
you trying to kill you
you can at least
spam potion a little bit
and maybe survive
sometimes.
Next one we've got
some bug fixes.
These are some of the
notable ones.
We do have more
coming in but these
are the ones I wanted
to call out.
Rogue Victimized is no
longer going to be
double dipping on its
damage which was
resulting in a lot
more multiplicative
or a lot more damage
really than it was
supposed to have.
Damage over time
effects were getting
double the amount of
percent damage that
they were supposed to
and Skeleton Reapers
were getting both
book of the dead bonuses
when the second option
was selected.
And again this is
just a little bit of
a preview but we have
other bug fixes coming
but these are some of
the bigger ones we
want to call out.
All right now let's
get to the classes.
So Barbarian they have
a new unique coming
in.
This is the Unbroken
Chain.
This is for you
support Barbarians or
really just more
defensively oriented
ones.
Basically what this is
going to do is create a
connection between
Steel Grasp and
Iron Maelstrom where
you'll be able to cast
Iron Maelstrom a lot
more often as you use
Steel Grasp.
And also enemies
damaged by our
Maelstrom are going
to be doing less
damage for a little
while.
So the idea here is
you could debuff
enemies, debuff those
bosses and make them
do less damage to you
so you can survive
better.
And next the Rogue
Flurry is going to be
getting a lot of big
updates.
We updated the
enhancement and both
of their upgrades.
So you'll be able to
see kind of a theme
here going on.
Before you know you
would damage a crowd
control or a vulnerable
enemy for the
enhancement then you
would heal.
Now when Flurry hits an
enemy you can just make
them vulnerable.
So actually Flurry
becomes a vulnerable
generator here which is
pretty exciting.
and it will also deal
more damage as you
hit vulnerable enemies.
It stacks up really
high so the idea here
is with Flurry builds
you want to make
everything vulnerable
and then just keep
whacking them with
Flurry and gain a
bunch of damage.
And now Improved
Flurry is changing.
Before it was about
vulnerable spreading
but now Baseline you
can just generate
vulnerable so we
don't need that
anymore.
So now Improved
Flurry is going to
actually give you a
dash.
So now similar to
things like the
Shred on the Druid
you can kind of dash
to your target and
also every time you
cast Flurry now it's
going to heal you.
So it's going to be a
lot more mobile a lot
more awesome.
Very cool.
And then last but not
least to compete with
a dash what could we
do with Advanced
Flurry?
Well we can just add a
stupid amount of
damage and resource
cost reduction.
So before you know
you had to evade
through an enemy and
then do damage with
one cast and stun
enemies.
Now as you spam
Flurry it'll basically
get a big damage
bonus and its energy
cost will go down
which will let you be
able to spam it even
more often.
So the idea here is
you just want to be
using it over and
over and over again
and it'll get
stronger and stronger
and ramp up pretty
heavily as you go.
I'm excited for
Flurry rogues.
Yeah.
Very excited.
They're going to be
like little hummingbirds
around bouncing around
and it's going to be
great.
Yeah.
Ironically I'm playing
Flurry this season so
I'm always off by one.
Like I always play the
thing and then like oh
we're going to massively
make it better next time
but you know it's fine.
It's fine.
Everything's fine.
Next Druid.
Shepard's Aspect.
We've gotten feedback
from players now for a
while now about how
you know Shepard's Aspect
kind of dominates the
meta for Druids
because you're basically
both it's both not great
from a design and a
balanced perspective.
On the design side you
know we're telling you
to put companions on
your bar and then
they're actually just
buffing you.
So you know we make
this companion build
fantasy but it's
actually just making the
player better.
And then on the power
side you know you're
just putting you're
basically just slotting
three skills on your
bar with your companions
and then not really
caring about buffing
them or using them
because they're just
kind of there as
proxies to make you
better.
So we've changed it now
where you know
basically it's going to
be about the companions.
So your companion skills
are just going to deal
damage for every
companion that you have.
So you know the bigger
your zoo the better
your zoo is going to
perform.
And to compensate
players we're doing
some pretty massive
buffs to Druid skills
baseline to compensate.
So you know your skills
are just going to be
getting that damage
baseline and in many
cases a little bit more.
So you can check that
out when you see the
PTR notes or yeah the
PTR patch notes after
this.
But we basically just
buffed everything across
the board and made it
so that Shepherds isn't
required anymore.
Next for the Sorceress
this is Axial Conduit.
I'm really excited
about this unique.
This is your Chain
Lightning unique.
So Chain Lightning
builds.
You finally have a unique
that really talks to you.
And you can see here
kind of our stats and
that new philosophy I
told you about.
You have a chance to
double cast Chain
Lightning on pants
instead of just a
weapon.
So that's pretty cool.
So basically the way
that this works we're
going to have a video
but I'm going to explain
to you how this works
because it actually
changes your skill
pretty significantly.
So now when you
cast Chain Lightning
the way it's going to
work is it's going to
cast and bounce on
enemies just like
before but then it's
going to come back to
you and orbit you a
little bit.
And then it's going to
go out and hit another
enemy and then come
back to you in orbit
and then come out and
go out and do another
enemy and come back.
It's going to do that
back and forth a few
times and every time it
comes back to you it's
going to drain some of
your mana.
And after it drains so
much mana after coming
back ten times the bolt
is actually going to
explode for a ridiculous
amount of lightning damage
on enemies.
So there's a mini game
here where basically
oh and by the way you
can cast multiple Chain
Lightning's when this is
out.
You're basically going to
be like running a
gambit here and the
mini game is you want to
stack as much resource
regeneration as you can
so that your lightning
bolts can survive being
drained over and over
and bouncing everywhere
so they can last to
their explosion and do a
ton of damage to
enemies.
One thing I want to
call out here also is
that because it drains
mana resource cost
reduction won't work on
that drain.
You're actually going to
want to focus on gaining
resource which is a
little bit different and
kind of makes us build a
little special I think
and unique compared to
other resource builds
based around resource.
So I like to see it in
action here.
So you'll see what one
cast looks like and then
I think we'll see what it
looks like when you spam
it.
So you can see here it
circles you, goes and
hits enemies, circles you,
goes and hits enemies and
then it does a big
explosion at the end that
we've tuned to damage to
be pretty high.
See there?
So then it explodes.
Oh wait.
Oh do we have one where it
casts a bunch of times?
Maybe we don't.
Oh there we go.
There we go.
So see here?
You can see that as you
go it will keep going,
going, going and they
explode a bunch of times.
Another thing I want to
point out is if you're
hugging enemies in melee
range as it's circling you
it will also hit enemies.
So you now have a way to
really maximize your
damage by hugging bosses
and such.
The damage goes way up.
So next, last but not
least, the Necromancer.
So we got some feedback.
We've had this for a while
and put this on the team
where, you know, the
golem we really love.
You know, we love our
golem, our golem boys.
And, you know, but
sometimes it can be
frustrating where you tell
the golem to go somewhere
and then he kind of takes
a while to lug his butt
over there and do his
slam or his shout or
whatever and, you know,
things can get in the way.
And so we've kind of upgraded
him a little bit.
I'll let the video speak
for himself here.
But so now you can see
your golem will Hulk smash
and just jump on enemies
and slam them down.
So this will work with all
of your golem types, by the
way, not just the iron golem.
But now your golem is going
to leap to the area that you
tell him to go and then
cast his ability.
So we're really excited about
this.
Shout out to Charles Dunn
who got this change in and
our animators who helped
us out.
But we're really pumped for
it.
It looks amazing.
Yeah.
So those were the class
and balance changes.
And I know we jumped a
slide there.
How dare you, production?
No.
But we are, as they wave
to me like, I'm sorry.
We do want to go into some
quality of life updates.
We do have a significant
amount of quality of life
updates that we do want to
go through that will be
available in season five.
And you guys will actually
be able to check this out
in the PTR.
So now we can go to the
next slide where we do
want to talk about some
Helltide and Whisper
updates specifically.
So I know this has been
kind of, at least it's been
a pain point for me and I've
heard it's been a pain
point for others, is that
as you guys are going
through Helltide, there
are Whisper objectives within
there to help you with your
progression on your
Whisper bar.
But the issue with the
ones in Helltide is that
it can sometimes take quite a
while to do.
And, you know, sometimes
players would have to leave
the Helltide to go to
another area to complete
some of these Whisper
objectives.
So we are optimizing this to
ensure that they don't take
nearly as much time.
The ideal goal is to get a
bunch of value within those
15 minutes and to
potentially end up getting a
full entire Whisper 10-point
bar within 15 minutes in one
Helltide 7.
Full Whisper every Helltide.
So that would be, it would be
a huge help because I know,
at least for me, I've always
had to, like, kind of leave a
Helltide and try to, you
know, knock some of that out.
It will especially help for
players that are looking for
additional gold because
Whisper Caches have always
been great sources of gold.
And now, as Adam mentioned,
you can also use Whisper Caches
to target farm.
To target farm.
So it's keeping things more
optimized for players, which
we know will be way better
there.
The next thing we do want to
talk about is also Baneful
Hearts.
I know this may not sound like
a huge quality of life thing
or a buff of any sort, but
we have noticed that players
have had a lot of Baneful
Hearts within their inventory.
We do want to make these a
little bit more valuable so
they won't drop as
frequently.
We know that players will
still have a significant
amount, but maybe not
hundreds and hundreds like
some people have within
their inventory.
But players should not have
any type of issues regarding
having a ton of these
Baneful Hearts.
But we are tweaking the
drop rate because they were
dropping a little too much
there.
Tempering.
Yeah.
The very, very, I guess,
like, brought up topic.
Well, like.
Yeah.
People like to worry about
tempering.
It's pretty popular.
Yeah.
So I want to take a minute to
talk about tempering and kind
of how the design team sees
it and kind of what we're
happy with, what we think
could be better, and some
adjustments we'll be making
in Season 5.
So first high level, kind of
how we see tempering.
We really think that it's
important that items have an
endpoint where players know
kind of that the item is
done and that they're not
hoarding lots of them forever
on the chance that they can
all be good.
Right?
One of the big key goals of
Season 4 was that we didn't
want you saving a million
items in your stash space.
And while we know that, you
know, bricking an item never
feels great, we do need that
to be something that's
possible to do in the game so
that you know when the
journey is done and you're not
just holding on to an item
forever.
So that part we actually think
is working very well where,
you know, an item is done and
you try and go get another
one.
And so you're always interested
in items and trying to, you
know, have that game loop go
in the game indefinitely.
Or until you feel like your
character is Maxonic's power.
But we do agree with players
that, you know, the RNG right
now is like completely out of
their hands, which doesn't
really feel great.
You know, you get so many
tries basically to roll and
then that's kind of it and
you're done and it doesn't
feel great.
So we're looking at ways in the
future for players to have
more control over that RNG so
that, you know, you have more
ways to maybe manipulate the
tempering or get the odds in
your favor and do other
things like that.
One update that's going to be
coming in Season 5, it won't
be in the PTR, but as we're
targeting for launch, is that,
you know, we've got a lot of
feedback that it feels so bad
when, you know, you get that
like triple greater affix and
it has the same number of
rolls and then you brick it
and then you have to try and
go get another one.
So in Season 5, to help with
this, you know, as your item
gets better basically that you
find, you're going to have
more chances to temper it.
So a much better chance to
get the one that you want.
Basically, the way it'll work
is you're going to basically
get one extra roll per
greater affix that you have.
So, you know, you have one
greater affix, one roll, three,
three rolls.
And again, just to clarify,
this is not in the PTR, but it
will be in for the launch of
Season 5 in itself.
And again, just to reiterate,
we are still looking at ways to
help out that experience within
tempering, as we've noted.
We agree with players that it
doesn't always feel great.
And so you guys should expect to
hear more updates to tempering
after we get through Season 5,
for sure.
Yeah.
All right.
Next up, weapons.
Yeah.
So I'll talk about this one a
little bit.
We took a look at...
Look at this chart.
Yeah, this chart.
We took a look at inherent
affixes on weapons, and we
found that, you know, a lot of
inherent affixes, like damage to
distant or some other ones,
were a little too conditional
and didn't get the update,
you know, in Season 4 that we
wanted.
So we went back and made them
a little bit more generically
useful and better across more
builds.
So we have a little chart here,
but you can see kind of this is
going to be the new inherent
affixes on all the different
weapon types.
So we've made quite a few
adjustments here.
You know, as an example,
you know, vulnerable damage is
on bows and dot damage is on
axes, which I believe vulnerable
on bows is new.
But yeah, so we made quite a few
updates.
We basically just looked at the
matricy of everything and kind
of adjusted it to see what
makes sense.
So basically you're just going to
have, you know, things that
actually impact your builds much
more often on the weapons that
you want.
And as another result of this
update, we are also looking at
what weapons classes can use.
And we updated them a little
bit to try and, you know, let
more classes use more weapons.
We want players to be able to
create interesting builds, play
the way that we want.
And so we want to open up these
things as much as we can in our
designs.
So now Druids are going to be
able to use two-hand pull arms,
one-hand swords, and daggers.
Sorceresses are going to be able
to use one-hand swords and
maces.
And Necromancers are going to be
able to use, I think it's
maces and axes, actually.
Yeah.
Despite this Necromancer
picture right here that is not
using...
Well, it's using a two-handed
sword, but you can already use a
two-handed sword, but not using a...
Yeah.
And the Necromancer here, I know
it's supposed to say all maces and
axes as opposed to all swords.
But yeah, basically we're going to
be opening up these classes to use
more weapon types.
And then also some of the uniques
are going to be updated for the
classes as well.
So the Butcher's Cleaver can now be
used for Necros.
Necromancer and Sorcerers can use
Doombriner and Azure Wrath now.
Yeah, Sorcerers can use Azure
Wrath, kind of like D2.
Yep.
Fits their theme very well too.
So I think that'll be pretty cool.
Some additional quality of life
updates.
Now we're going to talk about some
endgame bosses.
As I have experienced, as Adam has
experienced earlier, as he mentioned
in the stream, we are making changes
to the Beast and Ice.
You guys will no longer have to make
a sigil to summon the Beast and Ice.
Which is a huge quality of life
update.
The Beast will now live in a
standard dungeon.
The crawl to get to the Beast and
Ice is much, much shorter now.
It's going to be more similar to
what we've seen with some of the
other endgame bosses.
And then at the same time, Eternal
players that have maybe already
built out some of these sigils.
We made sure to keep you in mind so
you can still use those sigils to
fight the boss.
You won't need summoning materials.
You can just use the sigil right there
in the boss room in itself.
And this no longer requires sigil dust
to actually summon the Beast and
Ice.
So some big changes to the Beast and
Ice to help out that whole entire
feel, especially when you're really
target farming the Beast and Ice.
Sometimes it was kind of brutal to
have to go through the whole entire
dungeon each and every time.
You're telling me so many times.
Yeah.
So next we have Varshan.
Varshan, the body parts are pretty
much being reduced to one.
I know it was eating up a lot of
inventory space.
It was kind of hard to manage at
times and everything.
So we're optimizing this, making this
better.
So now you'll just need one body part
to essentially summon Varshan going
forward starting with Season 5.
And one big thing that we're going to
call out here before, and this is
kind of like the cherry on top.
We should, let's actually just play
the clip and see if people actually
notice it.
And if not, then we'll call it out.
What could be different this time?
Poor Durial.
Yeah.
Mythic Unique maybe?
No, that's not it.
Oh.
Good gear though.
Yeah, yeah.
But something that is interesting here
is the cauldron has reappeared.
You can just resummon him again.
And there's the altar right there.
You can now resummon all the endgame
bosses without needing to run out of
the dungeon.
Reset the thing.
And reset the dungeon.
So this will help a whole lot.
It will make things way better in terms
of like optimizing when you're, for
time and everything.
Especially when you're a party and
you're like, everyone leave the
dungeon so I can reset and stuff like
that.
Now you'll be able to do that
immediately for all the endgame
bosses.
Super convenient.
Which is a huge, huge feature I know
that players have been asking for.
So that will be also incorporated
into Season 5.
So lots and lots of changes for
Season 5.
One other thing.
I did want to call out regarding
tempering because, just to clarify,
because we've got some people going
like, oh, I don't understand like the
greater affix stuff like in terms of
additional roles.
If you have a one star greater affix,
you'll get one additional role.
If you have like a three star or four
star or something, you would get three
or four pending the amount of stars
that you actually specifically have
on your item.
Yeah, I think it goes up to three.
Yeah, three.
Three, sorry.
Four is more specific.
Four is unique.
Yeah.
If thinking about razor plate or
something like that.
But the other thing that I did want to
call out is that this is actually going
to be retroactive.
So for players that still have maybe an item
that they may have potentially bricked
and it's sitting in their stash, you know,
just for like memento purposes or anything
like that.
Yeah, eternal or whatever.
Yeah.
When your character does move to eternal,
if it was a greater affix, like a three star
greater affix or something like that,
you will end up getting those three additional
roles afterwards.
So that will appear after these changes
actually are implemented with the start
of season five.
It'll just be on your internal character,
obviously, because your seasonal character
will move to eternal.
As I fix my earpiece, that's like falling out.
Oh no.
But one other thing I did want to call out
as well for season five, we have some really
big like accessibility options that are being
added to the actual game.
And we really, really need some testing on this
in the season five PTR.
This is actually called out in our blog.
We'd really love if players can actually check
them out, test them out, provide feedback.
I will note, we aren't planning, despite it
being in the season five PTR, we aren't planning
on these features actually launching with season five.
We really want to take the feedback, make them,
you know, better for when they are ready.
And right now, I think that the plan would be
that they would be ready for season six.
But it's important for us to be able to get
that feedback.
So we really need people to actually test out
these specific features.
We have like an auto pin feature,
we have a compass feature, and then we have
like an audio navigation assistance feature
that is coming within some of these accessibility
features for season five.
So really important for people to kind of like
jump in, check it out, give us feedback,
and then you'll see those in season six
after the PTR is kind of over.
But that is kind of like a huge wrap up of all the stuff
that is coming for the season five PTR
and even a little bit more of even some of the stuff
for season five itself.
We do want to take some questions,
and we still have Dan on the line
from the burning hells of Albany
to answer any questions that we may have.
But I know we have a question specifically teed up,
so if you have questions, please ask them in Twitch chat,
which is where we have live chat going on right now,
and we will try to get through as many as possible.
Cool.
But first question I believe we have is,
because I teed up this question,
are there any new class buffs coming to season five?
Specifically, if Adam can answer,
Druid and Sorceress, because I know,
we hear you, everyone, about Druid and Sorceress.
I know we talked a little bit about it here,
but if you can like expand on it a little.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yes, there are new class buffs coming to season five,
covered it a little bit.
I think one of the call out
that people talk a lot about right now
is how barbarians in particular are pretty strong,
and then the classes that can't get
as far as they can in the pit feels kind of bad.
There's a lot to chew on there,
but I think the short answer is,
yes, we hear you,
and we're going to be looking to beef these things up.
We do have some specific ways
that we want to be targeting these things,
and there's a lot of history to it.
Barbarians in particular are tougher to balance.
I think I've talked about this on stream
a little bit before of, you know,
because of their arsenal system,
they have more items.
You know, any time that we mess with,
and we've messed with like the underlying systems
of the game very heavily in the last year, right?
Season two, we updated all the combat math,
which of course impacts items,
which impacts character power.
We've updated in season four all of itemization,
which obviously directly impacts
the arsenal system very heavily.
So when we do these large shakeups,
it's a lot more difficult in a short amount of time
to get everything, you know,
exactly perfect of how the combinatorics
of those effects are going to impact classes, right?
So that's one end of it.
Another end is what we're trying to do,
and we started with this in season four,
is we're looking at the other class mechanics,
and we want to kind of beef them up
and give them the treatment that we kind of gave
with the necromancer in the Book of the Dead.
You know, in season four,
we actually wanted to try this as an experiment,
like, hey, you know, the Book of the Dead,
the minions, the sacrifice bonuses,
they're what really make necromancer
feel really cool and special and unique.
So we're going to, you know,
try and catch that up, so to speak,
to the arsenal system on the Barbarian,
and not only just increase the numbers, right,
because just increasing the numbers is kind of easy.
We even did that in the mid-season patch.
If you look at the Druid Boons,
you know, we increased them by 50%,
doubled them in many cases,
but we think to really help solve that
on a fantasy and even just a design perspective,
we want to, like, overhaul
and really look at these mechanics
and make them way better
and more thematic to classes.
So we don't have anything to announce today
for season five,
but that's something more long-term
that we're doing to help that problem in the future.
In the short term,
we are, you know, looking at, you know,
fixing the issues with these various classes,
buffing them up in different ways,
you know, making different builds
and other things viable
and trying to keep that parity.
We're also looking at, you know,
bringing down the outliers of power
with the Barbarian in different ways
to make sure that they have more parity
with other classes as well.
But that's kind of our short and long-term vision
of where we want this to be.
Awesome.
I know we have a question specifically,
and this is something I've seen a few times
regarding season five for Dan,
because Infernal Hordes,
people are seeing this gameplay
and they're hearing about, like,
okay, like, I can play it.
Can I play this on Eternal and Seasonal?
Can I play this?
Is this, like, an ongoing thing going forward?
Like, what can players expect, Dan?
Sure, yeah.
So with season five,
we wanted to build out the end game.
And because we're building out the end game,
we wanted to make sure that
any of the end game things we're putting in
are on both seasonal and eternal.
And so in this PTR,
you'll be able to test out
the eternal version of Infernal Hordes.
And so any of the rewards you get from it,
all that's eternal.
So all players are going to benefit from it.
Awesome.
Yeah, so all players will benefit from it.
And as Dan mentioned,
it's a new end game feature.
So it's, like, something that will be, you know,
continuous beyond, you know,
even season five is what we're looking at.
So, yeah.
Players can expect to jump in Infernal Hordes
going forward, which is pretty cool.
Yeah.
And, yeah, the feedback is going to be
incredibly important during this PTR.
As Dan mentioned beforehand,
all the specific items
that we're really hoping to get, you know,
feedback on regarding, you know,
how the boons feel,
how the rewards feel,
how the combat feels
and the waves and stuff like that
will be really important for us
during this specific moment.
What is the,
this is another season five question,
and hopefully you might be able
to answer this, Dan.
What is this from Lucky Luciano?
Shout out, Diablo partner.
What is the equivalent pit level
of the eighth difficulty
of, like, the Infernal Hordes?
Pit level, I guess,
or Nightmare Dungeon
or monster level.
Yeah, you're making me do math here.
Yeah, we just adjusted pit levels.
Yeah, so tier, tier eight,
tier eight of the Infernal Hordes
is going to be equivalent
to about monster level,
I think it's 180 to 200.
So it goes up pretty high.
That's pretty late.
Okay, nice.
Nice.
So a difficult challenge for sure,
which is good to hear.
We have a question from Zapidas.
Man, you all need easier names,
I swear.
Do you foresee changes in grouping
in the pit to allow group play
to be more efficient?
There will be changes.
It won't be something present in PTR.
We'll talk more about it
at the Season 5 launch,
but the team is very aware of it
because we've heard about, like,
hey, it's kind of not great
to feel like I'm getting only 50%
of the rewards associated
when I'm in a group within a pit
if I'm not the party leader specifically.
So it's something that the team is taking in
and we will have an update
for players before Season 5
and it will be live,
whatever change we have,
live in Season 5.
So a question from,
let's see,
I don't know.
Well, this one's easy.
Okay.
Robot Jomo.
What's the team's philosophy
on rate of power gain?
It seems that tempering,
especially players,
gain too much power too quickly,
really removing the tension
from the leveling up experience.
Any chance to add more friction
to tempering,
materials, costs, etc.?
Yeah.
We have seen a little bit of this
and heard this feedback ourselves.
It's kind of going in two different ways here.
So the leveling experience
and then how tempering messes with it, right?
The leveling experience,
as people probably have seen,
has been sped up quite a bit, right?
We do want people to be able
to kind of level quickly
and get to the fun of the game
as quickly as possible.
So we do want them,
you know,
we don't want there to be
a ton of friction.
Like, you know,
when we first launched the game,
we had the idea that, like,
getting to level 100 alone
was a big accomplishment, right?
And we've learned that, you know,
players really want to, like,
fulfill their power fantasies,
get to the part where they're actually,
like, incrementally increasing
their character's power
and finding things
they'll use that power against.
And so they enjoy that endgame a lot
and we want to get them there
in a reasonable amount of time.
So that's the part that is like,
you know, hey, you know,
it's fine, level quicker,
it's good, right?
But then the other part is, like,
tempering and kind of the tuning
of the affixes.
We have heard the feedback
and kind of agree with it
that, you know,
the early tempering recipes
are really, really strong, right?
That was by design
when we launched Season 4.
One of the big kind of mandates
to the team
that we felt was important
was we wanted, you know,
before Season 4,
we constantly got the feedback
and knew it was true
that, you know,
your item stats
weren't interesting enough
and didn't matter enough
and weren't very impactful
and just didn't feel good, right?
And so we very much, like,
juice them up to be very strong
and in this new tempering system
that manipulates them,
we made it very strong
so that out the gate,
our goal was
that when you temper an item,
you can really feel the damage.
It wasn't like this incremental,
oh, my damage goes up
in, like, 10 different places
here and there
and now I'm strong.
It was like,
no, this one thing happened
and you felt it
and it was good
and so we're going to,
you know,
try and walk that line.
We're going to probably go
a little more in between here
where, you know,
we do agree that the tempering
is warping the early game experience
too much
to the point that it's like
you pick up an item
and you don't care about the stats
because you just temper something on
and it's, like, way better, right?
So we don't want that
but we do still want them
to feel and be really impactful.
So we have heard the feedback.
I don't remember,
don't think we have huge adjustments
in Season 5 right away
but we are going to be looking
at that leveling process
and streaming and lining that
quite a bit.
We're having time
and actually even talks
about that right now
with various members of the team.
So it will be looked at.
Not tons will change
in Season 5, though.
Awesome.
Question from Razzle Dazzle Daris.
Razzle Dazzle Daris.
It's a long name to log in on.
Did you say we can temper uniques?
Are you open to letting us
imprint affixes?
I had this thought
we can imprint a unique
but only once.
Yeah.
Going back,
that was kind of what I talked about
with the unique section.
We right now know,
I'm not going to say
never in the future,
it's definitely the obvious thing
that we could do,
like, you know,
just add temporary uniques,
of course.
But we want them
to have an identity
that is very different
from legendaries.
One of the concerns with that
is that the more
that you give uniques manipulation,
the more that they just
turn into legendaries
with a different item color
when they drop on the ground.
Right?
Like, they're actually not
different in how they work.
If we were able to manipulate stats,
add stats,
all those things.
So we do want them
to have a different identity
in the game.
So we're not doing it now.
But, you know,
in the future,
we've talked about it.
We're open to the idea.
But we do want to try
this first of, like,
double downing on what makes
a unique unique
and that you build around it
because there's a little bit
of friction
rather than just turning it
into the item
that you want every time.
Yep.
A question from Baric is,
hey, Adam,
or Adams.
I have a question
for the Q&A.
How is the dev team
feeling about the reception
of Season 4?
Is that making them
rethink any plans
for future seasons?
I mean,
I think one thing
that we can most definitely
call out here is, like,
obviously Season 4
has been really great.
Like, we've been hearing
a lot of great feedback
from players.
and, you know,
we're very well aware
of, like, you know,
how everyone's been enjoying it.
I think one huge thing
that's helped with that
as well was, like,
the idea that we had
a PTR for Season 4.
And now we're seeing that
again for Season 5.
So, like, we know,
like, having that moment
where players can actually
jump in, provide feedback,
give us some notes
on specific things
is really beneficial,
especially when we have, like,
new huge features
like what we did
for Season 4,
which was, you know,
obviously tempering,
masterworking,
the pit,
all new Helltides,
there was a ton
of new features.
And then, of course,
with Season 5, you know,
players are now going
to be able to run
through Infernal Horde,
tons of new gear
and legendary aspects
for them.
So it's just, like,
a ton of stuff
that we know
that we can most definitely
take feedback on
and having those moments
has really helped us
with some of those decisions.
Yeah, I would say
on the design team side,
I know, like,
the people on the team
are very happy
with how Season 4 went.
It couldn't have gotten
better, really, in our eyes.
PTR was a huge deal,
helped us a lot,
especially on the balance
and design side,
to, you know,
get things into a better place.
Another thing I may call out
with Season 4 is that,
I don't know how to phrase it,
like,
you know,
there's been a lot of disruption
to the game, right?
And so,
when there's that much disruption
of, like, you know,
we update all the core math
and all the items
and everything,
you know,
it's very difficult
to get things
into a fine-tuned state,
right?
And, you know,
without giving anything away,
we have big updates
coming in the future
with, you know,
expansion and other things.
But one of the things
that we're looking forward
to, I think,
as a team
is when we've kind of
settled down a little bit
on the big disruptions,
like, overall,
you know,
all of itemization
and things like that,
because, you know,
it becomes a lot more difficult
to fine-tune things
like balance
or even on the design side,
like, designs
and making sure
that they work
and that we're, like,
iterating
and upgrading things
versus, you know,
changing things around
in huge ways.
So while we think
it was really successful
and we're happy
with how itemization 2.0
turned out,
the team is looking forward
to, like,
making the things
as they are
and make them work better
and more do fine-tuning work.
And so I think
you can expect
in the future as a player,
you know,
after we've done
some more disruption
and made the game,
like, in a really good place,
we're very happy with it,
which we're really close to now,
I think,
that, you know,
you have tighter class balance,
tighter designs,
tighter roles for things,
and just,
you know,
one of the things
that excites me
and excited the team
about Season 4
was, like,
the tons of quality
of life improvements
and how much of an impact
that makes on players,
which I think we knew,
but it hit home
in Season 4, right?
Like, just the Codex of Power,
how that changed
and how that completely
fixed, you know,
the hoarding of items
and things like that,
I think,
are what really jazz us a lot
because it just makes
that flow experience better,
like the boss ladder,
you know,
being able to reset bosses,
stuff like that,
I think,
is actually really impactful
and good for the longevity
of the game.
So we're excited
to do more things like that.
All right.
Last question
that we have here
is,
it's just Satan's.
Satan's with a Z
and 666 afterwards.
Very good theme.
Very Diablo.
Yeah, very Diablo theme.
It's specifically asking,
what is the seasonal theme?
Are we, like,
holding back any information
right now
regarding that and stuff?
Dan, I don't know
if you want to clarify here
or if you want me to,
you can.
All right.
So we haven't announced
the name for the season yet,
as far as I know,
but the seasonal theme
seems, I guess,
fairly obvious.
You know,
we're going back to hell
and so the theme
is pretty much
returning to hell.
And while the Infernal Hordes
is just one part of that,
the rewards are another part.
And when we have
our season five live stream,
we'll go into
all of the rest of the things
that we have planned
for season five.
Exactly.
Yeah.
We have some additional stuff
to talk about
when we do actually have
our season five live stream.
We're just,
right now,
the biggest focus
for this stream
is for people to hear
about the content
that they're going to be able
to play in PTR
and we want people
to really hone in
and focus in on that
so we can actually
get that feedback
for the team here
and we can make any changes
that we may need to.
So, but yeah,
that is kind of
going to wrap this up
for today for Q&A.
I'm going to lightning round
like a few quick things
because I'm sure chat
will kill me
if I don't call it out.
Sure.
Now we're getting a lot
of questions about loadouts.
It is,
again,
still something
that we are very well aware of
and we still plan on.
It just takes a lot of time.
It's a huge,
huge amount
of overhaul changes
and everything
from that end.
Separately,
we,
this has been coming up a lot,
auction house,
there are currently
no plans right now
for something like that
but we hear you guys.
We,
we,
we feedback,
things like that.
Let us know
but right now
those are,
those are the two big things
that I,
I've been seeing a ton in chat.
I just want to address them
before people go like,
you're not reading chat.
You're,
you're in some like
alternate universe chat
or something like that
but PTR again,
just to remind everyone,
starts next Tuesday.
It runs for one week.
It's on PC Battle.net only.
Please provide feedback
on our forums,
Reddit,
social media,
our community discord,
things like that.
We're always looking around.
We really are,
we really value the feedback
that we get during
these PTR processes
and of course,
at the same time,
we,
patch notes on the blog
are live immediately
after this stream
so check out
diablo4.com
when those do get up.
Next time you guys see us,
next time we stream
is July 18th.
It's the Spirit Born reveal.
Ooh.
That's exciting.
Yeah,
everyone gets to check out
the,
the Spirit Born.
So,
we'll be back live
on stream
on July 18th.
We'll be revealing
the brand new class
coming to Diablo 4
that will be part
of Vessel of Hatred.
So,
we're really excited
about that.
And,
yeah,
I think that wraps it up.
I want to give a huge
shout out to Dan
in Albany.
Yeah,
thank you, Dan.
Enjoy the AC.
Stay cool.
The burning fire
under him
is all I see.
Yeah,
I know,
exactly.
And,
thank you again,
Adam Jackson.
And from everyone
on the Diablo 4 team,
we wish you
a wonderful weekend
and we'll see you
in PTR next week.
Thank you,
everybody.
See you guys.