you
so
Thank you.
You're going to be
Yeah.
mode that we want to make sure you're playing over and over again.
So we really wanted to create a broad set of enemies for you
to fight during this mode.
We've got many demons to choose from in the lexicon
of Diablo's monster families.
But we're also going to see some other foes you might not expect.
There are going to be certain types of enemies, like goatmen,
who have been banished to hell that have now rallied to Mephisto
and fight by his side.
And even some unlucky souls that marched on hell
from the Cathedral of Light have now been revived in hell
and fight against you alongside the demons.
Basically, everything that hell has to throw at you,
we're throwing it at you this season.
The Infernal Hordes has been built with multiplayer in mind,
but multiplayer is not required.
We want to make sure that solo players still
have a very fun experience in the Infernal Hordes.
Now, that said, if you roll in with a party,
you're going to have a lot of fun.
This game mode is going to appear in the Eternal
and in the Seasonal Realm.
And that means that once the season is over,
it's here to stay.
The Infernal Hordes is unlocked at World Tier 3.
So really what you need to do to access it
is earn your way up to World Tier 3
and then complete an Eternal quest line that takes you back
to hell and then unlocks the Infernal Hordes.
For World Tier 1 and 2 players,
we've built out a seasonal progression
that'll help them become more powerful in order
to be able to confront the Infernal Hordes.
First is you can earn reputation,
and that reputation applies to a reputation track that earns
lots of really cool rewards that'll make you more powerful
as you progress onto World Tier 3.
The other thing we've built are micro dungeons called
Hell Breaches that offer a glimpse at the Infernal Hordes
mechanics.
And they give you a chance to learn the mechanics
before you confront the Infernal Hordes at World Tier 3.
The final boss in this season is the Fel Council.
And the Fel Council is some familiar faces
that you might recognize from Diablo II.
These were priests of the Zacarum,
holy men who were corrupted and basically became vessels of hatred
in their own right.
The council members in Diablo II tried to help contain Mephisto
in his soul stone.
And of course, Mephisto being Mephisto,
slowly but surely corrupted them.
And eventually they had soul stones pierced into their hands
and became super powerful.
But eventually you overcame them and sent them to Hell.
Through the course of the story, resummon them.
They've been reborn, slightly new powers,
but the same animosity toward you.
What's interesting about this boss encounter
is there are five council members,
but you're only going to fight three of them at once.
This allows us to then create many different flavors
of the boss fight for the Fel Council.
In fact, it's about 10 variations in all.
And so every time you go into that council fight,
there's a very good chance you're going to have a different fight
than the last time you played it.
We think it's going to offer a lot of replay for players.
What we also introduced during these waves
are opportunities for you to earn ether.
Burning ether is the resource
that you gather during the Infernal Hordes
that you can then spend at the end of the activity.
There's going to be a fixed number of waves
that you have to defeat.
And once you've completed all those waves,
then you'll face the Fel Council,
defeat them, and collect your treasure.
So upon defeating the Fel Council,
the spoils of Hell will spawn.
And then you consume your burning ether
and opening those chests.
Now, the trick is when you are playing through these waves,
that's your opportunity to earn as much ether as you can.
Different events are going to spawn all throughout the waves
around the periphery of the arena.
And it's your job to try and defeat
as many of those events as possible
to try and gather up all the ether you can.
Really skilled players are going to be able
to really maximize that ether
so they get the biggest payout possible
at the end after defeating the Fel Council.
So with this burning ether,
you'll be able to get new uniques,
you'll be able to get new legendaries,
you'll be able to get rare materials,
things you might have scoured the whole of Sanctuary for
in previous seasons or in the base game.
But now we offer it to you here,
down in the depths of Hell.
A lot of these new uniques and legendaries
really build on top of this idea
that they've been forged in Hell.
And so they're going to have unique looks
that you can then make into cosmetics
to apply wherever you like.
They can also have unique VFX and sound effects
to really create the sense
that they were forged in Hell.
One particular one that I enjoy using a lot
are boots.
Boots, you say?
Well, these boots not only have been forged in Hell,
whenever you use a power with a cooldown,
they shoot out a ring of fire
that hits everyone around you.
That's just one sample of the types of powers
that we're exploring.
So death in the Infernal Hordes
is quite a big deal.
You're returning to the Realm of Hatred
where Mephisto was born.
Like, this has to be a big deal.
In the Infernal Hordes,
it's a lot like Nightmare Dungeons.
You only get a fixed number of revives
in order to be able to get to the end of your run.
So at lower difficulties in the Infernal Hordes,
you'll get a number of revives
shared between your party.
But at higher difficulty levels,
the game is going to start taking away those revives.
And that increases the stakes that you have.
If you die too much,
you'll be ejected from the mode.
In the Infernal Hordes,
we've created a lot of new ways
for monsters to ambush the players.
And so I'm pretty stoked to see
how our players respond to these.
The seasonal quest line
and the eternal quest line,
they have lots of little surprises
and twists and turns in them.
And there's even some surprises
we've buried deep within the Infernal Hordes
that hopefully players will have a great time with.
every member or other ones
callers play on board some of our favorite
Dev a hard work plan
of creating besides problems.
We want to give up this fashion...
Adam and Adam...
Welcome to the stream.
Yeah,
we did it.
We took it over.
It's just Adam and Adam show.
Now I don't even have to host.
It feels great.
Yeah.
And for everyone curious in chat, Adam is not going anywhere.
As you all know, there's a ton going on in Diablo.
Yeah, Adam Fletcher isn't going anywhere.
This one, yes.
Adam Jackson.
I deal with this one.
There's a ton going on in Diablo right now.
We've had a ton of live streams.
There's been so much going on, so it's just a lot easier to share the load amongst all
the hosting live streams.
We just finished the Spirit Born live stream, so it's been a little crazy.
And Marcus is here to help out.
So you guys may see Marcus more here hosting some live streams in the future.
But yeah, I'm not disappearing.
Today, you're acting as Colin today.
Exactly.
Today, I get to pretend I'm Colin.
Ooh.
Yeah.
I'm pretty excited about that.
Some big shoes to fill there.
So yeah.
That is absolutely true.
In terms of everything that's been going on in Diablo, we just had our Season of the
Infernal Hordes PTR.
And we've got a lot of learnings.
Yeah.
But we also do have one additional person.
Of course we do.
Mr. Dan Tanguay from Albany, New York.
Dan, welcome to the stream.
Hey.
How's everyone doing?
Doing great.
Good to see you.
See, Dan's in the Cathedral of Light.
We're in the Burning Hell.
Yeah.
It's perfect.
It's hot over here.
Exactly.
It tracks.
Yeah.
Thanks for joining us today, Dan.
And the Season 5 PTR.
Yeah.
We've got a lot of learnings.
This was our second PTR for Diablo 4.
So we have a ton of feedback to get into, but we also have some notes from the community
on the PTR overall and some learning.
So Adam, do you want to walk us through that?
Yeah.
Most definitely.
You know, this is now our second PTR that we had.
We had one for Season 4 and of course one now for Season 5.
And, you know, we've learned a lot from these PTRs.
PTRs are incredibly important.
They're huge.
They're really beneficial for the whole entire team here.
And one thing we heard a lot of feedback, at least from the Season 5 PTR, is obviously
as you're playing through a PTR, it's a non-final thing that you're playing.
It's still very early on.
There are going to be more bugs, more issues just present in the PTR because we are getting
something out there a little bit earlier just so we can get feedback in on it.
But one thing that I think we most definitely heard from the community is, hey, the tools
within PTR at times haven't been the best or the most efficient for players that need
to actually test the content that we actually do have.
And so one thing that we did want to at least address and highlight and acknowledge is that,
you know, we do plan on making the PTR experiences better in the future.
We do plan on equipping more tools for players out there so they're not having to sit there
and grind out, you know, maybe like all the new legendaries or uniques or something like
it.
Especially in like Season 5, for example.
We gave a character copy feature in this one.
And then, of course, we had the boost feature which came back from Season 4.
And when you boosted your character, a new character, you would end up getting some of
the new legendaries or uniques within Season 5.
What happened, though, is that it wasn't all of them.
And then we had players within Season 5 having to actually go out and spend their time that
they probably could be testing other things, like trying to find those items.
And obviously that's like not the most efficient thing to do.
So we do want to, we hear everyone, we acknowledge it, we do want to make the PTR experience better.
So I will say that like in future PTRs, and you'll see this gradually over the next couple
PTRs, it won't be all of a sudden, like things will be completely different.
But I do expect like, and players should expect like, that we will have better tools for them
to properly test as we gradually go through PTRs in the future.
And we appreciate everyone like letting us know, like, we most definitely hear you guys.
And we most definitely want to make that experience better from that.
But PTRs have been great.
Huge thanks to everyone for jumping in and checking it out for sure.
Yeah, definitely. Yeah, that feedback is so important.
So, you know, increasing how great these PTRs are is really, really important.
And I know for the Season 5 PTR, one of the huge features that we had in there was the Infernal Hordes itself.
So for everyone who didn't get a chance to jump into the PTR, Mr. Dan Tanguay, can you kind of walk us through
what the Infernal Hordes is and what players can expect?
Yeah, absolutely. I'll give you all a quick recap.
So, the Infernal Hordes is a wave-based activity with push-your-luck choices in between each of those waves.
So, imagine waves of monsters coming in, lots and lots of monsters, in fact.
And you also have some events, many events that you can also participate in.
Now, in between those waves, you're going to be making what's called the Infernal Offer.
And you're going to pick a boon or a bane, and that's going to change your gameplay for the rest of the run.
So, it allows you to customize what your Infernal run is going to be like.
And so, we probably see right here, yep, we've got an Infernal Offer that comes up.
So, you're going to select one of those, and that will then change, of course, the rest of the run.
Now, when you complete the required number of waves, then you're able to go confront the Fell Council, who you can see here.
And the Fell Council, as you saw from the video that just came on right before this livestream, are former servants, well, actually current servants of Mephisto, that you defeated in Diablo II, and have now returned.
And you must fight them once more.
And once you beat them, you're going to be able to spawn what's called the Spoils of Hell.
And these are chests that contain a lot of great goodies.
And so, with that Burning Aether you've been collecting all through the course of the mode, you're able to choose what kind of Spoils you want.
You've got Spoils of Legendaries and Uniques, and there's some absolutely great new Uniques and Legendaries in Season 5, and you can probably farm about half of them, over half of them, from the Infernal Horts.
You're also able to spawn Spoils of Materials and buy into that, and that will get you Gem Shards, that will get you Angel's Breath, and of course that will get you Master Working Materials, which you absolutely need to complete your items journey.
You can also cash out and get a bunch of gold, which, you know, for those folks who are re-rolling their items in order to Master Work them or to enchant their items, is going to be hugely beneficial.
And then finally, there's a special bonus chest at higher tiers where you can get a guaranteed roll on a greater FX item.
And so, since that's one of the main chases in the, you know, the final steps of the endgame, you know, we wanted to make sure there was an opportunity for players to really, you know, get a little more lucky with it.
So, final thoughts on the Infernal Hordes.
Remember that it unlocks at World Tier 3.
You need an Infernal Compass in order to unlock it.
And there's eight levels of difficulty for it.
And so, yeah, that's a quick recap.
Awesome.
Thanks for walking us through, Dan.
Super excited to jump in and try to grab some of those uniques.
Now, I know, considering the Infernal Hordes was such a big part of PTR, we did have a lot of community feedback with regards to, you know, getting into the mode, you know, some of the pacing.
So, can you walk us through some of those learnings we had based off the PTR feedback?
Oh, absolutely.
So, there was a lot of feedback that came in.
And so much so that we weren't able to address it all.
But we did distill down some big trends and feedback that we were able to tackle.
And so, the first off is that we wanted to improve access to the Infernal Hordes.
So, yeah, it was just too hard to get into the mode regularly to test it.
And folks who wanted to get into it very quickly couldn't get into it either.
So, we've pretty much overhauled access to the Infernal Hordes at this point.
Compasses still exist, but the drop rates on those have been boosted quite a bit.
You know, we want you to earn around four or five compasses an hour so that you can do about four or five runs per hour.
So, you know, you've got, you know, 50% chance to get them from item chests and Helltides unless it's one of those item chests that costs, you know, 250 senders, in which case that's 100% chance.
I mean, you put in the time, we'll just give it to you.
And then, you know, Nightmare Dungeon and Whispers, there's about a 75% chance to get one from a dungeon complete there.
You know, compass tiers at really high levels.
We wanted to make sure drop naturally from high-tiered activities like Nightmare Dungeons and the Pit.
And we've also given you a path to just crafting these outright with the Occultus with Sigil Power and Forgotten Souls.
And then finally, you know, it was a bug that the first compass that dropped from the Eternal Quest was actually a World Tier 3.
And if you were playing World Tier 4, you had to switch back to actually get in the Infernal Hordes, and that didn't feel great.
So we updated that as well.
Moving along, the next big thing that we focused on was combat.
The pacing of combat wasn't hitting our goals.
And, you know, we had done a lot of internal testing on it.
And, you know, folks who weren't as in-game focused gave us a lot of feedback where, you know, oh, this is super intense.
Could we dial it back a little bit?
So we did.
But then we put it out on PTR and clearly all said, hey, no, we want more.
So we're giving you more.
The first thing that we did, though, is we fixed some bugs that actually had a really big impact on the experience.
There was a boss health bug.
Man, that is hard to say.
Boss health bug.
That caused all the bosses to be super tanky.
And at Tier 8, there were some folks who were spending almost an hour's worth of time in the Infernal's Horde.
And that just, that's not what we wanted.
So we fixed those bugs and retuned everything.
So, you know, it's a much tighter experience at this point.
Similarly, there was a bug where difficulty wasn't scaling appropriate in multiplayer.
So we fixed that.
And then some tuning things.
So the pace of many events are pretty much rapid fire at high tiers now, you know.
And so you're going to be spinning a lot of plates in this mode.
The monster spawn rates have also been increased to, you know, really capture that feeling of being overwhelmed.
And then finally, we reduced the wave timer down to 60 seconds, which, you know, just creates a much punchier experience for players.
And, of course, retuned everything.
And then on top of that, we said, you know what, let's just make it easier for players to pick up Burning Aether to increase that pace.
So the pets now pick up the Burning Aether as well.
And that's not all.
Now, of course, you know, we're all playing this for the rewards, right?
And so it was really important for us to improve rewards across the board.
You spend time with the mode, you want to be rewarded appropriately.
And we weren't hitting that mark in the PTR.
So we raised the minimum amount of Burning Aether earned from any single run.
First off, every single source of Aether got boosted by one Aether.
And then we added Aether drops to the Fel Council so that you're also getting, you know, a lot of bang for your buck just by defeating the boss as well.
And that actually scales per tier as well.
Next up, we retuned all the costs of the Spoils of Hell.
So, you know, the greater equipment, that one with the greater affects in it, used to cost 250.
Now it only costs 60.
Similarly, we retuned the Spoils of Equipment and the Spoils of Materials.
So now they only cost 20 Aether apiece.
And then finally, we retuned all the rewards that were inside, you know, the chest as well.
So, you know, at your bare minimum level, when you first start playing the Infernal Hordes and you're not sure exactly how it works,
we still want you to feel rewarded just for the time that you invested.
And so the rewards at that bare minimum feel pretty good now.
But, you know, if you are spending a lot of time with it and you know how to optimize this mode,
we wanted to make sure that, you know, the rewards reflected that too.
So that higher, you know, ceiling of rewards has been raised as well.
So you're playing at tier 8, you are going to get significantly more rewards than you would at tier 1.
Awesome.
Yeah, that's quite a bit.
That's a lot of stuff to change.
I just want to call out.
Dan, your shirt is amazing.
I was going to interrupt, but I didn't want to.
I was talking.
Now I just want that shirt.
And I'm very jealous that I don't actually own that shirt.
So I will message you after the stream to let me know where I can get this shirt.
Yeah, I think someone on the team made it.
So I was like, yeah, I needed a new shirt for the live stream.
That is her art, 100%.
Yes.
Now we know.
Now I know.
And it is totally awesome.
I had to wear it.
So it is Aaron.
I totally know.
Aaron, we will be touching base after the stream.
Yes.
Yeah, Dan, that's a ton of changes.
It sounds like we're really cranking up the intensity for the Infernal Hordes.
Really, really cool to see.
Super excited to jump into it.
So I know for the Infernal Hordes, that's one part of the season that's coming.
But there was a lot that players didn't get to experience in the PTR that will be coming with the season.
So can you kind of share what's going to be new for players coming into Season 5?
Yeah, absolutely.
So the PTR was really focused on features that were on both the Eternal Realm and the Seasonal Realm.
And we have a number of Seasonal exclusive features that you all haven't had a chance to play with yet.
So we're going to tell you about them now.
First up, we've got the Seasonal Progression.
So you're going to see what we call the Reputation System in some footage here in just a second.
And the Reputation System is something that we had in Season 4 and actually earlier in some events.
And we've brought it back here because it serves as a great backbone for the season.
And we've evolved it in some significant ways.
So first off, how you earn reputation is a bit different now.
But it was really important for us in Season 5 to give you more choice in how you wanted to earn your reputation.
So previously in Season 4, you earned reputation through just playing Helltides, as you should,
because we made a lot of improvements to Helltides in Season 4.
But here, we wanted to broaden it out a bit more.
So you earn reputation in Season 5 by just defeating powerful servants of Hell.
Elites, Hellborn, champions, bosses, so on and so forth, right?
And so that gives you a lot more choice to say,
Hey, you know, I can earn reputation in Helltides, or I want to earn it in the Infernal Hordes.
Or honestly, I want to take a break and do a stronghold.
You'll get reputation there too.
Another small tweak that we made that's pretty important is that when you pick up reputation,
you actually get a small boost in XP as well.
So as you're continually filling out your reputation track,
you're starting to level up just a little more quickly than you did before.
Now, another thing that you might have seen are these big green tiles in the reputation system.
And those are seasonal quests.
So we made it very clear that hitting certain tiers of your reputation system now unlock the seasonal quests.
And it actually starts to weave the narrative through the progression a bit more,
which we really like the feel of and we hope to build on in the future.
And then finally, you know, again, it's all about the rewards, right?
So there's lots of great returning rewards in the reputation system.
You're going to be able to earn uniques, specifically class-based uniques.
They're going to help you figure out what you want your build to be early on in the season.
You're also going to be able to get other powerful equipment, big drops of crafting materials.
And of course, at the very end of the reputation track will be a resplendent spark
that you can use to ultimately craft a mythic unique.
Next up, we've got the seasonal quest line.
You know, I was teasing it up a little bit with the reputation system there.
So the season of the Infernal Hordes has a rather unique narrative flow
because we have an eternal quest line that introduces, you know,
a big new feature that takes you back to hell, right?
And so we wanted to make sure that was available to everybody, not just seasonal players.
And that also starts at World Tier 3.
Now, those of you who played the PTR have already seen it.
That's the one that features Locrin helping you to get back to hell
and confront the Infernal Hordes.
But we've developed an additional secondary, well, not really secondary,
an additional seasonal quest line named of Lambs and Wolves,
which we're kind of teasing right here.
And new NPC named Estelle is guiding you to become more powerful
before you join Locrin to journey back to hell.
Now, this one's going to be a little closer in tone to the Iron Wolves quest in Season 4,
but it's going to be a bit more expansive than that.
And like I said, it weaves in and out of the seasonal progression.
So how do they relate to one another?
Well, the seasonal quest line is exclusive to Season 5.
And so you are able to get a really more complete picture of the story
by playing both the seasonal quest line and the eternal quest line.
You can kind of think of the seasonal quest line as almost like a prequel
to you unlocking the Infernal Hordes.
But we also wanted to make sure that our eternal players don't get left out.
This is an eternal mode that we're introducing, after all, with the infernal hordes.
And so, you know, the infernal, or rather the eternal quest line here,
which is named Eyes of the Enemy,
is going to be available for all players and won't go away after the season end.
So it's going to be there forever.
So if you decide sometime down the road that you want to check out the infernal hordes
and say, I don't know, Season 6, you can do that, right?
And so, yeah, that's where we ended up with the quest lines this season.
And then the final thing I want to introduce are the Hellbreach dungeons,
which we've gotten a few teases of before, but we can go into more detail here.
So these are all new micro dungeons to show that Hell has started taking root in Sanctuary.
Now, since the Infernal Hordes is an endgame activity, World Tier 3+,
we wanted to make sure we had some content that targeted our World Tier 1 and 2 players.
And so you go into these, it's going to be a great source of reputation.
It's going to be a great place to get some powerful items.
And it's a pretty cool place to just kind of experience what the gameplay is going to be like down the road.
Now, originally we had kind of patterned these off the Donheim tunnels, you know, if you all remember those.
But, you know, with the introduction of Helltide in Season 4, we had to change it up a little bit
because I don't think that alone would have sufficed.
And so what we did is we pulled in a lot of elements from the Infernal Hordes,
and we're using this as an opportunity to introduce those elements.
So you see right here, we've got a simple Infernal Choice that shows, you know,
that basically says, okay, do I want my boss to be a little simpler or a little more difficult?
And you get to choose.
Hopefully the person playing chose the more difficult one I didn't see.
But you're going to be rewarded a lot more for taking that risk of making the boss more difficult.
And you're going to be earning Burning Aether.
And at the end, there are going to be some spoils that you can spend on.
And like I said, you'll get some really powerful gear that should help you on your journey toward encountering the Infernal Hordes.
So if you want more details on these, I recommend that you check out our blog that came out two days ago.
And yeah, thank you.
Dan, that's awesome.
I got to say, chat got pretty excited when you mentioned Domain Tunnels.
They kind of blew up there.
So definitely a fan favorite.
Everyone remembers the Dopamine Tunnels.
Yeah.
Right, right.
And it's great that there's now like opportunities for players within like World Tier 1 and 2
to actually be able to have other options of leveling up.
And with these new help reaches, it's...
Yeah, it's a good way for people to tease in the new content.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Then you get into those Infernal Hordes in World Tier 3 and off.
Away you go.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's awesome.
Dan, thanks so much for joining us.
As Dan had mentioned, we did publish the Season of the Infernal Hordes blog a little bit earlier this week.
We are going to have patch notes that we'll publish following the stream.
So for any details we reveal across the stream, you can check those out for more information.
Dan's going to join us towards the end of the stream for our Q&A.
So if you have any questions, please drop those in Twitch chat and we'll be pulling them to get into those towards the end of the stream.
So we just touched on a ton of stuff that's coming in Season of the Infernal Hordes itself.
But based off the PTR, we also have a ton of changes coming across Sanctuary.
And to walk us through from the other end of the stream, Mr. Adam Fletcher.
I get to pretend like I'm the person on the panel.
I'm going to pull out my...
You designed and did all of this?
Yeah, exactly.
Put in all the changes.
We have a fantastic design team here.
And I am going to bring in my inner Colin Feiner to talk about some stuff.
But yes, as Marcus mentioned, there's a lot of changes.
A lot of the stuff that we actually did talk about in the blog and some of the stuff that people heard from PTR.
But there have been changes even since PTR.
And we have a few new things in here that we'll also squeak in here as we're talking about it.
But one big topic I know that everyone brought up after PTR and that we even brought up even during our PTR stream was Helltide specifically.
One big topic within Helltide was Baneful Hearts.
If you guys remember back during the PTR stream, we talked about how Season 4, everyone had a plethora of Baneful Hearts.
I mean, it felt like everyone was always carrying about 100 to 150 at any given time.
And you could deposit as many into your heart's desire and still always have that same amount.
We wanted Baneful Hearts to feel a little bit more special.
And so during the PTR, we actually did take the number down in terms of how many you would be able to earn.
We did hear everyone's feedback.
People were like, that feels kind of crappy.
So we most definitely readjusted the drop rate of Baneful Hearts to really kind of close that gap in between Season 4 and Season 5 PTR.
We wanted to make sure that was, you know, it feels better.
Like, you won't have 150 on you at all times most likely, but you still have plenty now to be able to summon the Maiden as well.
So some of the changes that we have coming up for Baneful Hearts and the rates that will help with this
is we're bumping up the drop rates off of chests within Helltide specifically.
Players will also be able to get a guaranteed heart drop off of Helltide Commanders now.
And then one big thing is within world bosses, yeah, we actually have an image of, like,
where you'll be able to now get your heart drop rates guaranteed, is world bosses.
Sometimes world bosses actually do spawn within a Helltide zone.
And we thought it would be kind of cool that, you know, hey, you killed the world boss there
and a Helltide happened to be present in that specific zone where the world boss is.
Now you'll just get a guaranteed three within that world boss kill, which is kind of nice.
That's super cool.
We're also bumping up the drop chance to, like, local events, mastery chests within Helltide,
and, of course, harbingers within it as well.
And then one big change that we're doing within this as well is the blood maiden within world tier 1 and 2
in season 4 and even season 5 PTR, you would have to deposit three hearts,
just like world tier 3 and world tier 4.
We're actually tweaking that down to just 2 for world tier 1 and 2.
So there'll be one less, like, altar pedestal for you to deposit a heart for
to summon the blood maiden within world tier 1 and 2, which should help out with, you know.
It just makes your farming a little bit quicker in the early levels.
Exactly.
And it doesn't feel like you're needing to put in that many for those earlier levels.
That much easier to chain a ton of blood maidens back to back to back.
Exactly.
Yeah.
So next thing we did want to talk about is within Helltides as tortured gifts,
another change for world tier 1 and 2.
There'll be less cinders required to open up the tortured gift chest within world tier 1 and 2,
so it's dropping from 100 to 75 specifically.
And then this is something we talked about in the last stream
where it was, like, really difficult for players to actually kind of go through a Helltide
and complete, you know, a full-on, like, you know,
Tree of Whispers, like, progression line within Helltide.
So now you'll actually be able to earn all 10 Grim Favors within a Helltide for sure
when it's in one subzone and actually deposit that within the Tree of Whispers
and get the Whisper cash out of it.
I know sometimes it would take, like, sometimes two Helltides to actually do it,
or you would have to leave the Helltide and go to a non-Helltide zone
to kind of finish it off and stuff.
And so we wanted to make sure that was more efficient specifically within Helltides.
And then this was a big thing.
Big one.
So, you know, we talked about during the Season 5 PTR stream
that Profane Mindcages were a Season 4 mechanic.
It was only within that.
Well, they were, technically.
Yeah. And so it was removed from Season 5.
Heard the feedback.
And people were like,
wow, we really missed Mindcages.
Bring them back.
What's going on?
So we did bring them back.
And we brought them back in, like, a cooler form.
So now you can actually stack up.
So, one, Profane Mindcages are coming back for Season 5.
You can actually stack these now up to 3x in Season 5.
This is Season 5 only.
So this is only on the Seasonal Realm specifically.
But now stacking up to 3x does actually boost up Monster levels.
Better rewards.
Better energy.
Pretty significant.
Better huge.
Yeah.
So you'll end up, you could knock Monster levels up, you know, 30 levels if you wanted to.
And you will benefit or maybe suffer.
Or suffer quite a lot, yeah.
But it does give players the option now to use that.
And so Profane Mindcages are back and in a kind of a cooler form for Season 5.
Which is really cool.
And we really appreciate the feedback we heard from players regarding Helltides on that.
Next, overall, just general game updates that we do have.
One big thing that we're doing is we are boosting Legendary drop rates off of really pretty much almost like all most content.
Like Helltides, Nightmare Dungeons, Infernal Hordes.
For any monster that is level 100 or higher.
So you'll be able to see and just obtain more Legendaries that way.
Less rares, things like that.
Separately, Enchanting.
One big thing we heard is, you know, people were somewhat, you know, blocked a little bit with Angel's Breath.
And so we did remove Angel's Breath as a cost towards Enchanting.
It's no longer required.
We've actually now kind of just swapped this over to the respective Legendary salvage.
So, for instance, Armour, it would be Coiling Wards, Weapons, Baleful Fragments, and then Jewelry, Abstruse Sigils.
Tongue twister there.
Abstruse Sigils.
But you now have the ability of being able to do Enchanting.
Just note that, of course, gold costs are still associated with Enchanting.
But now it's a little bit, removing a little bit of that friction with the Angel's Breath requirement.
And then this is something that we had talked about beforehand, which is just crowd control.
Overall, within Season 5, it's going to be a lot better.
I know crowd control can be sometimes painful or either knock down.
Yeah, knock down and frozen for a million years and crying and then dying horribly.
And so CC duration has been essentially just pretty much reduced across the board to 1.5 seconds max.
And then one cool feature is you can also spam potions now while you're CC'd.
Really good for people in hardcore or maybe it creates more desperate moments of like, I'm still dying.
No matter what.
But you now have the ability of being able to spam potions specifically if you are CC'd, which is really nice.
Yeah.
You know, we were talking about like charging like...
Bloated Corpse Fiends when they like all stun you and they do the Poisoning AOE.
Exactly.
As a keyboard slammer myself, thank you for...
Yes, exactly.
...for this change.
Next update we have is World Bosses.
So funny enough, this actually fell into Season 5 PTR, but that we forgot to actually put it in Season 5 PTR notes.
And we actually forgot to actually mention it.
We got a lot of reports of people going like, hey, why are World Bosses like tankier and harder to kill?
They actually fight back now.
Wait, what?
I'm not used to this.
Yeah, it's like, what's going on?
So they actually had a feature called Resilience on there.
Essentially, Resilience normalizes damage across like all World content.
So it's like if you...
Shared World content.
So like if a bunch of people are all coming into a World Boss, you should expect to find that the World Bosses will be a little bit more tankier,
a little bit longer in terms of the experience that you're having as you're fighting against them.
And less, you know, like, hey, I blinked and it's gone.
Oh, sweet.
The boss was here for three seconds.
Nice.
Yeah, exactly.
Three.
Mine, they barely even spawn in.
It was actually present in PTR.
And we actually got a lot of people that were going like, hey, I think this is a bug.
And it actually wasn't a bug.
It was just something we forgot to actually mention in the patch notes.
So that is our bad.
But we do want to make sure that everyone's aware that World Bosses now have a feature called Resilience.
And that will end up helping out with those encounters specifically.
Separately for bosses, Pit Boss damage has been reduced pretty much across the board.
And then one big thing that we did want to call out is we got a lot of feedback within, you know, Season 4 and, of course, the PTR for Season 5.
We saw some people address the changes that we were having there.
But Pit Bosses had this tendency within Season 4 to have, like, very sharp damage.
Yeah.
Where it would scale up really hard.
And there were times where you would run into a specific Pit Boss.
And you could potentially just get one shot based off of, like, those.
The shadow boss, like, that would appear.
The extra one's coming.
It would just come, one shot you, and laugh as they left and you died.
Yeah.
So now there is a feature within Season 5 where those Shadow Pit Boss, like, affixes will appear.
And they'll actually leave kind of a stacking debuff onto players now.
So, and it can go up to three times.
And then, obviously, when it gets to the max, you have a very good chance of getting, like, heavily, like, punished for taking up to three debuffs from that end.
And this is really to allow a little bit more flexibility for players, you know, based off of the feedback we heard regarding a lot of the one shots and things like that.
Yeah.
You now have the ability of being able to, you know, take a couple of these debuffs and maybe not, like, completely get punished from that.
It's less about, like, the perfection kind of involved, but more so being a little bit more forgiving in some of those opportunities.
Now, if you are a person that just, like, face tanks things and goes in and immediately takes three debuffs, you're probably still gonna learn that, you know, that damage is still gonna be very sharp with the three debuffs.
So, but it is something to help out in regards to that.
Yeah, to be clear how that debuff works is every time that you get hit with one of those shadow boss mechanics, you'll take the debuff and it increases all of your damage taken.
So, the regular boss is gonna hit you harder and the shadow bosses are gonna hit you harder, too.
Exactly.
So, you know, you just don't want that to ramp up too much because then everything is gonna be more punishing.
Yeah, exactly.
There's a few people already asking about those debuffs in chat, so.
Yeah, it just increases all your damage taken.
So, basically, you know, you get some freebies of getting hit by them.
You really don't want to, but then after that, you gotta watch out because then it's about as hard as Season 4 was.
Exactly.
So, and then another big thing.
So, this was something that was actually not present in the PTR, but it's something that we've heard a lot of feedback about and actually a ton of feedback about.
And this is group play in pits.
In Season 4, the way that it worked was if you were in the pit and you were the party leader and you had three friends that joined along,
you would essentially get through the pit, you would get all the master working materials for yourself, 100% of them,
and then everyone else that joined you would only get about, like, 50%.
And it felt pretty punishing for people to really kind of join up with friends and run through pits.
And we heard a lot of feedback of, like, hey, it'd be great if, like, if I'm just joining my friend, we can all just get, you know, 100% of the pit material rewards.
And so, that is being tweaked for Season 5.
Now, the whole entire party itself will end up receiving 100% of the materials that you end up receiving at the end of the pit.
But, yeah, so we appreciate the feedback.
Thank you guys for letting us know.
And this is something that wasn't in PTR but will be for Season 5.
Next up, we have Endgame Bosses.
So, this is something, of course, we talked about during the PTR.
And we do want to highlight again because I think this is amazing and will save a whole lot of time.
So nice.
You can now resummon Endgame Bosses immediately after you end up killing them.
So, as you're going through the different boss ladders and stuff, you can just reset and the altar will reappear, as you can see in the footage.
And throw in the mats and, bam, again, you're fighting Durial, which is really nice.
No more exiting the dungeon, resetting the dungeon, running back, and then having to do it over again.
This should save up a whole lot of time.
This should help a whole lot with farming as well, specifically for gear.
And you'll be hearing a lot about all this new gear from Adam here in a second.
But there were some additional changes as well to some of the Endgame Bosses that we do have.
Like, for instance, the first one we're going to talk about is the Beast and Ice.
The Beast and Ice, of course, required a sigil to actually summon.
Or to actually create the dungeon to go in to fight the Beast and Ice.
There's no longer a sigil that will be required.
And also, the Beast and Ice is now way closer to the dungeon.
It's going to be a short dungeon crawl similar to the other Endgame Bosses.
So you're not having to, you know, go through a lengthy dungeon just for that.
Yeah, a whole dungeon just to get to the boss.
Yeah.
Likewise, no more sigil dust will be required for summoning the Beast and Ice.
And then, of course, we thought about internal players in this situation.
Because some of them have actually crafted a bunch of sigils.
And now, since sigils are no longer required,
you can still use those leftover sigils to immediately resummon the Beast and Ice
without needing the mats that are still required for the Beast and Ice.
So it's kind of a nice benefit to them.
And then, of course, Varshan also got some updates.
Varshan required a bunch of different body parts.
And now, Varshan just requires malignant hearts.
And, of course, we thought about internal players in this specific instance.
Eternal players can convert their old body parts to hearts
by going to the Alchemist.
That's a magical Alchemist.
Like, yeah.
Wow.
But if you ever need a spare heart, you just go to an Alchemist.
That's just how it works.
Just swap it out.
Yeah, that's just how it works.
But, yeah, some changes coming to that.
And then, separately, endgame bosses.
For endgame bosses, the Boss Ladder bosses,
they won't be dropping rare items anymore.
They're actually just going to drop additional gold.
And, of course, you'll have your opportunity of getting legendaries
and uniques and mythic uniques from them.
But now we just remove the rare item drops from them.
So it takes up, like, less of the drop chances that you could get
in terms of their specific tables.
And then on tormented bosses,
tormented bosses now drop five times as many boss mats as before.
And, of course, all tormented bosses have a better chance
of dropping a mythic unique.
So we are boosting up the mythic unique drop.
There's actually specifics on all this stuff in the patch notes
that people can read afterwards.
And we've also reduced the Stygian stone cost
for the tormented bosses.
Before it was two, and now it's dropping to one.
So it should help out with players wanting to experiment
or try out some of the more difficult endgame bosses
that are available, which are their tormented versions.
And then one big thing that is happening,
and this is something that was kind of mentioned in the blog,
and people will see more specifics in the patch notes.
Experience is changing in terms of, like, the XP bonus
from killing higher-level monsters.
It's no longer capped in, I believe it's now...
Well, it's...
I think it used to be 10 levels higher.
You didn't get more?
It's so capped, shall I say.
It's capped to 30 levels.
That's actually incorrect on the slide.
But it used to be 10 levels.
It's now 30 levels.
And that's across all world tiers.
So if you have...
For example, if you are a level 50 character
and you kill a level 80 monster in Season 4,
you would only get a level 60 experience.
Now you'll get up to that level 80 experience.
So it should help out a lot.
If you are willing to go through more challenging content,
man, you get more XP for it.
So it's really cool.
And it's also really nice
because it plays really well into
the stacking Profane Mine Cages,
which are now available within Helltide
because that can actually also increase
monster level by 30 levels as well.
So it's kind of a cool add-on, you could say, from this.
So yeah.
Pretty sweet.
Yeah.
I think that's it for general game updates.
Holy smokes.
Oh, my God.
That's it.
Holy moly.
Yeah.
As I talked about a bunch.
It's all on the patch notes.
You guys will see the patch notes afterwards.
But yeah.
Yeah.
Really amazing to have all those changes.
Chat was absolutely lighting up
with regards to all the changes to the pit.
And of course, even though we've shown
the boss summoning reset again,
they got just as excited.
Awesome to see.
And we really appreciate everyone's feedback
during PTR and hearing especially
about the Helltide stuff.
And we totally hear you guys.
And we want to make sure that
people got to experience,
still enjoy Helltide to the fullest.
Yeah.
Like, you know what I mean.
Exactly.
No, it's really cool to see those.
I talk too much.
Yeah.
Those profan mind cages coming back.
But yeah, Adam, thank you so much for that.
Yeah.
And now, everyone, I hope you're comfortable
because we've got a ton to go over
with regards to updates, uniques,
some bugs fixes,
a ton of class balance changes.
Who better to walk us through, Mr. Adam Jackson?
Yeah, let's do it.
So we've got a lot to talk about today.
I'll try and go as quickly as possible.
So yeah, firstly, you know,
thank you all for your feedback and comments.
You know, we got a lot of class-related feedback
on the PTR, a lot of balance feedback,
a lot of just how it feels to play things.
And we actually reacted pretty heavily
and did a lot of changes
between PTR and Season 5 launch,
some of which I think some people know
and some things are going to be new for you today.
So really, yeah,
we have a lot of things that changed.
In many ways, honestly,
it's going to feel like almost
from a balance perspective
and kind of what your class can do in your journey,
it's going to feel almost like a very different game
compared to what you experienced on the PTR.
I'm going to go through a lot of like
the systemic reasons why
and then some specific things
that we did to every class
as well as, of course,
updating all of our uniques
and kind of the impact
that you can expect from that.
So lots to talk about.
So first, we're going to be talking about bug fixes.
We've got quite a few to go through
that I think are pretty notable.
Again, we're going to be doing
the class balance updates after that
and then the unique changes.
So those will be the three things
I'm going to be covering today.
So firstly, as usual,
you know we're going to be publishing
the patch notes right after this
so you can read all of them.
I'm not going to cover everything today
but just some of the more notable ones.
So first is one on the Necromancer
that we've heard about for a while now.
It's Shielding Storm.
This is a legendary
that when your Bone Storm damages enemies
you get a barrier equal to your max life.
It used to be based on your base life
instead of your max life
and now we finally fixed that.
To be clear, this is a pretty huge buff.
We may have to reevaluate the power of this
a little later
but we're going to see how it goes.
But now that barrier
is going to be very significant
as you're hitting enemies with this aspect.
Next we've got a couple on the Barbarian.
The first one is the Twister Glyph.
This is a Paragon Node Glyph.
It wasn't properly giving you
bonus multiplicative damage
when casting Dust Doubles.
So Dust Doubles builds
will be a little bit stronger.
We also fixed an issue
with the Tempering Earthquake duration.
Beforehand there was a bug
where it was actually lowering
the DPS of Earthquake
because it would increase the duration
and then your DPS would go down.
So we fixed that.
So it's now actually
just going to make you hit harder.
Next one,
I'm going to call out
one of our content creators,
Woody Joe, here.
This is why we have PTR.
He found a neat little oversight
that we had
with a passive called Trick Attacks.
And I'm actually going to go over this
in a little bit of detail
because the specs will be coming a little later.
Rank 39 out of 3 seems completely wrong.
Yeah, 39 ranks.
Nothing to see here.
So offensive passive is pretty good.
So a little bit of background to this.
Basically we changed
how this passive Trick Attacks,
what it does.
It went from something
that was more utility-based
where it was around CC
and we turned it into damage.
But we didn't update under the hood
for tempering
and where it can appear
from a utility
to a damage recipe
of where it would show up.
And so it was appearing on utility
which is a lot more
common than damage
and then you could get it
to silly ranks like this.
So to fix this,
right now,
or on the PTR I should say,
it was on this recipe
called Alchemist Control
where it was with
Chilling Weight and Shadow Crash
which are also like CC-based passives.
For Season 5 launch,
we're actually going to be
disabling this recipe from dropping.
You won't be able to see it
for a patch
while we fix this bug.
And what we're going to do
is once we re-enable
the Alchemist Control recipe
to drop,
Trick Attacks won't be on here anymore.
What we're actually going to be doing
is we're going to be taking Flurry Size
from another recipe
called Rogue Innovation here.
We're going to be moving Flurry Size
which is more of a utility-based thing
and moving that over
to Alchemist Control
and then just removing Trick Attacks
from Alchemist Control.
So the net effect of this
will be that
now both recipes will have,
or yeah,
both Temporary recipes
will have three different options
of what you can have there.
And Rogue Innovation
will actually have a little bit
of a buff here too
because instead of having
four things to, you know,
roll for your Tempers,
we're only going to have three.
So it'll be a little bit easier
to get what you want.
Next, we're going to be talking about
some generic class balance updates.
So kind of to set you up,
a high-level theme
that we're going to see
in our feedback from PTR
was Barbarians are really, really good
and oh, every other class
is kind of a little bit weak
it feels like
compared to Barbarians.
So we did a lot of things
to address this.
So first I want to go into detail
a little bit of how we feel
about Barbarians
and where they're at
and what we want to do.
We feel like one of the bigger reasons
why Barbarians are so strong
is that they kind of have
two class mechanics
compared to other classes, right?
They have the expertise system
which is like a normal class mechanic
where, you know,
they have this fantasy
of leveling up their weapons
and then they get bonuses
but then they also get
more item slots
compared to other classes
so they get more access
to more legendary powers.
As far as how we tackle this
we don't want our only solution
to be the nerf Barbarians, right?
Like a common thing
that we hear is like
hey, they have more item slots
maybe you should just get rid
of the item slots
so that everybody has parity, right?
Like that is a way
to make parity
but, you know,
it takes away from their theme
of being a master of weapons
and it's not very fun.
So that's not the only thing
that we want to do
in this situation.
The other thing is
that we want to keep
their class identity, right?
Another common suggestion
we hear is
well, just give all the other classes
more item slots
so that they're the same
as Barbarian, right?
And similarly,
kind of like how
Necromancers have minions
we don't want to give
every class minions
just because, you know,
they don't have access
to the cool thing
that Necromancers do.
We don't want to just give
every class, you know,
more slots
so that they're exactly
the same as Barbarian.
We want to really try
and keep what makes them
feel special
as a special thing
and find other ways
to kind of bring parity
to the classes.
So here's kind of
our strategy
of what we're thinking
of with Barbarians.
We have a few different things
that we're going to be doing.
One is we're actually
going to be adjusting
how much damage
all the classes get
from their core stat
and this is going to bring
other classes up
to the level of Barbarian.
I'm going to be going
over that in a little bit.
We are going to be
reducing the power of Barbarians
as part of our solution
but again,
I want to point out
it's not the only thing
that we want to do
and then we also want
to target the other
class mechanics
and really bring them
up to the level
of the Barbarian
effectively having two
and making the other
classes feel cool
in the way that makes
them thematic and awesome.
We already actually
experimented with this
in season four.
This was an intentional
thing that we did
and we wanted to see
how it went
with the Necromancer.
If you remember,
we buffed minions
very heavily
and we also buffed
the Book of the Dead,
their class mechanic,
very heavily.
Not just numbers
but also in the
cool factor,
right?
You have mechanics
like your minions
can throw bone spears
or your golem
can do bone spikes
everywhere and make
enemies vulnerable.
We want to do
this kind of treatment
to the other
class mechanics.
Just to be clear,
we're going to be
probably doing this
after the Vessel
of Hatred expansion
launches,
so it'll be a little bit.
So we are doing
some things in the
meantime to catch them up
but you can expect
in the future
we're going to be doing
kind of a big overhaul
to the other classes
similarly to the
Book of the Dead
and so their cool factor
and their power level
is going to be going up.
So let's talk about
that core stat update
that I talked about
previously.
So basically what
we're doing here
is we're going to be
changing the amount
of damage that every
class gets from
their core stat.
So if you didn't know
on live right now
when you log into
the game you get
about 1% more damage
per 10 stat
of your class.
So as an example
you know the
I don't know
pick one,
the Sorceress
you know with
Intelligence you would
have 10 int
and then you would
get 1% more damage.
If you had 100 int
you'd have 10% more
damage and so on.
So now it's going
to actually depend
on the class
what that ratio is
of how much damage
you get per your
core stat.
So the Barbarian
is going to be
staying exactly the
same, 1% more damage
per 10 strength.
The Rogue is going
to get a little bit
of a buff here
because they do have
a little bit more
slots compared to
other classes
so they're going to
be getting 1% more
damage per 9 decks
and then the other
3 classes, the
Sorceress, Druid,
and Necromancer
are going to be getting
1% more damage
per 8 core stat.
So without doing
a lot of math
the TLDR here
is Barbarians
are staying the same
Rogues are going
to get a bit of a
bump, a bit of a
buff, and the other
3 classes are going
to get even more
damage.
So as you get
that core stat
which you get
very commonly
in Gear and Paragon
and other places
you're just going
to be doing more
damage.
It's just a passive
way that we're
going to be catching
up the classes
stat-wise.
So next let's move
on to kind of
our class updates.
So I'm going to be
going through all
the different classes
and talking about
kind of what our
updates are going
to be for them.
Some of the things
you can expect
that are different
from PTR to launch.
So Barbarian
you know currently
Barbarians in addition
to having more
item slots
have some of the
best key passives
in the game
like in Season 4
and on live.
One of the very
main ways that we're
targeting bringing
them down is
reducing the power
level so that really
their key passes
are comparable to
other classes.
We on the team
felt like you know
they already have
all these other
things that are
really strong going
for them.
They don't need
like overly
stated way
powerful key passives
that do like you
know over 100%
multiplicative damage
when the other
classes are doing
way less.
So you did see
that on the PTR.
We did see a lot
of feedback on like
why are we bringing
down Walking Arsenal
to have parity
when you know
it wasn't even
really meta
compared to the
other key passives
and I just kind of
wanted to bring
some light to this
of how we think
about it.
The reason why
we brought
Walking Arsenal
to be level
with the other
ones when we
brought them
to be equal
to other classes
is that you
know we want
all the key
passes on
Barbarian to
have parity
with each
other.
If we just
brought down
the other
key passives
that were way
over performing
and didn't bring
Walking Arsenal
down to be even
with them
then really
Walking Arsenal
is just going
to be the best
mandatory pick
and every
Barbarian build
is going to
have to interact
with this system
and we really
wanted them to
be equal with
each other
so that you
know there's
actually a choice
when you get
to your key
passive of which
one to take.
So I just
wanted to clarify
that of you
know what our
thinking was there.
But you know
it's not all
doom and gloom
for Barbarians
you know we
did hear feedback
of like man
it really sucks
you know I
understand that
they're being
brought down
and it's fair
but you know
we want to
have some
things to look
forward to.
So we did
introduce a number
of buffs coming
in between PTR
and live so that
you have some
things to look
forward to
and new build
paths or your
you know
underperforming
builds are not
being brought
down as well.
So I'm going
to give a couple
of examples here.
One is Hammer
of the Ancients.
We increased
its damage baseline
by 10%
and we also
adjusted the
of Ancestral
Force Legendary.
One of the
troubling things
that this build
has problems
with is like
single target
damage against
bosses and
things.
You know it
does really
good in AOE
and brings down
enemies but
it's single
targets a little
bit lacking.
So we're
upgrading this
legendary power
so now it's
going to be
doing more
damage against
bosses so it'll
kind of help
you with that
single target
issue.
Another one is
Upheaval.
Upheaval builds
can rejoice and
also a little bit
of a preview of
kind of how we're
changing uniques
which I'll be going
over a lot more
later.
We're increasing
upheaval damage
by about 15%
and we also
rounded out
Hellhammer now.
It's quite a bit
more powerful.
I can point out
a bunch of things
here of how it's
better but you
can see it gives
more skill ranks
of Upheaval
compared to before.
The damage of
its burning on
the ground just
baseline went up.
It also has
scaling on the
burning damage.
So before the
burning damage
wasn't really a
meaningful part of
the unique.
One of the things
you're going to see
with uniques across
the board is that
they're going to be
a lot more about
the thematic of
what the unique is
and that's where
their power is going
to be.
So here the
burning ground
actually will scale
with your strength
at a pretty
significant degree.
So it'll actually
be doing meaningful
damage hopefully.
You can also see
its inherent affix
now is damage
to burning enemies
instead of
overpower damage.
So it's going with
that theme of
Hellhammer burning
the ground.
It's also giving you
skill ranks of
wall up, a passive
so that's more
multiplicative damage.
You also get
Upheaval size.
So now your burning
ground and your
upheaval is going to
be bigger.
So there's just all
kinds of new things
going on.
It's going to be a lot
cooler, a lot more
powerful, and hopefully
a lot more fun.
Hellhammer looks
absolutely insane.
Yeah.
300 strength also by
the way.
No big deal.
300 strength no big
deal.
360 strength.
No big deal.
It's going to be
pretty good.
So next, the
sorceress.
We got a whole lot
of feedback that
the sorceress isn't
powerful enough
compared to other
classes.
We got so much.
I'm going to stop
us right here.
We got so much
feedback about the
sorceress.
Just a little bit.
And the druid.
And the necromancer.
I will just note,
we hear you guys.
We absolutely do.
Okay, now you may
continue.
So, for the
sorceress specifically,
we heard feedback that
they're not powerful
enough.
So we did quite a few
things to address it.
Firstly, they've got a
lot of large buffs to
their uniques.
I would say even more
than other classes.
Your uniques are going
to feel really good is
the hope, and I think
we've hit it.
And I'll be going over
some of them a little
bit later.
We also buffed all of
their core and mastery
skills by about 15 to
20%.
So just baseline.
Remember, this is in
addition to the core
stat buff.
All of your core and
mastery skills are also
getting buffed baseline
by a pretty significant
degree.
So you're just going to
hit harder.
We also did multiple
defensive buffs.
You know, we heard a
lot of feedback that
they have trouble
surviving in situations
that the other classes
could kind of get away
with.
These are some examples.
We did more than this.
But ice armor, your
base shield amount is
going up from 40% to
56% of your max life.
Snow Veiled aspect.
This one was updated
from PTR to launch.
So on PTR, it was that
your ice armor gave you
unstoppable and gave you
armor.
And on launch, you're
still going to get
unstoppable, but you're
going to get damage
reduction, which, you
know, anyone who knows
how the defenses within
this game work is way
more significant than
just getting armor.
Yeah.
When you hit that armor
cap, it's kind of like
Yeah, you just want to
gobble up DR like
Pac-Man.
As much as you can get,
the more the better,
and this is going to
give you.
Yeah, the DR is going
to be huge.
Very big.
Also, we did multiple
buffs to the Paragon
board.
Again, this is not
covering everything, but
one of the things is that
we put a lot of caps to
make sure that some
Paragon oses just didn't
go out of control compared
to everything else, but
we heard feedback that
those caps were a little
bit too punishing, so we
increased them.
An example here is
Burning Instinct, where
on PTR, it capped at
40% more multiplicative
damage, and we increased
that up to 80%.
So now your Burning
damage, that's based on
your crit strike multiplier,
multiplier is going to be
going up.
Your total amount is
going to go up, but
then also the rate that
you get it.
It used to be 1% per 50
int, now it's 1% per 20
int.
So you'll be getting
more efficient bane for
your buck for your int,
and a total cap that's
much higher.
So Druid, similar to
Sorceress, surprise,
surprise, got a lot of
feedback that it's not
powerful enough compared
to the Barbarian or
other classes.
So we've got a lot of
multiple quality of life
and damage buffs coming
in.
Again, these are just some
examples.
Also, you've got to
remember the Uniques
are going to be coming
in as well.
Boulder damage went up.
We increased the damage
across the board of their
core skills mostly, and
we missed Boulder, so
we're increasing their
damage a bit.
We also got a lot of
feedback that we came
out with this really cool
Unique for Cataclysm that
made the Lightning Bolts
smart and target enemies,
and a lot of people were
like, hey, why does it
have to get a Unique to
make my skill be smart?
And we agreed, so we
just made the skill smart
baseline.
So now those Lightning
Bolts from the Ultimate
will just target enemies.
Perfect Storm, the Storm
key passive is getting
its damage boosted from
30 to 40%.
Seismic Shift, this was
an aspect that we think
is really cool where your
Earth Spike kind of goes
in a line and does a
bunch of Earth Spikes.
It used to have a Kiss
Curse mechanic, and it no
longer does.
So before, it used to
give you this big bonus of
way more resource reduction
gen and more damage on it,
but it added a cooldown,
and now it just doesn't
add a cooldown, so you can
spam it and cast a bunch of
Earth Spikes everywhere.
It should be a lot more
fun.
Also, similar to the
Sorceress, we're buffing
their little bonus cap on
their Legendary Paragon
nodes.
So an example here, you
know, they went from 40%
to 60%, so you've got
Thunderstruck, Earthen
Devastation, and Survival
Instincts.
We've got a little visual
there at the bottom node,
but you can see that that
top end of the damage is
now 60%, so it's going to
be better than PTR.
Also, we came out with that
new Unique I mentioned for
Cataclysm.
It used to be on the gloves
on PTR, which a lot of
people, which we agreed
with, you know, it kind of
felt bad that, you know,
you've got the two Storm
related Uniques on the same
slot, you can't take them
together.
It was competing with
Unsun Aesthetics Wraps.
This was the Lightning
Storm Unique.
But now it's going to be on
the ring slot, so now you
can take them both together,
so they're not competing
with each other anymore.
Next is the Rogue.
So, to be frank, the Rogue
is, we feel like it's in a
pretty good spot, so we
didn't do as many changes
compared to other classes.
We did still do a few that
I'll mention today, but
they got the least changes.
The first one is Flurry.
So, as you know, if you
played the PTR, Flurry got
some pretty dramatic
updates, right?
Both of their enhancement
and both of their choices
that you could pick on the
base skill got changed and
made a lot better.
We saw that, you know, a
lot of the output of Flurry
was related to doing the
mechanics that the
enhancement and the advanced
Flurry were requiring you
to do, like casting it a
bunch of times in a row and
stuff like that.
And we wanted to move some
of that damage from those
enhancements and things into
the base skill.
So, the enhancement and the
advanced force are going to
be pretty potent, but we
lower their damage and
instead just juice the base
skill even more.
And what this is going to
mean is really just that
you're going to be more
consistently doing that
damage and you're going to
be less reliant on doing
the stacking mechanics to
get it.
Next, Windforce.
You know, this one has had
a troubled history of just
trying to find ways to make
it really good and useful.
Instead of knocking back
enemies when it procs, it's
going to knock them down
now.
So, you no longer have to
worry about knocking enemies
out of your CC, you know, or
you want them to be grouped
up next to you and then
you're just knocking one of
them or a few of them away.
Now they're just going to go
in place.
We have a before and after
here.
Again, a little preview of
what we're doing with our
uniques.
But, yeah, Windforce, you
can see some of the things
here as a preview is going to
give you move speed baseline,
which is pretty interesting
as a stat on a bow.
You've got chance for double
projectiles for your barrage.
You've got a couple passive
upgrades there.
And then, as you can see, the
damage went up, but also now
it knocks down enemies
instead of knocks them back.
Last but not least, the
Necromancer.
We've been hearing a lot of
feedback that blood Necromancer
players are a little sad.
They just aren't really
catching up to the other
versions of Necromancer.
So, we've buffed up a bunch
of their tempering recipes
and the damage on them.
We're also buffing their
legendary paragon nodes.
Here's some here that we did.
Bloodbath.
This one just makes your
overpower damage go up.
It's being doubled from 35%
to 70%, so that's pretty
meaty.
Blood begets blood.
That damage bonus when you're
picking up blood orbs is
being doubled and the
maximum amount is being
doubled.
So, you're getting more per
stack and you need less
stacks to get to your max
damage.
So, pretty good there.
And then last but not least
here, Lucky Hit.
We've heard a lot of
feedback from Necromancer
players that, you know,
they kind of rely a lot on
the Miasma corpse explosion
to get their Lucky Hit
procs off and that their
other skills don't really
compete and so they can't
really have fun with
Lucky Hit based builds,
you know, more generally.
So, we just buffed Lucky
Hit on a bunch of
different skills so you can
see there what all the
numbers are.
Again, those will be on the
patch notes, but really
they're just going to be
Lucky Hit hitting more
often and getting cool
procs more.
Alright, so next, let's
talk about Uniques a little
bit, right?
I'm super excited about
this.
Yeah, so, as we promised,
you know, in the PTR stream,
you know, we said that, you
know, we have this kind of
different philosophy when it
comes to Uniques and we
went into detail there and
we updated our Uniques
coming into Season 5 but we
didn't update all of our
existing Uniques in the
game yet.
So, we've done that pass now,
we've updated nearly every
Unique in the game and I'm
going to do a little bit of a
recap of kind of how we
thought and then giving you
some examples of what we
did.
So, these updates are fairly
dramatic.
They're going to be showing
you three from each class as
well as three generic ones to
give you a really meaty idea of
the different categories and
ways that we thought of
updating Uniques and kind of,
you know, what you can expect
for your builds.
Yeah, and I know, and
Marcus is going to remind us
about this at the end as well.
Oh, you'll be hearing it a
lot.
Yeah, but I will say we are
showing three here for every
class and three generic ones
but every single Unique is
actually in the patch notes
and we have a before and
after in the patch notes so
you guys will have easy access
and you can see.
You can easily compare the two
and see what was the
difference.
So, after the stream you'll
be able to compare and so
we're just only covering a
small amount here.
We'll see everything.
Just a little sample
serving.
The patch notes are absolutely
massive so you'll have a lot
to have lots of snack on
there.
So, yeah.
So, one of the things is your
general power level of
Unique Effects is up and by
Unique Effects I want to be
clear.
That is like the thing at the
bottom that is like your,
you know, deals 40 to 60%
more multiplicative damage or
whatever.
That number is going to be up
on the higher end.
So, instead of 40 to 60, you
know, it'll be 40 to 80 or
40 to 90 or 40 to whatever,
right?
So, that power level is just
going to be generally up almost
across the board.
And then really what we
targeted for these updates is
the stats on the Uniques.
So, the stats are going to
pretty much break every rule
that we had in the game
before when it comes to
being a cool item.
So, some things that you're
going to see, and I think I
got an example of most of,
if not all of these, but
you're going to see Uniques
that have different inherents
compared to other stats.
So, you know, your boot
inherent, you know, could be
something that's not even
related to boots or movement
anymore.
It could be something else.
Or sometimes we add more
inherent stats.
So, something that didn't
exist before, you know, some
items can have two inherents
instead of just one, which is
a pretty big difference.
We have a lot more that have
stats that break normal slot
rules.
So, you know, things like
movement speed on bows or
cooldown reduction on weapons,
stuff like that.
Uniques also can now have
tempering affixes, right?
None of them really did this
in Season 4, but now that
tempering's in the game and
Uniques have to compete with
these really great tempered
items, Uniques can have that
too.
They can also have much higher
potential stat values compared
to normal items.
So, you know, if a normal item
has 20 to 40% more damage, a
Unique can be like, you know,
1 to 300% more damage or
whatever, right?
And we even do this with the
tempered affixes.
So, Unique can have juiced up
versions of tempered affixes that
make them solve those problems
much quicker.
Also, we've introduced a lot of
stats that really have powerful
effects on them.
Sometimes even a single stat on
a Unique can have the impact
that a legendary power normally
would on an item as far as what
it does to a build.
And we'll have a couple
examples of that where, like, a
stat on an item is actually
giving you a new effect that
didn't exist before that you
could do.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
So, again, we're going to be
going through three examples
per class and three generics.
And I'm going to just try and
quickly go through and kind of
point out some of the key
things that are kind of neat
about the items.
So, we're going to shotgun this
a little bit.
And, yeah, you're going to see
some cool items.
So, let's get to it.
Yeah.
So, first, Penitent Greaves.
This is a generic Unique.
You can see here, this one now
has two inherents as opposed
to one.
Another thing that you can
notice is that normally,
you know, the inherent, the
evaded grants more move
speed is only for one second.
And this one is not only has
two inherents, but it's for
two seconds.
So, you'll evade and, like,
you know, boost around that
crazy sonic speed for a
couple seconds, which is
pretty neat.
And now you can run through
enemies while you do it.
We've also got some neat
stats there, like crit chance
against chilled enemies and
chilled potency there that are
new to the game.
Here, Fists of Fate.
This one a lot of people saw
a little bit early and they
were very happy about.
So, one thing I think that's
kind of cool is that with
our uniques, we're really
trying to, like, double and
triple down on the fantasy of
the item.
So, you know, something's about
cold or something here, like
this, the Fate is about, like,
RNG to the max.
So, we're really going hard on,
like, what the theme is.
So, here you can see, like,
your attack speed can go from
0.1 to 0.7.
And everything on it is, like,
has a huge range of what you
can roll.
So, like, a greater affixed
Fists of Fate could be, like,
a best-in-slot item for a lot
of builds.
The lucky hit chance on this.
Yes, this is the one that
people point out that we...
It's just crazy.
I talked with one of the
people on our team.
I want to shout out Alex on
our team who did a lot of
this work.
And we had a choice here.
And we're like, are we going
to go crazy or go
conservative?
I was like, you know, let's
just go crazy.
Like, this might be insane.
It might actually be best in
slot-in-break stuff, but it's
really cool.
So, yeah, greater affixed
Fists of Fate there is going
to be really cool.
Next, the grandfather.
Mythic unique example here.
You know, a lot of people
had issues with the ignored
durability loss, you know,
where you would, like,
Masterwork hit that or
something, and then you're
not getting anything.
We just moved that into be a,
you know, a baseline inherent
affix now, so you don't have
to worry about that, and then
replaced it with something
useful with a max resource.
And I will note, like,
even in Season 4, because
that durability loss was kind
of...
was actually a hidden
stat item.
Sometimes, when you found a
greater affixed version of a
grandfather, it would
actually apply to that.
That is now...
Yeah, that's all gone.
It's just...
Inherence can't be greater,
which is something that we
thought of a lot with this.
Yeah, so now let's go into
the classes.
Barbarian.
This is Battle Trance.
This one exists already on
live.
Probably the two big things
here.
One is, you know, you have
two different passives now
that you get.
A lot of times we're adding
skill ranks to passives,
because that's a way to add
multiplicative damage, or
just buffs to really cool
effects on a unique, the
other stats.
The other thing to point out
here is the actual effect.
Before, it was giving you
increased attack speed to all
of your other skills when you
had frenzy stacks.
Now you're going to be getting
damage and attack speed.
You know, we heard a lot of
feedback from players that
they would hit attack speed
cap, and then this unique
wasn't really doing very much
for them.
So now you're also just going
to get damage in addition to
making it easier to hit that
cap for your other skills.
So it's just, you know, more
stats, stronger.
Next, Reign of the Ravenous.
A couple things here.
One is it's giving you skill
ranks of Rend, which is
pretty significant.
And remember, that 2 to 3
might not seem so significant,
but when you greater affix that
and then masterwork it, like,
your potential of more damage
on this goes up very
significantly.
We're also giving you skill
ranks of brawling skills still.
The thing to point out here is
your Rend's duration, this will
also just increase the
throughput damage of it.
It has been doubled, so that's
just more damage on Rend in
addition to the skill ranks.
And then also at the bottom,
a small little detail, but
before, you could only apply
that special effect of your
brawling skills applying your
Rend's bleed every 4 seconds,
and now it's every second.
So now if you're able to spam
brawling skills, you're just
going to be applying Rend
bleeds to enemies and, you
know, stronger Rend bleeds
like crazy.
So it's a pretty big power
boost.
Next, the Fields of Crimson.
The thing that we really want
to call out here, I mean,
there's a lot of things that
are kind of unique and
different, but is that one
kind of rule that we had with
item stats that we're now
changing and breaking is we
never really buffed the things
like enhancements or like
the AB, like the different
choice upgrades that you
could do for a skill.
This one actually buffs
enhanced ruptures explosion
size.
So, you know, normally when
you rupture an enemy, it does
that explosion.
This will make that explosion
be way bigger.
So it's kind of a neat way
that we can manipulate
player power via stats.
Next, let's move on to the
Sorceress.
So the Staff of Endless Rage,
we actually have a combo
here that we're going to show
a little video of before and
after with this.
Fireball builds.
The Staff now does some,
and the gloves would be
doing some unique things to
Fireballs.
One is Butt Plus Fireball
Projectile Speed.
So this is actually going to
make your Fireballs fly
through the air faster or
bounce quicker.
And so you'll be able to get
through them and they'll,
you know, finish their path
faster.
You've got the Temporing
Recipe now so it doesn't
compete with your chance to
cast twice.
And you can see there it goes
up to 75% just on that one
stat.
So it basically almost solves
it for you by itself, which
is pretty huge.
You've got some massive skill
ranks to Fireball.
So now, again, way more
multiplicative damage than
before.
And then, you know, you see
at the bottom that the upper
end of that damage is going
up per the same as most of
our Uniques.
And next is combos with the
Gloves of the Illuminator.
A couple things to kind of
gloat on here is the Fireball
Attack Speed is going up by a
much bigger amount than other
classes or than normal Attack
Speed.
Sorry, on other slots.
Also, you get Mana when
Fireball explodes.
I played with this build and I
think it was Season 1 and I
constantly ran into Mana
issues because you always want
to spam this as much as you
can.
So when you think of this
stat, you know, you can
greater this.
You can masterwork this.
And you kind of combine this
with the Attack Speed here and
then you combine it with the
Projectile Speed.
Yeah, and you get a lot more
Fireballs.
Remember, it's every time that
it explodes, which when it
bounces, it's exploding.
Yeah.
And when you're splitting and
getting more from multiple
projectiles, you're getting more
bounce explosions.
So it's giving you a resource
engine.
Yeah, you're essentially a
Fireball machine gun.
Yeah, so we've got a little
bit of a Season 4 to Season 5
comparison here of what it
looks like.
A little video.
So in Season 4, you can see,
you know, every third cast gives
you three.
But Season 5, you're going to
randomly get three and then
sometimes even more when it
combines with the double
projectile bonus.
So you can actually really fill up
your screen with Fireballs
everywhere.
And every one of those
bounces is giving you mana
back to cast more.
That's ludicrous.
So it's pretty cool.
It's its own little engine.
Next, we've got Blue Rose.
Probably the cool thing to
point out here is there's
a chance for Ice Spikes to
explode twice.
So this is also something that
we haven't really done where
we have these, we call them
subpowers internally, but,
you know, these things like
Dust Devils or Ice Spikes
that are like powers that
generate when you cast a skill
that are usually through
Legendaries or Uniques.
We generally don't manipulate
them too heavily like this,
but we're going to be
experimenting more with that
in unique stat affixes.
So here, you know, your Ice
Spikes can actually like
double proc, so they get,
you know, double explosions
and then any other things
that would proc off that
would be doubled, which is
pretty neat.
Next, let's move on to the
Druid.
So Waxing Gibbous, this is
the Shred Druid unique.
So what we did here that I want
to point out, you know, in
addition to the fact that
you're getting a bunch of
skill ranks to Shred and
Toxic's Claws, which is a
bunch more multiplicative
damage, so power level is
going up significantly, is
Blood Howl grants stealth
for a few seconds.
So what's really cool about
this is, you know, we
basically added a new
mechanic via a simple item
stat in this unique, and it
combines with the unique
effect, right?
So before on live, you know,
you kill enemies with
Shred, you go into stealth,
and then you come out and
you guarantee crit.
So as you're killing enemies
over and over, you're just
critting constantly as you go
in and out of stealth.
But you couldn't really do
that against bosses, and you
had no other ways to get
into stealth.
But now we've created an
alternative way where if you
cast Blood Howl or get the
Blood Howl effect in other
ways, you'll go into stealth
and get this proc, and now
you can get this, you know,
against single bosses or in
situations you couldn't
before.
So we've given you a
potential way to create your
own engine, which is pretty
neat to get those infinite
crits.
Next, Great Staff of the
Crone.
I believe we showed this one
earlier to people, but I
just wanted to point out, you
know, what was special about
this.
Stormstrike, chaining to
additional targets, you know,
things like this.
Again, it's a single stat that
does something that kind of
really changes how the
unique works, right?
You're going to get all the
different procs and different
effects by chaining to more
enemies more often.
You can also see here that the
upper end of that damage that
you could get is going up from
150% to 200, so it's just
better.
And last but not least, we've
got Storm's Companion.
This one, I again, wanted to
highlight another new thing that
we're doing, and I want to
call it here, is the Lucky Hit
Chance for the Pack Leader
Spirit Boon.
So normally, we never really
manipulate class mechanics, but
here, you know, this Pack
Leader, this isn't like a
passive or thing in the
skill tree.
This isn't the Spirit Boon,
your class mechanic, and this
increases that Lucky Hit
Chance to get a reset on the
cooldowns of all your
companion skills.
So again, this is something
that, you know, normally we
don't get to manipulate, and
now you'll be able to do, and
I think it'll be pretty cool.
We have also decided that
Pack Leader is two words
instead of one.
Yeah, yeah.
Everything's getting updated.
Yeah.
Everything.
Everything's up to me.
Everything's changing.
All right, moving on to the
Rogue Eaglehorn.
Let me see, what did I want
to, I think just pointing out
here, this was about moving
the Tempered Recipe.
The Penetrating Shot
projectiles can cast twice.
Again, another example of
that.
We're also giving you a bunch
of skill ranks to
Penetrating Shot.
Again, this is a way that
we're adding just like raw
power and damage in ways that
aren't in the unique effect.
So these stats on these
things can be very strong
out the gate.
And then again, tempering
and masterworking just makes
these go really, really high.
Next, Word of a Con.
This one was a really silly,
fun one that we liked.
You see there, the one I want
to point out, well, one is
the ultimate damage.
Actually, ultimate skill damage
for the Rogue is kind of a
premium because they have
that Paragon node that makes
it turn into multiplicative
damage for all your skills.
So that's actually pretty
meaty.
It's also way higher value
than normal.
Also, the chance for
Reign of Arrows waves
to cast twice.
So normally we don't do,
you know, chance to double
cast on ultimates, but again,
uniques get to break the
rules.
So now you've got, you know,
juiced up Reign of Arrows
cooldown reduction.
They can cast twice and they
hit way harder on the Reign of
Arrows themed unique.
So again, really trying to
bring out the theme and the
fantasy of these uniques in
the stats, in the effects, to
really create something
special.
And next, Saboteur Signet.
I was running this in Season
4.
I'm a little sad that I'm
going to be doing something
else in Season 5, but I
loved my stun grenade build.
But here you can see a bunch
of grenade damage, obvious
theme for the grenade build.
We're also giving you a lot
of your stun grenade size
here.
And then again, a new affix
that kind of creates your
own engine.
You're getting plus one energy
when a stun grenade explodes.
And this is each individual
grenade, right?
So you usually release a
cluster of these things.
So now, again, I spent a lot
of my time in Season 4 trying
to solve resource and get ways
to cast this a lot, to
throw out those stun grenades,
and now this kind of helps
its own engine.
Also, one thing to point out
here is that it's no longer
just a flurry unique.
It's casting a core skill
through a stun grenade.
So it's a lot more
generically applicable.
You can use this with, you
know, all the different
core skills, not just flurry.
Next, Necromancer.
The big one I wanted to
point out here, we're going
to be showing both of the
Blood Surge uniques and how
they've been updated and they
combo with each other.
We have a stat here that
Blood Surge drains more
times from elites.
So to be clear, this is the
drain, not the explosion.
But the drain does feed into
the explosion damage and
there's a lot of, like,
synergy and things based on
draining enemies.
So now, you know, one of the
problems that Blood Surge has
always had is when you're
fighting a single target or a
boss, you know, you only
drain one enemy and then
you're not getting your, like,
explosion damage up.
But now you're going to be
draining multiple times from
those elites, so you're
getting, you know, more life
back and other procs when you
drain, but also your explosion
will be more significant now
against them.
Next, Death Speaker's
Pendant.
This is the other Blood Surge
unique.
We also added another thing
that combines with the other
unique where you're getting
essence per enemy drained,
right?
And so now, as you drain
enemies for the explosion,
you're going to be getting
more essence back to cast the
skill and spam it more.
We're also giving you a bunch
of ranks to Blood Surge,
which, you know, just makes
sense.
So, you know, 50% before
Masterworking and Temporing
multiplicative damage is
already a giant buff to this.
But then also you can see
that, you know, the numbers
also went up on this as well.
So it's just going to be
going to be pretty significant.
Can't wait.
And last but not least,
Greaves of the Empty Tomb.
This is your Sever unique.
Lots of stuff to point out
here.
One is you have multiple
inherents.
So, you know, normally you can
only get three max of eight
charges.
You get more here.
We also had a fun little thing
where you're evade now
these behind Desecrated
Ground because this is the
Desecrated Ground unique.
We also have chance for
Sever projectiles to cast
twice.
We have Sever size here.
We also give you ranks to
Reaper's Pursuit.
So this is really about just
like moving and grooving,
like going around.
One thing I want to point out
here as well is this new
aspect of Creeping Mist that
came in.
And you can combine this with
the Greaves of the Empty
Tomb.
So this new aspect, you know,
we heard that Necro players
want mobility and boy did we
give you mobility.
So what this does is when
you evade during, first of
all, you get evade cooldown
reduction, so you evade more.
But when you evade during
Blood Mist, you travel twice
as far.
And both when you enter and
exit Blood Mist, it resects
your evade cooldown.
And one of the things that
makes this crazy where we
might actually be crazy, and
I hope we don't have to
revisit this, but we're going
to see, is that that reset
of your evade cooldown counts
for all of your charges of
evade.
So what this means is, and we
have a video, is that you can
evade five times, then evade
in Blood Mist, and then
evade five more times.
So see here, then you're
evading in Blood Mist, and
you're leaving behind that
desecrated ground everywhere.
Just skating around, you
know?
Yep.
It's like an ice skating
ring.
So every time you cast Blood
Mist, you're going to be
getting ten evades.
It's silly and hilarious.
But we're putting it in the
game, and I hope we don't
regret it.
Necros are going to be
zooming.
Yep, they're going to be
zooming with this.
Wow.
Yeah, so that's kind of our
preview of our uniques, and
kind of what's coming into
the game.
Again, we're pretty excited
about it.
I think this will be pretty
cool.
Yeah.
But yeah.
Professor Adam Jackson, take
a bow.
That is incredible.
And again, that's not even
everything.
There's a lot of stuff going
to other uniques that are at
that level.
Patch notes, after the stream,
we will be showing a
comparison of every single
unique, and their changes
from season four to season
five.
So you can go in there and
check out all those
changes.
But that was a great, great
overview of all those
changes.
That is really, really
exciting.
This brings us to our Q&A
portion of the show.
Let's all shift our legs at
the same time.
Yeah, yeah.
So we've been following
along in Twitch chat, and
we've picked out a bunch of
questions, and we're going
to kick it off, tossing it
over to Mr. Dan Tangway.
How do reward choices work
in multiplayer parties for
Infernal Hordes?
Does the leader choose the
reward for everyone, or can
each player choose?
All right.
So yeah, let's talk about
this.
In the Infernal Hordes, when
you're collecting burning
ether, each individual
collects their own burning
ether.
And we did this for the
very reason that you're
asking questions about.
We wanted players to be
able to go in and choose
the rewards that they want
to choose, not necessarily
what somebody else gets to
first or what the party
leader wants.
So every individual party
member will have their own
choice of rewards.
Awesome.
Thanks for letting us know.
Marcus, you've got to read
the names.
Oh my goodness.
Did I not say Eldrick?
Oh my gosh.
Eldrick, I won't forget you.
Thank you, Adam.
Eldrick, thank you for that
question.
Of course, you're going to be
a stickler for that.
Yeah, no.
It's a great thing to call
out.
Pull the ladder behind you.
Because our next question is
from Dartless.
Actually, I think we have a
question here on the lower
third, which is this one.
We've gotten a lot of these
questions, so I do want to
actually address this one.
This is, when are we going
to hear more about Vessel of
Hatred?
Because we just had the
Spiritborn reveal.
We showed off the Spiritborn.
I will note that we also are
going to be at Gamescom.
There's actually some Gamescom
news that came out this
morning.
The Spiritborn will be
playable at Gamescom.
If you go to the Xbox booth,
you'll be able to play it
there.
So if you're attending that
show, it'll be really
awesome.
There's actually going to be
more news coming out at that
time, so of course, tune in.
And I will say, you guys have
only heard a very small
fraction of what's coming out
of Vessel of Hatred.
So we're really excited for
Gamescom.
So you guys will hear more
then, so stay tuned.
Yeah.
Grab your tickets and come to
Gamescom because we'll be
there.
I'll be super-sup.
Yes, exactly.
Go to Germany.
Come to Cologne.
There was some people
confused in chat.
This is a question from
Dartless who was saying,
we can temper uniques now.
Did I mishear that?
Maybe that was a mistake
being said.
So Adam, if you want to
speak to that.
Yeah, 100% clear.
Cannot temper uniques.
We want them to be different in
that they do not engage with
that system, at least for now.
But no, you're going to be,
what I wanted to say or be
clarifying is that you can get
tempering affixes on uniques.
Like they'll just drop with
those affixes or whatever.
But you can't like go to the
to the box with them,
manipulate them in that way.
You can't temper them.
Gotcha.
Cool.
Thanks for clarifying that.
It's really unique.
Adam.
It'sDafi has a question for
Dantangue.
Are there any plans to continue
iterating on the Infernal
Hordes in the future since it's
a permanent addition?
Are there going to be more
boons and banes coming?
Yeah, that's a great question.
And yeah, just to reiterate what
you had pointed out there,
this is an Eternal Realm feature
that's going to appear in the game
forevermore.
And so this is just the first
version of it.
I mean, you think back to what
Helltide was in the base game
and how we've iterated on that
over time to get it to where it
is.
We're going to continue investing
similar levels of effort into the
Infernal Hordes too.
And so boons and banes is
something we heard a lot about
feedback during the PTR.
And so we absolutely want to make
more improvements to the boons and
banes.
And so stay tuned.
That's not going to hit in Season 5,
but we'll figure out where we can
get it in in future seasons.
Awesome.
Great to hear that we're going to
continue tinkering on that feature
in the seasons to come.
I've got a really interesting
question from Mano underscore Imp
with regards to those...
Mano Imp.
We know Mano Imp.
With regards to the damage increase
per class resource.
Sure.
They're asking, is the Spirit Boring
getting 1% damage at 7 points if it's
their main stat just because they have
a lower amount of weapons?
Yeah.
TBD.
I don't want to go on a map on
Spirit Born yet, but they'll be
getting similar treatment to all the
other stuff.
All of this is kind of evergreen.
Awesome.
Lukewee.
When will we see the overhaul of the
Paragon system?
Would you consider removing the
Paragon limit?
There are going to be changes to
Paragon, but we aren't talking about
those changes yet.
Awesome.
Yeah.
TBD.
Stay tuned.
Love this name.
Chickenwing929.
Love it.
Can the reputation rewards for Season of
the Infernal Hordes be earned on only
one character or all your seasonal
characters?
I believe it's all characters,
similar to what we have for Season 4.
So you can actually go back in and just
play like, go through the reputation
board and then get another
Resplendent Spark.
That's really the question.
Really, that's truly the question.
Yeah, so you can get additional.
Pretty sure it's character specific.
So you can, yeah.
Nice.
Systematic5k, Adam Jackson.
Will our existing uniques be updated with
these new unique changes?
Yeah, we get this every round that we
update them.
It's the same rules as always, which is
the unique power, when we update that,
is your existing uniques will get that,
right?
So when we increase your damage range or
whatever, that's going to get.
But the stats, those are going to be
legacy on any items that exist.
So you're going to have to re-farm your
unique to get the new stats that are on
them.
Awesome.
And that's kind of the way that they're
going to work going forward, unless you say
otherwise.
Yeah.
It's just how things work under the hood
for when we do changes on them.
Yeah.
Nice.
Pudge, Pudge underscore BP.
Are there any plans for clan rework
slash improvements?
There are, I know there are some changes
coming for some social features.
We're just not ready to talk about them
now.
But you guys will hear about them soon.
Awesome.
This one's kind of a design philosophy
question for Adam Jackson.
Sure.
Evans423 wants to know, how future-proof
is the system of static uniques when
adding new slash better tempering effects
and new content?
How future-proof are static uniques when
adding new tempers?
Let me think.
Semi, right?
Because I think it is something where if
we add new tempers or new affixes or
whatever, we will probably need to go
back and update uniques that we wanted
to apply to and make it work again.
Our hope is that these uniques are going
to be pretty future-proof.
They're going to be very meaty in the
amount of power that they give you.
They're also extremely thematic.
But I think we do reserve the right,
like, hey, if we find a new idea for
existing passive or existing tempering
that is introduced to the game and we
want to put it on, we can do that.
I will say also one thing that we want
to do more is, like, just come up with
really crazy new ones that aren't even
really tempering recipes, but just,
like, crazy effects, right?
Like Blood Howl grants stealth or you
drain more with your, you know, Blood
Search, stuff like that.
So I would expect we'll probably be
updating them as we go forward.
Not probably as dramatically as this
all at once, but I foresee this
probably likely, yeah.
Nice, yeah.
Always tinkering, always updating.
Speaking of which, about tempering,
one thing that we forgot to mention,
and I know we mentioned it at the
PTR stream last time.
I'm sorry, my earpiece just keeps
falling off.
It looks like I'm, like, scratching my
ear, but I'm not.
The greater, I know there was a lot
of, like, feedback after season four
regarding tempering and potentially
bricking items.
And one update that we talked about
during the PTR stream, and I want to
mention it wasn't in PTR, but is in
season five specifically, is greater
affixes will actually get additional
temper rerolls on them based on the
greater affix, you know, quality of
what they are.
So for, like, greater affix one star
ones, you'll end up getting one
additional temper reroll.
And then it grows by how many stars
that there are.
So that is going in season five.
So we mentioned it last stream.
I just wanted to reiterate it because
I actually forgot we should have
mentioned it.
Yeah, sweet.
Yeah, great to mention that, Adam.
That's awesome.
We've got an easy one here from
ZWeapons.
What is a Mythic unique?
There was a purple item during the
stream?
Yeah, you can tune into our last
stream for it.
But yeah, basically what was Uber
Uniques is what people call them.
It's basically, like, you know, the
really best items in the game that
have, like, perfect stats and
everything.
We rebranded them to Mythic Uniques.
They now have their own special
color, special beam when they
drop.
They just got to hold treatment to
really make them feel like the
penultimate items that they are in
the game.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Sophie0257, are they going to make
it so that we can pre-download the
update or will it be available only
on the 6th?
That's a great question.
That's a good question.
Based off feedback from season
four's launch, the patch will be
available to download roughly an
hour before Season of the Infernal
Hordes launches.
So that season goes live at 10 a.m.
and roughly an hour before you'll be
able to pre-download the patch to get
in the game and get ready for the
season.
Yeah.
I know a lot of people are probably
going, like, why not multiple days
and things like that.
We're getting there.
We're trying.
But no, it's, it's, it's, we got a
lot of feedback about, you know, how
things started immediately on the,
like, you could download and actually
start the season.
Of course, we want to make sure that
people can be as prepared as
possible.
So one hour before the actual season
starts, like, you should be able to
actually download and get that all
prepared.
So, like, as soon as the season, the
time for the season begin, which is
roughly, like, 10 a.m. Pacific on the
day of, you, you can just jump in
without needing to download.
Yeah.
Skull MTV.
Hey, great job.
Thanks.
Any plans to rework master working in
brackets?
Higher cost, but, you know, you can
choose upgrades and tempering to make
these systems have less RNG?
Nothing to announce at this time.
We definitely have heard the feedback.
We are starting with the first step of,
like, you know, one of the things that
we know feels really bad for players,
like, I got a, how do I say?
The more greater affixes you have on an
item, the higher stress and investment
you have to, like, make it work the way
that you want.
So we are relaxing that, make it a
little bit easier.
Another thing that we're thinking about
that's a little lighter is, like, the
tempering recipes, making them have,
like, three on average instead of four
or more.
Something that we're talking about
moving towards, but nothing, like, of
overhauling the system and doing a
major change at this time that we
have to announce.
Cool.
Thanks, Adam.
Dan Tangway from Holy Smokes.
Their name isn't for Holy Smokes.
Their name is...
I thought it was Dan Tangway asking a
question, and I was like, wait, what?
No, no, no.
Their name is Frodo Bolson.
Frodo Bolson.
But all the O's are zeroes.
All right.
How does the Infernal Hordes work in
groups?
Do you need only one compass per group?
So the Infernal Hordes, you only need
one compass per group in order to be
able to get in.
Yeah.
Sweet.
Just like Nightmare Dungeon sigils.
Awesome.
All right.
Revask.
Any news on reworked Nightmare Dungeons?
Nothing.
Nothing for today.
Nothing to announce today.
Yeah, nothing to announce today.
Sweet.
Green Zombie Studios.
Can we expect cool new transmogs in
Season 5 from salvaging items?
I am not sure.
I know, like, the Season 5 does have
over...
has a lot of new legendary aspects and
uniques.
Like, there's, like, 50 new legendary
aspects and uniques being added into
Season 5.
So there's a lot of, like, more the
back-end type of stuff that affects
more so on the gameplay.
But I'm not exactly sure if there's a
ton coming in.
Yeah.
So we can, actually.
There are a couple of new uniques in
Hell that you can earn that will have
all new looks to them that you can sell
the gems and use in the cosmetic.
Yep.
Bam.
There you go.
Dan, the savior from Albany.
Frodo Bolson.
Hot pancakes.
Are there still plans for rare and magic
items?
I guess in terms of, like, a rework or
changing their functionality in any way?
Yeah.
I'd say nothing to announce today for that.
Cool.
Nice.
All right.
Checking through.
Mac and D's.
Can we expect skill trees or support
gems to change the way skills work?
gems to change the way the skill works?
I mean, we're not doing any skill tree
overhaul right now in Season 5.
I do think we have talked a bit on the
team about having a desire of the
upgrades for skills being, like, more
impactful and really impactful.
Nothing to announce today, but it is
something that is on our radar and I
think is cool.
I think one example that we talk about
along the team is, like, the kick
upgrade for the Barbarian, where
normally, you know, when we were
originally designing kick, it was this
idea that you have this, like, skill
where you hit an enemy and you care about
the geometry of the place around you and you
want to hit them into the wall and then
they get knocked down, take a bunch of
damage and all this stuff.
That part hasn't really played out, I
think, as well because the pace of our
game is so fast.
But one of the upgrades for kick,
especially I remember in the early beta,
like, way before, maybe it was alpha
even, kick, you know, it converts kick
from this cooldown-based geometry skill
into just a powerhouse where it just
spends all your resource and does a
buttload of damage to an enemy.
And it was, like, one-shotting world
bosses and stuff back then.
Like, it was hilarious.
I think I remember that.
But the skill still has that upgrade.
But I reference that upgrade a lot
because I think it's really cool when
you can convert a skill to, like,
used to be cooldown and now isn't or
used to be about this utility and now
it's just damage or vice versa where it,
like, really changes what a skill does.
We think it's really cool.
It definitely would be a lot of work to,
like, do that to every skill.
But I think it's something that's worth
talking about and pursuing.
So it is on our radar of something to do
but nothing to announce today for it.
Awesome.
That's really cool.
Thanks, Adam.
And that brings us to the end of our Q&A.
So I want to give a huge thank you to Adam and Adam
and Dan for answering all those questions.
Adam squared.
Back in action.
Hey, just like the PTR stream.
You guys are back.
There you go.
Screw those Joes.
Got them.
Yeah.
I'm just kidding.
And that brings us to the end of our
Season of the Infernal Hordes developer update stream.
Just a few notes before we close out the stream.
Just want to take a moment to thank everyone
for tuning into our Spiritborn showcase
a few weeks back.
Yeah.
It was really cool to show off that new class.
It was such a huge moment for the team.
So I really want to thank you all
for coming to check that out.
And if you want to play the Spiritborn in person,
as Adam mentioned earlier,
we are going to be at Gamescom.
So get your tickets.
Come to Gamescom in Cologne, Germany.
And...
I just went up through the roof.
But speaking of Spiritborn,
you can pre-purchase Vessel of Hatred today
and instantly...
Oh, can they hear audio?
Oh, can everybody hear us?
Twitch chat?
Where did the sound go?
Okay, we're good now.
We're good now.
Okay, awesome.
All right.
Thank you, chat, for keeping us up to date.
Speaking of the Spiritborn,
you can pre-purchase Vessel of Hatred today
to get instant access to some items in-game
before the expansion goes live this October.
For Season of the Infernal Hordes,
this season goes live on August 6th at 10 a.m.
The patch will be available for pre-download
roughly an hour before.
And 10 a.m. is in Pacific time,
for anyone wondering.
The patch will be available for pre-download
about an hour before the season goes live
so you can get in and get ready for the season to start.
The 150 patch notes are going to go live
after this stream for Season 5.
So for anything we talked about across the stream today,
that'll be available.
You can see all the uniques and everything.
Yeah, check out those GIFs.
They're pretty spiffy.
Team worked pretty hard on those.
We also had the Season of the Infernal Hordes
deep dive blog go live earlier this week,
so a ton of information there as well.
Stick around after the stream
because we're going to be raiding
some Diablo content creators,
so go and check them out.
For Adam and Adam and Mr. Dan Tangway and Albany,
thank you guys so much for joining us
for this developer update stream today.
Yeah, thank you so much.
Really awesome to go through all the changes.
And from all of us here,
thank you so much to everyone at home
for watching and checking out the stream.
And we will see you all in Sanctuary.
Yeah.
Uniques.
Woo!
Yeah?
Mmm.
pode
Thank you.