good afternoon everybody and welcome back to another last epoch devstream as usual i'm your
host mike hello how's it going everybody all right oh feels good to be back we are
on our last our last day of dev streams pre-season two uh so this is our yeah it's our last usual
dev stream we're gonna single do the uh two more podcast events which are arguably better
arguably much better um but yeah you got you got me for one more weekend uh here on on dev stream day
glad to be back here we got some good questions for me if this is your first time you're welcome
glad to have you with us we stream for charity boom right above my head all that goes there
um and if you have a question please feel free to ask in chat put uh at last epoch game and
kane will be pulling questions for me i'll be answering them thanks kane appreciate you
uh what other what other housekeeping stuff we have patch day is april 17th
uh we've got two more uh we've got two more
um podcast streams coming up next friday and the friday after that with talking of try on the first
one and then aaron and frosty on the second one uh those are gonna be awesome really looking forward
to those uh what other housekeeping stuff do we have i don't know what else we got going on i'm sure more
will come up all right first question will also um welcome everyone that's on uh watching on youtube
as well because we are streaming in two places at once now and we do take questions from both so uh
yes don't worry questions from both uh will we ever get a co-op dev stream with the ehg team i i feel
like we've done this once or twice question mark i'm definitely down for it we've we've been planning
on on trying to incorporate more people into uh the devstream process in general um and once the once
the what do we get oh cool once the uh podcasts sessions are done for the uh for the stream i think
like maybe a few early streams in the season i'd like to get some guests on yeah we'll do some some
co-op stuff there some devs you know there's there's lots of people that i'd love to have on get some
fresh perspectives on things um different like art disciplines uh just other people who work on
design stuff or coding stuff or all sorts of people that would love to come on so we want to get more of those on for sure
uh mike real talk i haven't seen these streams in quite some months did you lose a lot of weight
you look sharp thank you very much i did lose a lot of weight i lost a third of my body weight
uh in almost exactly a year now they started on april 1st last year
all right uh controller thanks yeah we're uh we are updating controller work um
um oh medic you know you know what's going on with the controller thanks for putting the names
there came that's why it's useful yes control updates are coming for season two um uh if you
haven't played with controller recently there's a ton of cool stuff happening with that um context and
specialization specific targeting functions for each skill that works so much better than than before
even just a simple just normal fireball being able to kite with it so nice like like just opening the
game at the very start on a new character and being able to orb walk is surprisingly something i didn't
think was as big a deal as it is oh thank the whole whole set where's give me that set we're picking up sets now
all right do you consider a hot dog a sandwich please elaborate your answer um
i'm gonna say no however i'm gonna say that a sandwich requires so if you look at the um
the like each side of an object of having starch or not in it a sandwich has starch on the on the top
and bottom but a hot dog has has starch on on three sides um or like this three sides so so it's three
sides instead of two sides so it's a different class of food delivery it's more like a taco really
um
i think there's a podcast called hot dogs a sandwich isn't there
like some car trip i was on once had someone playing it i don't know it's a weird memory there
um all right uh does that mean no dead stream next friday is that just because peewee will be there
uh uh be an interview that day ah right i i skipped a week didn't i ah um we will decide what to do next
week i think uh because next week is launch day for them yeah next next week is launch day for them
uh i'll double check and get back to you
i think it's reasonable not to do a stream on poe launch day
i have fallen you know that means right
it is an early spoiler
as penance for my death
here we are uh here is a node for the new reworked sigils of hope which is now symbols of hope uh skill
tree and uh yeah a little little little little little bit in there
shove that to the bottom corner and keep moving because we're not done yet
it's a little 90 timeline i'm level 76 all right cool
but we're punching up a little bit we're punching up a little bit
all right any thoughts on torchlight infinite doing their release on april 17th too uh april is crowded um
it is it is very unfortunate and uh
you know moving again is is is just craziness so i think uh i i'm not in charge of this in any way
uh but unless i hear otherwise we're sticking to the guns on it
thank you very much we've got a sub from a whole bunch of subs that's five gifted subs oh wow oh my
goodness what the i don't even know if we have a notification for this but that's new uh
uh endotoxin thank you very much for the tip that's that's just a straight hundred dollars that's
amazing wow thank you uh and and and jarzul also thanks for the five gifted subs and heavy for the 47
month resub whoo oh you got your your creator unique in the key art that's pretty sweet
all of the all the dimensions all the donations do go to charity for youtube as well uh so like
everything goes to charity the the charity above my head we change it up sometimes we've been on
child's play for a little bit we've come and gone back and forth so we really like this one
um but yes all of the everything does go to charity so thank you very much we do appreciate
that and they do appreciate it too um that that's wild i think we've ever had a had a had a
just a straight hundred dollars before that's cool that's very cool i hope you're enjoying the game
uh or at least listening to me talk about it
come back here yeah push you back towards me and away again
pebbles okay this is one this this is a this is an item set that i think is going to be
surprisingly the the three set bonus on this is is quite strong uh and i'm really excited to see if
anyone can do something with the set bonus on this with the new set crafting system and spike that's
23 months almost two years very nice thank you very much i love saying your name out loud
i recently watched uh
the the show that i think i'm like one of four people that liked it again um
the the the live action cowboy bebop um and the name always reminds me of that
it did cause me to go back and watch the anime which is which is cool
or cartoon i don't know the definition differences anyways moving on before i make a bigger fool of myself
uh
and some bits oh and there's notifications coming through oh we gotta turn those off
ah
okay we're just gonna live with it moving on and adrian adrian tempish thanks for the bits buddy appreciate you
wondrous wondrous wondrous all right
has the team figured out what day they hope to get the patch notes out by uh we we have not unveiled
the patch notes day yet um i i would assume that the uh the marketing team has a very good handle on
what day that's going to be um that sort of thing's planned out pretty far in advance usually
um and it had to get adjusted for the for shifting the release date but yeah it's i think that's a
pretty i i think that's that's that i don't know who i don't know what day it is or who it is or what
or any of those things
get back here you loot lizard
whoo
lots of candy
little ones
more questions more questions mike's gonna answer the questions stop playing your game
uh will element damage ever be affected by base damage ratio the the um the the added damage
scaling ratio so each each ability in case anyone doesn't know each ability has
uh a scaling ratio that added damage applies to it so um you get something like this and it's like
plus 90 melee damage that 90 melee damage applies differently to swipe than it would to say serpent
strike or upheaval or tempest strike and they all do differently
all aboard
i found it yeah that's that's that's like hype train rolling oh dj thank you very much
that's that's big we're going we're rolling
no room thank you very much everybody that's that's five gifted subs whoo
we're cruising
just dumping everything this is before i started organizing mustache
like a heathen everything just gets dumped
i can't bear to drop it on the ground
all right will ailment damage ever be affected by the base damage ratio of a skill big hitting skills
are almost impossible to make into ailment builds and it would be really cool to actually have those
builds in the game um i don't have a specific yes no on this we're not doing we're not making
a change to this for season two it's something that we've discussed a few times um medic resub
thank you very much appreciate you that's three months in a row right there
also congrats to everyone who got one of the gifted ones too um
but yeah the uh whether or not this changes in the future i don't know it won't change in season
two i can tell you that much
all right what's the first build you're planning on running in season two i'm going hard seeker to
start i it's what i've been playing the most in testing and oh my goodness this is insane it
just keeps coming in the best way possible
uh jarsul is more even more that's five oh is this a ploy to distract me so that i die
it's brilliant because it's going to work
all right mike focus up runescape i never played runescape never got into it i think i was playing
age of empires at the time um yeah i just never never never got hooked on it
all right hi mike how are you doing i'm doing good thanks i'm actually having a really good day today
we had we had a design meeting this morning that went great i'm pumped on the stuff i saw it's gonna
be awesome um just you know we got got through another another uh lock for the patch it's it's
the build stable right now i'm feeling really good having a great day uh anyway to the real
question will there be improvements on merchant skilled ui for example right now you can't search
for a triple exalt you have to search for results and then scroll hundreds of hundreds of pages
likewise will there be cof ui improvements sometimes it's hard figuring out uh where i want
to go next because the prophecies can't be sorted nor can we easily see what we have to do either
the panel or the echo map um yeah there's whoa that's a lot of damage um there's there's stuff in
the works for these things there's not a lot of changes for season two coming for either of those
directly um a lot of the ui works been being done on the new uh the new weaver ui the new echo ui the
new uh all the new stuff that's coming so there's not a ton of changes on the uh on on the
merchant's guild and see the circle of fortune ui but it is on the list and there are some changes
i think heavy heavy gets in a bunch mike 190 twitch twitch gets in a bunch there's there's there's
more subs coming through than i have ever seen this is just rolling just
i don't i don't even know what's going on here this is crazy this is crazy congrats
everyone's subbed at this point wild just wild okay let's let me see if i can answer something
favorably here uh do you guys find a way to make cosmetics available in true offline mode yet not
yet i'm sorry come on guys give me an easy question here uh will there be nodes that interact with heart
seeker and other skills trees um i don't think there's any nodes in other trees that directly
impact heart seeker there's there's items and there's nodes and heart seeker's too that impact
other skills uh i don't think so new player here why no hotkey to compare offhand item and second rings
aha yes this is this has been a problem for a long time and i'm very happy to say we have a fix for
it it's coming we've got offhand ring comparison we've got offhand comparison and off ring slot
comparison coming um i think it's uh okay but i don't remember which hockey it is but it's it's coming
it's on it's on the it's on its way it's happening uh the main reason why i didn't oh my god i just
oh my goodness what what is going on i can't i have no way of keeping up with this this is insane
oh oh nice
that's a max roll on that on a decent base too actually
that's not bad that's not bad uh all right well thank you very much for even more jarzul and
uh linker hanker for the sub thank you very much you guys you guys are and and tolmat ip
and an apple g72 i need to pull this window to a different spot so i can see it better how can i
reorganize this because i am just squinting it's like the farthest thing from me on a screen way
i can't even touch it uh
plutter oh that that's one that i guarantee if i find the capitalization on it it will make so much
more sense oh you're just rolling in it this is this is nuts charity charity it's all going it's all
going this way that way these guys all right one of the podcast streams fourth and eighth i think
they're on the uh
eighth and the 11th
i want to say back check me on that one
we've we've really got to get i've been saying this for like years now we've got to get a like custom
sound and uh sprite for for sub notifications and things like that
it thank you kane all right yes the eighth uh april 8th at 3 p.m and april 11th at 3 p.m central time
for both will be the
the two more here they are boom right there
thank you kane much appreciated are there any plans to make legendaries drop randomly or will
they always just be craftable even if it's really rare it would be a big hype moment to see one drop
thoughts um i think it's one of those things where the variance is so high
um and you usually want to craft specific you want to combine specific things on there for it
i'd say it's unlikely that we'll be dropping them as pre-made legendaries anytime soon
um but it's it's definitely possible
more there's even more tails tail tails three
or triple oh 11 one of the two
depending on if we're talking base 10 or base 2.
here's here's a terrible joke for you uh why do programmers confuse halloween and christmas
because octal 31 is the same as decimal 25.
yeah december the base 10 and base 8 numbering never mind uh anyway charcel thank you for even more
uh that's that's i don't know how many is it like 25 this stream or something ridiculous
that's insane
uh
thank you very much
uh okay uh any chance for a true berserk class possibly uh uh possibly ability using fists um
yeah i i think that's uh a theming that we've sort of dabbled in but not really like fully invested
in yet and i'd love to see it expanded
hello i'm a ballista enjoyer but can't seem to make ballista stand up on their own right they have
to be either exploded totems or raven combined with the raven being uh thalken being the main dps
any future plans to support ballistas as the main damage scaler they're definitely getting some love
um
uh there's some stuff in the future as well that that that's got some cool tech for them that we've that
we're introducing um
i i don't want to say like it's they're going to be a like top tier dps build or anything like that but
there's definitely some work we're doing on on ballistas recently for future stuff
oh
little harbinger get this
uh what's your favorite unique oh great question
do i have an answer uh
uh
i like uniques that do cool stuff that's special uh i'm gonna say
hmm
honestly it's probably the beekeeper club
terrible cop-out answer i i don't know i i really like the
there's there's a couple new ones oh i can't talk about that one yet there's two new ones coming
that i really want to talk about right now that i will talk about soon and we go over itemization
um
existing ones in the game right now probably
i really like the squirrel helmet i really like this raptor weapon too maybe it's just i'm wearing it right now
the new the new the new relic that we've that we've revealed as a boss drop from uber yeah
uh i just say david harvard's unique because yeah i mean
get it getting to getting to talk to david harvard about this was pretty crazy so yeah that's that's up there for sure too
all right does snow crash node in earthquake create larger or small large or small avalanche boulders
oh i definitely know what that node does off the top of my head
earthquake mess at lunch
snow crash
uh those will be
that's the base those those will be big ones
those those should be big ones because it because it references the base uh the base skill tree
i mean just allocate it and see what it does
if i was if i had the ability unlocked i would check it for you right now
next question aside from sentinel slash heart seeker what class spec is going to have something new and
cool you're looking forward to all of them um
um
most most of that most of it comes around like specific uniques and new uh
things you can do that way but yeah
all of them really something new for everybody
all right skill and class design question any ideas or plans on expanding the min mix and
matching for elements on skills i love the idea of the us machinations but having a problems in
end game yeah it's it's a tricky thing because there's so much natural synergy
in getting similar elements together because when you have increased effects that target a specific
element you can make them be a little bit stronger um it's it's kind of like that give and take of
you're getting access by by mixing your elements you're getting access to new effects and new uh
new things that you can trigger new like debuffs and there's there's all sorts of like little extra
secondary things you get access to by by mixing in a second element um but then you get the reduced
effectiveness of your damage increases and things like that so it's a bit of a trade-off there um
it's kind of i'd kind of liken it to adding another color into your deck and like a magic or
something like that and um we do we do try to put conversions into skills when there's going to be
specific thematically appropriate like uh connections specifically for that so you can still have
so you can use two abilities together that should be play nice together um
but still get the full benefits from damage but if you really want split theming we tried to put that on
on like root master as an example of something that would would function better
getting bonuses from mix and matching elements
all right
uh i have seen a 3d printer in your background previously yes any possibility of getting some
iconic in-game assets in a printable format for fan art purposes uh i mean i'd love to
do i have uh i've taken a couple objects from from game files and and tried to convert them to 3d printable
um i'm moderately successful on a couple of them um i would i would love to have like a little
library of printable things that people could could download and print out and things like that
that would be really cool um so i guess no plans but i love the idea
we can we survive just standing in this i think so
nailed it
can you get more information about putting lp back on items that you previously teased back on items
uh we're not adding a way to put lp back on i well the
um
the egg that's already in the game is the only way to add lp to an item that doesn't have lp on it
uh i think that's true
we'll go through uh one of the upcoming podcasts we're gonna focus on itemization
uh we'll go on a deep dive on all of the things like this i i i i think i know what you're asking
about um and i can't really answer the question without giving more away than i'm supposed to give
away uh but we will talk about this uh pre-patch notes and uh you'll you'll get some some some
some good solid info on this i promise don't worry i think this is asking about because we've
we've teased that there's going to be some system in the game to alleviate the feels bad moments of
slamming an item and uh not getting the thing you were looking for
i think that's what this is asking about
but it's gonna be it's gonna be really good it's gonna be really real good uh will we get to see
what the new quiver that you teased a while ago does in one of the podcasts or not i will
make a request for that for yes showing that off um
i don't i don't see why i don't see why not what do we get just some mana this is what we
we put in the egg not not exactly uh top tier
it's fine
i mean it's nice stats and everything but
i don't know
oh my goodness how my my face i didn't know i was asking for the face breaking treatment
i mean because there's there's i i guess i'm wrong like there's a legendary that just dropped right
there that i had nothing to do with it being created it just dropped right like i guess i kind
i did because i empowered it but so maybe we do dropped legendaries maybe i'm just wrong
are there any big changes coming to the shaman skill tree or more itemization to help expand the
builds i'm more in the itemization category there's some changes coming to some of the skill trees but
i'd say more focused in the itemization side of things uh what do you think about crossover skins
with lord of the rings or arthur's for forge guards i mean i i love the idea um i i don't i don't know
if it's the sort of thing that either of those franchises would find uh appealing given the
volume difference in reach
lord of the rings and wow are significantly bigger than we are
the third lord of the rings movie i think is the the biggest oscar sweep ever where they've um of
any time a movie has been nominated and or won all of its nominations lord of the rings had the most
nominations for movies that won all of their nominations i think that's what the stat is
all right are we getting buffs to endurance threshold affixes in general yeah there's um
there's there's some sort of just general endurance buffs that are coming
uh there is some support to electrify in healing hands yes and we know that most of electrify support
is coming for lightning skills specifically holy lightning skills just a little interjection
so is there lightning conversion for healing hands um
i don't know if that made it into season two or not we are planning either for season two or beyond
um more lightning support in holy hands healing hands holy hands healing hands
uh will the weaver this is the problem i get working on things in the future is i don't
remember what's actually coming this season and next season
gets all jumbled up into one
all right will the weaver faction have their own pinnacle boss encounter uh not in the same way that
uh not in the same way that abiroth is to forgotten knights
like kind of because is that is that more is that more my goodness um like there is the hardest thing
to do in the game gets accessed through weaver faction stuff um but it's more thematically tied to
forgotten knights so kind of uh since unlocking tears in merchant skill distorts the price of the best
gear uh since few people unlock later tears is there any plans on a rework example trading costs
as gold as uh friction and shards and runes as their currency used to buy and sell unlocking tears
reduce gold effect friction costs um there this is this is a concern um that we've been talking about
we do have a solution planned for it for the future um it's going to be a little bit different but uh
than what you're suggesting here but like because it's not done yet we're very welcome to suggestions
on it so if you do have a specific idea that you'd like this to consider please head on over to the
suggestions uh channels on our discord uh forums any of the places we take suggestions from
and we can incorporate that when we start implementing it but we do have some adjustments for that plant
let's let's let's get a little i thought i was gonna die sooner here's a weaver's node here's a node from the weaver's will tree
weaver's will tree the weaver's tree
this is another one of the like style of things that we're doing um yeah we're trying to give you
this is what we've been talking about but more control over more influence over what type of
um what type of things you're doing in the end game when you're playing what sorts of things are
you are you wanting to see more of trying to give you tools to get more of those things you want to see more of
all right any chance we get an option to hide multiple item types in a single loot filter argument
with 1.2 season 2 uh example belt subtype and chest subtypes uh
no that's not happening in season 2 uh we're combining something else though
but something else we're doing to combine two rules into one to make it a little bit easier to
to free up a couple rule slots for people because we're not adding more rule slots
um but we are trying to free up some of them
uh this one
this one yes
let's try it let's try it try it
and of course there's spires spires are getting reworked pumped on the spire rework yeah spire
rework is gonna be great
i had a moment of like have i not even touched this mage's health
this exiled mage
uh room of research
hardly knew ye
uh when is frozen enemies
uh when is frozen enemies shatter like in d2p are you gonna come oh yeah we're working on it
working on it because yeah
that is that is necessary isn't it i don't mean this facetiously or joking like yeah i agree
because because it because it is really sweet
the visual feeling uh there's there's some
was it like the narnia movies or something
it was like a really visceral like ice shattering moment in a movie i saw a while ago that was
i can see it i don't know what it's from anyways i want that
uh are you planning on making monoliths longer right now i feel like i am spending more
time sorting loot between them actually slaying monsters yeah some of the um so like so the
cemeteries are fairly big um so yeah some of these the new echoes will be some of them will
be bigger some of them will be smaller um
um
yeah there's a few options in there
oh nice nice added damage there
thank you very much master sword that is 47 months in a row my goodness next month's a big one
one
you look we got to start commemorating these huge ones somehow nutty nutty love it uh will there be any
change or updates to the graphics setting options uh any change at all i think so
there's a bunch of changes that happen to the settings panel
i should be in an easier space so i'm not even to actually not die uh how many uh new big bad
bosses being put into the new season a small handful
when season two starts can we get some sort of skip or factions like we do for alts now
uh first first characters on fresh loads will have to play through the game normally and get to the
uh get to the factions normally and and unlock them in the storyline where they're supposed to be
like it's it's a lot of power to to unlock them early
and the experience game that you're getting early on in the game is so small that it doesn't make much
difference as far as like leveling them up early or anything like that
right any updates for minion survivability uh i mean
dots they'll be much they'll be more resilient to dots in general
so yeah there's also like individual stuff for lots of different minions
uh are you ever gonna make more co-op dungeons or even something like wow raids
ever is a long time ever is a long time we don't have any plans and season two won't have any
um and i think we're getting to the point where we have a like substantial amount of content where
um adding something like this is much more viable than it used to be i think there was probably a
problem in the past where uh we didn't have enough stuff to do enough activities that if we said
hey here's here's here's dev time here's resources we put into making a um a specific
thing like a a content that requires minimum two people everyone who plays solo or just doesn't have
any friends to play with or doesn't want to play with anyone else or you know like for whatever
reason they're playing solo um is just like it's just content they just like can't do it's just not
available to them even as they even if they want about how much they wanted it's not there for them
and it's i think that's something that we wanted to avoid spending too much time on in the past
but we are getting i think to a more reasonable position of content where if like say we had 10
activities and one of them was uh co-op only that's that's a very different ratio than having 20
activities and one of them being couple you know like it's um it's all about that that that activity
ratio um i think after season two we're gonna be a much better place i don't know if it's enough or
not but uh it's a it's a note nothing for now but who knows what the future will bring situation
i guess i'm supposed to know there's another point
all right i i will say that there's i've had some uh there's been some boss design meetings that uh or
ideas that have been i've seen that have required multiple people that i've really liked the ideas
behind so i would love to try it just personal note all right what new elements are being added to
these sentinel skills like conversions new conversions a lot of new void conversions getting added in um
sub skills are getting new conversions uh mostly fire and lightning stuff
and void stuff but we're not we're not adding in like a new element into sentinel package like we're
not adding cold stuff into sentinel heavily we're not adding necrotic stuff into sentinel heavily um yeah
are you now chilling for two weeks what's the team doing no we're not chilling for two weeks we are
so we're in a stage now where the we're like content locked um and anything that's gonna go into
we still still lots of work to do um so a lot of it is just testing and polishing right now where
we're like playing playing the game as much as we can internally just making sure we're catching little
annoyance points and little bugs and things where it's like really low risk just feel good fixes um
that we can get in if they're if they're like blockers we'll try and make sure they're stable enough
to push in for the actual launch build if they're uh just nice to have stuff we'll get them in a hot
fix early on in the first few days you know that sort of stuff so like we are the stuff you see in
in a lot of the hot fixes that will come out in the first few days um will be stuff that we're working
on now it doesn't stop it comes it calms down a bit though it calms down a bit which is really nice
i knew i was standing outside that no problem
oh i thought i was gonna answer a bunch of questions thought i was saved took my hands off the keyboard and mouse
oh so good oh i am that that that serves me right perfectly
oh
how do we unlock the secret lizard level that doesn't look like anything to me
uh if symbols of hope is now casted automatically how will orient seal interact with the skill it
increases the rate that it casts at um so you it increases the the auto cast frequency
unwavering fate doesn't scale with amount of symbols then
definitely not opening this image back up so i can read what it actually says
activating symbols now heals you for a portion of your maximum health
uh it doesn't look like it does but
i would expect it to maybe it may not scale with the number of symbols
the way the node's written it doesn't scale but i would have to check to make sure that's
how it actually functions to be sure
let's go get that unique up there uh any chance a minion skill like raise specter and peewee oh my
gosh having like we're talking about the like like clones right like having copies of existing of
enemies as minions like uh like d2 revive and um we've we've talked about this a few times internally
we've we've batted around the idea a little bit um the way that our enemy abilities and enemy systems
are set up it's it's a very tricky thing to do um and we're not jumping on something like that just
yet we've we've batted this idea around a few times though and things that get batted around come back
usually at least i hope so all right with the stash taps things tabs lag that happens from time to
time especially when one character has a lot will be optimized yes coming up you can hold your breath
on this no a couple weeks still isn't it uh more search and sorting function not much right now but
it's something we're working on uh may have missed it in the interviews do set shards need the same base
as it was taken from or can i uh take that meteor it is now electric and throw it on a shield instead
of a staff sorry for the names that's a bit of a drones um it does require the same base type it
does not require the same subtype so for example um let's say we had oh let's say this was a set item
um and it was because it's on a great wood coat and that's the subtype is a great wood coat
um you could pull the shard off and put it onto any primalist body armor it would not be required to be a
a um specifically a great wood coat so the it's like this like this is required to be a one-handed sword
not necessarily to be a serrated tooth um which is confusing because it's a specific one for this
item it's a bad example um but yes it is required to still be a staff so you can only use um
lightning meteor when you're wielding a staff specifically
um assuming that assuming that that is the mod that gets pulled from the item
big big asterisk there
because we haven't unveiled which affixes are being taken from each enemy oh thank you very
much we've got another sub
i'm gonna ruin this name and i apologize now
uh second tabula
it's probably it's probably there's capitalizations there i swear
and i'm gonna i'm gonna see it and be like that makes so much more sense
i can't find it i'm sorry i've ruined it everything thank you very much for the sub appreciate it
uh next question why don't you choose more skills and uniques faster
takes a long time to make them the short answer
uh ggg is putting more than 100 uniques and support gems plus 25 skills in three months 12 months
uh in in nine months you've only introduced one new skill and it's coming next patch
all right i think this is two questions in one it is two questions in one i it takes a long time
we're adding stuff as fast as we can um there's advantages and disadvantages to both where skill
systems are set up for speed in different situations um
i would argue they've got a much i don't know i don't have a good i don't have a good like
this is the difference in workflow that i can call to because i've
knew what their workflow looks like um
but yeah they're adding a whole lot
i still help you on that don't hit that
connected in thank you for the gifted sub appreciate you all right next question here
will ailment damage ever be good for big hitting skills possibly um and like some big hitting skills
have lots of individual hits anyways and those ones it's really good for as well
um base damage ratio let's get we already answered this question
all right we are 45 minutes behind 35 minutes behind
all right any plans to show item filter colors to items within the inventory we
don't really have the option for this at the moment um it is something that we're trying to
get a good solution for though helmets and body armor the weaver will come helmets and
body armor with weavers will come anytime soon it's on the list
oh
i forgot to the last one too
all right here's here's a little a little little sneak peek
uh this is the i i talked about this yesterday i just drew on the screen it looked terrible so this
is what it actually looks like um we are adding a corruption display to uh the monolith map panel
so you will be able to at a glance tell which timelines are at which corruption
uh and yes these are definitely legit achieved corruption numbers that were not manually typed in
at all i promise
thanks jesson
all right the set item crafting is one of the things i'm looking forward to the most me too
are there any specific set bonuses that required an overhaul that you're looking forward to playing with
no a couple of them required minor tweaks we like we nudged a few numbers up and things like that
but there weren't any that were like oh this one needs to be just changed completely i don't think
yeah there were there were like there was a few base affixes we changed
like base item things we changed there wasn't a ton of changes we made to most of them
um a few number tweaks here and there one i think affix got switched out completely
but you know for the most part set items are relatively they'll be pretty familiar the items
themselves
all right well we see procedurally generated general procedural generation used in the campaign
slash mono maps not talking about side areas uh it is something that we are looking to expand this
system into the um uh the the system we're starting off with in just the tombs and the
cemeteries is like it's the first time we're using it we we got it in in time to make this work and it's
we're gonna learn a lot from the implementation here and then we're gonna push that out to other
parts of the game uh as it is useful and it's going to be very useful uh tour spear thank you very
much for the sub appreciate it also yeah if you have a question please put our last epoch game in
the question so i see it in chat um i know i'm really far behind i apologize i'm answering them
quickly if if i can get through all these i will do my best we're only seven pages behind on this
this document uh that's quite far behind whoops
all right might need to rapid fire some of these i would just look look at look at my shiny raptors and
and helmet look how pretty yeah did we get it oh we got we got my bite so this little little
easter egg uh every minion in the game oh most minion types in the game have uh specific names they can
randomly be assigned um so raptors one of them is bite bite mr fibble thank you for the 16 months
appreciate you all right have the team at each you considered making some end game combined affixes to
help with difficulty gearing in the end game compared to legendary crafting like fire damage
plus fire resistance or health plus armor um yes you're gonna see some new affixes available on
items that didn't have them available before through set items now um so there's some cool stuff like that
there which is sweet are you able to show us was the in action i'm not the client i'm on does not have
wasdi available i'm sorry it does not uh it's it's it's not a huge it is a beta system still it feels
great for people who really want wasd in the game um the like it doesn't add new functionality to your
abilities so like what you can do is the same on keyboard and mouse and wasdy uh is there any is
there going to be mechanical interaction changes to main damage skills like a racing strike and
forge strike apart from the numerical changes that should offset the vr rework yes uh will the new
faction bring an alternate method to leveling weaver pieces yes some builds can't support taking off key
pieces of the weaver in that slot yes there's a new rune that does this uh will there be any changes to
prophecies yes one of the biggest pains is not having high high level base types able to be targeted
only some bases are offered um i can't speak to this specific change off the top of my head but we
are making changes to some prophecies yes uh thank you very much
another name i'm going to butcher and i apologize now
that that has definitely got some capitals in there doesn't it uh plots's runder hintern
i wish i was better at this this is like the i wish i could just like practice i should just
go hang out in random streams and just practice saying people's names to myself out loud
is that something that people do
all right uh hi mike love the game have season two hi me too uh when i use evade often he's jumping
me back to where i evaded from is this a known issue or just me there are this is something that i have
seen reports of um i i do not know i i wish i had a yes i guarantee this has been fixed i i've never
experienced this myself um but i know it was big enough and prominent enough that i know people were
working on it at least it'll be in the patch notes if it's if it's fixed i hope it is if anyone is
listening that did fix this that knows please let me know all right hi mike how do you enjoy oh hi john
how do you enjoy working on last epoch i love it um and not just because it's my boss asking me this
yes fantastic it's one of those jobs that you kind of think about as a kid and you're like
haha wouldn't that be cool and then it happens and you're like yep definitely real
all right in the upcoming season the sentinel can hold a two-handed weapon with a shield this
does also mean a two-handed weapon and an off-handed sword can be used at the same time no it is very
explicit in the wording uh you can use a non-staff two-handed weapon in your main hand and a shield
in your offhand and it has to be specifically that combination so it is fairly narrow it is spear two-handed
axe two-handed sword two-handed mace uh one of those four items and a shield no catalyst no quiver
no bow no staff no wand
no scepter
love the meteor one all right we know forge guard gets a pinnacle passive node for two
mana shield plus shield at the same time our vk and paladin getting pinnacle passives too uh
there's some shakeups in the trees
do i know where these nodes are off the top of my head i don't know where the nodes are on the top of my
head
i don't think i don't think they're specifically at the top necessarily it doesn't mean they're any less
awesome though
so some of the some of the best nodes are near the bottom of the tree
like that a void knight one that just scales everything based on the number of points you
have invested in the tree so good uh hello uh there hello there just want to say adding
uh price checking to the inventory is the way torchlight infinite does it would help a lot i
presume price checking is the most annoying thing in fortune's guild at the moment yeah that would be
so nice to have price checking in the inventory oh my god it'd be great
uh anyway we can purchase or earn a second stash chest reward for beating eyebrows for example
uh like are you running out of your 200 stash tabs is not enough is that what i'm hearing
um we don't have any plans to to to crank that up even higher but
you know if we if there's if there's a really good need for it we can consider it we are pulling um
um we are pulling keys out of your stash so you'll have a little bit more rooms uh freed up for next season
or is this
are you asking on earning a second reward drop for the kill
oh you can uh respond and i'll try and find you in chat if this is asking about a second if it's
if it's a second reward for the kill at like for one kill we don't have that planned i don't think
that's what it's asking maybe though i love that
all right
i just left the name here very very mr ben diesel asks love the name uh what are your thoughts on
bringing seasonal uniques to the game that are built defining for that season like having a unique
that turns fireball into a void ball that spins around your uh your ball lighting i think that um
removing an item from the game that's a tough one
so my my initial reaction is i love the idea i think it'd be great i i think i would really
enjoy something like that personally my second reaction is like how well would that go over
ah i don't think that would go over i think either the item ends up being something people don't like
and therefore is inconsequential it doesn't matter or something people really like and are sad when it
goes away
i don't know maybe if it was like always scheduled to turn into something else or something
and then like depending on what happened in the season some like community effort it like changed
one of three outcomes or something i feel like there have to be something like that predetermined
i don't know
looks like we may have got a reply on the previous question already that'd be sweet
oh no longer in chat sorry bud
here's an item i love talking about uniques that i love
i love this unique because it does cool stuff to know the unique does
really like this unique all right is sentinel's passive tree getting a complete rework not a complete rework now
uh just about half the passes will change uh i don't have a fixed number sorry um
how much better will it be in comparison to what it is now so subjective uh
at least one better
sorry uh what is the design direction for shaman currently it seems torn between three different
archetypes yeah
it does it does have access to a fair few things what's the third i guess the spellcasting stuff
i don't know i always i always feel spellcasting stuff kind of bleeds into druid a bit
uh this is like where we tried to put it but shapeshifting is so prominent there that it's
uh it's kind of taken over a bit um
it's getting that mix of the my personal uh like touchstone base for a shaman archetype is a wow shaman
um specifically enhance shaman is what i played ah well then i switched to healing for a long time but
apart from healing um like an enhanced shaman i feel like was a lot of fun to level as and and getting a lot of the a lot of the totems are
end up being just kind of like buffs and you're basically just a sort of an alternate melee character
i don't know if that's a bad thing
hey you got an lp on that that's nice
the zerk kicking in strong
i think we're gonna see shaman lean into totems uh and melee a lot more
how much love is hammer throw getting the new sentinel stuff i'm sorry i don't really have a
lot of good specifics for like hey this node's getting buffed this much or or like this this
specific archetype's getting this much love and this one's getting buffed more than that one or something
like that uh there's uh some feel and functionality stuff we just tweaked on on hammer throw uh
uh and i know some new functionality we just added
but all the specifics i can go into uh can you share anything on other char on the other charm we
don't know about uh it'll be it's an either or thing so you'll be picking that if you want to go
through the dungeon itself and enhance the dungeon experience
so it is an either or option that might be new info
oh what's the chance of us getting a crossover with stranger things since david however is a huge fan
he brings uh vekna as a boss we could have to kill i mean i i'd love to once once again that's like that's
dnd vekna's dnd right
someone tell me i'm not crazy here
that's not strange things specifically that's that's wizards isn't it
yes i'm gonna confirm that's wizards okay cool um
i i i same answers for i'd love to uh i think it'd be incredible and amazing all these sorts of
like dream come true moments but like i don't see the uh i don't see the appeal from their side of
things as much so i i'd say it'd be a hard fought a hard fought thing to get
you know like when um
it's this it's this it's kind of a bad example because it's the same owner of the ip
but when like magic did uh i guess lord of the rings crossover there we go it's it's because they're both
so huge you know like lord of the rings gets a bump from magic and magic gets a bump from lord of
the rings so it's like they they help each other none of them really get a huge bump from us
one day one day we will have a grand enough game that they will relish the opportunity
dead cells got a castle of any crossover that's cool i did not know that i was just just trying
out dead cells recently love it uh regarding balancing does the patch include any general
balance pass on skills not necessarily sentinel dated oh yeah oh yeah lots so there's um more
mechanical heavy things done to sentinel than the other classes but the other classes definitely have
you know like if there's if there's certain nodes that are just like going completely unused and
everyone's like oh what's the point of this you know like we'll look to try and buff a little bit
or if there's nodes that are like ubiquitous and completely overpowered because they're just like
one point wonders that take your defenses into the stratosphere then they're getting nerfed you know
things like that so we're um we are trying to give more viable options across the board
still just one
there's a lot going on in there it doesn't feel safe at all
i should really have a stricter loot filter
will minion necro and beastmaster get any better rework and second what do lizard what will lizard
tail do um i'd say necro and beastmaster will be a bigger focus uh for us next season than this season
um there's still some stuff in there for them for sure but uh i would expect to see more later
um there is there is a very there is one necro build that i can tell you will be very powerful
uh specifically
at least i shouldn't say that much confidence i i have a feeling there'll be a really good necro build
uh
pretty boss
number six thank you for the sub appreciate it
uh
and i have no idea what lizard tails are i don't know what you're talking about no clue uh when
developing new skills and balance changes are there things that you think that could be extremely
overpowered but only with very specific scenarios that you leave in the game because you don't
think anyone will find them hmm no uh i i fully expect anything that we found you to find too
i i don't think there's a world where we can like sneak things like that into the game
i think that yeah you you all are so good at finding
like very strong combinations that i don't think there's a way we can we would
yeah
uh built not bought we are looking at youtube chat i promise you
i'm not looking at it directly but i'm hardly looking at twitch chat directly either i've seen
like three messages from it but kane is pulling questions from both i am just really far behind
i've got a document with seven pages of questions on it that i am uh rolling through at 10.5 font
that i'm rolling through as fast as i can here oh here here's what we're going to do we are going to take
a gameplay break
i'm just going to answer rapid fire questions here uh when developing new skills and balance
changes are though answer that uh what are some skills some types of skills you personally love
to see in the game you can pull from other games or something you think of on your own i mean this
this is tricky because i'm on the skill design team so like the things that i'd really love to see
uh frequently eventually end up in the game um i'd really like to see i'd really like to see some
abilities that are um not possible right now because of some weapons that we don't have in the game so
like uh fist weapons or like crossbows um you know like things like that where there's like weapons
types that we don't really have in the game yet um
um that i'd like to see some thematic skills that go with those really nicely
but i don't really want to say them because i i'm pitching them right now uh what are some types of
skills you'd personally love to say is that uh any plans to add uniques to interact with storm totem more
yes uh for example the second totem or ability to shadow the storm totem for a massive lightning
explosion those are both great ideas uh is there any chance we might see a rework or polish to the
skill upgrade lagonian diplomacy so that it targets things better uh it's a gathering storm node
thank you for that tip uh i know where gathering storm is on the tree it's right there
uh we're wielding a staff the melee attack gathering storm is replaced by a direct range oh yes this one
is on um there was we changes there's something we changed recently on this
there was some there was animation changes we did for this i think and there was something else
we changed recently too i'm gonna go with yes is the answer uh hello mike can't wait for season two
keep up the good job thank you uh you do with last epoch will with changes to set items and set
charge crafting how will cof bonus dropping the whole set instead of one be balanced
i it already is balanced uh so it won't change it's it's you just drop the whole set
uh yeah uh do you guys the that uh that bonus for dropping the set items was kind of put in
knowing that we were going to do something like this um and people like it's useless and terrible
and we're like yeah it is now but it will be good and now it's being good uh do you guys plan
on doing public ptrs in the future like how diablo 4 does it maybe we've got a ct program a community
tester program that we really really like um we probably want to open it up a little bit more
we're still working on how we're going to do that it's it's it's tricky um yeah
no specific details but we are planning on revamping that system for us
ah hi what's your stance on snapshotting minions with gear fixable um it is
it's a really frustrating problem
uh we've we've experimented with some different ways of fixing it um
um falcon fixes it decently well but it has a lot of advantages that we can't use for regular minions
um so we're we're working on it all right got an idea for we're at the 130 mark or the 330 mark
so it's uh we're 45 minutes behind still in chat so i apologize if i haven't gotten your question yet
i've got an idea for a question while you've talked about elemental damage does it make sense
to make similar thing for necrotic poison void damage something that can be corrupted damage
i've literally pitched that exact thing before we're not doing it yet uh any plans on letting
us change what means look like yes uh there will be minion cosmetics eventually i don't think there
is any for season two drop though all right and and there are some times uh there's there's
items that change as well like um uh something's a little out of the effects to it or um there's
some of their skills uh like like the saber tooth when you take the cold nodes and the saber
two that changes the cold saber tooth uh last if i can we get a sell all button ah we need to have
a lock button first for locking items in your inventory we don't have that at the moment so
maybe in the future not season two uh what are the cocooned uniques they are cool uniques they're new
uh the ones shown in the season two trailer uh stay tuned to the itemization podcast that we will
reveal that in uh any plans to allow the complete reset of all monolith progression
um you can do this pretty quickly oh like complete reset of all progression uh no
if you really want to do this like it's kind of like make a solo character um
or or or start the new season when it starts type thing
uh any chance we could get xp per hour when you hover over the xp bar like peewee 2 has
hold on a break like me yeah um i don't think that's unreasonable uh we don't have time for season
two to put it in right now but uh i i like that idea i think it's cool uh hey mike any thoughts on
implementing an achievement system either for in-game or through steam oh yes we've been brainstorming
achievement ideas and cool things to get people on for uh what's up mike hello can we get a bit more
parity between movement skills right now you get some over terrain through walls others do not for
instance you leap are currently the leap you are currently using won't leap up ridges but the acolyte
transplant will yeah um and other ones will go right through walls all together sometimes we we are
the way part of it is the problem that the way that the they they each try to figure out if it's
a legal place to leap to or teleport to um i think it does make a lot of sense that thematically
they have slightly different functionality um mechanically it is very frustrating i can i see
where you're coming from so it's it's a good discussion topic but there's nothing changing to it right away
all right if it can be commented will the new update for controller allow aiming with the right
stick and movement with the left stick in any capacity uh no it doesn't do that
i don't know if this question has been asked before
uh sorry if it did it's okay will there be some new things during the campaign you know just to spice up
a bit yeah um for example the champions uh appear in the campaign
all right any possibility for mtx for transformations uh you buy wherebear mtx instantly yeah uh we are
working on mtx transformations there are none available in season two uh they're they're one of the things
where it's like each each transformation ntx is the amount of work of like 10 15 other ones so it's um
especially early on we're like how many can we get into the game and we can we can put some in
that you can that can be affected by you when you're still in transformed mode because you're
triggering other abilities so you can still take advantage of it when you're transformed um
yeah it's it's it's not in the first wave but yes we we do we have mtx we have cosmetic
um visual changes and audio changes to uh every every ability type planned
uh most of the armor mtx looks like it was designed on an acolyte or a sork a lot of them
the model weirdly on a primalist are you guys going to design armor mtx using a primalist the base or
thought of it um the they all get uh all all of the cosmetics are individually made for each one
like so they are that there's like a it's a it's an actual different model that's on the primalist it's
not a stretched model um but i don't know how the uh the base design process happens for that i would
assume it's on a on a generic uh none of them piece like it's not any one of them individually
but maybe it's closer to one of the other ones i don't know
hello good to see you good to see you too quick question why there is no option to set skills to the
left middle mouse button when changing the hotkeys uh the left mouse button is pretty it it's reserved
for a lot of functions that uh it probably still live uh it's reserved for a lot of functions that
we don't want to override um you can set an ability to your left mouse click here so uh let me do this and
i mean i'm i'm left clicking when i do that
so it is like it is it is possible to to set an ability there
uh middle mouse i'm not sure why it's not an option and i realize that uh you can't see me when
i did that example but i promise you it worked i did get frenzy
yeah um in the future would we ever be able to get a system to combine unwanted idols to re-roll to
a new idol like a recombination for idols um i i think that's possible um it's not something we're
adding right now but i do like the idea and it's i've have heard it pitched before
uh with the updates to electrify and time rock coming are there any plans to take a look at the
other damaging ailments to make them more varied uh currently bleeding knight and frostbite and poison are so
mechanically similar that the optimal way to use all of them is just the same just apply as many stacks as possible
and it's pretty boring um
i i yes do you have any good examples i'd really love to hear the specific examples on this
um the time rot overhaul is in season two um and i think that's a really good example of finding a way to
a way to do one of them um but yeah the if you got any ideas for the other ones i'm all ears
all right uh one thing i realized today i don't know if it has been mentioned yet stash is usually
organized by item type because we got filters for that but for every item type a row gets left empty
at the bottom yes uh if i fill the stash tab with boots for example there will be a single row left
which is not enough for boots is possible to add one more row uh it's a huge pain to add one more
roll row and we absolutely should have originally i don't know if we can fix this or not but it's
yes uh please yes please please please please
all right how many total points in the weaver tree will we get and how many the total points are in the
tree we haven't said this yet um i don't know off the top of my head you'll you'll have fewer you'll
have less than half the number of points you will be able to invest less than half the number of points
i can say that so you're gonna have to make some some hard choices on what you actually want to go for
um and there's a there's a fair few options
uh right it's it's a it's a big enough tree that you have to the window scrolls like the
window scrolls around it's not you can't see all of them on one window
all right hey mike what's up with the judgment gloves equip level being 20 levels before you unlock
the skill uh it's just there's other stats in there that are uh that are good to use and
i i don't think there was any big big thing about it it is kind of funny though uh anything that will
make it easier to distinguish my pets from enemies i mean the the health bars if you really want to
distinguish your pets from enemies the health bars are the best way to do it i think um
there we go minions get green health bars your enemies get red health bars
uh how are spires changing can you say more they're going to be uh i don't know how to say
exactly what it is they're going to be much more um
localized and uh interesting encounters
yeah
uh what is the average spawn rate for nemesis i'm curious to know around what my chances are i've
encountered them since if i go 3-3 into faded nemesis weaver node
um i don't know what the base spawn rate is i know that when you're at like um
like extreme corruption numbers it's it is almost every echo
uh any chance that other classes will be added to act as exiled mage alternatives like exiled powder
or exiled lich uh the way that they're there um like the the reason that they're there doesn't make
any sense for other classes so probably not um i would love to i mean this is uh i see where the
the this is something that has been suggested a few times and i understand based on what happened
yesterday why this question is getting asked today um and i think that there's a good opportunity for
things like it in the future but uh the whole reason exiled mages exist and the theming the story
behind that is it wouldn't really make sense for other classes uh is there any plans for improving
minion control particularly for melee minions it's possible to keep them from running into big boss
attacks um not specifically but they're really really durable to area of effect attacks
uh will all items uh have parity between two and three d models uh i mean that's the goal we make
2d items way faster than we make 3d items um so it's the idea of slowing down the 3d item production
or the 2d item production in order to let 3d item um catch up uh feels very counterintuitive to me for
uh just having a fun game so probably not anytime soon but that is the goal uh hi any plans on
implementing dlss or the and the latest fsr uh i i don't know specifically if that's going to happen
or not i know it's on the list uh i don't think it's coming in season two are champion bosses going to be
real bosses with mechanics or they essentially beefed up rare mods um they do have specific
mechanics they they are like it's not just like any minion can be championed they are specific
boss encounters more mini boss encounters um but they do have like bespoke mechanics and abilities
and things that they do that are thematically appropriate and uh are reflected in the affixes
they drop and things like that hey mike it's me again welcome back uh any chance we can add the
extra passives and idle slots to dungeon completion i i i would prefer to add them to the uh monolith
completion quests personally um but yeah that's a chance uh any chance for heart seeker to become both
throwing and ranged per default uh i assume this is asking about throwing and bow like have both tags
simultaneously no definitely not uh would you guys consider revisiting some current season mechanics
say two years from now maybe the team wanted to do more things with the weaver expansion but couldn't
squeeze it in absolutely um i i think you won't have to wait that long uh what is the issue team
approach to balancing player agency against build power levels as a discussion point the team often
says they don't want to have non-interactive builds which are also s tier to me proactively adjusting or
limiting this for example reflect damage seems like a huge trade-off for the ability to player to
choose certain kinds of skills can you hear your thoughts um i think that yeah so in general we're
much more in favor of of kind of just like letting letting putting putting stuff out there into the
world and and seeing what happens let's let's see what what wacky and cool stuff you guys can come up
with that's sort of the um the best case scenario uh sometimes there are uh in very rare cases builds
that pop up that are really really boring to play like like and we're talking extreme cases that we that
we try and limit these in so like let's say there was a build that um you could you could you take
this build it was it was pretty easy to make uh and you could take this build into into uber abroth
and you could beat uber abroth no matter what like guaranteed win success no problem you can literally
walk away from your computer but it takes 12 hours and we're talking hyperbole example here this is a
stupid example it's not real but like that's bad that's that is you like having 12 hours to kill
something like if it's the objectively easiest way to do it where you're like okay i got these items
together put my character i stepped into the ring and i left and i came back tomorrow and i beat the
boss great it it kind of devalues the achievement the accomplishment um
um and it's just it's boring sitting there for that long so it's like um i i think that it's a
in the extreme cases is is when we really try and steer away from it
uh also i missed these ago but burt popcorn and
undread one thank you for the subs i appreciate you both and they all go to charity
all right oh something in my eye
spilling ginger ale on my play mat oh my goodness
all right any thoughts on lowering the skill level requirements the last three skills by five levels
uh 20 to 15 35 to 30 50 to 45 probably not um
um they're the like passive requirements not levels but generally you get that from levels and
and
idris thank you very much the sub appreciate you too
um i would say it's very unlikely um it is something that we do look at and adjust so there
could be some tweaks and things like that um you are talking about specialization points aren't you not
the actual skill unlocks i think looking at what those numbers are um still probably pretty unlikely
but it's possible i don't know if this exists in the game but has there been any thoughts to doing
group up maps or modifiers scale based on the number of people in the party well the modifiers do scale
based on the number of people in the party um like it just when you group up stuff gets harder in general
like and it's just it's a flat scaler so everything affects it um and we've we have talked about
uh you know other other multiplayer specific mechanics and things like that that's something
that we've we've discussed and it's possible it's not something we're looking at right away yet but you
know uh i'd i would love to do mechanically specific multiplayer things where it's like
like the the fight's not really uh like required to do as a group but like i don't know some some
cool thing happens the example i always go back to is diablo 2 diablo you're fighting him he like there's
a big like bone prison cage that like comes up and like grabs a player and like another player can like
uh beat the cage and it uh breaks it open and then you can keep playing again and it's this like
there's this teamwork moment and like it almost never happens and all that sort of stuff but uh i do
really like the idea behind things like that all right any word on a ps5 release we'd love to do
consoles we don't have any specific info on which consoles uh when consoles anything like that yet but
it is something that we are looking into and we would love to see move forward we just don't have
any details at all i'm sorry all right we are still 45 minutes behind but we only have
five pages of questions in the backlog hey oh getting better
i'm just i just got i just gotta burn through these these are it's it's great i'm sorry i'm
not really doing anything more exciting on screen to do a dance at the same time
uh are there plans to make bosses mechanically more interesting and difficult at higher
difficulties like empowered monoliths rather than just percentage boost two stats i think boss
fights evolving with difficulty isn't amazing um and is amazing and much more interesting absolutely yeah
i agree heavy yes i agree um i'd love to
i'm working on it don't worry uh hey mike i had an idea on whether we could
uh be able to change the base item and slash of unique slash legend they're using this using an
in-game mechanic like a temporal sanctum wondering if this is something that could work be too powerful
or even be possible um the way that our uh unique the way their item system works changing the base
type of an item would require us to create that item as a base type for that unique um and have it
kind of sitting in the background not doing anything we have had uniques that have had multiple base
types and since have removed i think removed all the multiple base type variations for unique so that
they're all just one now um it's possible i could see it coming back uh i think it would be like
specific options having it be any option would require a pretty massive change the way the item is
built um it's not impossible pretty unlikely though uh can class specific set bonuses be used by other classes no
um mostly because you won't be able to equip the item in the first place because there will be a class
requirement on the item uh like you could uh if you could get the items all equipped uh the class
bonuses and you could get that that that ability to proc somehow like if you um uh i guess so
hypothetically here's here's one uh yeah actually yes it would work so here's an example of one that
would work uh if you have the harbinger of stars belt and hypothetically if the lodger staff does have
the um i mean you can do this now actually can't you is the staff class locked even now
i don't have one um if the staff's not class locked you can do it now um
but yeah like the sitting under everything uh sitting on this um on this character right now
is the mutator for meteor uh and if you get the stat if this character somehow got an item equipped
onto it that had the stat uh lightning conversion for meteor it would work and then if if this character
somehow had ability to trigger meteor like the belt it would trigger and work for it so it is
hypothetically possible um i don't know if that staff is class locked and i'm not confirming or not
if the if that mod is moving over or not
and i realized that i'm
zooming in and stuff on a character that you guys can't see
see
here we go you can see me hi i think i have one more i think i have one more teaser
we're just gonna shove that one up i think this is new hope it's new
all right uh will we get class reworks for season three again or is the you pleased with the current
classes specialization um i think the
i think the changes required for
there are certain there are certain classes that i think are in more need of love than other classes
right now in the game even i i want season two launches a little bit there'll be some that are
more better than others um and so we will be looking at specific ones to get more changes more
mechanical changes than others um but i think it'll be less a lower scope than the sentinel one that was
just done and we'll be looking to add more new things in the future instead
any plans to give players a possibility to cover less rare shards to convert less rare shards into
more rare shards at a ratio or something yes we are planning this um we have way too many regular
shards on our hands and in game yeah we are we're working on a shard conversion system where you can
trade in shards uh in mana strike with 100 spark charge nodes with the left side mana arc skill node
does mana arc also have 100 spark charge chance mana arc affected by mana strike nodes uh question mark
i'd have to double check uh i i'd have to double check exactly how it's worded
can we check quickly can we check quickly mana art
mana arc creative and mana storm cost less increase kit
mana storm mana strike additionally strikes enemies it hits with mana arc yeah this should
yeah
this should inherit everything
because it's it specifically says mana strike additionally strikes enemies so it's mana strike
that's doing the striking which means that it is inheriting things that mana strike already has
unless it's worded wrong it works
uh what's the ultimate goal with the sentinel rework to make more fun and viable options with higher variety
in available abilities
uh will we be able to search ex accepted prophecies i don't think so uh will you get different set
shards for each piece of the set or will the weapon set item always give you this uh give you the weapon
such the weapon such the weapon from the set item will always give you the weapon set chart yeah like so
if you break down uh if you have a set that has like a few pieces
like
okay so if you put the like the gloves if you break down the gloves
for xeric's gloves you'll never get xeric's belt
set chart you'll always get xeric's gloves set chart
uh any plans to improve and my goodness i'm wow i actually got that mostly
mostly on screen not quite there we go
oh
any plans to improve npc models yeah there's lots of npc models that got changes yeah
uh a bit confusing question about merchant scale but since there isn't really a good way to remove
gold from the game as the season goes on it just gets traded between players causing prices to rise
up any plans to address that in the next patches i would encourage people to go to the
lightless arbor there's you can have tons of uh sweet items dropped from there yeah
uh any chance we get avalanche and earthquake totems and variations for them
uh so we get full totem on so we so we can go full totem on these nodes i think yeah i think that's
something that we are looking into for future releases but yes
i i wouldn't i i don't want to say okay i shouldn't say yes explicitly but i think there's
uh a very good argument for those things
all right any major balance changes for warlock or mostly balance changes around war generation
mostly around war generation there's some nodes that were overperforming that are getting a little
bit of a nerve um the sweet new unique item though uh any thoughts on any chance thoughts on changing
corruption scaling to increase exponentially rather than linearly i think we're doing uh
uh it's still gonna be linear but the multiplier is changing
i think
i think that's what we're doing so it's not one to one anymore but it is still linear it's just not
like changing this to like this you know still linear but it's well if i could draw straight it'd be
linear um but you know changing changing the the slope of it i don't know why i raised those first
all right any plans to unlock the game for steam family share no it causes a lot of problems of things
we don't have control over that we just can't do um it it there's there's things that the steam family
share does that like steam would have to change how family share works for us to re-enable it i think
um yeah which i i do not expect them to change it at all at all all right was the jump in difficulty
between monolith bosses and harbingers adjusted um
in a roundabout way yes
i mean technically no but in effect yes i like your your the average character power level will
be higher at that point in the game so you'll um you'll have an easier time making that transition
um but it's still it's still a decent jump
i know we have a bunch of b uniques we are running low on time here catch i think we're
going to stop taking questions fairly soon um i'm trying to get through as many we've devolved
into just a straight question answer stream instead of me playing which is fine uh and i
hope i hope you guys are liking it still but um i do have a lot of questions to get through here still
uh i know we have a bunch of b uniques how about some growl uniques yeah like turn bear into some
girl love it love it yes please sign me up um nothing coming in season two sorry uh if there was one
feature change you're most proud of that the team achieved for this update what would it be
uh procedural generation definitely
uh i can say that because i had nothing to do with it
uh if there was one feature change uh will we get more freedom on some weapons like bows
or new weapons like crossbows yeah um season two doesn't have a ton of this um but we are definitely
looking forward to new weapon types new weapon base types um i think a lot of those will come
with new classes uh or new abilities that go with them specifically things like that but yes we are
actively looking at new uh new weapon types in the future uh will primal ancient hunt be more be
a model of activity or separate system like arena dungeons um it is not implemented uh i don't have
any specific details on it and even though i did i probably couldn't share them um
so i'm sorry i'm gonna have to skip this one uh are you guys working on sounds for drops in the
loot filter kind of like how peewee does it uh i'm i'm working on it uh in the sense of uh pitching it
still over and over and over so keep suggesting it in our suggestions forums and discord channels
and places that you can suggest it uh do you see any set items being relevant to use the item itself
at base slot or all the set items now just basically pinata for affixes no i do think that there's going to
be situations uh where you'll want to use the base set item more than before specifically because
you'll be able to access the set um the set bonus for that set item a lot cheaper so the opportunity
cost right now of accessing a set bonus so if there's a set bonus you want um the opportunity
cost of accessing that set bonus is three pieces right um and if there's a or two pieces in some cases
if there's a uh so this is a set item there's a specific affix on a set item that you want it's
like a really powerful set affix um sometimes you will uh like what you're what you're getting out of
that set item sometimes isn't enough to make it worthwhile putting in your build but you can look
at it a little bit differently now in the sense that the opera the the the amount of space that that set
item is taking up in your build is now maybe one set item and two affixes on other items and then
you're getting then you can look at like the set item and the set bonus that it brings all as one
thing and the opportunity cost is so much lower that you're much more likely to uh to want to pick
up that set item and i do i understand the quite i kind of i misspoke a little bit here when i said um
actually didn't misspeak but i kind of implied that i was talking about the set bonus instead of the
actual affix on the item itself because there's going to be some set item affixes that don't get
pulled over with the set shards themselves um which will still be very desirable to have on the item
and the reason that they're balanced is they're balanced around having other crappy affixes on the
item um so there's though some of those affixes needed to stay on the set items in order to still
be balanced and not break when they come over as a set shard so we will still see in some select
situations there's a ring i'm thinking of specifically in this example that will stay
that will that will be viable as a set item because you can take the other items in that set
and put them and shadow them into affixes and slap them onto items and there's like you're using two
affix slots and it's a low uh a low requirement there and you get the set bonuses um and so yeah it's i
think there's gonna be there is room for this um and i'd love to i think this is gonna make um
um new set item creation more fun uh like for designing them
oh you mentioned cemeteries can or will be large how much larger you see the average echo
good question how much larger three times average echo is pretty small two times
i don't know somewhere in that range i am 50 minutes behind now oh my goodness mike
but it's only four pages that's good uh for weaver's tree passive in multiplayer will all effects stack in
gameplay uh yes it has nothing to do with multiplayer though
like if um whoever's whoever's monolith you're in is the one that the tree will take into account for
spawning things um yeah so if if if like uh if you and i are in a party together and we're doing your
monolith and i have a node that's like more champions will spawn um that no won't do anything
because it's your monolith that we're in all right we are cutting off new questions right here
no no more new questions i'm sorry um maybe maybe one or two if you sneak them in real fast but yeah
we're we're done with new questions because i gotta get out of here at some point
all right uh for weaver tree passive audiences uh one of the biggest challenges in merchant
skill has been trading high lp items that are extremely valuable due to the gold cap
uh any changes coming out would you share your insight on it um i i think
i don't have a good answer to this one i'm sorry i'd love to
do
there's stuff we're working on that's not going to make it into season two to help with this
uh are you going to up the character limit from 25 or is 25 your highest you're going to go yeah
we're gonna increase it still um i'm shocked it's still as low as 25 i could have sworn it went higher
than that um do you know what righteous fire build is yes uh and if so will paladins be able to make
something similar with the rework uh not easily not not as effective as the one you're used to
in other games uh how do you know uh how far out will which season how far out which season do you
plan to split off season cycle from legacy resets that are still the same content
oh like like um like where you stop applying some content from the new season to legacy on c on
patch day drop i have no idea um i hope it's not too far out though because i actually like doing that
uh will stash tabs carry over into next season or will you need to buy them again you'll need to
buy them again just like normal uh locked one lp unique item prophecy cost is higher than other
prophecies uh but with nemesis some can say without lp item is better because you can place it in the
nemesis egg to upgrade it is there any changes coming to prophecies in season two much love can't
wait for season two patch um there are changes to prophecies coming in season two there is not this
change you're requesting coming to season two prophecies there is a different system to address this
issue in season two coming so we are fixing this not the way you're asking to it's gonna be great
uh i hope we can talk about this in the next podcast though yeah uh do you guys have any bias
for or against big slams and single big hits nope um i i think i probably have a slight bias towards
them because i think they're fun uh i like setting up or building around big single instances of damage
but the game seems a little more geared towards spamming uh i don't i don't think there's an intentional
bias there but there might be some unintentional stuff going on maybe um talking about rampant
wishlisting slash future dreaming could you ever envision an mmo set in the last epoch ip uh epoch
holders having to work together in dungeons and raids across time sounds pretty dope on paper um yeah i
yes i've definitely imagined this in the past um
it sounds it sounds very daunting uh but kind of in a good way i don't know love to uh is there any
interaction combination you feel is op but underused mm nah you guys are really good at finding stuff
uh is there any desire to change how channeling skills work to not be snapshot style for example
healing hands only proccing once you activate the warpath but never again until you stop to
reactivate warpath uh oh that type of snapshotting no i i think that's i'm pretty happy with how that works
reading party
so this is my aoe2 showing again like those the the hockey's
at the start i don't know if that was from something else though anyways um
i'm really enjoying playing purifier in grim dawn so season two launches will we ever see pistols in
last epoch i think it's possible i think it is it's not something we have currently planned but i mean
it's a time travel game can you kind of you can kind of do what you want right right um
i i i there's no there's no like hard lock of like never pistols never gunpowder anything like that
like we it's not something we are planning on right now it's not something that's in the storyline for
the main campaign that we're that we're we have three more chapters to go in the campaign that's not
planning to have um uh gunpowder involved in the campaign but you know there's time yeah all right
are there any changes to exiled mages yes there's changes to exiled mages they'll they'll drop
different stuff and tweaking some of the numbers and the way they play and stuff but yes there are
some little changes there uh prophecies can get a bit clunky at times um having proc three at once
massive loot piles and a hectic map you often do backtracking or risk your life while looking at loot
is this an issue to you yes it is definitely an issue do not have a great solution for it at the
moment it's definitely an issue um we are if you do die while you're in a big loot bomb like that
the items uh something we teased last week uh the items that are in the in your immediate vicinity
when you die do get transported to echo of a world where i'm standing right now um when you die so you
will those items will at least come with you so in the worst case scenario there's still uh um
good a good improvement a little bit uh hello very excited for upcoming expansion me too uh question
will there be any changes or updates to minion ai skills that uh can alter their behaviors um
nothing like major any changes yeah there's there's little changes here and there but uh
not not systematic wide changes
uh hello are you trying to balance the different character classes yes or it's okay if some are more
powerful and faster yeah i mean like we we'd like um
if someone wants to go do the hardest content in the game if they're if they're opening the game and
they're like i wonder what class i'm going to play i want to be able to complete the hardest content in the
game um i'd like that first decision on which class i'm going to play to be which class do i connect with
the most which class resonates with me the style the theming what's what's the most exciting thing
for me to take on as a character to embody in a fantasy to enjoy rather than which one's going to be
the most powerful because the even if you're even if that's your main goal they're all going to have at least some
path to victory for you uh when will be new class it's been too long it's a little bit still new
new classes are humongous um because there's because you can't we don't take that we don't
nothing's cross class for us so like um like summon wolf isn't an ability for if we if we add a new
class that someone wolf doesn't there's nothing that someone does that makes that easier to make
well that's some little things behind the scenes but not much especially not from the art team um
oh we're getting low technically three minutes until this is over there are
two pages of of of questions left i'm gonna finish these questions out
we're not taking more questions i'm sorry i'm gonna here let's slap up all the rest of the stuff
whatonge who gets  tinha
well
uh
good
There we go.
You can see me.
Hi!
Alright.
Any performance improvements in the
upcoming patch? Oh yeah.
Have you guys thought about trying
rewards to echo
objectives? Alter spines, ambush, and possibly
letting players choose what objectives to go after?
Yeah.
Like, are you saying
having multiple objectives in a
single echo?
Lesser
on that one.
But yeah, a lot
of what this
a lot of what the Weaver's tree has to do
is that. Yeah.
Can we see you do
and explain a bit of crafting?
Oh, we are right near the end of the stream.
I tell you what,
crafting is...
There's enough in-depth stuff on crafting
that I'm going to...
I'm going to point you at...
There's so many creators that have wonderful
crafting videos
that explain crafting
that I'm going to point you at one of those.
Just type, like,
go to YouTube and type
last epoch crafting
and you'll get a full rundown.
There's...
I know there's a whole bunch
of really good ones out there.
Alright.
Why are information on blessings
locked behind having them
show up
when you pick one?
Having to look up
where the ones you want
outside the game
is a minor annoyance
if you can't memorize them all.
Yeah.
This comes back
to a little bit of the whole, like...
Back when I was a kid.
And...
That sense of, like,
discovery, I think.
A little bit.
We love to have
in situations like this.
And you're right.
Because, you know,
it's a thing.
It makes it kind of pointless.
Um...
I don't have a great answer
for you.
But I think it's a bit
of a holdover
from a wanting
to have a sense
of discovery
on something like this
and a bit of nostalgia
for us, probably.
Is there any plan
to be able to turn...
I think it's...
I should also say as well,
it's a bit of...
If you're at the point
where you're min-maxing
your blessings,
you've probably already
unlocked a good chunk
of them or, you know,
like, you've done a little bit
of that discovery process
already as well.
Maybe they should...
Uh...
An option...
An option might be...
We're not doing this,
but I think it's something
that we could considerably...
Something that could
conceivably be pitched is
if you have...
When you unlock Empowered,
having all the blessings
from completed timelines
of normal
get unlocked
at base rate
so you'd see
at least what's there.
Because there's the normal
and the Empowered blessings
and so if you unlock...
Or if you complete
a timeline
on Empowered
or something like
having all the base ones
unlocked or something like that.
I don't know.
Is there any plan
to be able to turn down
skill effect opacity?
I'd love to.
We don't have it right now,
but I'd say it's on the...
On the long list of likes.
It's very hard to see
what's going on
when spamming some skills,
especially in multiplayer.
Uh...
That was me
adding that last bit.
How viable is hardcore
in LE so far?
Very, I would say.
Has anyone beaten
the end game
completed in hardcore?
Oh yeah.
What's your predictions
for hardcore completion
time frame for season 2?
Like, Uber, Abby,
season 2,
hardcore
completion kill
on the season.
I'm going to say
six days.
someone does it
in six days.
No, that's way too little.
I'm going to say
someone does it
in nine days.
That's better.
That's the prediction.
Nine days for someone
to kill Uber, Abby,
and hardcore
on the season.
Not solo.
Solo I think
will take a lot longer.
Alright, will
Temporal Sancton T4
boss get nerfed?
Probably not.
I think she is
really punishing
with almost everything
one-shotting you.
Not even Abraoth
does that,
or at least Abraoth
is more mechanic-focused.
I think Abraoth
is a lot stronger.
In general.
But yeah,
there's always room
for improvements
on the bosses,
and I think maybe
it might be just like
a, as you say,
more mechanic-focused.
Maybe it just needs
to be more clear
on what's happening.
But I think
it's appropriate
that completing
very hard stuff
gets you very good stuff.
You know?
Alright, have you
considered adding
more forms for Druid?
Absolutely.
It's a pretty huge
undertaking adding
in new forms for the Druid.
Those are some
of the biggest skills.
Spriggan Form,
I'd argue,
is the most involved
skill in the game
because it's like
minion abilities
and transform abilities
are the hardest to do,
and it is a transform
ability with minion abilities.
Alright, would there
be any way of making
arena a loot explosion
at the end of the waves
instead of individual drops
during, to make it
a dopamine hit
and make it more fun?
It used to be like that.
Is it not like that now?
The arena.
How long has that changed?
Kane's saying he thinks
it's still that way.
So I, I,
I think it might be that way?
Question mark?
Double check that.
You can come to
the Discord channel
and ask the devs
and ask me again
if it's not like that,
but I think it's like that.
Alright, will there be
more monster lore?
Oh yeah.
As a big D3 fanboy,
I kind of miss
the lore around monster types.
For example,
the tongue eater,
which lashes out
their tongue
into others' mouths
and eating them in D3.
That's gross.
Yeah, adding a best area
is something that we've
long wanted to do,
and I really hope
we're able to.
I think there's,
the game guide is,
when it was first made,
it was made in the,
in the assumption
that the best area
would go with there as well.
Or bestiary,
whatever you say it.
I don't know.
I always get it wrong.
Mike,
last time you have mentioned
to me about the primordial
content,
may I know,
is it moved to much later season
or is it scrapped?
I have no details
on what's happening with it.
The only information
on future content
that we have available
is in the,
uh,
sign,
in the,
um,
roadmap document.
Um,
nothing really gets
scrapped forever.
Uh,
are there,
are there plans
to add more group
play tools?
Things like buffs
for Farty members
and PoE or bots,
not incentives
like Magic Find.
Um,
yeah,
I think there's,
we do frequently
put in things
that are functional,
that are useful
in multiplayer.
Um,
it is tricky
because a lot of people
play solo again
and so like having,
um,
having too much power
going to multiplayer stuff
can,
can restrict some
of the content
at the end.
But I think it's the,
the usual thing
is the,
that a well-oiled
machine of multiplayer
should be slightly
more powerful
than a,
um,
a well-thought-out
individual build
which should be
slightly more powerful
or significantly more powerful
than a,
um,
haphazardly slapped together
multiplayer build
of multiple characters.
And,
but yeah,
there's,
there's some new,
there's some new stuff
we're adding in there
that'll be sweet.
Uh,
especially in a new,
uh,
unique item
that I may have mentioned
earlier in the stream slightly.
Uh,
currently there are five
conversion options
for Abyssal Echo.
Presumably it fit the theme
with Forge Guard
and Paladins.
Uh,
Warpath has an autocast node
for AE,
but it's locked behind a node
that changes Warpath to Void.
And it says it invalidates
the fire conversion node
of Warpath.
It's something addressed
in Season 2.
I feel like
we talked about this
in Ask the Devs?
Or someone else was asking
the exact same question
in Ask the Devs
and there's a gigantic answer
I wrote in there recently.
Um,
it's,
I don't think this is a
problem to be solved really.
I think it's important
that the,
like,
it needs to go behind
one of the fire
or void conversion nodes.
Um,
and it fits best
behind the void conversion node
for sure.
Um,
I think it could go,
a second similar node
could go behind
the fire conversion node.
Um,
but the better solution
would be to put this
behind a mutually
exclusive node,
like a new style of node
that we don't have existing yet.
Um,
which would be something like,
hey,
this node,
you can pick either A or B.
So it'd be like,
this node,
you can take the fire
or void conversion.
It's a single point.
You have to pick which one you get
and then you can put things
behind them both
that are mutually exclusive.
That's the way I'd want to
handle something like this instead.
Um,
but we don't have that tech
so we're not doing it yet.
Uh,
are you guys planning on
upgrading servers?
Yes.
Also,
how is trading faction,
duping,
exploiting issues
are going to be handled
this season since we pretty much
breaks the game
in the first week?
Well,
we haven't had any,
um,
duping or exploiting
things like that happen
in the most recent,
like the most recent ladder
and,
um,
uh,
bazaar were clean.
There were no issues there.
Um,
there was no
incident.
Um,
since the last incident
that happened,
um,
like a couple times ago,
uh,
we have
entirely new,
uh,
detection,
and,
uh,
reaction systems.
Um,
we have new safeguards in place
to make sure it won't happen
again as well,
that on top of the ones
that we did last time,
um,
you know,
there's,
we,
we have new tools in place
in,
in like prevention,
detection,
and fixing.
Um,
and,
you know,
it's,
it's one of the most
important things for us
is keeping this,
uh,
like keeping the
bazaar and the economy
running smoothly
is extremely important.
So we're,
we're doing everything
we can to make sure
that stays that way.
Um,
and we're gonna be
keeping a very close eye
on everything
right as things go live.
Um,
as far as upgrading servers,
yeah,
like since,
since 1.0 dropped,
we have entirely new
backend code.
Um,
we have entirely new servers,
like the physical machines
are completely different.
Um,
tons and tons of updates.
So yeah,
yeah,
like we're,
this is all stuff
we're working very hard on,
um,
and is extremely important.
It's not super flashy.
So we don't advertise
this stuff quite as much
in like the,
like the trailers
and the videos
and stuff like that.
So you don't see like,
like,
um,
new detection for,
uh,
for duping methods.
You're like,
who cares?
Like,
why is that?
That's not something
you show from the rooftops
really.
But yeah,
it's,
it's all stuff
we are very interested
in,
uh,
in keeping,
tight.
And so it's,
it's,
yeah,
we're working on it hard.
All right.
Any plans to have mass shattering?
Is it still one item at a time?
Um,
we don't have any specific plans
for mass shattering at the moment.
It is still one shard at a time.
Technically we are adding it
in a weird way.
You're gonna be like,
that doesn't count Mike.
And I'm like,
yeah,
you're right.
It doesn't count.
Um,
uh,
I,
I would love to see it
to be a little bit quicker.
Um,
I'd love to say,
I think the thing we,
I think where we're leaning towards
right now is having a,
like a system where you can
mark items as trash in your
inventory and be like,
this is junk,
junk,
junk.
And then you just like shatter
all junk,
sell all junk.
You know,
I have those types of buttons.
Um,
so that's probably the most likely
method,
but we don't have anything planned
for it at the moment.
Specifically.
Is it possible to move all
respec NPCs to Echo of a World
in season two?
No.
Uh,
is it safe to assume that
starting season three
season three,
we should start to see a lot
more set implemented since
it's been a drought recently.
Yeah.
I mean,
a lot more of zero in the last
what two,
three releases.
Yeah.
Um,
we're going to start,
we're going to start
assuming the set rework goes
well,
which I think it will go really
well.
I'm very confident in it.
It's like the testing is going
great for it.
The reception,
um,
is from the public has been
fantastic on it.
Like,
I think this is,
um,
this is going to be a really,
really great system coming out.
And,
um,
as long as everything with it
goes smoothly enough that we
can either fix the issues that
do arise or just revel in the
awesomeness of it.
Uh,
I think we'll be looking at,
um,
ramping up set item development
again.
I've got,
I've got a sticky note on my
desktop sitting,
right?
Not like a physical one,
but that's,
that's got just like set item
ideas that I'm,
I'm waiting for the,
for the green light to start
posting those internally.
All right.
Uh,
can you do a character transfer
like SSF to normal trade
bonus option?
Um,
you can,
uh,
every,
yes.
The short answer is yes here.
I'll show you what it looks like
really quick.
So right at the end,
last thing,
settings,
challenges.
Um,
if you are,
if you are on a character
that is specifically character
found and like a solo account
found,
so all character found
characters are also solo
account found characters
and also account
factors are also regular
ones.
So it's like,
um,
you can abandon your
character found challenge
and become a solo account
found character.
And then you can a balance,
abandon your solo account
found challenge and become
a normal character.
Um,
so you can,
you can take those two
steps and you can jump.
Um,
but it's a one-way transfer
only if it cares,
you cannot take a character
and make it solo and you
cannot take a character and
make it character found.
so it's one way only
and yes the
lots of stuff gets
my picture is showing is hiding that stuff
does get
some stuff gets deleted some stuff
doesn't
but yes we do
carry over
things like your ranks
your faction ranks those get merged
and whatever the most favorable way for them to merge is
but you do lose the
a character found
stash does vanish
when you take a character from character found to normal
the stash goes poof
you gotta take everything you wanna carry
with you on your back
put on those four layers of shirts
alright
that's gonna do it for us here
let's
put this one last thing up if you missed it
there it is
super cool
corruption display
ooh I'm really happy about this
alright
I will be back
with
I don't know who's actually gonna be on that stream or not
some of us will be back
with
with try on the 8
so same time
on tries twitch
talk to tries twitch
not ours
we might try and
restream it or something
just to
so there's more
it's out there more
all sorts of stuff
I don't know what we're doing for next Friday
I assume we're skipping next Friday on the 4th
but I will double check
and some announcement will go either way on that
I had a great stream
this was a ton of fun
we're through it
oh
I'm gonna go
I think I'm gonna go set up a trampoline later
I hope you had fun
I know I did
I'll see you next time
let's go
let's go say hi to someone
oh
here we go
here's a familiar face
I pick familiar faces
because if I pick just randoms
I get in trouble a lot
because I make mistakes
but yep
have a great time everyone
drink lots of water
see you later
I'm gonna go