hello are you doing good how are you i am good
let's see who else we got joining here
hello hello you're alive already oh cool so they can already hear you
oh great hello everybody i cannot see i actually need racks to set up the cameras
well i can't set up the cameras until rex is here all good let's see
are you guys good i'm noticing i'm looking at my background right now i've got the uh i've got the
ziz cup back here see that nice oh nice i'm right over there i was i was debating wearing my zizzerin
shirt but i'm like oh it's fanboying too hard isn't it i'm wearing my last ebook shirt oh i should have
i should have nice that's hilarious let's see
oh
i think he's just ending stream and then he'll be here
no problem at all
no risk of the bird flying in judd is is he is he locked away i think i think it's locked away
yeah you have a bird let me tell you i'll tell you the stories is we uh i've got i've got kids i've
got i've got four kids and um the neighbor has this cockatiel this bird and they're like yeah you
know with all the kids you guys should take this cockatiel i can't really home it any longer yada yada
yada of course the kids were like please dad please i'm not a monster we end up getting this bird
um but the kids will wake up in the morning before they go to school and they'll unlock the cage and then
the bird roams free through the house and so i will be on like serious calls and all of a sudden a bird
will fly into my office and land on me and it's it's the most bizarre thing to somebody on the other
end even for me i'm like oh my gosh we have to we have to do something about this bird situation that
we have going on uh so i i think i think jack is locked it's amazing right now i hope um let's do
some audio tests um judd can you speak a little bit audio chat testing testing this is two three
test test test
not a little bit quick okay i'll turn them up
try speaking now testing testing one two three hello welcome travelers all that good stuff
still low i'll turn it up to 100 let's see all right what about now testing testing testing
can you guys hear me now i talk a little bit louder when i keep going on these things so it'll probably uh
it'll probably even out
all right
okay that sounds good okay i guess i'll go next testing testing testing testing one two three
good
good nice
nice holly
testing testing testing i don't know i'm really bad at this nervous i'm sorry
finding god
i can't hacerlo
good it's gonna be fun
you
there
your
thanks
i'm
how long do you guys have by the way for the podcast so you give people an idea of expectations
the only time limit i it's not a real time limit i told my wife when she picks up the kids from
school to you know maybe maybe stay out of the house for a couple hours uh because they'll come
in and they'll want to be involved in the podcast if uh if they show up that's fair
so a couple i i got a couple hours at least yeah me too yeah see i didn't really have a time limit
awesome all right i think rex is wrapped up so you should be joining the call any second
then i'll set up cameras
because ross and holly it's uh it's a little bit later for these guys they're across the pond
yeah it's not too late 9 p.m um it's it's only it's only when it gets to 1 a.m that my partner
often says i'm being too loud or too excited or whatever it's when we get those good game design
discussions at one o'clock your time one o'clock in the morning time they can see it a little bit
radier all right rex just right in and he's here all right hey rex what's up can you guys hear me
yeah sure can yes sir very well
let's do a quick volume test on racks and then we're good to go
can you see me oh yes sir there he is beautiful all right there he is i feel i feel like i should
go ahead mode as well but i won't let's see there's one camera up how you doing rex how was your stream
he just stepped away for a second by the way oh he left a bastard
okay there's a third camera up
it's like a nice color spectrum going on here ross's room is very blue
racks has got the green holly's is kind of nice
i guess mine's a little more red we don't have the camera showing yet so we're actually just going
to describe the video
imagine imagine a bunch of uh different colored backgrounds is what you guys are missing at the
moment it's okay they'll see soon enough okay just setting up me and rex's camera and we are good
i'm excited yeah it's been a while this is fun
i'm just so excited you guys are doing ascendancy respect like that's huge
yeah there's a there's a there's a lot of good quality of life stuff coming
yeah it's pretty pretty exciting
let's see last one
i guess for uh any of the audience who hasn't seen the
teaser trailer that could be something that you guys do for a couple minutes before we get into this
just so people have a good frame of reference for the stuff that we're talking about
um honestly we could open the podcast with me watching the trailer that actually could be a fun
idea yeah that's that's good i'll do that um all right everybody should be able to see everyone
just gotta fix ross's camera a little bit
right
there
right i'm just gonna make sure nobody has a green border when talking judd talk real quick
test test test
ross talk
perfect holly
test test test
okay cool um
tiny bit there
rex
hello hello
all right perfect
excellent
maybe slightly bigger
all right cool
rex is low
okay i'll turn him up
i had him on 60 percent rex try talking
hello my name is rex
here i am
all right let me
move my podcast scene up next to an actual full screen thing
and then i can show stuff
all right
let me just find the last ebook trailer
and then we'll open with that
and i guess we'll just have to be quiet during the trailer
and
we'll kick it off
after that
sounds good
thanks
um
rex for youtube i'll do like a quick um
hmm
that's annoying
um
i'll do the kick quick
with our faces
say that we're gonna do it
and then i'll
play the trailer
all right
sure
hi
welcome to
a podcast
about last epoch
i'm joined here
with
rax
and loads of people from
last epoch 11 hour games
but before we begin
i want to quickly show
the last epoch official
launch trailer
echoes
from the void
and uh
you'll have
a better idea
of what we're going to be seeing
and what we're going to be talking about
so i'll play that real quick now
you
wait is this the wrong one
tombs of the erase
ah this was the top one that showed
right we'll start over
that was a good one too
we can watch that one too
why not
yeah yeah
okay we'll do it over
we'll do it over
are you guys
are you guys watching the stream
as you guys are doing this
there shouldn't be a need to
okay okay
i'm not
so if you were watching the wrong trailer
i would have no idea
different this was a last minute idea
i was a little confused
i was like
i swear i played this already
it was a good one
all right
we'll start over
one more time
um
oh actually hold on
give me one sec
there
and there
perfect
all right
hi
scissorin here
and we're doing a podcast
with 11 hour games
and we're joined here
by some of the developers
and i'm joined by rex
we're going to be doing an interview
and talking about the upcoming
tombs of the erased
season two
and this is
we're going to start off
with showing the
official trailer
so they have a better idea
what we're going to be looking at
and talking about
you've come
to the right place
traveler
and in this time
you can share
in her embrace
so
and
oh
I don't know.
I gave him a 12 réps CREAL
I did.
I çok меньше peur.
electronicша
Let's go.
Awesome.
So, yeah, we are joined here by the devs and we have a lot of topics to cover.
Very excited.
Thank you so much for taking time out of your day to join us here and answer a lot of questions about the game.
I think we'll start with some introductions just so everybody knows who's who.
Judd, do you want to start?
Yeah, absolutely.
Hello.
My name is Judd Kobler.
I am the founder of 11th Hour Games, game director for Last Epoch.
I'm located over here in Texas.
I started 11th Hour Games back in 2017 through Reddit as just a diehard action RPG player.
So I've been on the other side as a player for much longer than over on this side as a developer.
Yeah, I'm excited to chat with you guys.
Awesome.
Ross?
Hey, I'm Ross, a creative director at 11th Hour Games.
Just a bit about myself.
I've worked on the front end design and implementation of a lot of different systems and features in the game,
plus a bunch of stuff outside of the game as well.
I wasn't part of the OG Kickstarter crew.
I think I started contributing perhaps in patch 0.7.
You know, this was a while back before we had things like idols, you know, we were using protections rather than resistances.
So a while ago, but not all the way back to Kickstarter days.
In terms of how I joined the company, it's definitely a slightly unusual process there.
I remember looking at the last Epoch Kickstarter page when it was live.
And my main takeaway from that was that, you know, the team seemed really genuine and I thought the systems design was really solid.
I am ashamed to say I didn't actually back the project though.
Oh.
You know, in my defense, this was just before my son was born.
So, you know, I was saving money for the baby.
That's what we'll go with.
But yeah, sometime later, I saw one of your streams, Zez.
And I think you were streaming with Mike and Judd.
And yeah, that stream convinced me to dive in.
The game looked better than it did at the Kickstarter phase.
And yeah, when I played, I thought there was a real charm to the game.
And I thought I would offer my help to the team.
So I just started designing things and sending that across mostly to Judd initially.
You know, I worked on elements that I knew the team could probably implement fairly quickly.
Things like reworking tooltips, reworking the dialogue system and things like that.
But in addition to that, I saw the team at a roadmap and I just started mocking up systems that were much further out there.
You know, I just picked the eternity cache because I thought that sounded cool.
And I started experimenting with what I thought that would be.
In the end, we didn't use my ideas there.
Holly came up with something much better later on.
But it did help to kickstart some of those conversations.
And, you know, I started talking with Judd.
And then eventually he convinced me to join the team later on.
And here I am.
It took me about two years of courting Ross to get him to come over from his previous position.
He was this guy that like he would show up on Discord and like hand us gold.
He would just be like, here's a better design for the thing that you're doing.
And we're like, this is fantastic.
And it took me two years.
About every three months I'd message Ross to be like, it's time to go.
It's time to come over.
And finally, we've got him here.
So a lot of the good quality updates that you guys see coming through is because of Ross.
Great to have him.
Yeah.
And I guess if I hadn't seen Ziz's stream there, maybe I wouldn't be here.
You know, who knows?
You're welcome.
No, that's awesome.
Very, very cool.
Thank you, Ziz.
Cheers.
Holly?
Yeah.
I'm the principal designer.
I was there right at the start.
I replied to one of those Reddit threads from JAD back in 2017 and got into it as just a company
Discord at the time.
So I've been there since then.
I'm primarily a designer now, but it was, I was one of the only developers back then.
So I implemented a lot of the base versions of the early systems, like the stats system, ability system, AI, things like that.
And then design last epoch is a collaborative effort.
So there aren't really many things that you just could point to and say, we've designed that as the whole thing.
So I have come up with a base ideas and did a lot of the design work on systems like skill trees and item factions.
Awesome.
And a lot of people already know Rax, but Rax, do you want to do a quick introduction for yourself?
I'm Rax.
I wear a blue hoodie.
I play ARPGs like this.
That's me.
And I'm the blue counterpart to Rax.
So together we are blue man group.
For those that don't know me, I also play a lot of ARPGs.
So it's been a while since season one.
It's been a large gap.
So yeah.
Do you want to give us a TLDR on that, Jed?
Yeah.
The gap between season one and season two was much longer than we'd like it to be and much longer than we'll be aiming for going forward.
You know, I do hope that when people see the patch notes, they'll immediately know that we weren't just, you know, sitting idly.
A lot of great content coming out with season two.
The reason that it took so long to get season two out is because it was clear what the community was asking for us to work on.
And we decided to deviate from our prior season two plans to prioritize the addressing of the community feedback coming through.
You know, people were asking for, you know, more things to do in the end game updates to dungeons, more balance, getting those crafting materials out of your inventory, etc.
And, you know, while these were all things that we were planning to do over time, I think if we had proceeded with our prior season two content plans, we might have seen tone deaf if we were to have proceeded with that over addressing some of the wants coming from the community.
So we took some additional time to address the biggest wants coming out there.
And because of that, I think people are really going to enjoy the content coming out with season two.
Awesome. And you mentioned seasons were going to be coming faster going forward.
Like what kind of timeframe are we going to be looking at for like future updates?
Yeah, that's definitely the plan. We're still aiming for that, you know, three to four month releases for these seasons.
And we did take some time this development cycle to work on things that'll better set us up for success.
In that regard, we've done things like we've upgraded the engine so that doesn't become a roadblock going forward.
That also gives us some some great performance wins alongside a lot of efficiencies internally for the working team.
We have some of the team already working on future content, which is quite new for 11th hour games, as we've always been racing to get that next piece of content out the door.
And we haven't found ourselves in the position to be working on content for further in the future than the upcoming immediate next patch.
So that's that's very cool to see that we're now at that point.
And then we've also been working on systems that will help us produce content more quickly, like our new procedural content generation engine, which is what powers the new tombs of the erased content, all of the procedural side zones that you'll encounter.
And then I should probably say for for any viewers that don't know what procedural content generation is, it's basically a way for us to clear a set of rules and inputs to create content.
And then we put that into the engine and the engine will spit out a random zone layout with encounters and events and things of that nature, which will be a huge, huge boon for us.
As previously, we were having to create all of these zones manually.
And of course, one of the biggest challenges with creating an action RPG in seasonal content is just being able to deliver PVE content at high quality as fast as people can consume it.
So that's going to be a huge boon for us.
And are you aiming for like every three months, every four months, any idea on something like that?
I think I think our ultimate goal is to get it down to three months.
I think it's more reasonable to say four months is more what 11th hour games is capable at the moment.
Again, we are continuing to create things that will just help us make sure that we can develop content more quickly.
We're certainly not at the point where we want to rush things out the door and have things be buggy and broken and things like that.
So, you know, with the team size that we have right now and the tools that are disposal, aim for three months.
If we land at like the four, four months or so timeframe, that's generally what we're happy with.
Awesome. And then we have season two starts on 2nd of April. Is that right?
April 2nd.
I'm very excited.
All right. So yeah, on that three or four month thing, every time, every time someone promises us three months, it ends up being four months anyway, it seems so.
We probably won't hold you to that.
Producing TVE content.
I mean, just the, if you think of the entire development cycle of a piece of action RPG seasonal content, if you think of everything that has to go through, be bug tested, be iterated on, get feedback on, scale test, bug fix, all that stuff.
It's a, it's a really challenging timeline to get that amount of content across the board that quickly.
But we understand that it's important because people, of course, don't want to be sitting there with the same content for a long number of months without something new to do.
Yeah.
And, and one of the first things that you said, you said you spent way more of your time as a player, rather than a developer, it'd be a cool, like different podcast.
If we could pick your brain on what is actually like the differences there.
Cause you were like rattle off those.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Being on the other side is, is very, very interesting.
You know, one of the main reasons I developed or created 11th hour games is because, um, you know, I had been a part of other ARPG communities in the past.
And, uh, like Ross, I would go, we would go with groups of people and we would say, Hey, the game would be so much better if you would implement this thing.
And we would provide mock-ups and, you know, we were just dying to get any responses from the developers.
And we would be handing over things that, you know, community collaborated community agreed on would make the game much better, but it would be radio silence.
And I really wanted to make a studio, an action RPG that I knew that I could build a team that would constantly listen to community feedback because nobody knows these games better than the players that are playing these games for hundreds and thousands of hours.
Us as developers, we don't have time to play last epoch for a thousand hours in a quarter.
Uh, we just, we just don't have the time because we're sitting there developing it.
So it's in studio's best interest to, uh, intimately be listening to all of the player feedback coming through because generally they know better what needs to be done.
Maybe not how to approach it all the time, but better what needs to be done for the game to be great.
That's pretty true.
Very well said.
Okay.
Well, why don't, uh, why, why don't we get into it here?
All of the cool new stuff.
Why don't we talk about the tombs of the race that you just brought up, which I think are the new side dungeons, I guess, just that's way to phrase is, can you just give us an overall, uh, view of the system and how it's going to work for us?
Yeah.
Um, I'll, I'll, I'll do that for you, Rex.
No problem.
Um, in terms of tombs of the race, uh, you know, with season two, we're introducing these new side zones.
These are the tombs and cemeteries of the race that you might've seen in the trailer.
Um, these zones, as Judd mentioned, use our new procedural generation system.
So each layout there is unique.
Um, that's something we've not been able to do before, uh, and we're really keen to deploy elsewhere in future as well.
Um, these zones are the main entry point to interact with all of the new end game systems and content that's coming for season two.
Um, so we have a new end game faction to progress through the woven, uh, and a weaver tree that allows you to influence the monolith, uh,
both in terms of its rewards and its encounters.
Uh, the theming for this season, uh, is based on the weaver, which we've only alluded to previously through things like the weavers will lower, uh, lower text.
Um, she's a big old spider titan who's trying to shape the world, uh, into her own version.
Uh, and she's busy gathering and experimenting with souls from raised timelines as a source of memories to shape this new world.
So the new woven echoes that you'll be exploring are based on these weird experiments by the weaver.
Uh, and we'll talk more about these shortly.
So to summarize all of that, the start of the journey through the new end game content really begins when you start exploring these tombs and cemetery side zones.
And did you say there's, there's a tree connected to it?
So we get an end game tree.
Is that what I'm hearing?
Yes.
The weaver tree, you know, you'll be familiar with systems like this where you can, uh, you, you know, you can adjust, uh, the, the monolith, uh, and modify certain aspects of it.
So these are in game stuff.
These are in monoliths.
Will they be like separate, like islands or blocks that appear or will they be inside existing monoliths?
And like, how often are we going to see them?
So, uh, both tombs and cemeteries are in the monolith specifically.
Uh, tombs spawn inside echoes, um, roughly about 50% of the time.
Although there are some ways to influence that.
Uh, cemeteries are rarer and they spawn as a passive echo type where completing the cemetery is the objective for that particular echo.
Okay.
So how do you complete them?
And like, so is it like a full clear?
Is there a boss?
Do you have to do objectives?
Do I have to pull levers?
How long do these things take?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
When do you go?
Yeah.
There's a boss.
Uh, they're, they're a bit smaller than a regular echo, uh, but the layout's quite different using procedural generation.
But it's, it's just a case of getting to the boss.
You don't have any levers to press or secondary objectives.
Definitely don't have to full clear them.
Yeah.
You know, in, in terms of, in terms of length, they're fairly short.
Um, tombs are slightly smaller than the cemeteries, uh, and you can complete them, you know, in, in about a minute or so.
It really depends on how fast you kill the boss.
If you're lower DPS, it'll take a bit longer.
Uh, there are some specific woven echoes later on that utilize larger versions of tombs.
Uh, but, you know, we'll get to that.
Well, okay.
So, how balanced is it that, like, a lot of min-maxers especially will, like, end up skipping things?
Like, what's the rewards going to be like?
Yeah, so we do think that exploring this content is going to be rewarding enough or icing for most players.
I think in terms of, uh, you know, players that are just skipping content, you're trying to get to empowered mon-less as fast as possible before interacting with anything.
It's always going to be tough to make, uh, additions to the end game that those players are happy to pause and delay for.
Yeah.
Um, but, but in terms of the specific rewards, uh, both zones have the chance to spawn treasure rooms with chests and caches.
And as mentioned, the bosses, uh, the unique bosses for each, they drop their own unique items as well.
Uh, you'll also start finding woven echoes as items, uh, when you progress through these.
Um, and both of these zones are the main location where you pick up memory amber.
Uh, this is the currency that you gain and spend in various ways to progress through the ranks of the woven faction.
Uh, in terms of memory amber, uh, both zones have cocoons in them that when you destroy them, uh, that releases a soul.
And then that soul seeks a nearby enemy and empowers it.
Uh, those enemies gain a modifier, they gain more health and damage, and then they drop more memory amber on top of that.
Uh, and yeah, the memory amber ties closely in with all of the various reward systems in tombs and in the faction as a whole.
Uh, and I guess I'll pass it over to Holly, who'll, you know, talk about, uh, some systems that we haven't introduced so far.
Uh, the idol enchantment system.
Okay.
Next.
Um, so when you get to the end of a tomb or cemetery, uh, you'll be able to enchant an idol, specifically a class specific idol.
So one of the ones that takes up three or four slots in the idol inventory.
Uh, and that adds a random affix to it from a new pool.
Uh, and also gives us an amount of weaver's touch.
Weaver's touch is like weaver's will, but for idols instead of uniques.
And it'll upgrade that extra affix it's added and also have a chance to add a new one.
So you'll be able to get up to four affixes on your class specific idols now.
And the third and fourth affix are from, uh, a new pool of affixes.
So they're ones that haven't appeared in idols before.
And like regular affixes, but unlike other idol affixes, these have seven tiers.
So you can, they, they, they can upgrade with a weaver's touch system.
Wow.
So that's going to be kind of OP.
That one wasn't in the trailer.
That sounds incredible because before all the time we were just running around, just picking up these idols.
And now we're going to actually be like enchanting.
And it's almost like when we, when I talked to this is around the previous podcast about POE, about how much he likes the lab.
It's like using like the divine font at the lab to like upgrade your gems.
But this time we're doing it with idols.
And then did you say you add like weaver's will on it.
So then you go play and the idols power up even further after that.
Did I hear that right?
Yes.
So it's just like weaver's will in that aspect.
Um, but with weaver's will it's permanent.
Once the item has that it's locked.
Whereas with idols, you can take them back to, um, a tomb or cemetery and effectively respect them as if you're enchanting them from scratch.
Uh, but that costs memory amber.
So I can keep rerolling the same one.
So if I found like a best in slot idol, I can like keep rolling it until it's perfect.
Yes.
It's just time.
Um, because we, uh, we wanted to have this extra aspects and extra affixes on idols, but we didn't want to drastically increase the amount of RNG required to get a perfect idol.
Which it would be if you had to randomize four affixes instead of two.
Yeah.
And, uh, with the, with the tomb cemeteries and the bigger versions of tombs, they all have a different amount of times that you can, uh, you can enchant the idols as well.
Uh, the, the tombs that you encounter most frequently, you just get one, you get one.
Uh, yeah.
Okay.
Awesome.
Initially, it sounds like an amazing system.
So you spoke about woven echoes.
What exactly are those and how, how are those different from the regular echoes that we've experienced before?
So woven echoes, um, are basically the, the, the closest comparison is unique maps in Path of Exile.
Uh, they are bits of the weaver's new world, um, crafted out of the memories of the souls of the urays.
Uh, they drop as items normally in tombs and cemeteries, but you can get them elsewhere as well from possessed enemies.
Uh, and at the end of a cemetery of the raised is an altar to the weaver.
And you can put, you can go there and slot your woven echoes into the timeline.
And then you can run them like, uh, regular echoes.
And some of them will have effects on other echoes around them.
And they'll, they'll have new content like new bosses or new types of encounter.
Uh, yeah.
Awesome.
Am I missing anything?
Chad, can I trade this with other players?
Not currently.
So with the way the bazaar is set up, it's very much intended for, um, items that aren't identical to each other.
Like, um, close comparison is runes.
So if you have two runes of discovery, those are identical.
And so if we had loads of listings on the bazaar of different runes of discovery, that wouldn't make a lot of sense.
Uh, whereas if you've got loads of different, even versions of unique, there's going to have different roles, different amounts of LP.
So it does make sense of them to show up here.
Uh, woven echoes don't have roles on them.
We, we did consider it.
Uh, but in the end, we decided to make them easy to organize in the inventory.
And that meant that each copy would have to be identical.
Can you gift them to friends if they're like, you're playing together and stuff like that?
Uh, no, it's just like crafting materials, but you can run them with your friends like other echoes.
Okay.
And are multiple people able to use like the reward or is that just like the person, one person?
Yes.
It, it normally drops for everyone.
Oh, okay.
Very cool.
Um, and you were speaking about the, the new faction, the woven.
Is that something you choose?
So it's at odds with the other mechanics or is it like forgotten knights where you fight Amroth and it's separate?
It's like forgotten knights.
So the way we split it up is we've got item factions and end game factions.
Item factions and merchant's guild and circle of fortune.
You pick one of the two and you don't get access to the other.
As end game factions, you just get all of them.
Okay.
And how do you progress it?
Uh, you collect memory amber, which drops from enemies in tombs.
It drops from possessed enemies.
And you also progress by spending memory amber.
It's like favor in that respect.
Awesome.
Okay.
So yeah, everyone's going to be progressing the woven.
And it's not going to be like something exclusive and you'll be playing SSF or trip.
It's pretty cool to customizing end game.
So you want everyone to have access to it.
Makes perfect sense.
Um, I saw in the trailer, you said champion enemies and new affixes.
Can you tell us more about what those are or what we'll be experiencing?
Yes.
So champion enemies are basically, they're like mini bosses and rare enemies, uh, cross together.
They're more powerful enemies that are based on existing enemy types, but they have new abilities and they have an extra random modifier, which adds a random ability to them.
And then they always drop an item with a champion affix, uh, that goes in the sealed slot.
But there are quite powerful effects there, like plus one maximum companion, uh, or piercing additional enemies with multi-shot, things like that.
Um, and because they're sealed, that means that you can never get these on legendary items, which allows us to put a little bit more power budget into them.
Ah, okay, cool.
Can you get exalted IOS stats on these as well?
Yes, but because they're sealed, you can't change them afterwards.
So you have to get them to drop exalted.
Okay.
So, sorry, go ahead.
Even if they're exalted, I cannot merge this with a legendary potential no matter what, right?
Yes, because they're sealed and the sealed affix has never taken into account for making legendries.
Very cool.
Sorry, Rex, go ahead.
No, no, no.
Yeah, uh, from, so from a design aspect, it sounds like from what I'm hearing, these champion, uh, affixes that are going to be on these items are just super powerful.
Um, is this something where you envision like design wise, how many of our item slots do you think people are going to want?
Like with these champion affixes, like do you, is it going to be like a one or two kind of thing or, or people are going to be farming to try to get full champion affixes on all pieces of gear for all builds?
So, they're quite build specific.
So, firstly, some of them are more generic, but generally they're only going to be a few that are applicable to your build and each affix only drops for one slot.
So, even if you want those champion affixes for your build, it's not going to take over all your itemization.
It's just going to be those slots you're farming.
Very cool.
Um, and there's new bosses and Uber Aberroth as well.
Can you talk a little bit about that?
And with Uber Aberroth in particular, there's going to be two difficulties now, right?
There's going to be normal Aberroth and Uber Aberroth.
Um, what's the, what's the difficulty levels on the two, uh, Aberroth fights basically?
So, Uber Aberroth is quite a lot harder.
Uh, we have made some changes to base Aberroth, so it's not quite as difficult as it was, uh, back in 1-1 of the event patch.
Uh, but Uber Aberroth is definitely a level above that.
Uh, some of it's just numbers changes, but there are mechanic, there are mechanical changes as well.
Uh, like extra things will show up in the fight.
I don't want to spoil all of it, um, but it's definitely harder.
Cool.
And, and what about the, uh, the other bosses?
Like, are they Uber Aberroth level or?
So, uh, most Woven Echoes, because you're putting them into your, uh, timeline, like regular Echoes,
they do scale with Corruption, they do scale with your other Monolith mods.
Uh, so the, the difficulty of those will be variable.
Uh, if you put them in at low Corruption, almost certainly be easier than Aberroth,
but you can put them in at any Corruption, and because that scales infinitely, um, they can potentially be harder.
Awesome.
Cool.
Um, thanks for, um, move on and talk about, um,
should we do crafting?
Well, actually, are there any, uh, special unique rewards from Uber Aberroth that are different than a normal one?
Yes.
So all the, uh, new endgame bosses we're adding through Woven Echoes do have new unique drops.
Um, Uber Aberroth has two that only drop from him, and you have to kill Uber Aberroth to get those.
Unless you're MG, in which case you can, you can buy them, but that's, it's not the same.
It's not the same.
So, you don't have the same sense of accomplishment attached to that.
Does Uber Aberroth still drop some items from the normal pool as well?
Yes.
Okay.
It's regular Aberroth loot, and then more on top of that.
Um, do some work crafting then.
Are some of these unique, I, yeah, real quick, on the Uber Aberroth drop, you said he had two unique drops.
Are these going to be, like, godly things?
Are these going to be, like, mage blood or headhunter things where we've got to have these?
Is it going to be, like, pinnacle items?
They're, they're definitely chase uniques.
Uh, they're not quite headhunter level in terms of how they modify the, the way you play the game.
Um, but they're definitely very powerful, and things that you will want to chase, uh, and get for your characters.
Can they drop a legendary potential?
Yes.
Awesome.
God, that's going to be fun.
Okay, uh, let's move on to crafting, as Ziz said, and, uh, something that, uh, if I may speak from the community, I've heard it a million times, it's something you guys do very well.
So, endgame set crafting.
So, you shatter set items to get set shards.
Um, I, I saw it from the video, but how exactly, what do we do with these shards?
How does this help us?
Uh, this one's still me.
Yes.
Okay.
Um, these, they, they mostly work like regular shards.
You craft them onto your items, uh, and then they get the, uh, they get set affixes.
So, set affixes have a couple of the stats from the original set item.
Not all of them, because that would, that would explain the tooltip.
Um, but they also count as the item from that set.
So, if you have a Velarchia Stormcrown and you shatter that and you get the Velarchia Stormcrown shards, you then put that onto a helmet.
The helmet becomes Velarchia Stormcrown reforged.
It has this extra, uh, set affix and it counts as Velarchia Stormcrown for the purpose of getting the set bonus.
So, you can equip it with staff, uh, or with a, an exalted staff that has the equivalent affix there.
So, that's basically competing with legendary potential then?
Yes.
Cool.
We're expecting these.
And importantly, you can't craft these set affixes onto legendaries.
Yeah.
So, it's, it's an alternate thing.
You can't just smush everything together in one item, because we want better to be item diversity.
For endgame builds.
Very cool.
And shout out to Holly on that, because that was one that we actually weren't sure that we were going to be able to get through for season two.
And Holly really wanted it, so she put in some additional hours over the weekend to get that, uh, that system through.
So, thank you, Holly, for that one.
I, I wasn't the only person who worked on that.
Like, uh, Justin did quite a lot as well.
Yes, yes, yes.
So, this actually opens up, like, this is like a whole new, like, paradigm with set items, right?
Because when I, when I think of a set item, I think of, like, Diablo 2 or World of Warcraft, where, okay, I just pick up the eight pieces, I put them on, and I'm wearing the set.
But now you're saying you can shatter it for the set affixes, apply it to other items with different stats, and now it becomes counting toward the set items.
So, now it's like another layer of the itemization where you're trying to somehow figure out if there's a really powerful set bonus for your build, and how you could craft it into your items if the set item itself is not powerful.
Right?
Yeah.
Correct.
Wow.
So, they, they, they, they, go ahead, sorry, before you finished.
But the, the issue we had with set items for a long time, and the reason we couldn't just buff them to fix them, because a big part of the problem was that they were too weak.
But the underlying problem was that they were dead-ed items.
They're items where once you get it, you have that item, you can get better rolls, but essentially that slot's done now for your build.
And that's very dangerous for the item system, especially because these are taking out multiple slots for each set.
And compare this to unique items where you can get legendary potential.
So, even once you've got it, it's not a dead end, there's still itemization to go.
So, with set items, we wanted a way to get those set bonuses and the core of these set items and allow players to use them in a way that doesn't make that slot a dead end.
I mean, that's actually a pretty brilliant solution because that's been like the age-old discussion about set items where, okay, you find it and you have it and the, and the progression is done.
But also, it also solves the problem of, okay, if you want to put set items in the game, well, how exactly would you balance it?
If you make them godly, then they're just best in slot items.
And if you make them suck, then sets are a meme.
But now that you shatter them and now that you can craft them into other items, it almost like solves that.
I don't know, man.
I'm very impressed with that solution.
I never thought of that.
I never thought of that ever.
Now that I'm a smart person, I'm kind of dumb.
But I don't know if I would have, I don't know if I would have got there.
That seems pretty smart to me, actually.
That's good.
That's very cool.
Mechanically, set items are very interesting.
They're cool to chase.
They're unique in terms of character, and we really wanted to be able to have set items in the game.
But for years and years, we were just very timid to add additional ones.
Because, again, the problem that we're calling out here, where they're either best in slot or you just don't want them whatsoever.
So, yeah, this is exciting for us.
And then hopefully we'll be able to start developing more set items because the system now exists.
And, yeah, I don't know if we mentioned, but these types of crafting rewards are, you know, they're at the end of specific Woven Echoes.
So, you know, you complete a Woven Echo, a specific Woven Echo, and you get the ability to shatter set items there.
Yeah, and there's Woven Offerings as well, where you take two items, you sacrifice one, and you buff the other one.
Do you improve it more than it currently is, or is this similar to, like, a Divine feature in Path of Exile 1?
Like, how does it work?
So, Divine, you're re-rolling it.
And because we wanted this sort of feature for a while with re-rolling unique affixes,
but we wanted to do it in a way that doesn't drastically reduce the rarity of having a perfect unique.
Because we've got the LP as well.
And unlike exalted items, uniques don't have an affording potential amount.
We couldn't really consume legendary potential for this because the extra affix is almost always going to be better than re-rolling it.
So, the way the system works is you're sacrificing another copy of the unique with equivalent legendary potential
or equivalent Weaver's Will plus affixes if it's a Weaver unique.
So, that means that you're using two for one re-rolled one.
And that means that we can still control the rarity of that through the normal truck face.
Awesome.
Cool.
Okay.
Anything else on that one?
Yeah.
So, can we move on to a little bit about the new items and, like, chase uniques and stuff like that?
Like, do you want to tease any, show any, talk about any?
I'm very all about, like, chasing things down.
Same.
I don't know.
Did we bring any tooltips to show?
You guys want to talk to you next for a second?
We can just talk about it, too.
I'll message our team and see if we might be able to get, like, a tooltip or two.
Okay.
Yeah.
So, you know, in terms of Season 2, we've got 25, I think, new ekes.
And eight of these are Weaver's Will specific uniques.
You know, there are some really powerful ones, things that drop from Ubarabroth, and they're not random drops in the world.
And there are a couple of specific uniques with some cool new effects, things that we haven't done before.
Things like redirecting a percentage of damage taken to your minions, things like that.
And, of course, there's different ways to craft uniques through Woven Echoes as well.
Awesome.
Cool.
Okay.
Well, while we look for, see if we have any tooltips for any teasers, there are, I think I saw three new crafting materials.
I jotted them down here real quickly.
Maybe we can just kind of rapid fire through all three of them and see how they're going to help us.
So, Rune of Weaving transforms a small amount of the remaining Weaver's Will on a unique item to legendary affixes.
Is this just a way to, like, accelerate what the Weaver's Will is giving us?
So you don't have to put on a crappy item and play for an hour.
Is that what that does?
Yes.
And that's the main purpose, because, obviously, with the Weaver expansion, we want to have more Weaver's Will uniques.
We want to drop them more frequently from the enemies in tombs and possessed enemies.
So we didn't want players to feel like they had to keep equipping all of these items and all their item slots are taken up by these,
where they're just working out whether the item's going to be good for them.
So, a lot of the time, the purpose of the Rune is to use it on a fresh Weaver's Will item.
And then you can see what affixes it's getting first and decide whether you want to actually equip that and use it up to its full potential.
And it's not just Weaver's Will uniques.
You can also use it on idols that have been enchanted with Weaver's Touch and see where those came.
Awesome.
Yeah, so that's definitely how I was feeling with the old Weaver's Will items.
So I get a Weaver's Will pair of boots.
I know almost always they're going to upgrade into crap that I'm not going to use.
And in order to find out, I got to put the boots on and play with them for an hour.
And I'm like, oh, this is terrible.
I'm just never going to touch Weaver's items again.
But now this Rune is going to accelerate that so we can actually see what it gets.
Okay, we have the Rune of Havoc.
It shuffles the tiers of non-sealed affixes on an exalted item with four non-sealed affixes.
The tiers are preserved.
They can't be exactly the same.
They cannot be used on items with all the same tiers.
So if it shuffles the tiers on an exalted item, does that mean, oh, I have movement speed over here,
but I have exalted fire resistance or something, and I don't want exalted fire resist.
I want exalted movement speed.
So you can shuffle it and try to move the exalt to the godly stat.
Is that what's happening here?
Yes.
Yeah.
So if it has two T7s and two T5s, it'll have two T7s and two T5s afterwards,
but which affixes those tiers are on will be shuffled around.
So, yeah, that's the exact purpose.
Mostly you've got something like boots that have T7 in one affix,
but you want that T7 to be on movement speed, and you shuffle it to get it there.
And these are quite powerful.
Like, this has a big effect on crafting exalted items and also crafting exalted items
before you combine them with a unique with LP and make it legendary.
So these are relatively rare.
They're about as rare as a Rune of Ascendance.
Oh, okay.
That's not too bad.
I think it's amazing how these runes are, like, yeah,
specifically targeting, like, a lot of pain points that we had.
Oh, I find exalts, and they're garbage.
I'll never use this.
Or I find weaver's will.
I'm not going to put it on to level it up.
But now I'll actually interact with these things.
It's great.
Last one, Rune of Redemption.
And then I think we got some goodies in the chat here.
Rune of Redemption randomly changes the exalted affixes on an item into different affixes.
So it doesn't change the tiers of the affixes.
So if you just get, if you get, like, a double exalt or something,
or a triple exalt and just hit all the garbage exalts, bam,
Rune of Redemption, you try to hit the miracle stats, right?
Exactly it.
So often you get these item drops that feel hype because they've got lots of exalted affixes,
but it's like one's health regen, one's fire vets.
Well, that can be what you're looking for with some builds.
So often it's not, and being able to have the chance to re-roll that is good.
It's not quite as powerful as Rune of Havoc in terms of getting exactly what exalted affixes you want.
But it can have a higher upside because with Rune of Havoc,
you've got to craft on the affix you want,
sometimes use a Rune of Removal and risk losing the exalted affix in the first place
to make room for the affix you want.
Whereas with this, you can just roll into it with one Rune.
Perfect.
Awesome.
Yeah.
And the other cool thing about Rune of Havoc is that's the one method that you can get exalted affixes
that you can't normally get,
things like experimental affixes or the new set affixes as well.
Yeah.
That's the only way to get exalted set affixes.
So, I have all the images you sent ready to pop up as well.
So, I can show them on stream.
And we'll start with this one.
Scissor of Atropos.
Five Weaver's Will.
That looks really cool.
Gain a stack of Kismet when you direct to use a melee attack.
What's Kismet?
Is that a class skill thing?
Sounds like Kismet.
Yeah.
It's a buff that's unique to this item.
So, the effects you see here are the full effects of Kismet.
Ah.
When you use a throwing attack, consume stacks to gain eight throwing critical strike.
Very cool.
Per stack.
Is there a max amount of stacks?
Yes.
It's eight mental save as any old text.
Oh, okay.
Cool.
Awesome.
I will pop open another one.
Then we have Klotho's Needle.
Block chance is converted to parry chance.
25 melee crit.
Multi per meter from the target up to five meters.
20 increased range with Fireman and Puncturer.
90 melee damage.
So, is this the same max Weaver's Will as on normal items?
Like, it's not always five?
Yes.
But Weaver's Will items still have an effective level for Weaver's Will, the same way that regular items have an effective level for Legendary Potential.
And that affects how likely they are to roll with high Weaver's Will or high Legendary Potential.
And so, it can roll with 28 Weaver's Will, but that's even less likely than a regular existing Weaver's Unique.
Very cool.
Can I ask a question here on these Uniques with the Weaver's Will?
So, when we play with this and we move through the Weaver's Will, does it add additional power to the existing affixes?
Or does it add another affix that it pumps up?
Or can it add multiple affixes?
It adds one or more new affixes, the same way that Weaver's Will does on existing items.
Okay.
So, it's not buffing up the existing affixes.
It's going to be something separate as you play with it on these.
Yeah.
Okay.
And then, next up, we have Immortal Lies.
30% of hit damage taken from bosses and rare enemies is dealt over four seconds instead.
While you have more than 10% of your max health is delayed damage,
damage to health below your neuron threshold is reduced by 30%.
Elite melee attack speed, 90 health and lots of strength.
This is one of the uber Abbey Uniques right here.
And actually, Ziz, are you showing the one that has the roll ranges attached to it?
Let's see.
I got a...
The team is feeding them to me right now.
It's one without ranges.
I see.
Yeah, both.
Cool.
Yeah, so Immortal Vice and Shattered Worlds are the two uber Abbey Uniques.
And we have both of those with roll ranges on there.
Oh.
And so these are with legendary potential, not with Weaver's Will.
Yeah, there's legendary potential.
The Weaver Fiend Uniques that you get inside tombs and from the tomb bosses,
those tend to be Weaver's Will, whereas the new uniques from Woven Echoes
with the other new bosses, new Brabbloth, are just regular legendary potential uniques.
Cool.
Can I ask something again about the Weaver's Will?
So when you get one of these uber uniques with five Weaver's Will,
and it's going to add a new affix,
are all Weaver's Will items pulling from the same Weaver's Will affix pool?
Or if we get a Weaver's Will item from Uber Abbey Uniques,
can it put like a special Weaver's Will affix that we can't see on other regular items?
The Weaver's Will always pulls from the regular affix pool for that item type.
So if you've got a unique two-handed sword with Weaver's Will,
it'll apply regular two-handed sword affixes to it.
Okay, so with our current knowledge of the game,
we should be able to plan out what would be the ultimate item,
like, oh, you have this sword and you want to hit,
I don't know, melee damage again or something,
and that would be the ultimate Giga Chat weapon.
Yeah.
Okay.
And you can plan all of it out with any Weaver's Will Uniques.
Awesome.
I'm also showing Shattered Worlds.
You are immune to Stho,
you have haste, 5% crit, 10 all the tributes,
100% infect of frenzy,
and plus one all skills.
And I actually really appreciate that you're showing the role
that I'm going to be dropping from my first kill.
So that was considered it.
It's missing the legendary potential that it's going to have,
but other than that...
This guy.
That looks nice.
That looks broken, actually.
That was very cool.
I think we have one more that I didn't show.
I don't think I showed this.
I didn't show this, did I?
I like how that one's all about going fast.
Can't be slowed.
You have haste.
Double the frenzy.
You're just the crackhead.
Must go fast.
Yeah, I don't think I showed this.
Plus two Max Kelly mages.
Nice.
Wow.
That's like plus a lot of stuff.
Very cool.
This is going to be very exciting with Weaver's Will.
Yeah.
Awesome.
That's one of the unique drops from one of the team bosses.
Very cool.
Yeah, thank you for showing those and teasing those.
That's very cool.
For sure.
I also got some of the new rune tooltips in here.
If we can spread those out later.
They're actually high-res ones.
Because I think they...
Did we show these in the trailer?
I think...
Yeah.
Yeah, they're in the trailer.
Okay.
Real quick before we go to the next topic.
Question on those runes.
When you use them,
do they have the opportunity
or do they consume forging potential on use?
Do you need to have forging potential to use them?
Yeah.
So fairly standard.
20 forging potential for both.
That's still potentially subject to change
based on balance testing.
But we think it's going to take us 20.
Okay.
Awesome.
So we have a rework.
The Sentinel rework.
Can you give us more insights into that?
Are these buffs or nerfs or new functionalities?
I remember last season,
I had a thing on my stream called Forge Guard Friday.
And believe me, I did.
I haven't hated Fridays ever more in my life
than when I was forced to do Forge Guard Friday.
I really hope we're getting some good news over there.
That's awesome.
Apologies that Friday was hard on you,
but it shouldn't be that way going forward quite as much.
Yeah.
We expect there's going to be a lot of new competitive builds
for Sentinels in season two.
Generally, they will be more powerful than they were previously.
We have a big rework coming in for Volatile Reversal,
which of course was a very powerful skill.
So we've been able to redistribute some of that power
across the rest of the Sentinel class,
which is giving it a lot more options here.
For example, we've done things like we've given a big boost
for Electrify builds.
We've reworked Time Rot.
It's quite powerful.
It's much more well-supported throughout all the trees.
We have some really cool additions to the passives,
like the ability to wield a two-handed weapon
alongside a shield at the same time.
So Forge Guard should be a little bit more fun with that.
And yeah, absolutely.
And we've got a lot of improvements,
a lot of updates to the passive trees in general,
especially for the Paladin and the Void Knight,
as those haven't been touched in quite a long time.
So yeah, I think people are going to have a really good time.
With the Sentinel reworks that are coming out this season.
And we'll be unveiling more just little pockets of passes
and stuff like that as we get closer to launch.
Awesome.
It's just so much stuff that I'm looking forward to.
And one of the things I'm really looking forward to
is Mastery Respec.
What's the cost of that?
And also, thank you so much for allowing the Respec of Mastery.
For those that don't know,
that's the last Epox version of Ascendencies.
And you can respec those now.
Yeah, we were stubborn about changing this for quite a long time.
We're the diehard ARPG fan base that's like,
once you get a clash, you're absolutely that character.
And you can't change.
You have to re-roll a character.
We finally gave way.
It is a good user experience boost
for people that don't want to be spending
a significant amount of time re-rolling characters.
So I think it is going to be very healthy for the game.
In terms for the cost associated with this,
it's fairly reasonable.
I don't have the exact numbers in front of me.
Ross or Holly, if you guys have any exact numbers here,
we can share.
But reasonable once you get to late,
like late 80s, 90s, and stuff like that.
Ramps pretty significantly.
But if you're a user experimenting with different masteries,
you're not going to have a hard time swapping to something else
if you decide that you've gone the wrong route.
Yeah, the last re-spec I did, I was level 85,
and I think it was half a million gold.
Early on, it is very cheap, though.
You should have enough gold initially, yeah.
Cool.
Yeah.
It goes up quite a bit after level 80.
But it scales with the level.
It's just gold.
That's our stubbornness coming through,
just at later levels.
I don't mind that it costs a lot.
I just want to be able to do it.
You got to put your foot down at some point, right?
Okay.
I saw that you guys are giving us some new inventory tabs.
That's amazing.
And I thought I heard you say at the very beginning,
you said something about crafting things going,
like not being in our inventory.
Is there something there?
Yeah, yeah.
We've actually made a big update
where when you pick up crafting materials,
they will now automatically go to your crafting inventory,
getting them out of your inventory panel
and not having to transfer them before they go away.
I will say that this is a massive quality of life feel.
It's probably one of my...
It's such a simple change,
but it's probably one of my very favorite things
coming out with Season 2.
That paired with the different stash tabs,
you're just not having to do inventory management
nearly as frequently as you had to previously,
and it feels very good.
Especially if you're playing on gamepad like I play
because my wrists are all screwed up
from playing these for thousands and thousands of hours.
Yes.
Massive.
Wow.
So I remember that was maybe one of the first Reddit posts
I ever put on Last Epoch when I started playing.
I was like, can we please...
So just to clarify,
we're talking about the little vacuum button
that we press all the time.
It just auto...
It says transfer,
and then it goes into the crafting.
That now is completely bypassed.
It is an option.
So for those of you that really like
pressing the transfer button,
I know there's a lot of you.
You can still do it,
but for everybody else,
they can go to the settings and check on,
and it'll just go immediately to the crafting inventory.
Yeah.
You can also...
You can opt out of certain things for that.
Sorry.
If you want rare crafting materials
to always read them
and make sure that you're understanding they're going in,
you can exclude them
from automatically being stashed,
which is helpful.
Oh.
Awesome.
Or keys or waving echoes,
but you can stash all of them if you want.
And it'll show the little tooltips
up on the top left of the screen
that it does when you manually click the store button.
So you do get that extra notification
of what you're picking up.
Cool.
Beautiful.
Another thing that's being added
is portal charms,
which bypasses the dungeon,
goes directly to the boss
for like drool run and stuff like that.
Is this a one-time use
or something I unlock
and then I can just skip the dungeon?
They are consumable items.
Yep.
And we're adding a couple different portal charms.
You know,
we know the one that people are going to be
the most excited about
is the one that allows you
to just skip directly to the boss on use.
Rarity-wise,
they're about as rare as a rune of ascendance,
but we also have a key vendor
inside of Majelka
where you can trade three
of the different dungeon keys
and then get a portal charm from that.
So yeah,
for people that are looking to skip the dungeon
and are doing things like farming keys
and stuff like that,
you should have them fairly readily available.
Yeah.
And do you need the key and the charm
or do you only need the charm?
You need the...
Yeah, you need both.
Yeah.
Awesome.
So I know tons of people
are going to be super excited
about the WASDE beta support.
A lot of people play that way.
It's a massive thing.
So I'm going to follow it up
with a very, very pivotal question.
So you guys got to be very careful
with this answer here.
Is there any news about
Last Epoch coming to consoles?
There's a lot of players out there
that are dying for you to release it over there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, okay.
I'll start with WASDE.
So WASDE is something, you know,
recently people have gone and played in WASDE
and there's a lot of people that says,
you know, I'll never be able to play an action RPG
without WASDE.
And so we did want to go and experiment with this
and see how quickly we might be able
to get a prototype of this across the line.
We were actually able to prototype it fairly quickly
and verify that it feels good.
And then we had to take a little bit more time
to do all the user-facing, you know,
input schemas and stuff like that.
It actually took a little bit longer
than actually implementing that base functionality
of WASDE.
For consoles, nothing to announce currently.
But what I will say is that
there is an absolute ton of work
going into the gamepad experience for PC.
Lots and lots and lots of updates coming to UI.
Gamepad targeting, things of that nature.
Lots coming with Season 2.
But that's just the beginning.
We are, we have ramped up that pipeline significantly.
So gamepad experience is going to be really solid in Nelly.
Cool. Awesome.
That's awesome.
Abarth as well is getting a lot of changes.
Is the base version a lot nerfed?
And like, what's, is the goal here
to just make like the first version
more accessible to people?
Tell me a little bit about that.
Yeah, it's, base Abarth is being nerfed a little bit.
On top of that, you know,
the power ceiling is rising just slightly
with the addition of idle enchantments
and, you know, a number of buffs
to existing classes and skills.
So base Abarth, we want that to be something
that an engaged player can pursue and get to.
Now, Uber Abarth is going to definitely be a chase kill
for anybody that's really hardcore into the game.
Oh, actually, is there any like race or anything
for the Uber Abarth?
If Scissor wants to make one.
Oh.
Okay.
We can maybe do that.
All right.
Let's talk.
Yeah.
Let's, let's see if we can do that.
Could be fun.
All right.
Well, kind of kept this one short and sweet
because there's going to be a whole month
of these podcasts going on.
We're doing one a week, right?
And the next one, I believe, is going to be with Gazzy.
So I assume all of those uniques that we saw in there
about the minion stuff,
I'm sure he's going to dissect them in tremendous detail.
I think I speak on behalf of the community
where we're just glad to see EHG and Last Epoch are back.
I consider this a wonderful update.
It's clear that you guys, as you said,
are we're not sitting around twiddling your thumbs.
It's coming out April 2nd.
That's correct.
Follow Zizarin everywhere.
We're here on Zizarin's channel.
He's on all social media.
And I don't know.
I had an amazing time here, guys.
Do you have anything else, Zizarin,
you wanted to throw out there before we close out?
I do, yeah.
Make sure you follow Rax everywhere as well.
He's also amazing.
Together, we're completely smurfed.
The Blue Man Group.
Here we are.
Love it, guys.
Absolute pleasure.
Appreciate you guys having us on.
Always a good time talking.
Awesome.
Thanks so much for doing this.
And hopefully we'll do more talks in the future.
All right, guys.
See you in game April 2nd.
Cheers.
Bye.
I...