Hello, this is Mike. I'm talking in my microphone.
Too loud, too low.
Good chat has to say.
Sounds good.
All right.
Wonders.
Carve, you're up.
One, two, three.
Here we are.
Too loud, too silent.
And it's in chat.
Totally good.
Good, good, good, good, good.
All right, everybody says good.
A bit quiet. Wait, who's quiet?
Twitch chat's saying good, though.
Carve will be quiet. I'll raise him up then.
And suddenly I'll move closer to my mic and I'm going to be super loud.
It's going to be great.
It is what it is.
Part of the job, right?
I think we got everything.
You guys just want to jump straight into it?
Yeah.
All right.
Let's make a little quick intro then.
Hi, everybody.
Welcome to my interview with Last Deep Work Devs.
Mike in Carve.
It's been a while since I saw you at Carve.
It's what?
X-LocCon, I think?
Yeah.
It's good to see you again.
And Mike, we've had a couple of interviews in the past already.
Welcome aboard, everybody.
How are you doing, Mike?
Doing great.
Feeling good.
It's, I always love doing these.
So excited to see what we get some spicy questions in here.
We've got some good stuff to share.
For sure.
And Carve, how are you doing?
Yeah, I'm good.
Pretty excited.
We got some good stuff to talk about.
Yeah.
Photon sent me some images here in the Discord here that we're going to be showing.
Quite excited to show these, actually.
And there's probably more images to be coming later that we just didn't want to dump immediately here.
That's fair.
All right.
Well, we have about one or two hours to basically put you guys in the furnace.
So I'm just going to go straight into this.
And you guys have been spammed.
I've been spammed.
Everyone's talking about it.
I was going to get rid of the elephant in the room.
And that is obviously the scheduling.
Two days after you guys are launching.
PeeWee 2 is coming out.
What's the take here?
Like, what's the...
How do I read this room?
Because everyone's kind of upset about it.
Yeah, we're disappointed along with everyone else on this.
And we're just focusing on our Season 2 right now.
And, you know, just building the hype and excitement for what we've got coming out.
That's our big focus right now.
That sounds good.
Yeah.
We've got good stuff coming in.
So it's worth it to get excited for.
Yeah.
Always disappointed.
But, yeah.
Of course.
I mean, I've been trying my best not to spill the beans on the CT stuff.
But the stuff I've seen is very exciting.
Thank you.
Well, let's go into...
It's hard not to say anything, though, isn't it?
I know.
I'm just sitting here with a grin on my face.
People asking questions.
What about this?
What about that?
And I'm like, I know exactly the answer to that.
Well, we haven't gotten access to everything, which I think is good.
And I've been trying not to explore too much of the in-depth stuff.
So on launch, a lot of things will still be kind of fresh for me, which is going to be very fun.
So this interview, we're going to be focusing on basically class rework and balance.
So those are the main overlaying themes of this interview.
So that's the questions we're going to be following up for the rest of this interview.
It's going to be with that theme.
And I'm going to start off with number one in my little list here, which is about meta shakeups and how you guys are intending to tackling balance in general, both in terms of timelines, such as, you know, only having changes on every launch or mid-seasonal changes, and also asking if the idea is to earn nerf outliers at the top or rather exclusively bringing underperforming builds up on par.
Yeah, it's...
So, yeah, it's a combination approach of basically everything you've got there.
So we really want to take those builds that are crazy outliers, because there's a few of them that are a little wacky, what they can do, and bringing those down into the realms of reality.
And...
But we are raising the floor on a lot of builds right now.
So there's a lot of new stuff coming in that's going to make a lot of builds that were not working, not having a great time.
You get to endgame, you're trying to push through some of the more difficult content.
So bringing the floor up on a lot of builds is really important at the same time.
Getting everything into that, like, 80%, 80-100% range is, I think...
I think...
It's the goal in general, yeah.
And we're not really interested in the mid-season changes yet, so we are still focusing on that, getting things near the start of the season as much as possible.
Yeah, when we asked the community, I don't even remember when it was about mid-season changes.
They were pretty against it, for a good reason.
It's like, imagine playing something really fun and then it just gets nuked out of orbit because it was just too good.
So we generally try to avoid that as much as possible.
And then only, like, do it like buggy interactions and whatnot.
So, yeah.
That's true.
But what comes to the nerfing, like, over-performers versus just buffing everything else...
This patch, the floor is going to come up because we have new stuff that's going to give you new power.
So obviously the maximum of power you can get is going to go up.
And then the gearing, like the plateau of how quickly you start having issues upgrading your gear is going to last longer because there's going to be so much new stuff to help you craft.
And obviously, let's say...
This is random numbers.
Let's say you have a thousand builds.
And out of those thousand builds, there's like ten that are just like a thousand times better than everything else.
It's a lot easier to target nerf those down while buffing the rest a bit versus trying to bring everything up because that would also buff the over-performers.
Because when the games get as complicated as we have, if you buff something, it's most likely going to affect something else too.
Because we have stuff like triggering other abilities and if you buff an item that is used in like ten builds, then every build is going to get a buff and so on.
That's fair.
I remember former class lead designer Adam Jackson for Diablo 4, he used a hand gesture and basically said they want to have builds within this frame.
And they want to bring builds above this line down to this frame and builds beneath it up to that frame and have basically everything in existence exist within this parameter of build performance.
And we have other games like P.O.A., for example, who are perfectly fine with builds basically just being really bad.
And then they want to try to have a kind of a healthy frame in this hand gesture moment here with a couple of outliers every meta shakeups that are performing a bit better.
What is the approach of that kind of theme moving forward with last deep book?
Are you okay with builds being underperforming or do you want all of the builds to exist within this parameter?
I mean, I think it's a good way of describing it.
And I think in a perfect world, everything would be in that range where like there are certain things that need to be more stronger and there are certain things that need to be weaker.
In order for like you to make you feel like when you're making good decisions in the game and you are you're like, hey, I figured out a way to make my build stronger.
Something has to be weaker for that to be true.
And so there's never getting everything to the exact same level is is a fool's errand and it's never going to work.
It's never going to happen.
And we don't want to.
But yes, getting everything into a closer range where like the the lower performing ones are still viable is is ideal.
We know we're never going to have like if someone wants to try and take some build that is I get in trouble when I say this because I say some ridiculous build and someone's like, I'm going to make it work.
Like if there's always certain things that are just so ridiculous that you're just not going to make them.
It's just not going to happen.
That's fair.
All right.
So we're going to move on to the next question, which is kind of a big one.
And it's about defenses.
And the first one we're going to cover is balance approach comparing health versus ward.
And we've been existing in this pendulum swinging back and forth.
We had this huge life meta and then he swung back to ward meta.
Then we was back to to a life meta and then we're back in ward again.
So what's the approach of available toolkits and balancing the differences between health and ward moving forward from here?
Yeah, we might just end discussing this topic for the rest of the podcast.
So, yeah.
So, yeah, you're right.
Ward has been really good and it's been really bad.
And on launch, it was really good.
And then we brought it down a bit.
Not enough.
So there's going to be more changes to slightly nerf ward where it needs a nerf.
But we're also buffing health.
I think the first thing would be that int is just a very good stat to stack.
You get all the great stuff, especially for specific classes like acolytes and a mage.
So we are reducing the ward retention you get from 4% to 2%.
And then we're going to be targeting cases where skills or passives are just very good at generating ward out of nowhere.
I think we gave you a picture of one of the nodes for Acolyte.
The pure fruit?
I can bring it up.
Yes.
Yeah, that one.
Yeah.
So that one specifically, you get ward when you hit a target that is afflicted by spirit plague.
So that is just whenever you hit something that has it, you get ward.
With 3 points, that's like 12 ward per hit.
And with some cool skill interactions, you can get a lot of hits per second.
Especially because stuff like bone curse is considered a hit.
So you can like double the effect there.
So what we're doing is we are curtailing the power of like these absolutely insane amount of applications per second.
But we're buffing the individual cases.
So builds that aren't like abusing those million hits a second are going to be better.
And those that we're abusing are going to be worse.
So we got cases like this in a couple items.
I think just a couple rings that have like ward on a hit and stuff like that.
And then overall, ward is just like way too easy to get from passives and skills.
So we're moving a lot of that into items.
So there's a couple new like, I think, affixes for it.
So it just, it takes more gear now to get that.
So basically the powers moved more from away from the pass and the free access and moved into gear progression to build it up.
And just to everyone's clear, this one up here is the current version of future recovery.
And the one down here is after the changes on the bottom here.
Yeah, so numbers going up.
It's a big buff, right?
It's quite extensive, yes.
Unless you are hitting like 100 times a second.
Unless, yeah.
Then it's enough.
As for health, health was basically all tied to gear in most cases.
You get a decent amount of passives and whatnot.
But then we have like these crazy items like, you know, the stout idol that has a double health.
It has increased health and it has a flat health.
So I think we removed the flat health from there.
And then, because it's now we're nerfing the health belts there.
So what we ended up doing is we're buffing some of the health values and affixes.
I think we introduced one or two new health affixes, like hybrid affixes.
One is region.
So region is going to be pretty good.
This patch.
Which previously haven't really been.
It's only like couple built, very specific built that were really good with region.
But now it's going to be more available.
Yeah, like the vessel of strife, right?
From Jura.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, that item might specifically have been nerfed a tiny bit to compensate.
God damn it.
Yeah.
And then we also increased the health gain per level.
So I think it's currently eight health you get whenever your character levels up.
In season two, it's going to be ten.
So you're just going to get more health just from levels as well.
And health potions are more effective now too.
Okay.
Do you guys think that this is going to be enough to get like a balance between the two?
So you don't feel like you're scuffed for playing life or the other ward instead?
Do you feel like they're going to be pretty balanced with this?
Or how's the confidence in this?
You're going to see health builds, especially in classes that are good with it.
And you'll hopefully also see reward builds for those classes.
Especially like Mage and Acolyte.
Because they have a lot of support for that.
So they should be good with it.
As for like the ultimate, like...
I've seen a lot of talk about we should just cap ward.
To be like a percentage of your max health or something like that.
I mean, we could do that.
But it's just boring.
It's just boring.
We'd rather try to slowly balance it so they're both really good and cool.
And maybe some hybrids where you do both and stuff like that.
Because it's just fun trying to break the game with stuff like that.
It's just fun.
Fair enough.
I mean, I like the approach.
Especially like with removing the whole double life idols.
It's been...
Oh, it's so frustrating is a good way to put it.
At least for COF to try to find these double life idols.
Because of how valuable they are for the defensive layers of your character.
But speaking of defensive layers.
There's another question we have.
Which is about the crazy differences in performance between different ailments.
And the question is if this is going to be tackled in the new season.
With ailments specifically.
I'm not talking about just taking the damage amailments.
But also applying those type of ailments.
So is there something you can cover or leak for us here regarding this for season 2?
I mean, there's no leak.
There's only teasers and knowledge, I guess.
You'll be taking less damage from damage over time.
Overall.
Just globally.
Enemies will deal less damage than you know.
I think it's like 15%.
15, yeah.
And then, on top of that.
Corruption.
You know, the corruption providing more damage to enemies.
That is half as effective for DOTS.
So if they grant 200% more damage.
They only get 100% damage for DOTS.
Okay.
So I've been doing some rounds talking to some Last Epoch creators.
That mainly make content for Last Epoch.
And Sagan Survives is a content creator that I was talking to.
That had a question specifically about damage over time that you take.
Because of how reducing the DOTS damage taken and higher corruptions.
It has become such a mandatory stat.
So the changes you were talking about.
Lowering the corruption.
The impact on that specifically.
Is the solution to that problem.
Am I understanding you correctly then?
Yeah.
So we could just introduce more different mechanics.
For you to reduce DOT damage.
But then that puts more pressure on gear.
Which you already have a lot of pressure on gear for damage mitigation.
Because we're scaling the damage and health of enemies with corruption.
Like the same time.
So they end up doing more damage before they die from your damage.
So it's very heavily lopsided.
Just investing in the defense in the endgame.
In Last Epoch currently.
Fair enough.
As for some of the elements that players do.
So specifically two elements tied to Sentinel.
So Electrify.
Which is like the holy lightning damage over time.
Is getting a lot more support for Paladin now.
I think you might have a couple pictures of that somewhere.
We do.
It was just so buried.
And impossible to get things that scaled with it.
It had a couple uniques.
Yeah.
That were basically.
You had to use them.
We're probably still going to use some of them.
I think we nerfed some of them a tiny bit.
Because we made the.
It's just more accessible to actually scale.
Electrify.
As a Paladin now.
So we introduced a new Affix.
Which I think spawns both on helmets and body armors.
Which is just Electrify chance with lightning skills.
And then.
On the Paladin passive tree.
There's some more Electrify support.
As well as a new like an actual scaler.
There's a new node that provides you more lightning damage over time.
Based on your Crit Multi.
So if you have like 300% Crit Multi.
From gear.
So this is.
The Crit Multi.
On top of the base.
So the base Crit Multi.
Isn't calculate here.
So if you have like 300% Crit Multi.
That's.
I think 150% more.
Lightning damage over time.
So maybe there's some.
Hybrid hit.
Without lightning builds out there.
Who knows.
I think we've got a picture for that one too actually.
Yeah we do.
The.
Judgment of Storm.
Yes.
Is the node.
Here's the Electrify example.
Judgment of Storm.
This is for the Electrify support for Paladins.
Yeah.
Which has a threshold node.
A very important point out.
It's a threshold node.
Which you kind of want to see more in Acolyte by the way.
Shock Chance.
Lightning Rest Shred.
And Electrify Chance.
And the threshold is.
You'll deal more lightning damage over time.
Multiplicative with other modifiers.
Per 2%.
Add a Crit Multi.
Above the base 200.
So that's how you bypass the base.
Then save it.
Add a Crit Multi above.
That is what's adding to it.
Yep.
And somebody in the chat asked.
If this affix is only for Sentinels.
And yes.
Sentinel.
Well.
Paladins more specifically.
Because it's a.
The ailment is like the Holy themed.
So that's why it's very heavily tied.
To just Sentinel and Paladins specifically.
Does that mean that the Electrify modifier.
Would only show up on Sentinel specific items.
Yes.
That affix.
The Electrify Chance with lighting skills.
Is only for Sentinels.
Just like.
Just like you have like plus level of skills.
For individual skills.
For different classes.
On like body armor relics and chests.
So then I would assume that.
If you get the craft charts.
For that modifier.
You can then put it on non-Sentinel pieces as well.
But you don't.
You will never drop a non-Sentinel piece.
That has that modifier on it.
Like you won't craft it on it.
No.
It has to always go on Sentinel.
You can't.
You cannot get that mod on any class.
Other than a Sentinel.
Can't even craft it on it.
No.
Same thing.
Yeah.
Same thing for other.
Yep.
Like affix like that.
And then the other.
The other element.
Is something that people know exists.
But it's basically just.
It's just a.
The stat that you have for some builds.
And that's Time Rot.
Yeah.
And.
Yes.
Time Rot is actually a.
Alement now.
That you can make.
Pretty crazy.
We didn't want to.
We didn't want to just make it like every other element.
Which would be uncapped.
Which caused a lot of.
The problems with balance.
And just tech issues.
We're not going to probably go into too much with that.
But.
That meant we had to have.
Like unique scalers for it basically.
Because like.
Uncapped elements.
You like.
You get like pen.
You get damage.
You get duration.
Like how many you can apply.
As soon as possible.
So since Time Rot is still capped at 12.
We need to find.
Basically more multipliers for it.
That.
Allow you to scale the damage of it.
So.
One of them is.
Timer chance.
With.
With void skills.
And this does not.
Account for.
The.
Chance on individual skills.
So this is like.
The global stat.
So if you have.
Like Warpath.
Let's say you had like.
100% chance.
That wouldn't apply for this.
So this is just.
Globally from like.
Passive skill trees.
Sorry.
Not skill trees.
Gear like idols.
Or.
In this case again.
Body armor and helmet.
Because we made an affix for that.
And then we have slow.
Because that's very thematic.
Time Rot.
It's a time base.
Right.
So we have slow.
And then.
We have the.
Lowest.
Of I think it's attack.
Cast and throwing.
Speeds.
So you have to invest.
In all of those three stats.
And it picks the lowest.
As the multiplier.
So there's a.
You can make.
You can get this.
To do some crazy damage now.
Previously.
It was just basically a debuff.
For some abilities.
Like.
Erasing strike.
Does like more damage.
If enemy has 12 stacks of it.
But now you can just.
Make time rot.
Actually do damage.
Which is pretty exciting.
No for sure.
I mean this one's.
Really really interesting.
You guys were talking about this.
In the previous interview.
With spreading out.
Some of the power.
From the sentinel.
In general.
To create more of a.
Balanced approach to it.
Right.
And this is one of those changes.
To allow the time rot.
To be more of a competitive damage.
Approach.
Right.
That's my understanding.
At least.
Yep.
And.
You will be able to see.
You will be seeing.
Time rot builds.
In season two.
Yes.
You will definitely be seeing them.
For sure.
Let's move over to another question.
And that is.
Well actually.
Before we move over to the question.
I do want to talk about.
Damage every time.
And ailments.
We've seen the time rot stuff.
Electrify.
Are there any other.
Changes to.
Existing dots.
Like frostbite.
Or poison.
For example.
I don't think we have.
Any actual changes.
To any of those ailments.
But as.
We create more items.
That support those ailments.
They can get better.
Like.
Bleed is.
Bleed probably has the most.
Amount of support.
Yeah.
From different ailments.
That's also because.
Yeah.
Because that's.
It's available.
For basically every single class.
In the game.
We have the electrify.
That is very.
Tied to just be in Balatin.
We have frostbite.
That is basically.
Mage.
Primalist.
And now.
We are.
Slowly.
Adding some of that.
Into.
Rogue.
With some of the.
The changes.
But yeah.
Fair enough.
There.
There isn't.
Any actual.
Ailment.
Changes to themselves.
Dispatch.
All right.
The base functionality.
Of those ailments.
Is staying the same.
But there are.
Other things.
That can affect those.
Coming.
Okay.
I'm excited to see.
Moving over to the next topic.
It is monoliths.
Which is kind of like.
The main theme.
Of the season.
Essentially.
The end game.
Right.
So end game.
Is being heavily focused.
For this specific.
Seasonal launch.
And I guess the question.
One of the small questions.
We can start with here.
Is.
Will we have.
Player agency.
Control over.
Manually.
Using individual.
Monoliths.
Like examples.
Could be like.
Scarabs.
Or Deliores.
And PoE.
For example.
Is that something.
You guys are planning to do?
Yes.
To elaborate.
Do you want to take this?
Yeah.
I can talk about.
So.
Yeah.
The.
One of the.
One of the main key features.
Of.
Of this.
Of this patch.
And this.
This whole season.
Is.
Woven echoes.
And those are.
Specific activities.
That you know.
What they're going to be.
You can see what they're going to be.
You can.
And you.
You physically place them.
Into your.
Into your timeline.
Echo web.
Web.
Um.
And.
You.
You can.
Make new paths.
Opening up with them.
You can connect nodes.
That you're like.
Oh.
I don't want to go through this one.
I want to go around it.
You can make.
Paths around it now.
Um.
And there's.
They.
They are itemized.
So they are things that you are.
Going to be finding out in the world.
Uh.
And as you find them.
You'll be able to be like.
Okay.
Now I've got one of these.
In my pocket.
I can go do this whenever I want.
Uh.
And you can start it.
It.
Sits into the web.
It sort of behaves.
Uh.
It.
Respects the distance from the center.
Modifiers.
And corruption modifiers.
Um.
And.
And all of those apply to it.
So you can.
You can juice up some pretty sweet stuff there.
If you want.
Uh.
Not quite in the same.
I should probably shouldn't have used that word.
Not in the same sense.
That you can use it in other systems.
Um.
But yeah.
There's.
There's a lot of.
There's a lot of customization.
That you can have.
With.
What content you're going to be tackling.
That you just.
Didn't have before.
Yeah.
To.
To add there a bit maybe.
Uh.
We are not.
We are.
Not really keen on like.
Super micro management.
Stuff.
Like.
You know.
Elder rings.
Or.
The old.
Uh.
Old sextants in POV.
Or scarabs.
Or delirium orbs.
Like that.
So we've been.
It's actually very.
Challenging.
To try to come up with.
Systems that allow you to do.
That kind of.
Choosing.
That.
Doesn't.
Devolve into.
This.
Massive amount of.
Preparation.
For every single.
Area that you go to.
We have.
Maybe.
I think we have a few.
Of the WoW and Echoes.
That will.
Have an impact on.
Other WoW and Echoes.
Like other other Echoes.
Also.
Sometimes in WoW and Echoes.
When you do them.
But we don't.
Have crazy plans.
Or adding dispatch.
Anything like that.
That you would.
Think of like scarabs.
Or.
Tablets.
And towers in POV2.
Or stuff like that.
We are.
We are very on the.
Go in.
Have fun.
Get out.
Then you go into the next one.
Instead of.
Setting up.
Half an hour.
To go in.
And then.
Do a bunch of stuff.
Fair enough.
What you guys talked about.
In the teaser.
Was shown.
Stash.
The inventory tabs.
Right.
Can we assume.
That these.
These juicers.
If you will.
Will be available.
In a separate tab.
Or will we have our inventory.
Clogged up with these.
Every single WoW.
Echoes has a slot.
On the tab.
Yes.
Just to verify.
Yeah.
They each have their own.
Individual slots.
That they go into.
And there's an option.
To have them go directly.
There automatically.
Without having to sort them.
There manually.
They just go in.
They never touch your inventory.
If you don't want them to.
If you do want them to go into.
Your inventory.
Or you can.
Okay.
So you can move them out.
If you want to.
Okay.
Yeah.
I like that.
You can.
Yeah.
I think it's shift right click.
You can just spam those.
And they will be dropped.
From the inventory.
To the ground.
If you want to.
And obviously.
You can just pick them up.
On the inventory.
And then press the button.
To slurp them in.
At the same time.
If you like that.
But yeah.
They will all.
Be with you.
All the time.
And I think.
It's also.
Shared between the stash.
So yeah.
You'll just.
Have them there with you.
All the time.
It should be stash linked.
So yeah.
So all of your like.
Non-solo.
Softcore characters.
Have them.
And all of your.
Non-solo.
Hardcore characters.
Have a separate set.
They're not shared.
Between those things.
So everyone that shares a stash.
Shares the.
Woven Echoes.
Stash.
I do have a follow up question.
I mean.
It sounds great.
And I love the idea.
Player agency.
Same thing with the whole.
Shards being automatic.
Couldn't assume.
Crafting shards that is.
Or you can choose to have them.
In your inventory.
To click the transfer button.
I got.
I have no idea.
Who's psychopathic.
Like the psychopaths.
That would actually want to do that.
But they exist.
However.
These things.
Being.
Itemized.
If you will.
To become an actual physical item.
That kind of.
It brings up the question.
Whether or not.
Are they tradable.
And giftable.
As well.
No.
They're not tradable.
Or giftable.
However.
Because you can.
Bring anyone.
Into your Echo Web.
You can just.
You can just start it.
In your Echo Web.
And bring someone else with you.
And they get the full benefits from it.
So it's.
They're.
They're shareable.
In the sense that you can.
Do them together.
In a party of people.
But you can't.
Physically.
Just be like.
Here you go.
You go take this one.
They're not going to be for sale.
On the auction.
On the bazaar.
Yeah.
They are locked.
Their character.
Or their account bound.
But yeah.
Yeah.
It's the same case.
For everything that.
Is a.
Like an unmodifiable item.
Like runes.
Shards.
Stuff like that.
We could.
Go into a very.
Deep rabbit hole.
Discussing.
Why that is.
But there is a world where.
Those might be tradable.
In the future.
But it regards some big changes to.
How.
Item factions work.
Oh.
It is.
It is something that is.
Technically possible.
But it runs into some.
Some design problems.
But yeah.
We'll.
Maybe.
Maybe we'll talk about it.
At some point.
We'll get there.
All right.
Moving over to the next part.
Of the end game.
Is the.
Current state of bosses.
Have a ward system.
That prevents them from.
Essentially getting one shot.
And or kill too fast.
There's obviously a lot of comments.
Around the system.
Including things like.
Culling strike.
Where you execute the monster.
At a certain life threshold.
Having a severely diminished value.
As a result of this.
And it's considered more often.
A moment of frustration.
So the question of this is.
How is the system going to be changing.
The new season.
If at all.
Well yeah.
First of all.
It doesn't actually.
Like full one shot prevention.
It's not there.
Like if you hit it hard enough.
That you can deal enough damage.
For it's all of its health.
And all of the ward bars.
All at the same time.
It will just one shot it.
Like so that is.
That is technically possible to do.
You can one shot them.
If you have enough damage up front.
It doesn't create like.
Spots where it just like.
Removes all damage off.
And then you have to start over.
Or something like that.
But yeah.
It's it is.
It's a.
It's a hotly debated topic.
For sure.
And it's.
It is providing.
We think.
A very important functionality.
To.
To the end game system.
But at the same time.
It is.
Showing up in a lot of places.
That it doesn't need to.
So we are.
We're removing it from.
Almost.
The vast majority of.
Of cases that are.
That have it.
It's not going to be there anymore.
It's just going to be a straight health bar.
Like normal.
And then in the.
The more significant.
Like really.
Really.
Grandiose.
Boss fights.
Those are going to still have.
A boss ward system.
Because.
And.
And what it really does.
Is it does help.
Those.
Those builds that are.
You know.
Maybe struggling to do.
Is quite as much damage.
To get.
To get those boss fights.
A little bit quicker.
So when you say.
That like.
There's a clear.
There's a line.
Where.
They don't.
They're not needed.
Now they're needed.
We don't have to go into the detail of it.
But I guess.
The only question I have.
Is.
Does this mean.
That the campaign bosses.
Do not have this ward system anymore.
I think it's on some.
Campaign bosses.
Is.
But it's nowhere close to.
As what you're used to seeing.
Okay.
Fair enough.
I think that's a good change.
Yeah.
Also for the.
For the.
It's very scary.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Also for the kill.
Kill threshold part of that question.
We think it's a good thing.
Because it's very.
Very powerful.
So it actually.
Doing that.
Is.
Yeah.
It's a good thing that it.
Produces the power of that a bit.
Fair enough.
Yeah.
Kill threshold is.
Is really.
It's almost mandatory.
Without.
Without a system like this.
And even with it.
It's still crazy powerful.
But that's not like a bad thing to have.
That you need to slot in.
Because basically every class.
Does have access to it.
In some way or another.
That's true.
Another end game question.
Or model of the question.
Is.
A rather big one.
Covering corruption in general.
So favor farming.
Which is also impacting.
Item acquisition.
Experience gain.
And LP item chances.
For example.
And most importantly.
Favor farming.
Being such a big factor.
In how you progress your characters.
It seems very heavily favored.
Around a 1000 corruption.
At the moment.
In the current state of the game.
At least.
So I guess the question.
Comes down to what the intended.
Corruption.
That EHG.
Wants people to consider.
To be the actual.
End game.
For good.
And great.
Or beyond builds.
Before Mike goes.
On a rant here.
One thing that we didn't say.
About the boss word.
Is that it also just.
Decays faster.
No.
Oh.
That's even better.
Thank you.
Carp and I debate this.
We were prepping for this.
We actually got into a bit of a.
Debate on this topic ourselves.
So it's something that is.
You know.
We.
It's not always cut and dry.
On what the best idea is.
And I think.
As long as there's like.
Crazy.
Like extreme.
Outlier builds.
There's going to be.
It's going to be.
It's going to be a bit of an issue.
And bringing those extreme.
Outlier builds down.
Is probably the most important part of.
Balancing this.
I think.
So where would you say.
A good.
End game build.
What is the considered.
End game corruption level.
From the ESG standpoint.
I would say.
If you have a build.
You go ahead.
Sorry.
I'll go.
Yeah.
If you.
Like I was about to say.
It's very hard to quantify that.
Because there's so many things.
That you can do with your builds.
And.
If you make nothing but bad decisions.
With your builds.
It probably shouldn't be able to do.
A certain amount of corruption.
And.
We want there to be.
Options for people to also.
Make.
Bad builds.
Because if you can't make a bad build.
You can't really make a good build.
Because everything is the same.
As for.
Let's say that you have a.
You know.
A decent understanding of the game.
And how to make a build.
If.
It can.
Comfortably do like.
300 corruption.
I'd call it a successful build.
But.
The.
The amount of.
With so many topics right now.
In my mind right now.
So.
When we're talking about the.
Like the favor.
Farbic and whatnot.
We already have.
Timidish returns.
Starting from.
I think.
Is it like 300 corruption.
Then 500 corruption.
And then finally on the.
The thousand mark.
The.
The benefits you get.
From each point of corruption.
For experience.
Matters a lot less.
So.
And then there's the question of.
Okay.
Should at some point.
There be no.
Nothing anymore.
The only thing that matters anymore.
Like.
When corruption arises.
The only thing that goes up.
Is the difficulty.
If we were to do that.
Now.
We are setting.
A.
Very specific.
Threshold.
That.
Means viability.
For every single build in the game.
If it's.
At.
500.
There's a lot of viable builds.
If it's at a thousand.
Suddenly.
There's a lot less viable builds.
If it's at a two thousand.
So.
It's.
We'd rather.
Not.
I don't want to say not punish.
We rather.
Reward people.
For being able to do.
Higher difficulty.
But it's just a question.
Like.
There's a balance of.
How much should they be rewarded for.
And that's why we do have.
The diminishing returns.
Maybe those.
Should be.
Higher.
Maybe the corruption scaling.
Should be.
Faster.
Than it is right now.
There's a lot of.
Questions around this.
Just ignoring the balance.
There's a lot of like.
Pure design.
Questions here.
That.
Needs to be answered.
Before you get.
Undecided on.
Before you can get.
Proper.
Decisions made there.
And we have people.
Like.
We have.
We debate this a lot.
Internally.
So yeah.
It's also about.
There's an important factor here.
About the.
The time it takes.
To.
To get that corruption.
As well.
So.
At some point.
If it is a.
Like.
What paths you have to.
How fast you can increase your corruption.
And how.
How long that actually takes.
Of gameplay time.
Because if you are.
We want you to stay challenged.
We want you to stay.
That's the important thing.
Is that you are still being challenged.
As you're.
As you're advancing.
The.
The difficulty of content.
That you're.
Like.
Able to do.
So you get more powerful.
But you still get.
Challenged.
Because you still have more.
Challenges to take on.
And having.
Having that.
Curve.
Feel good.
Is.
Is really important.
That's fair.
I mean.
My.
Next question.
Was to talk about.
The time requirement.
In moving from normal monos.
To corrupted ones.
But before I touch you.
That I want to verify.
One question.
In the current state.
Of the game.
The.
Apparote.
The big endgame.
Pinnacle boss.
Is something you unlock.
At 300 corruption.
Now.
We're.
Being told that.
That fight is going to be made.
Slightly easier.
And the power.
Free power scaling.
Your character is going to go up a bit.
As well.
Like the very ground.
Is going to move up.
The bar.
With these things in mind.
Are we going to still see.
This first initial version.
Of Abarth.
Being at 300 corruption.
That's not changing.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's not changing.
And it's still going to be.
There isn't many.
Like.
Nerfs to it.
It's still going to be.
A challenging fight.
For a lot of.
People.
And builds.
That aren't like.
Super optimized.
It's still going to be.
A difficult fight.
Yeah.
Bringing a homebrew build.
To Abarth.
As you've just finished.
300 corruption.
Is going to be.
A very significant achievement.
To be able to do.
Um.
Right.
Right now.
Most people are hitting 300.
Trying Abarth.
And being like.
I'm nowhere near powerful enough.
I've got to farm a bunch at 300.
And I'm actually going.
Significantly above 300.
Before I'm able to do Abarth.
Um.
And so you're still going to be.
Probably still.
Like.
Still going in.
Immediately after.
Completing 300.
And immediately unlocking it.
If you're.
If you're not on a.
A heavily optimized build.
It's still going to be very.
Very.
Significant accomplishment.
To be able to.
Complete it right away.
It's also.
A very interesting.
Discussion that.
We originally had.
The Abarth access.
I think it was.
500 or 600 corruption.
Uh.
And we got a lot of feedback.
That.
Uh.
It would be fun.
To be able to.
Attempt the fight.
Much earlier.
Even.
If the difficulty.
Of the fight.
Isn't.
Quite correspondent.
The.
When you have access to it.
So.
If.
Abarth took like.
I don't know.
600 corruption.
It would take you.
A bit longer.
To get to.
You would have.
Easier time.
Fighting it.
Because if you can do.
600 corruption.
You're going to have.
A lot easier time.
Fighting Abarth as well.
But we wanted.
And that's also why.
We provide you like.
Ten.
Harbinger eyes.
For testing.
Like attempting it.
If you really want to.
Push yourself.
And try to learn the fight.
Already immediately.
At that point.
So.
Okay.
That's fair.
So what about.
The time requirement.
On your very first character.
There are catch up mechanics.
In your alts.
But the time requirement.
In moving from normal monos.
Into the corrupted versions.
On your first character.
What's the changes.
Happening there.
If any.
I think the only changes.
For that.
Come from.
The weaver tree.
I don't think.
If we have any other changes.
Coming.
But you can specialize.
Weaver tree.
A bit.
So that you can get there.
Faster.
Not by much.
But it's already.
Pretty fast.
If you just push one.
Timeline.
With the mechanics.
That exist in game.
Like.
Cliff of Envy.
And then you use the catch up.
Mechanic.
For the other timelines.
It's.
It's surprisingly fast.
Already.
And.
Speaking of the alts.
We are adding.
Couple.
Couple new cool things.
For.
Alts.
To be faster.
So.
The.
Normal timeline.
Is now shared.
So if you have a character.
In.
Empowered Monoliths.
And you make an old character.
You don't need to go through.
All of them anymore.
You just go do one of the.
Nineties.
I believe.
And.
You go.
Straight to empowered.
Again.
If you want to.
That is a massive change.
Yeah.
Yes.
And then.
The other one is.
We had.
Items to push corruption faster.
But.
Let's say that you have.
That one character.
A thousand corruption.
Yeah.
It can feel a bit daunting.
To think.
Okay.
If I have like.
This crazy gear.
Prepared for my next character.
And you just want to go.
You know.
Fight.
Actual harder.
Harder corner with that.
It takes a while.
To get back to the thousand.
So.
One of the Bowen echoes.
Allows you to.
Catch up corruption.
From the highest corruption.
In the stash.
So.
If you have one character.
A thousand corruption.
And then you make the alt.
Once you complete the Bowen echo.
It gets to that corruption.
That the builder character was.
Oh.
That's also really big.
That's a good change.
That's very big.
Yes.
And that's something that you can farm.
On the first character.
And then use on the second character.
Still.
Because it's shared across the stash.
As well.
Nice.
The only.
The only play more.
That doesn't have that.
Is if you're playing.
Solo character found.
Because it.
It's like actual.
Full individual character.
And stash.
With nothing shared.
But solo accounts found.
And then just.
No challenges.
Past that.
Yeah.
It is.
It is stash shared.
So yeah.
Everything.
As long as the two characters.
Have the same.
Access to the same stash.
Then they will have.
This mechanic.
Working with them.
That's fair.
One of the questions.
We have in the list.
Is the massive amount.
Of extra content.
Included in the new season.
And the question.
Was about.
If whether or not.
Capping corruption.
Scaling.
Have been brought back to the table.
But we kind of already.
Covered that part.
So I'm just going to skip that one.
And instead.
Bring up another question.
Which is from another.
Last Apoch creator.
Called Lizard.
IRL.
And he was.
Talking about.
The idea of the.
Expectant.
Approach.
The EHG.
Has to the game.
The question goes as follows.
And that is that.
A lot of us are rather interested.
In hearing this.
And it's to circle back.
To a commonly asked question.
From the past.
And that is to ask.
What the expected.
DPS.
Threshold.
EHD.
Wants players to reach.
To handle.
X amount of corruption.
So essentially.
What I'm trying to get.
Here is.
It seems like.
The expected.
Endgame approach.
Is to make the normal.
Version of Abarth.
Be a fight.
Most people can handle.
Or if not all people.
Can handle this.
So I guess.
The question.
To come down.
To actually get.
A proper question.
Out of this rant.
With me.
Rambling on.
Is there a DPS.
Threshold.
That you guys.
Want people to achieve.
At say.
The Abarth fights.
And the short answer.
Is no.
We don't have.
A really fixed.
A fixed DPS.
That we've.
Like.
Gone and measured.
Oh.
This character.
With this type of build.
Can do this much DPS.
Or anything like that.
We don't strictly.
Like.
Just measure DPS.
And compare that.
From build to build.
As a balancing metric.
Really.
Because there's lots of things.
Lots of secondary effects.
That builds do.
Like.
Abilities they have access to.
That can.
Really change.
How they perform.
In different situations.
So like.
If.
As an example.
I guess.
If a boss.
Is applying slow to you.
And your build.
Because you've gone full glass can.
And full DPS.
And you don't have a way.
To cleanse that slow.
You can't really complete.
That fight effectively.
Maybe you're like.
Okay.
I have to go rethink my build.
A little bit.
And I've got to.
Take some DPS away.
And.
Suddenly.
So you have like.
A way to get.
Cleansing into your build.
And suddenly.
This build.
That has less DPS.
Is actually better.
Overall.
And so.
Like.
Strictly just DPS.
Isn't.
It doesn't tell the whole story.
And it does.
I guess it is.
Something that we can use.
To like.
Get a view of.
Some parts of what the build can do.
And it is probably the most important part.
Of what a lot of builds can do.
But.
Once you get into really.
Really heavy late game.
Defenses and utility.
Become more and more.
And more and more.
And more important.
And so we don't.
Really want to put a number out there.
To say like.
This is what we expect your.
Your DPS to be.
At any point.
And we don't have good tools.
For our players.
To measure their DPS.
Strictly as well.
So it's.
Especially character to character.
Comparison.
Yeah.
Target dummies.
Being in the game.
It's like.
Just a little.
Side question to that.
Is there any ideas.
Or are you guys against.
The idea of adding.
Like a DPS.
Meter check.
On the target dummies.
Is that something you guys.
Would consider.
It's.
It gets suggested.
Pretty frequently.
It's not something.
We're interested in right now.
Okay.
Moving on.
To talk about the portals.
Which I think.
Is a really cool way.
Or a nice way.
To provide a.
Key sync.
If you will.
I think that having a.
Currency sync.
Of the different.
Currency is very important.
In ARPTs in general.
And.
But it does bring up.
The question of.
How valuable.
Running the actual.
Dungeons will be.
Because the portal.
Will just take you.
Straight to the boss room.
For example.
Jewelry.
If you go through.
Different doors.
You get to choose.
Right.
This door.
Allows you.
The boss.
To drop.
X amount of extra.
Exalted items.
And this one says.
Well now you're going to drop.
Extra glyphs or whatever.
So the question would be.
Are the portals.
Going to give you.
Random set of these.
Or you're just bypassing.
And the boss.
Will just give you.
Less loot.
As a result of you.
Skipping the dungeon.
No.
Has anyone.
Gone to a door.
And been like.
I'm going to see.
What the other door.
Actually has.
And like go back.
Through the maze.
The other one.
And check it.
And be like.
No the first one was better.
I'm going to go back that way.
No one does that.
Ever.
You get to the door.
And you're like.
Yep.
I'll take that one.
Whatever it is.
I guess that's what I got.
So yeah.
We are.
The portal charm.
Does pick one of them.
Randomly for you.
So you do still get those.
Mods.
And so it doesn't affect.
The actual.
Final outcome.
Of your rewards.
For the dungeon.
Also important.
That it does that.
Because those modifiers.
Are also.
Buffing the boss.
Yes.
So.
Follow up.
We actually.
We actually had a bug.
We had a bug.
Yeah.
Where they weren't applying.
So.
Using a portal charm.
To go fight dungeon bosses.
Was actually the optimal way.
If you just wanted to kill it.
Because it was easier.
Because the mod weren't applying to it.
So.
Yeah.
And we are bringing.
Like random things.
Into the dungeons as well.
So like there are.
You like.
A loot lizard can spawn in a dungeon.
And like.
So there are things like that.
That can happen in there as well.
So my follow up questions.
Is more than about.
The actual value of running it.
When we have access.
To just skipping straight to the boss.
And we get the juicing up.
Of the loot.
With difficulty added.
What's the point.
In running the dungeon then?
I mean.
Maybe you don't have a portal charm yet?
You don't have a portal charm.
Okay.
Because I mean.
Are there plans.
To adding more content.
Inside these dungeons.
To make them more attractive.
For people to choose to run.
Rather than skipping.
I was about to ask Gassi.
How many times have you actually.
Farmed the dungeon.
For the purpose of farming the dungeon.
And not.
Whatever is at the end.
Of the dungeon.
Oh.
The boss uniques.
Or the.
Yeah.
You're going like.
Way back.
Multiple years back now.
If you're saying.
The temporal sanctum.
Was good for like.
Belts.
Or boots.
Or stuff like that.
You're going way back.
Then.
I was about to say that.
Yes.
We.
Yeah.
Eventually.
But the dungeons.
Need to feel way better.
From like.
User experience.
Before we feel like.
It's worth.
Making the reward so good.
Because.
If something is really.
Unfun to do.
But.
It's the most rewarding.
People are going to do it.
And they're going to.
Really hate.
Playing the game.
While doing it.
So.
The user experience.
To be good.
Before.
Stuff like that.
Will happen.
And there is a bunch of tech.
You're going to see.
In season two.
For the tombs.
Especially.
That I think we're going to be.
Looking to leverage.
For dungeons in the future.
So.
There's.
There are a lot of things.
We want to do.
I feel like the dungeon system.
Is a really.
There's a lot of.
Untapped potential there.
For.
Interesting content.
Fun content.
For.
Rewarding content.
All these things to happen.
But.
They're.
The quality of that experience.
Isn't.
At a point where we want to.
Really.
Incentivize people to be.
Heavily interacting with it.
Like.
We like.
Some light interaction there.
Because I think it's fun.
The first few times.
Especially.
And then.
Your.
80th time.
Through the temporal sanctum.
And you're like.
Ah.
This dead end again.
Yeah.
No.
I know that feeling.
All too well.
Especially when you play.
Builds that wants it.
You know.
Vessel's Drive.
Jewelers Obsession.
Mountain Helmet.
Etc.
For the different dungeons.
Right.
But let's move on to.
Class reworks.
We've already.
Teased a little bit.
With Electrify.
Time Rod.
Judgment.
Of the storm.
We're going to talk a little bit more.
About the Sentinel rework.
And.
What I want to do.
Is take a moment.
To take a.
The cool things.
Aside.
Such as being able to wield.
A two-handed weapon.
And a shield.
For example.
That's a cool thing.
We'll take that aside.
So what's the approach.
To the season.
In making melee.
A more attractive.
Playstyle.
Compared to the current meta.
Killing things.
Entire screens.
Actually.
Of monsters.
Just from afar.
Yeah.
I mean.
Do you want to talk?
Yeah.
Okay.
You can go ahead.
If you got something for this.
Yeah.
So.
I mean.
Obviously.
We could make melee.
Every single skill.
Literally.
Hit the entire screen.
But is it melee then?
Not really.
Right.
So.
It's a.
It's like an age-old question.
In RPGs.
How.
Or in games in general.
Do you do that?
There's.
There's a.
There's a lot of things.
You can do there.
Very.
Difficult.
And.
Time-consuming.
And whatnot.
I think.
A lot of the stuff.
We're trying to do.
With melee.
Is making the.
Like.
The feel.
Of their abilities.
Feel a lot better.
So.
Like.
Getting more responsiveness.
And getting.
Like.
Better VFX.
Getting better SFX.
Things like that.
Having enemy reactions.
And like.
A lot of those things.
A lot of the.
Like.
Having.
Better fit and finish.
On those.
Abilities.
Makes just playing them.
A lot more fun.
And getting the power balance.
In there.
As far as how fast.
You can kill things.
Is.
Kind of a different conversation.
But is.
Maybe that's more.
What people are interested in knowing.
Is like.
Can I just kill stuff faster.
As melee.
And we are adding a ton.
Of.
Different ways to kill things faster.
In melee.
I guess.
Especially in.
Especially in Sentinel right now.
That's the big.
The big focus.
And like.
We're getting.
You know.
Abilities.
There's lots of.
Abilities that we designed.
Specifically to.
Make you more efficient.
On melee.
Focus classes.
So like.
Even just down to the base functionality.
Of lunge.
Where.
It.
Like.
You're targeting an enemy.
And it gets you right up close.
Really fast.
It is one of the fastest moving abilities.
It is.
You know.
It's a very efficient movement ability.
At engaging into close range combat.
And.
Leaning into that as much as possible.
I think is.
Is the important part.
It's also very.
Yeah.
It's also very difficult.
To have like a global.
Something.
Something globally for melee.
That doesn't bleed into.
Non-melee.
So.
Like.
If you have.
Let's say that you have a.
Enemies near you.
Deal less damage.
Well then.
Every single ranged build.
Will just go into melee range of enemies.
Because now they deal less damage to it.
So it's.
It's very difficult.
To.
Do something.
Especially for classes.
Like.
We don't have a class.
That is just melee.
Every class can.
Do other things.
For example.
Sentinel.
Well.
You have minions.
You have.
You can do throwing.
You can do spells.
So.
It's very difficult.
To.
Buff the one side.
Without.
Accidentally bleeding.
Into others.
Obviously.
We are.
Looking into ways.
To do that.
But it's very.
Very difficult.
To find something.
That works very well.
It also comes into.
Like.
Boss.
Enemy attacks as well.
With.
With having.
So like.
Someone.
Like.
The things that are.
Attacking you.
Being.
Having abilities.
That they can use.
Only on.
Enemies that are.
At long range.
And then incentivizing.
Characters that are not.
Melee characters.
To stay at long range.
Through their own trees.
So it's this.
This tension that they have.
Of.
Okay.
If I'm going to stay at range.
I'm going to get hit.
With these abilities.
That melee won't get hit with.
Or that it's easier to dodge.
In melee.
Because of the shape of the ability.
Or something like that.
Yeah.
We have a lot of.
Cone shaped.
Like.
You know.
Triangles.
So if you're close to the boss.
You just take a small sidestep.
And you're out of it.
Whereas if you're far away from it.
You have a very big distance.
You have to go through.
I think a good example.
Is the Aberos.
Like the.
The triple.
The slam.
It hits front.
And then the sides.
If you're right next to it.
It's very easy to dodge.
It's pretty hard to take away from it.
So yeah.
We had a question.
From another LE content creator.
Perry the Pig.
Was talking about.
You know.
Beyond the melee play style.
With the introduction of Uber Arborath.
The question had.
Was about.
Having tools for melee players.
Utilized when it comes to.
Positional important fights.
Such as endgame pinnacles.
Like the new Aberos fight.
So you're saying that.
With the way the abilities are designed.
It is.
Beneficial to be in melee range.
Which is more lucrative.
Or beneficial for melee players.
In general.
That they don't seem to have.
The need for any specific new tools.
To mitigate damage.
Is that what I'm understanding?
We'd like.
We are.
We're always exploring.
The ways to actually do that.
But a lot of it comes from.
Enemy ability design.
Yes.
There's a lot to that.
Yeah.
So Mike.
You mentioned.
There being tools added.
To making it more effective.
In terms of the power scaling in melee.
Because you talked about.
SFX.
VFX.
All those things.
Making it feel good.
But there's a difference.
Between the build feeling good.
And then.
Being put into the game.
And now it's being compared.
To builds that are clearing.
Significantly faster.
Especially in the game.
That is.
Incentivizing very heavily.
On favor farming.
Which means clear speed matters a lot.
Minion builds.
Suffers from this as well.
In terms of clear efficiency.
You mentioned.
There being.
Abilities.
Or.
Introductions of tools.
That were the.
Toolkit for melee players.
To utilize.
To increase the efficiencies.
Is this something we see.
In season two.
And if so.
What.
Specific.
Specific examples.
For season two.
I don't have anything.
Off the top of my head.
That I can share right now.
Okay.
The.
I think it comes down to.
I think a lot of it right now.
Is.
It's going to be like.
Small balance changes.
And I say small.
That'll have big impacts.
As things like.
I don't.
I don't have a good.
Fix.
A hard example.
Something we're actually doing.
But as an example.
Something we could do.
Hypothetically.
Is like.
Even just taking a second.
Off the cooldown.
Of something like lunge.
Or giving you.
Or giving.
Less pressure.
On.
An item slot.
That has.
Increased cooldown recovery.
On it.
Or something like that.
Like there's.
There's little things we can do.
That either hit.
Like wide range of.
A wide range of builds.
Or not.
So we can.
Maybe have.
Maybe there's like.
An item slot.
Where.
Like cooldown recovery.
Exists.
And there's another.
We put something else on there.
That's really good for.
Like long range characters.
And so they.
They no longer want to get.
That cooldown recovery.
So then.
Then their movement abilities.
Are slower.
So there's.
That.
Like sometimes it's like.
The pressure gets put on.
These abilities.
And the balance from.
Like really far away.
Sometimes even.
And.
I.
I don't think that there's.
I don't think we're actually.
That far away from.
Having melee feel really good to play.
In a broader sense.
And I think that a lot of the changes.
That we're making.
Bringing to.
Especially.
Things like volatile reversal.
And forge guard.
That the changes there.
Is so huge.
And we still got.
We still have that to get into.
Yeah.
Speaking of.
Speaking of all the cool things.
Gazze.
How hard would it be.
For you to.
Just capture.
If I actually show my screen.
I'm in a CT build right now.
And.
I.
I've been.
I'll make it work.
I have stupid stripping stuff.
So I don't leak anything crazy.
But we could just.
You know.
Show you some of the.
Start it up.
And I'll see if it screws it up.
And I'll fix it.
I'll.
I'll sort it.
Don't.
Don't tell anyone else.
Okay.
It's just.
Sure.
We're all.
We're not going to say anything.
Let's see if I can.
Yeah.
Because.
Model reversal.
Specifically.
Is like.
It is an.
It's a.
Travels or ability.
That.
Doesn't regard a target.
Like a launch.
And isn't.
It doesn't regard a shield.
Like shield rush.
I mean.
Sure.
You can.
Expect shield rush.
To not have.
Not regard that.
But it is.
A mobility skill.
For sentinel.
Which is.
Going to help.
And I've got some.
Other cool stuff.
Now.
Because we totally reworked.
What the reversal is.
So yeah.
That's fair.
If you.
Turn off your camera.
And then start the stream.
I think that will.
Actually add up perfectly.
Yeah.
I mean.
We can.
We can try that.
Or just start the stream.
And I'll see.
I can just add.
Let's.
Let's see.
What if I just do this first.
Oh.
Beautiful sound.
I need to do this.
Let me do.
Yeah.
It's going to.
Screw it up completely.
Let me just add that.
Give me a sec.
You might want to just go full screen.
I think.
Maybe.
A little easier.
In a moment.
That's the wrong one.
In the capture.
Quick.
Before someone stops us.
Yeah.
I had to like.
Take all of my idols out.
So I don't.
You know.
Leak anything.
Okay.
Your.
Your screen is now full screen.
And then.
Then I.
And I had to replace.
My.
Some of my items.
To not.
To just be the base set items.
Because.
You know.
You can.
Yeah.
Anyways.
Okay.
So.
Voltar reversal.
Is now.
A combo ability.
That.
First.
It jumps.
Forward in time.
And then.
When you use it again.
It.
Goes back.
And it does.
Some melee attack.
On both.
Both cases.
I think.
I'm just going to.
Unspec this.
So I can.
You can.
I can show you the default.
So.
The first.
And then.
If I do second.
It just slams backwards.
Where I was.
So.
It's.
It's pretty cool.
And you can do.
You can do some interesting stuff with it.
For example.
Devouring Orb.
Has.
Some cool new.
New tech here.
Where.
You can consume.
All other.
Orbs.
So.
You actually have it here.
If I just cast.
Devouring Orb.
Here.
Normally.
If you cast another one.
It's just there.
But now.
It consumes the other one.
And.
It does more damage.
And it's bigger.
As a result.
One of the cool things here.
Is that.
You can.
Bring them.
With you.
With the.
And.
That means.
That you can.
Like pile them up.
Into like.
This one big.
Pool of stuff.
And then it does a lot more damage.
And there's.
Other.
Other interesting stuff.
Like.
You can.
You can actually make it.
Not be.
A traversal skill.
It still has a cooldown.
But.
Then you can use.
Other abilities if you want.
And there's just.
There's just.
A bunch of.
Interesting stuff here.
There's a.
So.
The skill design.
The base function.
You have the.
The first.
And the second one.
So.
You are in the.
You have the ability.
To go back in time.
So.
We can do stuff.
In that time period.
For example.
We can just.
Provide you frenzy.
When you are between.
The first and the second.
But.
If you want to.
You can just remove.
The second combo.
Altogether.
So.
Now you can actually just.
Have it as a proper.
Traversal skill.
That doesn't go backwards.
Ever.
Or.
And that removes.
The possibility of staying.
With a frenzy.
For example.
Yes.
Because you no longer.
Have the ability.
To go backwards.
So.
What I.
What I like a lot.
Is.
You know.
There's my.
My little.
Devouring orbs.
I put them back.
And then.
We'll just.
Yeah.
There's.
There's some.
There's some cool stuff there.
What else?
We have.
We have so many changes here.
Oh.
Oh yeah.
Sigils of hope.
Is no longer sigils.
It's now.
Symbols of hope.
Some reason.
Yeah.
And we completely changed.
The base functionality of it.
So previously.
You had basically two.
Well.
I guess three ways.
Since we introduced the unique.
But for the vast majority of the time.
Of the skill was.
You cast it.
It costs a lot of mana.
And you have a duration.
For the sigil.
That gives you some buffs.
So now.
They just.
Automatically generate.
Over time.
And then.
When you actually use the.
The button.
You get a defensive buff.
And it consumes them.
And then you.
Wait.
Them to get again.
So.
Okay.
You see here.
I have five.
It shows five.
On the icon here.
Because I used.
When I had five.
And now they just.
Come back.
Ramping up.
Yeah.
And you can.
You can like.
Influence how fast.
They come back.
I think.
Yeah.
Here.
And there's some other changes.
In the skill tree here.
But the skill tree.
Like the overlay here.
Looks pretty much the same.
But there's been.
Some changes.
Like for example.
The divine flare.
I think you can.
Kind of maybe.
Even make it.
An actual build now.
You remove.
The defensive part of it.
But.
Now you just.
You don't have to.
Generate the sigils anymore.
To then use divine flare.
Now.
They are just generated.
And then you just use divine flare.
Instead.
So.
It also saves you mana like that.
A lot.
Other cool things.
It's vengeance.
The first skill you get.
I think this cookie has.
Changed a bit.
Yeah.
Okay.
So.
You can now.
Convert it to void.
Which is.
Kind of cool.
Oh.
We got a.
Nice little.
Scaler here.
That gives you.
Fistpen.
With.
Your extra.
Overcap.
Physical resistance.
And I think if you convert this.
This also applies to the other ones.
So if you convert it to fire.
It goes to fire.
If you convert it to.
Void.
I think you have fire.
Conversion somewhere.
Yeah.
That too.
You can turn.
Your.
Iron blades.
That nobody really used before.
Into.
Forge weapons now.
And.
The iron blades.
Can also be.
Kind of useful.
And there's some other stuff.
Like.
Buffing your erasing strike here.
You know.
You're smashing your face.
Against Abby.
With your vengeance.
To get your damage.
Mitigation from vengeance.
And then you.
You know.
Smack it with erasing strike.
And do more damage.
Just.
Yeah.
Don't let me stop you.
Keep going.
What else?
You can just hover over every node.
Real quick.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here.
Here's.
Here's big.
This is a big one.
So.
Previously.
In the past.
When you.
Combined.
Siege Baras.
With Divine Fury.
The Divine Fury.
Which is just.
Adds.
Like.
New.
You know.
The POE.
Sorry.
D2.
Lightning Fury.
When you hit something.
It just.
Throws more stuff.
So.
Previously.
These two.
Did not work together.
Well.
That's changed.
So now.
Now.
Now it does work.
So you can.
You can throw a lot of.
Lightning.
With Javelin now.
That looks amazing.
Show me that one more time.
It looks good.
Yeah.
For the people in the back.
Need to see that again.
Yeah.
It's pretty fun.
It helps a lot.
Yeah.
Spear scaling.
With Javelin is automatic.
And as Forge Guard.
You can now do.
Yeah.
Spear with a shield.
I'm not sure if I want to.
Open my passive trees.
For you here.
Yeah.
Right.
That's a mind deal.
There's.
Yeah.
There's a lot of changes.
In there.
So maybe.
Maybe we'll save that for future.
Mulder Strike.
Like.
You can now.
Oh.
Shotgun.
Yeah.
You can shotgun now.
So you have some really good single target.
With Blade Storm now.
Which is.
That's beautiful.
It turned.
It turned the skill into an actually.
Really good skill now.
You're saying it was really bad.
And now you actually made it good.
Is that what you're saying?
It lacked on the.
Like the single target.
Like you couldn't invest into making it.
A really good for single target.
Yeah.
You could do stuff like.
Smite proc.
Stuff like that.
But now.
You can actually make.
The skill do you really good damage on its own.
What else?
Any Forge Strike stuff?
I've got Void.
I think both.
Forge Strike and Smelder Sprat.
Are just.
Better.
Basically.
Ring of Shields.
Yeah.
This note that nobody ever took.
I think you might be able to do something with it.
Because.
So.
Ring of Shields.
Is.
Is a minion skill.
I don't think many people know that.
But.
It's a minion skill.
And.
It had this.
Fire damage for a time here.
But nobody will use.
But.
It might.
Work.
Now.
We've done a lot of.
Like small changes around.
Judgment.
Because.
One of the things with.
With Void.
The Reverser was that.
It was providing.
A lot of mana.
If you build it like that way.
So.
There's like the.
Judgment.
Mana dump build.
That you had to use.
For the reverse to get mana back.
So.
We.
We kept how much mana.
You can actually consume.
Without.
Without nerfing the damage.
So.
It doesn't empty your mana pool.
Like crazy anymore.
Which is.
It's kind of nice.
And also it just.
Does more damage.
Well.
That's a nice new change.
A lot of quality life in that.
Yeah.
Shield throw.
No longer has a cooldown.
As a baseline.
Which is kind of cool.
It still has it.
So that you can only throw.
A shield at a time.
So if your shield is still.
You know.
Ping-boing between enemies.
You can throw another one.
Well.
Now with one point.
You can also remove that.
So you can't just.
Throw them.
As much as you want.
Previously this node.
I think regard.
Going through.
A lot of points.
To even get there.
And if you still want to play it.
With a cooldown.
You can do that.
And do more damage.
And then.
It allows also.
Now.
Can chain off you.
So.
You can do more.
Seeing target damage.
If you want.
And you can.
Combine it with like.
You could just.
Be like a.
Hybrid.
Of.
You know.
Shield throw.
And then something else.
Use it in the cooldown.
And whatnot.
And so it's just spamming the one skill.
So this is part of like.
The throwing.
Niche.
That you're like.
Kind of.
Setting into the sentinel.
Yeah.
There's a lot of.
I think shield bash.
Just does more damage.
Oh yeah.
One thing that people have been asking.
For a long time.
It's.
Drive.
With void conversion.
You have that now.
Nice.
There's a.
There's a lot of.
Changes.
Around here.
So a lot of people.
Love.
Spin to win.
What are the changes.
For season two.
Since we're opening up.
This can of worms.
What's the changes.
To warp path.
If any.
Uh.
I don't think.
There's too many changes.
On warbath.
Specifically.
Some.
Some buffs.
Here and there.
I think.
Warbath is already good.
Yes.
Especially if you're playing.
It doesn't avoid nights.
With the echoes.
And.
The masteries.
I mean.
Just the changes.
To the passive trees.
Are making it.
A lot better.
Regardless of how you play.
Basically.
And you were not able.
To show the skill tree.
I'm probably already.
Getting fired.
From showing this.
I'm.
Maybe I'll not get sued.
If I don't show them.
But yeah.
There's a lot of.
Changes in the passive trees.
And you'll definitely.
Learn about them.
So.
Yeah.
We're learning right now.
Like I'm not going to stop you.
Anything else you want to show us?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Maybe.
Maybe we just show the heart cheaker.
Like this too.
It's way.
Way cooler.
Well.
Okay.
I.
When I do this.
I need to go.
Check that I don't actually leak anything there.
So I'm going to close my screen now.
And Mike can talk about heart cheaker.
While I.
While I set up my character.
No.
I'm going to hide it from YouTube.
Yeah.
Do that as well.
In case.
Are there.
Oh.
Let's do it.
Never mind.
One second.
Let me.
Let me hop onto.
Onto a marksman real quick.
There we go.
You're off screen as well.
Everything's set.
Fine.
I have a lot.
I have a lot of DMs in my slack.
I bet.
Thank you.
By the way.
It is fine.
You know.
One of my follow up questions.
Was about Sigil of Hope.
To get you talking about it.
But you covered that already.
So.
We're good.
Oh yeah.
I have idols.
Here I am.
Not showing.
So.
Maybe when you're checking that.
Maybe we can have Mike.
Elaborate a little bit.
On the part you said.
Carver.
Where you said that.
Forge guards is better.
So I'm guessing my question.
Would be forge guard.
And manifest armor.
Maybe Mike could spill some beans.
On what he.
What Carver started.
Meaning.
When he said they're better.
I mean.
So a lot of the stuff with.
Forge guard.
Mechanically.
We were actually pretty happy with.
Where it's.
Sitting and feeling.
And.
But because it did lose some.
Damage numbers from.
From volatile reversal.
We have buffed up some.
There's some.
Like.
Hey this now does.
This number is higher.
This number is bigger.
So there's not a lot of like.
Huge mechanical changes.
Other than the.
One huge passive node.
That has.
A lot of implications.
Around.
Around the.
Basically every ability.
That it has.
The big thing for forge guard.
It's the.
Two-hander.
And a shield.
Yeah.
It allows you to do some cool things.
One thing that.
You couldn't take the manifest armor node.
Where it gave it a sword.
Like.
Like a weapon.
And a shield.
That you can only ever use a one-handed weapon.
With that.
Now you can use a two-handed weapon.
You can have your manifest armor clone.
A two-handed weapon.
And a shield.
At the same time.
So like.
Yeah.
There's.
There's a manifest armor buff.
Right.
Just right there.
From that node.
So a lot of these like.
Knock-on effects.
And things where like.
If you're.
If you're doing.
Like forged weapons.
And you're trying to use.
Like shield scaling stuff.
At the same time.
It wasn't really viable.
Because you wanted to have a two-handed weapon.
For manifest weapon.
Spawning.
So it's.
There's.
That node has such huge implications.
And ripples across all of Forge Guard.
That it's.
Like.
There wasn't a lot that needed to change.
Without having it touch.
Basically every tree.
And at the same time.
We did bump up some numbers as well.
That's fair.
At least.
Sorry.
At least two uniques.
That we made for this patch.
Had to be.
Slightly.
Looked again.
Because Forge Guard's node exists enough.
So.
Yeah.
So one of the questions.
I had as a follow-up.
For the Forge Guard minion.
Specifically.
With manifested Forge weapons.
Is that.
It feels very.
One-dimensional.
On the terms of the aspect.
Of playing minion builds.
With Forge Guard mastery.
As a whole.
So.
I guess the question I have.
If there are any plans.
Whether they're for patch 1.2.
Or beyond.
That we'll see Forge Guard minion play.
Properly utilize the minions.
In a way that is more comparable.
To.
Other masteries.
That also uses minions.
Such as the Acolytes.
Yeah.
So we really want to keep the minion.
Play.
The gameplay feel.
Of minions.
To be unique and distinct.
From.
Class to class.
So like.
The obvious.
The really easy ones to talk about.
Is companions versus.
Like primalist companions.
Versus necromancer minions.
Yeah.
And there's a really obvious difference.
The way we approach those.
The companions can be revived.
You have far fewer of them.
The necromancer minions.
Are designed to be sacrificed.
Literally.
With the ability to sacrifice.
And.
So like.
That's really easy.
To look at them differently.
And then the.
The Forge.
Forge Guard minions.
It's.
It's in a.
It's a tricky thing to.
To.
Nail down an identity for it.
And we kind of look at them.
Almost like an extension.
Of the character.
A little bit.
And.
Because they're so heavily.
Tied to your gear.
And.
Because they're so heavily.
Tied to your gear.
The one thing people expect from them.
Is them to actually.
Mimic the unique effects.
That your gear has.
I think that's the key.
Missing mechanical piece.
For Forge weapons.
Which they still will not do.
In season two.
I'm sorry.
But we are looking to.
Extract some of the essence.
Out of those.
Unique items.
That you want to capture.
For.
For future.
Stuff down the road.
Yeah.
And just.
Random note.
So.
There's this.
New ring that we added.
I think it was in.
1.1.
Maybe.
The.
Yeah.
Phantom grip.
That had some.
Interesting bug on it.
And.
Since we fixed that bug.
We.
We just gave.
A flat.
Really big buff.
Both damage and.
Defense.
To Forge weapons.
So.
If you were.
One of those people.
Who were having like.
Really crazy setup.
With the ring.
In the bug form.
You probably got nerfed a bit.
But for everyone else.
Forge weapons are better.
Like.
If you didn't have like.
Crazy setup.
Abusing the bug.
Your Forge weapon.
Should be better.
This match.
Also.
I'm ready.
I'm in.
Heart Seeker.
Right now.
If you.
Let me know when the stream's up.
And I'll put it up.
Back up.
It is.
It is up.
Misa again.
Your full screen.
And ready to go.
Yeah.
So this is a very interesting skill.
Okay.
So.
Skill itself.
The base functionality.
Is as simply as.
You shoot an arrow.
To a target.
It ignores everything.
On its way.
To whatever you were aiming.
And then.
It hits that.
And then it has a chance.
To hit it again.
So basically.
It goes through it.
Comes back.
And hits again.
And one of the key.
Mechanics of this.
Is to.
Increase.
The recurve chance.
So you can hit the same target.
With one use of the ability.
Many times.
So if you guys remember.
Guided arrow.
From D2.
In its quarry.
When.
It was able to pierce.
And hit the target.
Multiple times.
We basically just did that.
And added the skill tree.
Okay.
There's a.
Very long.
Interesting discussion.
And a lot of.
Design.
Portions of this.
One being.
How.
What is the.
How do we do the.
The chance to hit the target.
Multiple times.
So.
In D2.
You just have a pierce chance.
Right.
And.
Each percentage that you get.
Is just way better than previous.
So if you go from.
50% to 75% chance.
And then you go from 75% to 100% chance.
You're just.
It's so much more.
Powerful.
So we didn't want to have this.
Where.
It's just.
Every single point.
It gets crazy good.
For multiple reasons.
It.
Makes it harder for us to.
Provide the chance.
In gear and whatnot.
You have to be very careful.
To not allow you to hit like.
Over 95% chance.
We want.
There to be some.
Volatility.
So that.
It's not always hitting.
Five times.
Every single time.
Or six times.
Or seven times.
Or whatever.
So we didn't.
We couldn't really go with.
A.
You have.
You know.
The first one.
Every single time.
You just pierce once.
And then you.
Invest into.
Another appears chance.
Or stuff like that.
So.
What we ended up being.
Is.
Every single time.
It successfully recurves.
The next one.
The chance is just.
Multiplied.
By.
A number.
That keeps going down.
So if you start with.
I wonder if we have an example here.
So let's say that you have.
200% chance.
You're guaranteed.
On the first.
To hit again.
And then.
That 200% chance.
Gets multiplied by.
0.8.
The ones.
My.
I'm not going to do math.
On stream here.
Sorry.
Yeah.
So.
So you just keep.
Going down.
Until.
Eventually.
It's no longer.
A guaranteed chance.
And now you run into this.
Point where.
You have this chance to.
Get like.
A really nice chain.
Of getting multiple hits.
Or it just fails.
So there's.
That's where the.
Volatility comes from.
And then we did.
A lot of.
Cool stuff.
On the skill tree.
But before I go there.
Do you have any questions.
On that?
No.
I think that.
That sounds like.
A really cool way to.
Create a volatility.
Without it feeling bad.
I like that.
Yeah.
We did a lot of math.
And simulations.
And.
Probably.
Somebody could go.
Dig it up.
From some of our chats.
But yeah.
It was fun.
Maybe showing action a little bit.
Once you're.
Yeah.
Okay.
So.
I have.
Oh yeah.
This is a base skill only.
So I don't have much.
But.
It's all.
I have some gear.
That keeps me.
So.
It's just.
You know.
It goes through the enemy.
And it goes back.
And it hits again.
That's nice.
So.
One of the main reasons.
For this skill.
Is that.
We didn't have like a.
Like a strong.
Like a single target.
Like a physical based skill.
Like.
We have the.
We have the detonate arrow.
You can't convert the physical.
So basically.
The only physical abilities.
Are just.
Flurry.
Puncture.
And the multi shot.
And you can make multi shot.
Into a single target ability.
But.
It's not really.
A single target ability.
By base.
So that's what.
The heart seeker.
Is.
By.
By it's.
Like.
Basic design.
Doing.
All right.
You can clear with it.
For example.
If you take this node.
So.
We were talking about the.
The chances.
On how many times.
It goes through an enemy.
So we actually.
Pre-calculate this.
So.
If you kill an enemy.
And you have this node.
For every additional chance.
It would hit the enemy.
The additional time.
Instead.
Puncture.
Comes out.
So.
If you.
Let's say that you had.
You know.
Ten hits.
And you just one shot.
The enemy on the field.
First hits.
You get ten punctures.
Just flying around.
To other enemies.
So that's.
Huh.
Kind of.
That.
That's basically the.
Only node.
Inside the skill tree itself.
That builds.
Like.
Like AOE.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I guess.
Another thing about the basic functionality.
If the target dies.
It will just find a new target.
To hit.
With the remaining.
Recurves.
I think that's really important.
So.
It doesn't just like.
Vanish.
It'll just.
It'll seek another one.
To damage to.
Yeah.
And there's a screen wide.
Or.
You can.
You can shoot it.
It's a.
It's a very large.
Range of retargeting.
Yeah.
The retargeting is very large.
Long range.
Okay.
It'll just.
It'll just keep hitting the same target.
And then.
If it dies.
I think.
I think the retargeting.
It's probably like half a screen or something.
I don't remember exactly how far.
But it's.
It's pretty far.
Yeah.
Okay.
I mean.
If you could probably go.
Find out.
By going into an area.
With some normal monsters that die.
Then I can actually show.
This node too.
But yeah.
Some other stuff.
So.
Obviously we have some.
Just base.
You know.
Recurve chance.
And then.
This is.
We talk about the volatility.
So.
This is a cool node.
Because this just.
Sets it.
So that it'll never go below.
66%.
So.
This allows it to.
Potentially.
Go for some.
Crazy.
Amount of hits.
Yeah.
And then.
Obviously.
We had to put a deck scale over there.
So.
Stack decks.
And you get more.
Recurve chance.
We got.
Cold conversion.
And we mentioned about the frostbite.
So there's.
Some frostbite supports.
On.
Rogue.
There.
You can convert it to fire.
Obviously.
We have.
Decent amount of.
Bleed.
And poison support.
Like for example.
Here you can convert your armor shred.
Into poison chance.
Kind of reminds.
I think runemaster.
Has armor shred.
To frostbite chance.
So.
That there.
Yeah.
Obviously we have.
The crit hit base stuff here.
And then you can combine this.
So you can go.
Gold crit.
You can go.
Fire crit.
If you wanted to.
For example.
You know.
Like.
Dragon song.
With the crits.
Or you could do.
Rhino winter.
As you can see.
They're proccing there.
They're proccing a lot.
Yeah.
You can do some.
Fun stuff here.
You can make it.
Into mana generator.
The base mana cost.
I have a bow.
That's reduced mana cost.
I'm so excited for this skill.
Yeah.
It has a pretty low.
Base mana cost.
Obviously you can increase it.
But with some of the passives.
The drog has.
But you can.
Just also turn it into.
The.
Mana scaler.
But yeah.
There's.
There's some cool stuff here.
You can also.
You can change.
How the.
I should probably put bow back on.
I think.
Like the.
See how the.
The visual pattern.
Yeah.
It changes the visual here.
Because.
We.
This was another thing.
We debated a lot.
Is how should it look like.
When it.
You know.
Recurs back.
Because.
This looks really cool.
When it goes like that.
But not everyone liked it.
So.
That's why we just put it.
Into a node instead.
And it.
It has a slow chance there.
So it's.
Not entirely just.
For the.
The theme.
But.
Yeah.
All right.
I really want to show you this.
So let me.
Let me.
Yeah.
Knock yourself out.
I mean.
It's fine.
You got a couple.
A handful of more questions.
Before we're done.
So just take your time.
Don't worry about it.
We got time.
Yo.
We got plenty of time.
Go for it.
I'm going to show you there.
The page funks right there.
A little leak.
I should probably do.
Specialized puncture too.
Even.
I don't need to do that.
But.
So you see some punctures are flying off here.
Jesus Christ.
Obviously this is a pretty weak enemy.
So.
But this is a way to build it.
Oh my god.
And then.
I guess another cool thing.
There's a.
Unique weaver.
That I don't currently have here.
That.
Converts puncture to cold.
Currently in the game.
What it does not do.
Currently.
It doesn't convert the plea chance.
From.
The blood thirst.
The frostbite.
But it does.
In season two.
So you can do.
A frostbite puncture.
Plus.
Heartseeker.
Stuff.
If you want.
Feels good.
So how are you going to make.
I should try.
I'll have a conversion here.
How are we going to make.
Other builds compete.
With this type of clear speed.
I'm pretty sure.
We are in.
Like.
The lowest.
Yeah.
So here's.
Here's the.
Gold converted one.
So.
When you don't have a target to hit.
It's just going to bounce back and forth.
Where you aimed.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you could actually stack up.
A bunch of arrows.
Before a boss.
Because attackable.
Yeah.
And then.
There's a fire.
That is.
Looks fantastic.
Yeah.
You can also turn this into.
A throwing ability.
You actually show that.
On the trailer.
It comes from a unique.
That I don't currently have.
It's a triggered throwing ability.
At that point.
Isn't it?
Yeah.
So you don't actually.
Throw it yourself.
It just comes from the unique.
But you have.
You have some.
Interesting support here.
For throwing and spell.
Builds.
For example.
The.
You know.
The dragon zone.
That I was showing earlier.
And it's interesting.
Because this scales.
With how many times you recurve.
So there's a.
Reason for you to stack.
The recurve.
As much as you can.
Because you just want.
The buff to go.
As high as you want.
Right.
And it also keeps throwing.
So.
This is where the.
You could.
Also.
Use this as a support kill.
For.
Some throwing marksman.
Build.
Maybe that.
You know.
Those exist as well.
So.
There's a.
There's a lot of.
Cool stuff.
Cool stuff in Heartseeker.
I'm.
It is important to note.
That this is a.
A marksman specific ability.
You cannot use this.
On Falconer or Blade Dancer.
Yes.
This is only for marksman.
Yep.
So it's past the chain.
Basically is what you're saying.
I think it's a 30.
30 point.
It's 30 points.
I would.
I would look at the game.
But then I would show the skill tree.
And I'm.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's all good.
I do have a question.
I don't think there's a lot of changes.
For the passives on marksman though.
But yeah.
It's.
Locked to marksman.
Let's not get you sued.
We appreciate the showcase.
I did have a question.
Regarding.
Like.
Extra skills.
Past the chain.
Right.
We.
We know there's one lacking for the lich.
And.
We know there was one missing for the paladin.
Is that still the case for season two?
Yes.
The only new.
The only brand new ability for season two is heart seeker.
And it's a doozy.
There's.
Volatile reversal is essentially a new skill.
Because it's so heavily reworked.
But yeah.
The only new one is heart seeker.
We are still looking to.
We.
I know what the.
Like we.
As a team.
We know what the.
The.
I love this build.
Sorry.
Getting distracted by card flank.
The.
We know what the abilities that are going to go in those slots are going to be.
And.
We have started working on some of those.
New abilities for future updates.
That sounds amazing.
I mean.
Right now we have like this electrical theme.
Going on for the.
Paladin.
Specifically.
Would it be.
A far stretch to.
Seize another type of.
Minion archetype for that.
I'd have to ask.
I'm sorry.
It's just me.
I think we're going to be leaning more into the.
Holy warrior side of the character than the minion side.
Because we want to keep minions.
More a focus on forge guard than on Paladin.
So.
I think that's unlikely.
Okay.
I have to ask.
You know he's not made yet.
Yeah.
What happens in development room.
You know.
Yeah.
I got some ideas.
You set me up.
You know.
I think.
I think it's time to.
For me to close this.
To not keep Mike distracted.
Sorry.
My bad.
Yeah.
All good.
I'll.
I'll close.
Let me get that out.
Let's do it this way.
There we go.
We're back on track.
Let me get this.
You got some more questions.
I heard.
No.
That kind of covers.
That part.
On the topic of minions though.
I do have a couple of mini questions.
That lined up.
So it's a pretty good segue.
Into that one.
Especially after seeing.
The heart seeker.
Having.
You know.
Clear speed.
Is obviously going to be.
Depending on you know.
The difficulty.
And the damage output.
You can do of course.
But the area coverage.
Is clearly very very vast.
And this weaves back.
Both to the melee question.
We talked about earlier.
But also.
Specifically melee minions.
And the first question.
I have on the minion parts.
Is actually minion AI.
Can feel.
Or very often feel.
A bit frustrating.
So.
My question is.
If there are any plans.
In making them more aggressive.
To begin with.
Yeah.
So.
Every minion right now.
Is its own.
Entity.
Its own thing.
It thinks for itself.
There's no hive mind effect.
Happening here.
And I think that in.
There's a few ways.
We can.
Tackle.
Making minions more efficient.
At.
Like target acquisition.
And.
And all that sort of stuff.
And it's.
It's.
I think there's a few.
There's.
We don't have a ton of changes.
For season two.
Coming for this.
I think there's.
A few.
There's a few.
Few things that are getting added.
And specifically.
As far as like.
Items.
And new balancing things.
That can make them stronger.
But there's.
Behavior wise.
We don't have any big changes yet.
For those.
I do still.
I really want to do.
That minion stances thing.
We've talked about a few times.
So players can be like.
I want mine to be more aggressive.
We have tried turning up.
The aggressiveness of minions.
A few times.
And.
It doesn't always work.
The way you want it to work.
Especially with the way.
With how minions.
I guess.
With the way their AI works.
In general.
The other option.
The other approach.
Is making a hive mind.
Of some sort.
Where something was like.
Okay.
Well I've got.
Eight minions.
And there's.
Eight targets.
I'm going to send one minion.
To every target.
Type thing.
Right now.
And that.
That naturally happens.
A little bit.
If the enemies are spread out.
But if all the minions.
Are the same distance.
Have the same closest target.
They'll all focus.
That first target.
Right away.
And so yeah.
We.
We're really happy.
With the ability.
To target.
With like.
To force targets on.
With the.
With the A key.
By default.
You can be like.
Okay.
Attack this target.
And that does work really well.
But we know a lot of people.
Don't want to.
Do that.
Or need to do that.
And sometimes it's.
Nicer if they do spread out.
And attack multiple targets.
And that doesn't.
Allow you to be like.
Okay.
Spread out.
And attack multiple targets at once.
Because that's that coverage.
That you're talking about.
So this is something that we are.
Looking at still.
But it's not something we have.
Big sweeping changes for.
In season two.
Fair enough.
So.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Like.
I can continue a bit.
So.
Yeah.
I think one thing.
There's a couple.
A couple of cool things.
Like.
Dreadshade now.
Is permanent.
So that's going to help.
Your.
Your Acolyte.
Summoners a bit.
And then.
You know how you have.
Crazy amount of.
Like.
Movement speed for some minions.
And they start.
Sliding and skating.
You know.
Yeah.
There should be some improvements to that.
So they don't just like.
Slide.
Right across the enemies.
That they were supposed to stop to hit.
Hopefully.
What else?
Mana costs.
On some of the Acolyte.
I think.
Skills are lowered a bit.
Like for example.
Walletal zombie.
The bear.
You know.
The summon bear.
On primalist.
We're reducing the cooldown.
On the swipe.
A lot.
And then we are giving it a.
Like strength scaler.
So it just get.
The bear just gets.
Additional melee damage.
From strength.
I think it's like.
One per three strength.
Or something like that.
So.
You know.
Strength stacking primalist.
The bear might.
I'm really excited to see.
What someone does with pedal set.
In.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Let's not.
Let's leak all the.
All the.
The set changes here.
But yeah.
Bebel sets might be.
Pretty good there.
Yeah.
So there's some set changes.
There are some.
Sabertooth fixes coming too.
They.
Now swipe every time they leap.
Not just when they use their own ability to leap.
They.
Um.
There was some.
We.
Sabertooth.
That was fixed.
And then we gave it a couple new nodes.
I think.
Yeah.
So it's actually pretty good now.
I think.
Yeah.
Okay.
So.
I was still doing the rounds.
As I explained earlier.
Talking to some.
Uh.
Creators that mainly make.
Carnival last Epoch.
And.
Obviously.
I have some mini questions.
Which I kind of baked in.
But one question that.
Myself was very interested in hearing.
Was also coming from.
Actually RPG Aaron.
As well as dreadful.
And it's a two question part.
So I'm going to start with one of them.
And that is.
The.
Weaving back to melee issue.
And that is that they feel lackluster.
For both.
For melee minions as well.
That they feel lackluster.
In terms of clearing.
Compared to range.
Because of area coverage.
And.
So.
I guess one of the big questions there.
Is there going to be improvements.
On melee minions.
To allow them to hit a wider.
Uh.
Target.
With their attacks.
Like.
Basically.
Will they have bigger AOEs.
Is what I'm asking.
I don't think we have any.
Specific changes to that.
Uh.
I think that.
The bigger problem for melee minions.
Would be just.
Like.
How easily can they.
Engage with the new pack of enemies.
Like.
They don't have the run there.
So maybe.
Giving them some dashes.
On stuff like that.
Is going to help a lot.
But like.
I don't think.
I don't think there's an.
Almost like.
Any skill in the entire game.
Like a melee skill.
That is just like.
An actual single target.
They all.
All have like.
A small AOE.
So.
As long as the enemies.
Are close to.
Each other.
It does help.
There are.
There are the little changes.
That we mentioned.
Just a second ago.
With.
Um.
Bear getting swipe.
And Sabretooth.
Getting.
Uh.
Better.
The fury.
Fury swipes.
Happening more often.
Uh.
With its leap engagement.
And so yeah.
There are some little things.
But there's not.
Like a.
A huge systematic change.
To like.
All melee minions.
Getting more AOE.
Or something like that.
Yeah.
We also just have.
Like Meg said.
All the minions.
Like.
They are their own thing.
Uh.
And we have a lot of them.
Um.
We'll.
Every now and then.
We'll find things to buff.
So yeah.
Let us know.
What needs to be buffed.
And we'll buff them.
In the future.
Uh.
So yeah.
I got you.
Um.
Another part of this question.
There is.
I was talking to these creators.
As well.
Which I'm curious about.
Is.
Build diversity.
When it comes to minions.
Now we have the unique play style.
Of Forged Guards.
With their type of specific minions.
When we.
If you look at the Acolyte.
For example.
Due to the strength.
Scaling and power.
Of the double shade play.
Infernal and dread shade.
We're now getting permanent dread shade.
That sounds fantastic.
But due to the power scaling.
Those.
It's been very often.
More favorable.
To put them all.
Stacking all the power.
Onto one minion.
Like an archmage.
Or an abomination.
More so.
Than actually having.
An actual army.
Uh.
Playing for you.
In terms of actual performance.
So I guess the question.
For season two.
Or beyond.
Are there any intentions.
In addressing the diversity problem.
Of actual in-game performance.
Of minion builds.
With that in mind.
I remember at least.
A couple minion builds.
That were army builds.
And they were absolutely crazy.
And we had to nerf them multiple times.
Because they were so crazy.
So it's a.
It's a.
It's a very fine line.
That needs to walk.
Especially for something like.
You have a minion.
That does everything for you.
And you just run around.
And they do everything for you.
So yeah.
It's a.
It is.
We don't have any.
It's like.
We are not targeting specifically.
So that.
Single minion builds.
Are better than the others.
It just.
When people.
Minimax.
Complicated game.
Something.
Is always better.
And sometimes.
It's.
Single minion builds.
It hasn't always been the case.
Yeah.
So I would expect.
That eventually.
There will.
Be a.
Minion army build.
That's going to be.
Crazy good again.
And then we have to nerf it.
So yeah.
And this is not.
What we're seeing in season two.
That might be something.
We'll talk about.
In the season two.
Yeah.
I don't think we have.
Balance changes.
And itemization.
The changes might.
Make.
That the thing.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Okay.
I don't have.
Any crazy changes.
To minions.
Specifically targeting.
Minion army builds.
To be better.
Okay.
To be the answer.
Yeah.
I do have one last.
Mini question.
I don't want to take the interview off.
With too many mini questions.
I know it's me.
I have to ask some of them.
The last mini questions.
I have specific.
Specific for minions.
At least.
Is golem specifically.
It feels more like.
A consistent.
Utility option.
For minions builds.
Rather than having.
A performing option.
As an actual.
Offensive addition.
To a minion build.
I believe this is from.
Frozen Sentinel actually.
And that said.
Will we see.
Some specific changes.
To minions in general.
For the season.
Which you already covered.
But in this case.
We're talking about the golem.
One of the best references.
I have for this.
Is the pyre node.
That the golem has.
Which consumes minions.
To do fire damage.
Like it charges up.
It's taking all of these minions.
And consuming them.
Only to.
Light the little tiny match.
And hope that does damage.
What's up with that?
That specific node.
I don't think there's any changes coming.
Okay.
But yeah.
These are just.
Where.
We have.
We have so many nodes.
In so many skills.
That some just.
Some may need more love.
That's it.
We just.
We just need to get the.
The feedback.
And we need a couple more.
You know.
Devs to just.
Just hire some devs.
For us to fix skills.
And buff them.
You know.
You just need a.
It's a.
It takes a lot of time.
Because we could just.
You could just make number go big.
And then things die.
Right.
That.
You could make a.
Vengeance literally one shot.
To the entire game.
With a single thing.
But.
We generally.
Want to be a bit more.
Involved.
With the.
The buffs and changes.
So that.
It isn't just.
A number go big.
Kind of thing.
Of course.
I like that approach.
And I think that you.
Especially seeing the heart seeker.
It seems like that's really.
The theme of it.
To have more.
Interesting mechanics.
And options to play with.
So it's not just.
You know.
Big number go up.
Right.
I think that's a really good approach.
Stepping aside.
Away from minions.
For the most part.
Not entirely.
In the trailer.
There was images.
Showing.
One of them showed.
A lot of new unique items.
And it was really cool.
But it was one in particular.
That stood out for myself.
And a lot of people in my chat.
And we talked about this.
And it is.
Nest of nightmares.
Now we don't get to see much of it.
But what we see in the teaser.
Is a line of text saying.
Applying spiders.
On melee hits.
Now there's a wording in the game.
That says summon this.
Summon that.
Like the bee gloves.
And stuff like that.
So we've already come to the conclusion.
This is not a minion stuff.
But we really want to know.
What is applying spiders.
On melee hits.
Could you elaborate on this?
Yes.
I can tell you exactly.
What the ailment spiders does.
Spiders is a new ailment.
Okay.
It lasts four seconds.
And can stack up to four times.
It gives the afflicted actor.
Five percent flat added chance.
To be critically hit.
Per stack.
So it is.
Five.
Ten.
Fifteen.
Twenty percent chance.
Added to be crit.
So basically.
If you've got four stacks.
Of spiders on something.
You only need to hit.
Eighty percent crit.
To always crit.
Does this stack.
With acid skin?
This is just.
Its own.
Added 20.
On top of whatever else.
They might have.
Yeah.
Oh shit.
Okay.
Yeah.
I like.
I like the sound of this.
That's good.
And because it's applied to the target.
It does affect.
Other people hitting it as well.
So like.
If you're.
If your minions hit it.
They get that as well.
If other people in your party hit it.
So it's everything hitting the target.
All right.
Another question we have is.
Idol crafting.
We talked about idols before.
You're removing the.
Was it the flat HP.
From the stout idols?
Yeah.
That's only on stout.
Does this include the big idols?
Yeah.
So the big idols.
That can have double life.
I think there's only one big idol.
And that's on.
Acolyte.
I think.
It might be.
There's a lot more pressure.
You won't want it.
Yeah.
I think it's one of the three.
I think that might.
Might still exist.
Okay.
So the season two is introducing.
Weaver's touch.
Craftable idols.
With four modifiers.
Rather than two.
So I guess the question here.
Is if you could share some information.
What type of modifiers.
We can expect in the side and slots.
Or are we going to sit.
And expect us to go for.
Trying to weavers.
Touch our way into double life.
And armor.
And arrest roll.
Or is there any.
Just more offensive scaling.
Could you elaborate more.
On the modifiers.
We will see on these.
Yeah.
I don't think we can go.
I don't think we can do specific.
I don't think.
I don't have a list of specific ones here.
But yeah.
There'll be.
There'll be more interesting things.
Rather than just like flat stats.
Quite so much.
So you'll start to see.
Don't.
I don't want to.
I don't know if I'm allowed to say.
Specific ones or not.
That's why I took.
That's why I took them out.
From my inventory.
When I was looking at.
I mean.
Are we talking more offensive.
Mechanically changing modifiers.
Or are we.
Are they also including.
Like baseline stats.
Such as life resistance armor.
Stuff like that.
I guess that's a better question.
It's a mixture of both.
For sure.
The ones that do call out.
Specific skills.
Are.
I don't think they ever call out.
Like offensive clearing skills.
As.
Specific ones.
So it's.
It's like there's.
There's.
If it does ever.
If a.
Idle.
Enchantment.
Does ever call out.
A specific skill.
I think it only ever calls out.
Defensive skills.
Or utility skills.
And.
Then they can call out.
Specific.
Classes.
Like.
One of those.
Like something for fire skills.
You know.
Things like that.
So the categories of.
Abilities that it'll do sometimes.
I think the.
Important takeaway.
About.
Idols.
Things.
Is that.
There's new power.
In idols.
That did not exist there before.
I think that's.
Hence the curiosity.
That said though.
When you said that the.
Flat life and stat idols.
Were removed.
The follow-up question.
Are.
Is it.
Are there any improvements.
Coming to the baseline idols.
That exists in the game.
Now that we are not.
Going to see double life.
Stout idols.
So there are any other changes.
Happening to the baseline idols.
Besides that.
There.
There is.
New power in idols.
That you haven't seen before.
Okay.
That's it.
Yeah.
So that's not just.
The weaver's touch.
That's how I understood it.
So this is baseline.
All of them gets new added.
Modifiers that can roll.
Specifically the.
Size one and two.
Idols.
There's.
There's a bunch of new ones for that.
Okay.
Perfect.
Next question we have.
Is champion modifiers.
Coming to the game.
And we have.
Zero information.
Of what type of modifiers.
They can be.
Can we get some.
Knowledge on this.
Are you sure it's zero.
I'm pretty sure.
I saw some of the trailer.
I think.
Yeah.
It's very minimal.
It's borderlining.
Zero.
Then.
Those ones are.
Those ones are generally more specific.
For.
They'll call out.
Individual abilities.
Really.
Frequently.
So those ones are.
They're frequently more specific.
And.
Narrow.
And niche.
Things.
That you're going to be getting out of those.
So those.
Those are.
Those are designed to be more specific.
Yeah.
I think that.
The important bit here.
Is that.
They are always sealed.
Which means.
You cannot put.
Any of the champion affiches.
Into legendaries.
That's the.
You can make.
Set items.
With them.
Because you can just.
Craft.
The set.
Affix in there.
But you cannot.
Make.
A.
Champion.
Affix.
Into.
A.
Legendary.
So a lot of people.
Have been having.
A different takes on this.
With it.
With which modifier.
Were sealed.
Champion modifiers.
Are sealed.
So they cannot go on unique.
Games.
Set item.
Craft.
Chards.
Can become.
An actual.
Prefix.
Suffix.
Modifier.
On the item.
And affix.
But so the set item.
Can be put on a unique.
Because my understanding.
Was that was not possible.
Okay.
Those are also not going to be able to put there.
When a set shard.
Gets applied to an item.
That item.
Becomes effectively.
A set item.
Okay.
And set items.
Cannot be combined.
With unique items.
To make a legendary.
Good.
Then we got that cleared.
For everyone.
Because so many people.
Have had different takes on this.
And I'm like.
Mike said.
It's not possible.
But what about the sealed.
Affix.
I'm pretty sure.
That was champion modifiers.
Let's just get that out of the way.
So we have that clear state.
That clearly stated.
Here in the interview.
Perfect.
We are running.
Really tight on time.
Right now.
But.
One last question.
Before.
I'm going to jump into some Q&A.
You can tag Mike.
Sorry.
Not Mike.
But Wick.
Or Photon in the chat here.
If you have any questions.
He'll pick them out.
He's already spammed me up.
On Discord.
With some questions.
But before the Q&A.
We have a question.
From yet another.
Last Epoch creator.
His name is Frozen Sentinel.
I call him the spreadsheet god.
At this point.
And his question was.
With more items.
And item types.
Being introduced.
How is balance approach.
Coming.
Being approached.
When it comes to.
Merchant guild.
Versus.
Circle of Fortune.
Well.
Specifically.
It's talking about like.
So this is like.
An additional layer.
To the.
Itemization hunt.
So.
I think most of the.
Weaver.
Weaver tree stuff.
Should work.
With.
Circle of Fortune.
So that you'd still have.
That's.
Extra multiplier there.
So it's not.
Suddenly that everyone plays MG.
Because there's no reason to play.
CoF anymore.
And there's some stuff.
In the weaver tree.
That we'll get into.
Another time.
That you can.
Influence.
The item types.
You're getting.
A little bit better.
And.
The cof.
Does scale off of that.
As well.
So they play off each other.
And.
It gets amplified.
As a cof player.
Okay.
So we know.
We have some new.
Glyphs.
And runes.
For example.
The whole.
Shifting the.
The modifier tiers.
On the.
Sorry.
The tiers on the modifiers.
Can shift.
Right.
Is this something.
We'll see.
Not constellations.
But prophecies for.
In Circle of Fortune.
Is that something.
We can expect to see.
Moving forward in season two.
For getting the new runes.
The new crafting materials.
One of the new runes.
Will it be.
Will it have a prophecy.
Yes.
But.
CMF.
I'm sorry.
My head's inside.
But merchant skill doesn't.
You can't trade.
You can't.
Buy and sell those things.
On merchant skill anyways.
But yeah.
Cof does get a little bit.
Of a boost.
Of one of them.
It's getting back.
Now I can hear you.
I didn't hear shit there.
Can you say that.
One more time.
You chat here.
Because that's all that matters.
I think so.
Did I miss it.
I think I missed it all.
They're saying.
Poggers.
Watch it later.
Yeah.
You were asking about.
The prophecies.
So.
One of the three new runes.
Will have a prophecy.
Yeah.
I think through no weaving.
But the rest.
Will.
The CMF.
Beliars.
Will get more of those.
Through just.
The CMF perks.
And the other prophecies.
Like.
If you have a rune prophecy.
That could potentially.
Give you the other new runes.
But there isn't.
A specific.
Targeted.
Prophecy.
For.
Havoc.
Or redemption.
All right.
Since we're running.
A little low in time.
I'm just going to dive.
Straight into the Q&A.
Again.
You can type.
At.
EHG.
Underscore.
Wick.
Or underscore.
Photon.
For any questions.
He's picking them out.
So I'm just going to go from the list.
He sent me here.
He's been picking the questions out.
And the first one is.
How do you plan to handle.
Patches.
Slash.
Bug fixes.
With the new cycle.
Season.
In the new season.
Yeah.
Like.
I don't understand.
Handle them.
We're rolling out.
As soon as we can.
Hot fixes.
Yeah.
Yep.
Hot fixes.
Yeah.
Is.
I'm sorry.
Yes.
Yeah.
Oh.
It's Q&A.
We'll do some rapid fire with them.
Push about fast and furious.
Yes.
For family.
So the next one is about family.
It's with minions.
Falling further and further behind.
In the overall state of balance.
Is their plan.
Change.
The upcoming release.
To help those archetypes out.
Yeah.
There's so much being shaken up.
By.
Item changes.
Coming this.
This season.
That it's going to be.
I wouldn't bring any.
Preconceived notions like that.
Into the new season.
All right.
Are the time rot nodes.
Additive.
Or multiplicative.
With each other.
They are all three.
Different multipliers.
If talking about the rot creep.
Yes.
But within itself.
Right.
With itself.
Yeah.
They're all multiplicative.
With each other.
The time rot chance.
Is its own.
Like a bucket.
Of a multiplier.
And then the.
The other two are also.
So you get three different multipliers there.
All right.
Will arena prophecies.
Still appear.
If you have removed arenas.
With the new weaver tree node.
I don't know.
The answer is yes.
I think so.
Yeah.
But you can.
You can just.
To lock arena prophecies.
I think there's a new.
I think there's a new lens.
Coming in.
In season two.
That should.
Make your life.
A bit easier.
Okay.
Next one is.
I feel like.
For ARPGs.
The history is better told.
Through end of chapter.
Cut scenes.
Any plans.
On expanding.
That front.
I know.
I know we've talked about.
Having better cut scenes.
In the game.
And that's something.
That people have been.
Pushing for a lot.
Me amongst them.
For sure.
I think that those are.
Improved cut scenes.
Yeah.
Storytelling.
It's a huge way.
We've been talking about this.
For years.
About how.
Like.
You can.
You can get the story.
From like Diablo 2.
By just watching the cut scenes.
For the most part.
And there's not that many.
Cut scenes there.
And.
You know.
Like.
I think.
I think adding in those.
Would be.
Really hugely beneficial.
We don't have any major ones.
Expansion.
Because there are.
There are.
There are those.
Little cut scenes.
We do have for them.
Which are great.
But yeah.
Getting more.
I'd love to have more.
And as we add more chapters.
All right.
So here's another question.
Which is from Mike.
It's a bit personal.
I was very curious about this.
I even wrote to Fulton about this.
Saying.
What happened to Mike?
Like.
Is this good?
Or is it bad?
I don't know what is happening.
And the question is.
When are you releasing the workout routine.
And diet plan.
You look amazing.
You've lost a lot of weight.
You look fantastic.
And I was like.
What is happening?
I don't even know how to answer it.
Or ask it.
But here's the question.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
It is all good.
It is.
Yeah.
It is a lot of hard work.
And.
Eating less.
And working more.
Working out more.
It is.
Yeah.
There's.
There's no secret to it.
You've.
You gotta.
Calculate how many calories you need to maintain your body weight.
And eat less than that.
And track them rigorously.
And that's literally all I did.
All right.
It's definitely fair enough.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Feels good.
Just got in.
Just got the home gym set up.
Nice.
Next door.
And starting to get into that pretty hard.
Which is great.
Perfect.
Next question is.
Can we be able to trade mats?
We are not.
You're not able to trade mats.
And that's not something we're currently looking at doing.
It's possible we could in the future.
But right now it is nothing.
No.
No trading on mats.
Yeah.
This is the one thing that we mentioned earlier.
Is that.
It would regard very major changes to how item factions currently work.
Fair enough.
Yeah.
Any improvement slash changes to localization coming?
Yes.
Yeah.
I think that's it.
We want.
We want the localization to be good.
Yeah.
So.
It's always.
We either just expanded it.
Or are expanding the languages.
I don't know.
I don't know if that's out yet or not.
All right.
A lot of languages now.
Fair enough.
Will we be able to control somehow the Weaver's tablets via the COF Observatory Prophecies?
There is nothing specifically interacting with the COF and the Weaver stuff like that.
There are things that naturally just work together.
But there isn't a very specific interaction like that.
Yeah.
So if you have something in COF that says like you just get more of this thing and then the Weaver stuff drops that thing, you get more of that thing from dropping it.
All right.
What about making it easier to actually pick up items from the floor without having to click precisely on it?
UI scaling is coming.
So you'll be able to make them bigger if you'd like to be able to have a bigger target to click.
Nice.
So that's just loot filter improvements.
Is that my understanding of it?
No.
Like we're scaling the entire UI options now.
So you can crank the size of everything, the whole UI up or down.
Yeah.
Player agency again.
I've said this before.
I think it's fantastic.
Yeah.
I think here's also like a pickup radius or like how far away you can click to pick up items to not run to it.
I don't remember if we have any changes to that.
It is something we discussed at some point.
And I think it was overall just yes, we should do it.
I don't remember if we did it.
It's one of those.
I guess we're going to bring it up now and see if we can, you know, if we didn't, maybe we can.
You know, I don't know.
That's good.
I mean, that's also one of those.
You can only make it bigger.
You can never go back once you made it bigger.
So it's a very touchy topic, right?
Next question is plans for seasonal objectives.
That's something we're very interested in down the road.
Season two does not have seasonal objectives with like the whole thing.
I think there's there are lots of great examples of that where there's like complete these bosses and, you know, finish this challenge in game.
And you get this like cosmetic thing for the season to remember to like, so you can remember having completed that challenge in the game.
You look back at that season.
These are all awesome stuff.
You get achievements.
We're interested in diving into that world.
We don't have them for season two yet.
We have invested time into making the game better instead of keeping you playing more from giving you free MTX.
Basically, it's friendly.
It is something that we definitely want to do.
They're really cool.
We just have other priorities being on the game right now.
That's fair.
Is the Uber Abaroth fight accessed through the same method as the normal one?
No, kind of.
You need to kill a normal Abaroth to get Uber Abaroth.
It drops a WoW Echo that you put into your Echo Web if you have a high enough corruption on it.
And then you'll fight Uber Abaroth.
And important to note is that even though it is in the Echo Web, modifiers or corruption does not affect the difficulty of that.
It's a static fight.
And you will have access to it way before your character is trying to fight it.
So similar to the Abaroth.
All right.
It is a lot harder to fight than normal Abaroth.
So a good follow-up question to this is actually what corruption is the Uber Abaroth balance around?
What do you expect players to be at when they can't clear him?
A lot.
Can we tell you when you can access it?
Is that something we can say?
I don't know.
Yeah, I think we can say when you're able to access it.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's 500 corruption.
500.
And that is...
You need a minimum 500 to access it.
But even if you're able to farm 500, it's going to be a very, very difficult fight.
All right.
So you should be significantly higher for it to be a comfortable fight is what you're saying.
Yeah.
The interesting bit is that once you put it into your Echo Web, if you fail, you can just, you know, you can go again.
Ah, that's nice actually.
There might be some stuff like maybe not giving you the loot.
I'm not sure.
But we probably do need to do something there.
But yeah, you can just keep fighting it.
Okay.
Next question is, can Woven Echo's items change the corruption of the Echo it is applied to somehow?
There is one Woven Echo that does change the corruption of that timeline.
We already talked about that one.
Yeah, the one that copies the highest corruption of that player.
Yeah.
So that's the only one so far that is fitting this question.
There might be one more.
I don't think there's any Woven Echo that change the corruption of the Echo it's.
No, because the corruption is based on the timeline.
So whatever the timeline's corruption is, the corruption is for the Echoes.
Okay.
Following this up, we have, can there be more sinks for rare materials?
Oh, sinks.
Yes.
But, I mean, the, well, some, one of the rare materials is going away.
And the new ones that are there are, you know, like, I think you're going to be wanting to use them up on your items.
Because I think you're going to get more opportunities to craft good items.
Because there's going to be more base types that are potentially awesome.
Because these new crafting materials are available for you.
So I think, yeah, just the existence of them is going to make you use more of them.
Okay.
Fair enough.
Can you guys talk about how much better arenas are now?
If at all.
Sorry.
I'd add that.
You can influence them through the Weaver tree.
I mean, one is you can just not do them at all.
But you can also just add some other stuff to it.
And the base functionality of it is also, I think they are, the enemies are faster.
I think they, so they come to you much faster if you stand in the middle.
I think.
Time between waves, I think, is reduced as well.
Yeah.
We did a bunch of, like, small adjustments to it.
I've heard, I've had at least a few people say that, that hated them, say that they're kind of fine now.
So.
Okay.
That's a good sign for me.
I was never a big fan of them.
I'll have to try them out.
There's more mechanics, like, of the, like, the side mechanics and things that spawn in the know as well.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Next question.
I think there's, like, no way that any of the extra mechanics could appear in them.
But I think at least champions can now.
Well, that's, that's kind of big, though.
I think.
If it's true, since you said think.
Yeah.
I'm, like, 80% sure on that one.
Okay.
Next question is, can you guys talk about, no, sorry, are portal charms consumables?
Yes.
I believe you guys covered this in the last interview.
And a good refresher is that you can trade any of the three existing dungeon keys in Majelka in Divine Era.
I think there's an NPC there that you can trade up those keys for portal charms.
So, that's it.
Yeah.
If you only care about temporal sanctum, but you have a lot of the other two, you can just trade them up for what the portal charms.
All right.
Is the damage taken increase from dual wield being changed?
No.
This is a very interesting, like, both the deciding and balancing topic.
Because it's like, okay, do we want dual wielding to be, like, so we have a sword and board, then we have, like, two-handing, and then we have dual wield.
Where should the dual wield fall in, like, in the middle?
Like, should it be doing the most damage?
Should it be doing more damage than a sword and board, but be slightly tankier than with a shield or with a two-hander?
And I think we fell on that you just take more damage, but you're, in most cases, doing more damage.
Fair enough.
Are Forge Guard minions robots?
I have no idea what that means.
That was the question I got.
Yes.
And no.
Okay.
Yes, and no.
They have feelings.
I mean, I think I can make a robot out of Lego.
My manifest armor has feelings, okay?
I mean, that's coming from a true summoner perspective.
I didn't know you were a real summoner, Karv.
What has changed?
I've been a summoner player since forever.
What do you mean?
Well, not always.
Not always.
We've seen how happy you were playing Heartseeker.
I'm just saying.
Yeah, there you go.
Speaking of Heartseeker, what level is it to learn Heartseeker?
It's past the chains.
How many points in?
20 for the base class, and then how many points in for the marksman?
30.
I think it's 30.
I can make a look.
I can confirm.
I'm sure it's 30.
Okay, so around 50 skill points in, which means...
Yes, regards 30, yes.
Yeah, so the level then would be, depending on how many skill points you got from the campaign,
right?
Yeah.
And that kind of summarizes the Q&A.
Before the little outro, I have two more things to cover there in the outro.
I'm curious, Mr. Minion Lover, what are you playing as your starter for Season 2 yourself?
Ooh, I don't know.
It has to be minions now.
I'm just saying.
I mean, does Falcon count?
I could play a bow falconer.
I don't know.
Who knows?
A falcon does not count.
No.
Okay.
I think I'm going to play...
Either I'm going to play Heartseeker or I'm going to play something Sentinel, Void Knight,
probably.
Void Knight.
What about you, Mike?
I'm running it.
I've been saying this for months now.
I'm going full Heartseeker.
There's no question in my mind.
It is...
My favorite class has always been Marksman.
And it's the first time we've had a new skill for it since it launched.
It is Marksman, Marksman, Marksman for me.
I'm playing Heartseeker.
Fair enough.
So the last question before the outro, we're going to wrap this up, is obviously the common
question that we've seen on Twitter when we talk about Bex many years ago.
You all know what it is.
And that is patch notes when?
When they're ready.
Just don't give us a patch of three days before launch.
Give us at least a week.
You will have several dates to read through all of the changes for sure.
But I don't know.
I don't think we can give you the actual dates.
We asked.
We're not allowed to say the patch notes date.
I'm sorry.
We did check before this.
Okay.
A follow-up to that.
When you say several days, can we as a collective then say that we would prefer to see them around
a week before and not just a couple of days?
Is that something that is more in line with what's going to go down?
Or we're talking literally a couple of days?
Give or take.
I think we'll keep staying on the several.
Okay.
Yeah.
We just can't.
We asked, but we weren't.
We've only done too much damage anyway.
Okay.
Come on.
Let's keep our jobs here.
Avoid the suing process.
We're going to wrap this up by thanking Mike and Carver coming on for this interview.
It's been a blast.
Thank you so much for putting your job at risk and everything.
Appreciate that very much.
Next week, Friday, same time, I believe, right?
You guys will be having a friend of mine talkative try to talk about itemizations.
I'll be sure tuning into that.
Hope you guys that are watching will tune into that as well.
And show us the love for last Deep Book.
And I'm very excited for the launch on the 2nd of April.
Thanks so much for coming in, boys.
And I'll see you guys later.
Thanks for having us.
Great time.
Yep.
Thanks.
Bye.
And we're out.
Woo.
Let me see.
Uh.