Good afternoon, everybody, and welcome back to another last Epoch Devstream.
As usual, I'm your host, Mike.
Hello.
And you may notice...
Oh, there's actually more people here than I thought there'd be at the start, considering
what's going on today.
But you may notice something lovely behind me here that I'd like to highlight right off
the bat.
And I've realized that I almost need a better webcam just to show this thing off, because
it is unbelievably incredible.
This was sent to me from the Terra Monthly post that we've been covering the development of
this thing.
It's been being sent out.
And it's here.
And I can't believe it.
It's incredible.
It's like so detailed.
It's so big.
Like, I'm pretty far from it right now, so it actually looks smaller than it is.
But like...
Like, it's huge!
I just such a huge, huge, huge thank you.
I don't even know your real name, but...
I don't even know how to pronounce your handle here, but if you're watching, I hope you are.
Um...
Uh...
Vezidroga, I love it.
Thank you so much.
It is incredible.
And, uh...
Yeah, it's lit up.
It, like...
A little remote.
Sometimes you gotta get close to it to take the remote work, but...
That's like a rainbow in there.
It's hard to see if...
Rainbow colors, though.
It's hard to see the rainbows.
The thing is...
Incredible.
And it is...
Like...
I'm gonna...
I'm not 100% sure that's where it's gonna go.
I had to get one of the sides and a stud.
So there weren't a lot of options on places to put it.
But I think I really like where it is.
And...
It's just unbelievable.
If you want to see more information on how it was made...
Um...
And, like, up close.
Incredible shots of it.
There's...
Uh...
We've been, um...
Sharing their YouTube channel in our...
In our, um...
Entire monthly posts.
So there's links to there.
It's just...
It's so cool.
I can't get over how cool it is.
Uh...
And so I'll actually get into the proper stream now.
Thanks for indulging me.
Because it was so awesome.
Um...
Yeah.
We're just gonna keep...
We're just gonna keep playing.
Have some fun here.
But I will answer questions.
So, as usual.
Um...
Start of stream.
Highlights.
And info that we need to know.
Uh...
We stream for charity.
Boom.
Bob my head here.
All of the...
Everything that we get from stream goes directly to charity.
Um...
If you'd like to ask me a question...
Uh...
I'd be very happy to answer it.
You put...
At Last Epoch Game.
Or...
At Last Epoch if you're on YouTube.
And we do collect the...
Uh...
Questions from both of those places.
Kane will be feeding those to me.
And I will be answering as many of those as I can.
Um...
I expected to be a little bit slower today.
And that's totally fine.
Um...
First question.
How do you have four raptors?
I have...
A wonderful ability.
Uh...
From this weapon here.
It says...
You can summon raptors up to your companion limit.
Um...
And so this lets me summon four raptors.
Because my companion limit is four right now.
Uh...
Okay.
So...
Oh yeah.
First sub.
Resub.
Cajun Canuck.
Yeah.
That's a good name.
I love that.
I recognize that name.
Thanks for the resub.
Much appreciated.
How am I feeling about the servers for Season 2 launch?
Launch?
I am feeling great about the servers for Season 2 launch.
Um...
If...
If anyone is like...
They were here for like Season 1.
And oh my god.
I just saw a huge big list of stuff go by.
I'm gonna look at that in a second.
Uh...
We have entirely new physical boxes.
For servers.
We have...
Uh...
Like...
Basically an entirely rewritten netcode for it.
Like it's...
It's...
It's so much more efficient.
And uh...
I'm feeling very good about it.
I'm feeling really good about it.
Mike190Twitch.
Thanks to the...
The three gifted subs there.
And also uh...
One...
Hot...
Genga?
Thank you very much for the sub.
I appreciate it.
Um...
We are uh...
Yeah.
I'm...
I'm feeling really good today.
Getting this thing up.
It's...
It's very heavy.
And uh...
I was doing...
My wife's um...
Uh...
Quite sick right now.
And unable to help me.
And I had to put it up today.
Um...
And so like holding it up.
While like trying to line everything up.
It was...
It was tough to get that up on my own.
It's...
It's a meter long.
It's crazy.
I'm gonna keep babbling about it every once in a while.
Because I'm so excited about it.
All right.
More questions.
Mike, will you guys ever sell merch?
Like sticker or shirts, etc?
Yes.
I have been uh...
Basically...
I guess ask this question every stream.
And every stream I go.
And I ask the people who are uh...
In charge of this.
I'm like...
When's it coming?
When's it happening?
Um...
So yep.
Uh...
It's...
It is...
It's on...
It's on the agenda.
I have no idea when it's coming.
I don't have any more information than you do on it.
Um...
But I do know that it is something that I have been uh...
I've been also asking for it for a while.
And...
Should be...
Should be on its way.
I hope.
Uh...
Any great leaks today?
Oh yeah.
Uh...
I'm not gonna spill...
We're six minutes in.
Just...
Just a little bit in.
But I got some.
Don't worry.
Uh...
Will we have an old man mode?
Aka cursor size adjustment coming.
We don't have a way to adjust the cursor size just yet.
Um...
There are a couple uh...
Workarounds that people have found.
Um...
I think if you increase the size of the cursor like in Windows itself.
Or in your operating system.
Um...
Before launching the game.
I think it carries over into the game.
So you can get a pretty big mouse cursor that way.
Uh...
You can also use...
Um...
Uh...
Yolo Mouse is acceptable to use.
For uh...
Increasing your cursor size.
Which I know is not everyone's cup of tea.
But um...
We...
It is something that we do want to do.
To improve the cursor size.
And have that be customizable.
Like...
Uh...
Different colors for the cursor.
And um...
Different sizes is something that we do really want to do.
This is not a for lack of trying.
Uh...
It's not here type thing issue still.
Alright.
I'm really excited.
To have everyone try the new...
The new Season 2 content.
So excited.
Alright.
Mike.
PoE 2 launch.
Having bad performance.
Really?
I haven't uh...
I haven't had a chance to hop in this morning.
But I know they're like...
They're just...
They're just up right now.
Um...
I've got it downloaded.
And I'll be...
I'll be checking it out this weekend.
Got some time.
Maybe this evening.
Oh no.
I got a bug to fix this evening.
Maybe this weekend.
Um...
Oh we're out.
We're out of here.
My thoughts on avoiding it.
I mean we're gonna...
We've been planning and preparing for this.
Um...
I don't know what their numbers are looking like right now.
I assume they're gigantic numbers right now.
Um...
And...
Uh...
Like we've got...
Way more than we're...
We've got...
Everything set up for way more than we're expecting.
Um...
And we've got plans for like...
In case we're wildly off.
We've got plans...
Contingency plans for that as well.
By people that are much smarter than I am.
All right.
How many teasers have you prepared for today?
I have.
I think I have five.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
I have five.
Hi Mike.
Chronicler class when?
Ooh.
Chronicler class is interesting.
It's um...
So like...
I don't have a specific time frame.
I'm not gonna confirm or deny it coming or whatever.
But like...
As an idea of a class.
I am really interested in this style of class.
Um...
And I don't know if it's like...
I think...
I think it's a mage mastering.
Not its own class personally.
Um...
But...
Who...
Who knows?
I think like...
In the hypothetical scenario that we were gonna do something like that...
I'd be pushing for it to be a mastery.
Not its own class.
Because...
It's...
I think it's really hard to get like...
Specific masteries.
Like three full masteries for it.
Alright...
Last Epoch.
Can you remap joysticks in the new version?
Trying to play Ellie on my arcade that runs by Steam Deck.
I can't figure out how to remap the movement.
Uh...
I don't think so.
I think you have to do some like...
Software shantigans beforehand to get that to work.
Get back here, boy.
Get back here!
Run, Forest!
That's...
That was that...
Uh...
Um...
That lizard's name was Forest and it didn't run fast enough.
Go, Rune.
Alright...
Even if...
Uh...
Super rare...
Will we be pleasantly surprised by hybrid or champion affixes when using...
Discovery or other RNG-based runes and glyphs?
Uh...
No.
So...
Hybrid yes, champion no.
Um...
You can get hybrid affixes to show up with...
Uh...
This runes of discovery already.
Um...
But the champion-specific ones are only available...
From the champion affixes.
We've earned a hype chest.
Click to see a reward.
Okay.
Hey, there's an emote.
Cool.
Things happen sometimes and I'm like...
I didn't know that was a thing.
Alright.
Uh...
Hey, Mike.
Do you guys know the date of the full reveal video?
Uh...
I think that comes with patch notes, right?
That's...
I'm pretty sure that's always same day as patch notes.
So the...
Uh...
Eleven.
Right?
Yeah, the eleven.
Alright.
Loving the new shrines from 1.5.
Are there going to be any more introduced in Season 2?
Yes, we are.
Um...
We've reworked a couple of the shrines that maybe didn't...
Didn't quite stick the landing.
Because most of them have been great.
Some of them not so awesome.
There's a few little things here and there that we're tweaking on some of them.
Um...
There's a few reworked ones.
A few new ones.
It's not a huge focus.
But there is, uh...
There's some new shake up there.
It's a system that we're very happy with overall.
Um...
So there didn't need to be, like, a huge, like...
Overhaul of the structure of it to...
To really get to where we want to be with it.
Just because I can't bring myself to throw stuff away.
Hello, Mike!
Hope you're doing great.
I am.
Thank you.
Any chance of an updated roadmap coming out soon?
I think we're going to wait until post...
Uh...
Post-season 2 a little bit before we look at...
Look beyond it.
Right now we're really focusing on Season 2.
Um...
And getting that...
Uh...
Getting that out the door.
And...
And all of our, like...
Pipe focus is around Season 2.
So we don't want to distract from that.
Be like...
Season 2 is coming!
But, like...
Here's a roadmap for what's after that!
Like...
Yeah.
Uh...
Can you say something about Void Beams?
Anything?
Are they more...
Are they more purple now?
Um...
There was...
Hmm...
I don't know enough off the top of my head.
I remember working on something with Void Beams near the start of the patch cycle.
And I can't remember what happened to it.
Hmm...
There was a bug around Void Beams that we fixed.
Months ago.
I don't remember what the bug was.
There's a bug fixed with them!
Um...
How much did combat...
Feel, skill visuals, and sound SFX improve in Season 2 compared to Season 1?
Uh...
I would say significantly.
Partially just from the, like...
The...
I guess...
A lot of that stuff is the...
When there's something that doesn't fit...
It...
Or feels weird.
It really sticks out and can...
Can take you out of the experience.
And...
Um...
Like...
Like, even if it's just like a sound that you're using an ability on that's...
Um...
Like, you use the ability 800 times.
And it's just kind of a...
Not quite great sound effect.
Uh...
And it starts to really stand out and...
You really notice the bad pieces.
And...
And a lot of those, like...
A lot of those have been smoothed out.
Um...
Like a nice piece of sandpaper to finish it off.
And...
Uh...
I think...
I think a little goes a long way with that sort of thing.
So, like...
Maybe it's not a complete overhaul of something.
But you get...
A lot of value out of...
Um...
Small changes.
Things just feel better.
There's just...
You know...
In general.
Or this way.
Also the...
Uh...
The new...
Wow, there's a lot of people here for...
What I expected.
Because of what's happening today.
Um...
The...
Also...
Uh...
The skill visuals.
The MTX.
Skill MTX for...
Cosmetics for skills.
I think has a huge impact on the fit and feel.
Of...
Of abilities.
Because you can really...
I don't know.
Make them pop.
Uh...
Especially with...
When you want something to look a specific way.
You can do that now.
Um...
I think...
I think that's gonna play a big role in...
The...
Like...
Awesome factor.
The X factor.
Uh...
Do you see a problem with the release date?
Because Torch...
Torch, Light, Infinite have the same date.
Um...
I mean...
April...
April's a minefield, right?
Is...
Is there a day in April that's...
That's really amazing.
Um...
I think that it would be...
You know...
Better if we were able to...
Be completely...
Avoiding all of the other games...
Similar games.
There's...
There's games releasing every day though.
So like...
We're never gonna avoid everything.
And lots of people play mini genres.
So it's...
I think we just gotta do the best job we can.
It's not ideal.
It's what we're going with.
When can we expect a new weapon class?
Anything in the works?
Uh...
Anything that you can tell us...
That you're super interested in bringing to the weapons?
Although keep the weight loss man at the head.
Say it every time.
You look great, dude.
Thank you.
I feel great.
It is...
Wild.
Um...
As far as new weapon classes...
I was...
There's some vague...
Rumblings about some new weapon classes.
But nothing...
Really specific.
Thanks, Cain.
Um...
There's...
Yeah, I would say there's...
There's definitely some weapons that I really want to get in.
I'd really love to get in...
Some one-handed spears.
Um...
Like, let me know how they're doing...
In...
Um...
In PvE2 right now, right?
Uh...
I'd really love to get in some fist weapons.
Like, whether it looks like claws...
Or...
You know, just like...
Like...
Arm attachments where you're like...
Your animations are very, very punchy.
Or where they're actually like...
Like brass knuckle style fist weapons.
Or...
I don't know, like...
Um...
Not really boxing gloves necessarily.
But you know, that...
That style of...
I guess a martial arts extension...
Um...
Type weapon would be really nice.
There's...
There was some weapons...
There's some armor from...
Like, Guild Wars 1...
Had...
I thought some of them...
The monk class...
Had some unbelievably cool theming around their...
Uh...
Some of their armor as tattoos.
Which I loved.
Um...
And...
I don't know, I'd love to do something like that.
I know that's armor, not weapons.
But...
I think that would be really cool.
I think the big thing is that...
Most of those things need a class...
Uh...
To go with it.
Next question.
Will any other classes be getting much interaction...
With void damage in Season 2?
No.
Uh...
Void damage is still pretty localized...
To Void Knight in Season 2.
There's some...
There's some outliers here and there.
Um...
Like the...
Uh...
There's a little touch of it on Mage here and there.
Um...
That's already there though.
It's not like something new.
Um...
Yeah, I don't think there's...
There's more stuff in Sentinel that's getting Void Conversions...
To make that a more...
Uh...
Like a less restrictive element style to play as a Sentinel.
Right.
When you break down a set for shards...
Do the two affixes that break down exist on a single shard?
Or are they separated shards?
Um...
They exist on a single shard.
So a set affix...
Shard...
Uh...
Contains two affixes...
A hybrid affix on it.
Similar to...
Like...
So...
Like this one right here.
This is...
Uh...
There's one prefix...
On this item.
Um...
Like if we...
If we do...
Not gonna...
That's fine.
So here like...
There's an empty slot on this item.
There's...
There's only one prefix here.
But there's two stats...
To it.
So it's the same style of thing.
Where a single prefix will be...
Uh...
Multiple stats...
On an item.
Uh...
For the set shard affixes.
Our chest is not great.
It's fine.
Because that minion melee damage is nice.
That one stat is like holding it up.
We've got more!
We've got more subs coming in!
Uh...
USA, American, and Anonymous.
Thank you for the subs.
I appreciate it.
Alright...
Uh...
What...
has the team been doing with the extra time?
Um...
Mostly bug fixes.
There's...
So there's a lot of things where we are...
We know like...
As we get closer to a patch launch, we lock down the version that's going to be launched
as the first version for the patch, and we do very rigorous testing on it to make sure
that it is bug-free.
And...
Woo!
So that it is bug-free.
You know, it feels good and all that sort of stuff.
And then we start working on hotfix elements to put in for early hotfixes after the patch
launches.
So we just kind of pushed back the process a little bit, where the things that we had already
been working on for hotfixes, because we'd already locked it down, and so we opened it
back up again and took stuff that people were working on for hotfixes and put those into
the launch version.
And now we're working on new things for hotfixes.
There's always new things to add.
There's always new things to improve upon slightly.
It's usually pretty low-risk, high-reward items as we can get at this stage.
So finding narrow issues where it's like, okay, if a character walks in with these three abilities
equipped and they use this ability right in this spot, there's a painful bug that happens.
You know, things like that.
So, when are we getting minion AI improvements?
Melee minions, especially all target one mob at a time instead of intelligently spreading
out.
Makes clear speed awful with them even when they have great damage.
Yeah, this is an interesting thing, because I think thematically, you know, they shouldn't
coordinate perfectly necessarily.
But at the same time, you know, nothing needs to be 100% perfect thematically appropriate.
So we can, you know, make them coordinate a little bit better.
And I think there's situations where it's easier to stretch that a little bit to make
them coordinate better.
We don't have any major changes for like a coordinated AI to manage the different minions.
We've tried a few tweaks on the system a little bit to try and make that happen a little bit
organically.
And usually it causes worse clear speed.
But we are, it's on the list, I would say.
It's especially an issue when you get really, really large armies.
So like right now here with four Raptors, it's really not that big of a deal because they're
not fighting the space to find things with each other.
But with like 30 skeletons, it's an issue.
All right, well, maybe not as big as PoE.
What is it like having such a dedicated fan base that completely and absolutely supports
you, especially amid recent controversies?
It's it's incredible.
It's incredible.
You know, like I remember when we when we started out and like we're sitting around
celebrating like like one person of like back to us on Kickstarter, like the first like
and that was a huge celebration, just like the first person.
And you know, like the first like real sale of the game after after we were officially launched.
And all these things of like milestones of just just one was incredible.
And
it's yeah, it feels amazing.
And like I'll talk to like family friends who I haven't seen in a while.
And and they'll be like.
I've I've I've I've had a few organic moments of like people who I've talked to didn't realize
I was working on on this specific game.
And, you know, and I we get chatting.
Like, oh, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Like this catching up sort of thing and they realize and there's that connection of like,
oh, you're working on that.
I've been playing that.
And that's really cool to see, too.
Um.
Yeah.
I wear my shirt to the store sometimes.
I haven't I haven't been stopped.
But no one's no one's walked out to me and been like, I play that game, too, which is probably
a social interaction that doesn't happen very often.
But one day it will be awesome.
I really love it was I was I was wearing.
I was wearing a shirt that just had like a little Protoss insignia on the side of it.
Just just like just the Protoss like logo on the on the on the right left shoulder here.
And I was at a grocery.
This is like a decade ago.
I was at a grocery store and someone else's is is there and they've got like a similar
style shirt, but it's like a Zerg logo.
And it's just like a we didn't say anything to each other.
It was just a moment of like we both noticed it at the same time and notice each other noticing
it and have like a little like type moment, which is which is fun.
I like that a lot.
And Fernal 246, thank you very much for the sub.
I am also super pumped for season two.
Kind of unreasonably pumped.
Is that a thing?
Maybe it is reasonable.
Very.
All right.
More questions.
No question today.
Oh, no, that's OK.
We'll read the comment.
That's fine.
Just want to talk to you about controller.
Just want you to talk about controller for 30 seconds.
Sure.
We can talk about controllers for 30 seconds.
What's it?
I want to put our weapon in, but I don't want to lose it.
Stargoon TV!
Thank you very much for the sub.
I appreciate it.
Oh, we gotta put something good in here.
What are we putting here?
I want to put our weapon in, but I don't want to lose it.
Do we have another tooth?
We have no other teeth.
The weapon that everyone wants
Voidcleave to work with.
Hey, an OG gambler's fallacy.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Sure.
What can we talk about controllers for a minute?
I mean, the big thing with controllers, I feel like I'm just rambling and repeating myself with controllers.
The new targeting system for it is really great.
I was actually playtesting last night for an unrelated bug, but I was just like, I'm just like, I'm going to test on controller because I feel like it tonight.
And I really don't play controller very often, but it feels a lot better to the point that I'm kind of like considering doing it more.
Because it's finally able to, I don't know.
It feels a lot better that the having a target smartly is so great.
The context and specialization specific targeting is so much nicer.
Just the, like, it doesn't always shoot.
I was testing a boss fight and having it, and I was shooting fireball.
And as you're running around the outside of the boss, like running the perimeter, like dodging an attack and pressing fireball.
And it shoots at the boss instead of shooting forward, just like, just out of your face was so nice.
Yeah, like, this is an example of the things we were doing.
So, like, an example of things we were fixing at the last second that we did with the extra two weeks, the question earlier, just to add on to it.
So, like, there's a bug where the new bosses, some of the new bosses that are available as Woven Echoes.
If a player joined midway through that boss fight, the animations for the boss fight never started.
So, you couldn't, you couldn't see the boss properly.
It would, like, function, but you couldn't see the boss doing its attacks.
And so, we had to fix that.
It was only for the second person who joined, not the first person who joined at the start.
And he, like, created it.
So, it was, like, obscure things that you don't, uh, you don't really find right away.
That's the sort of stuff.
Alright.
Hello!
Guilds with maybe guild locked trading slash gifting is something that you guys have thought of?
Uh, party is cool, but guilds are better.
Yes, we thought of that.
We aren't going to...
One of the options we considered when we were designing the, uh, the conditional trade system in the first place,
when we went with the bazaar, one of the options we considered was having, uh, something we were calling warbands.
Um, which were, like, basically, like, mini trade groups, like, trade guilds, uh, that people could be in.
Um, we're not, we didn't go with that, and we're not planning on doing that.
Uh, if we do, we are interested in a guild system, um, but it won't, it'll have the same restrictions for, uh, when we eventually get around to doing it,
it'll have the same restrictions for trade as with anyone else.
There won't be, like, uh, we're not planning to have a way where you get to trade easier inside your guild.
Um, you can be able to connect with each other easier that way, but, um, you'll still require the same amount of favor,
and still have the same merchant skilled ranks, um, and all that sort of stuff.
Alright.
What are your thoughts on bringing finishers to the game, like, on death, like an on death huge hammer that slams into the enemy, onto the enemy?
Like an, like an on death?
Like,
like,
like, like, like we're talking like Mortal Kombat fatalities type thing,
um,
where it's like,
they're already dead,
and there's just like a cool animation that happens to like, really sell it,
or,
I mean, I could see that being really awesome for boss fights,
where like, when the boss fight finishes,
and there's like an epic coup de grace that happens that like, finishes the,
the,
the actual fight as,
as a,
like a,
almost like a in-game mini cinematic or something like that,
that I think would be awesome.
Um,
whenever I see on death,
I always seem like,
like when the thing dies,
it uses the ability,
and then that thing that everyone asks,
like just hates.
Um,
not planning that.
All right,
I think I asked too early,
but when is hype week?
Normally it ends when the patch,
with the patch notes,
the update,
but the patch notes are six days before the update,
so it's hype week leading up to the 11th,
or the 11th,
17th,
and end with the update.
Um,
I don't know.
patch note,
usually it ends with patch notes,
so I assume it would end with the,
the like,
the posts going out would end,
like the,
hmm,
I don't know,
it's a good question.
Cain,
if you know the answer to when hype week is scheduled,
please let me know,
because I don't know.
All right.
Mike,
did you hear that EHE has been rumored working on,
a character sheet rework,
this is your reminder.
I can no longer confirm,
or,
yes,
we are working on that.
Um,
if they will not arrive in season two,
I apologize.
I got,
I got a little note here that says hype week,
sooner than you think.
Exciting.
Uh,
any new unique idols?
Ooh,
yeah.
Um,
oh,
no,
we didn't make it into season two.
Uh,
maybe for season two.
the sweet one plan for season three,
I'll tell you that much.
All right.
Will the skill MTX also affect how the skill looks in the skills bar?
I forgot how it was killed.
No,
it doesn't affect the,
the skill bar icon.
Um,
that is something that we are interested in doing though.
Having the,
having some sort of indication on the skill itself,
if it's been converted.
So there's,
there's a couple options that we're considering there.
One is making like thematically,
uh,
flipped versions of this skill.
So like having like a summon,
thorn totem,
but there's like a cold theme,
summon,
thorn totem icon.
And when you,
when you specialize it,
it like switches the icon out.
Um,
the second option is just putting this icon in the corner to be like,
it's specialized to cold and boom,
there's a cold icon there.
Um,
we've been,
I know that's not MTX specifically,
the cosmetics,
that's the like functionality version of it.
Um,
it's possible.
The cosmetic one could come with the same thing.
If we did the full icon swap,
it's a,
it's like just an extra thing.
That's something you like.
It's kind of,
it's a tech debt thing.
So every time you,
when you add a system like that,
it makes the process of adding in,
uh,
conversions or new cosmetics take a little bit longer.
It's a very low cost tech debt,
but it is like,
that's,
that's exactly the sort of thing that you kind of try and avoid in a lot of
situations.
Um,
but I think it's something that we are probably going to do eventually.
Just,
there's a lot of icons to redo or,
uh,
I have all our alt art versions of for that.
Cause like there's some skills that have like three or maybe even four
elemental versions sometimes.
I guess,
I guess one of the big things is delve a little bit deeper.
One of the big things is we want the abilities to be really recognizable on
your bar.
When someone's like,
okay,
what ability is that?
Or like you open up,
uh,
like a,
a,
a build tool type thing.
And it,
it shows specific abilities on there.
You want to be able to recognize what that is quickly.
And having that quick recognition is really important.
Um,
and color has a lot to do with that.
All right.
Are you planning to add a system that we can invade other players,
model it as a PVP aspect.
So like,
um,
like,
uh,
from soft PVP style.
Um,
not something that we're currently planning.
Uh,
I don't hate the idea though.
I think it's like,
it gives me real D2 vibes where,
you know,
like you can just be playing in a public game and someone shows up and
hostiles you.
And you're like,
Oh,
um,
and cause everyone just like auto parties at the start.
They,
they know where you are and you're like,
Oh God,
they could be around any corner.
And,
and like some of the most fun I've had in D2 came from moments like
that.
Um,
I think it would need to be,
I think it worked in the age that Diablo two was released in
initially.
Um,
and I don't think it would go over quite as well.
Uh,
being so,
uh,
like such like a wild west type thing.
Um,
if we,
if we didn't allow people to opt out of it,
I think that's the big thing.
Yes.
But have to be able to opt out of it.
I w yeah,
that was,
that was one of the things I had,
uh,
now I'm not going to show that story.
All right.
Uh,
last Epoch is,
is,
at last Epoch,
is one of the woven echoes,
a boss rush type?
Yes.
I,
it's,
it's not like,
like every monolith boss or something like that altogether,
but there are,
um,
there are boss echoes where it's specifically like a,
a,
a boss format.
Um,
and like there are some,
there's,
there's somewhere it's like a whole bunch of mini bosses,
uh,
like a whole bunch of them.
Uh,
yeah.
Here's,
here's,
here's a good one.
Here we go.
It's a good time for this.
Okay.
This is a little peek at the,
um,
at the weaver tree.
Here's a full picture of all of the nodes in the weaver tree that is coming.
So you want to know the size.
Um,
here it is.
It's decently large.
It is,
uh,
yeah,
you can,
you can zoom in pretty far.
You can pan around.
Um,
yeah.
You got an ad ready.
It's happening.
Okay.
I'll wait.
I'll wait for your ad to finish.
I didn't,
I don't know how to run ads or stop them running.
They just kind of happen.
Well,
we'll,
we'll wait a bit.
We'll leave it,
we'll leave it up for a second.
I'll answer another question.
So not just,
I just noticed someone asked you start in the center.
Yes,
you start in the center.
Um,
and then you branch out from there.
Uh,
the,
I'm pretty sure everything's only a one point requirement to move on.
Um,
but there are multi-point nodes.
So you can,
um,
uh,
yeah.
So you,
you can like get,
you can,
you can traverse it pretty quickly.
Um,
yeah.
And this is the sort of thing that will like,
as,
as the seasons go on,
this is designed very much to be,
um,
expanded upon.
So we can add in like really easily.
If we add like a new type of activity to happen at end game,
we can expand this tree and add new things into it.
Or,
you know,
like modify nodes to be like,
okay,
well this works in,
uh,
echoes type a,
B and C.
And then we add new echo type D E and F.
And then we just add D enough to that node.
And so it works in multiple places.
So we can,
we can expand individual nodes and expand the number of nodes on this.
We can add new point max,
like point maximums.
If we add too many new nodes,
we'll be like,
here's more points.
Um,
maybe there's certain nodes that like,
this is something that we'll be rebalancing and,
uh,
and keeping an eye on going forward.
Cause it's going to be a prime part of our end game for a long time.
Yeah.
All right.
Any chance of a corruption leaderboard being in the books?
We are looking at new leaderboard types.
Um,
and that is one of the most highly requested ones.
I don't have an ETA on it.
I'm sorry.
All right.
How much graphically can you guys improve the game more on this version of unity?
I don't know.
I don't,
um,
I mean,
there's,
there's always room without changing the engine to improve the graphic quality.
Um,
but I don't,
I also don't think we're like stuck on this version of unity forever.
I think since doing the last update,
it'll be a lot easier to do more updates.
Um,
I have no idea if we're going to do more anytime soon or not.
Cause this was,
it was a pretty big deal to do the one we did.
Um,
but I hope so.
I hope,
I hope we keep updating the version of the engine version,
both from a,
like what we can do in a tooling perspective as well.
It's actually like working in,
it gets nicer as well.
It was really good.
Do I have an approximate size,
uh,
for the download for season two?
No,
I don't.
I'm,
I'm assuming it'll be several gigabytes.
It's about as vague as I could say that.
I just don't,
I just don't know.
If you're,
if you've got a good internet connection and you're,
uh,
and like steam will pull it down so fast,
but I know for some people it takes,
it takes a long time,
uh,
to get that downloaded.
And therefore is a significant concern.
Uh,
are there any changes coming to the normal,
and endless arena?
Yes.
Um,
mostly just like quality of life stuff.
There's not huge mechanical changes happening for the arenas.
Um,
there's more stuff that's going to be happening in there.
Some more mechanics that'll exist in there.
Uh,
it's sped up a little bit to like smooth things out.
Um,
it just,
it plays a little better.
It feels a little better.
There it's,
it's just a little more fun and sort of lots of touches.
There's not,
um,
a massive overhaul that's happening.
One big change that we did do,
um,
in,
it just in the UI.
So this,
you can see this as Docklands arena.
So you can see that this says arena.
There's also different types of arenas now too.
Um,
in,
in the,
uh,
monolith,
there's different types of arenas.
And so this says arena.
So you can tell that it's an arena,
but like,
so few,
so few people actually read the name.
They just like look at the stuff and then right click on it.
And when you right click,
you don't get the name populating here.
Cause the name doesn't populate on the right information panel.
Um,
so now the icons in the,
uh,
monolith for arenas look like an arena.
So you can see at a glance,
which ones are the arenas without needing to use the search function.
Um,
which there's,
there's new,
this is getting updated to this.
It's getting moved over to the right and it's getting new filters added to it as well.
Uh,
which percentage of skills,
all classes have had their numbers balanced buffs and nurse in,
in any way at all,
like one node having 1% change counts for this question.
90%.
Maybe,
maybe,
maybe 90 plus percent.
It's like in some way,
like just any change at all.
A lot.
I don't really know the number.
Cause it's,
yeah,
a lot.
It's,
it's very rare that a skill receives no changes at all.
And sometimes they're like,
they're just incidental changes,
but you know,
there's,
there's stuff to be affected all over the place.
Uh,
will there ever be an option to inspect in other players gear in the game,
like in towns or in your party?
Possibly.
This is something that we've,
um,
we've,
we've definitely considered applying before.
Um,
we came very close to introducing it a while ago.
Remember when we held back on it.
Maybe there may have just been like a,
something that was stopping us from doing it.
The data is,
the data is not synced.
So like that information doesn't exist on the player client right now.
So the,
like,
this isn't like,
if you could like hack the game and like look inside the data that's
floating around inside your client,
um,
that information is just not there.
When,
when another player joins your game,
the information that gets synced over is the visuals.
So it just says like you,
like,
Oh,
this person's wearing MTX.
Okay.
That MTX is what gets sent over.
And we just,
we just know they're wearing that MTX and we have no idea what's
underneath it at all from like,
if,
if I was playing with someone else,
my clock,
my game client wouldn't know what they're wearing,
what gear they're wearing.
It would just know what it looks like.
Um,
and if it's got a cosmetic over top of it,
it doesn't even know the base type at all.
Um,
so,
you know,
it's,
it's one of those things like it's more information to sync.
It's,
that's a performance cost.
Um,
it's not that much information.
It's not that much of a performance cost really.
Um,
but it's all stuff we've got to consider.
More questions.
Keep them coming.
Loving them.
All right.
Will there ever be cold conversion option for someone bear?
Ah,
a polar bear skin would be amazing.
So there is a white bear you can get with Kermode's cage,
uh,
as a,
as a armor piece that does change it to look like a polar bear.
Um,
but it's different.
It's not actually a polar bear.
It's like a,
it's a different species.
Anyways,
it doesn't,
it doesn't matter.
Um,
Oh,
yep.
Um,
I'm getting reminded that they're asking about summon bear and not where bear,
because I know this game.
Well,
thanks gain.
Um,
I,
I think there's a decent chance that we'll have a,
uh,
MTX for a polar bear,
not a functional cold alternative.
Um,
but it's possible.
The,
the,
the cold theming and saber tooth is very strong.
Um,
I would,
I would say more likely for a visuals and,
but possible for a functional as well.
Not in season two.
Sorry.
Uh,
right.
Have you seen any feedback?
Probably.
Regarding melee versus range in Ellie from content creators.
Like,
yes,
uh,
Gazi,
dread current.
Uh,
do you guys have any thoughts on feedback that current age?
She plans for balancing melee versus range is not enough.
Like current age,
she plans for balancing.
It's not enough.
I mean,
if they're,
uh,
sharing,
they don't think what we've done from,
the CT program is not enough.
Um,
then they're breaking their NDAs.
I would assume maybe,
maybe not.
They don't understand how that works,
but,
uh,
I,
I have read lots of feedback around specific thoughts people have on the current version of,
of melee versus range.
Um,
there are,
we're,
we're continuing to leverage and leveraging more so than before the ability for,
um,
enemies,
especially specifically bosses.
It's the most important place that it appears in.
It's,
it's definitely less of a big issue.
I think on trash than it is on bosses.
Um,
and it's definitely most prominently a big deal at like hyper end game stuff where you're like min maxing to the top.
And,
uh,
we are,
we are leveraging,
especially with new boss encounters.
Um,
so abilities have,
uh,
every ability in the game in last Epoch has,
several range values associated with it.
I've talked about these range values before,
but there's like,
there's a minimum engage range,
um,
a minimum pursuit range,
uh,
a minimum use range and a minimum,
and a maximum use range as well.
Um,
all right.
Max.
Yep.
Sorry.
A maximum pers.
Oh,
I can't roll in titles that we use,
we use different terms for them on the backend,
but the,
uh,
the point is,
is that there are,
you can set an ability to only function if a player is a minimum distance from the,
uh,
from the minion or enemy or any AI is running their things.
Minions and enemies use the same AI functions.
Um,
and so the,
there's certain abilities that we've put in boss fights,
especially new boss fights where they will only trigger if they're on,
uh,
like on a range character and you're,
you're playing at range.
And so there's certain things that was like trigger more often,
or if it's like,
maybe it's an ability that uses that has like a windup to use.
And if you're standing really far away,
maybe that windup,
it'll use a different version of it.
So if you're like,
let's,
let's pray my minions,
keep me alive.
And if you are like within this ring of the enemy,
let's use this enemy.
Let's bring side of this as the example.
So this is your,
this is your enemy and you're within this ring.
The ability that it uses,
it has like a one second charge up time before it slams in a,
in a space where it's like going to target a target to you with a slam and you have a second to move.
But if you're outside of that ring,
like if you're,
if you're out,
if you're out here and it targets you and it targets a box,
it only gives you half a second to move or something like that.
So you,
it makes it harder to dodge when you're farther away.
Um,
and we'll do,
we'll do things like that more than we're doing it now.
So sometimes it's in the enemy behavior that we're changing that to,
uh,
to make being in melee a little bit functionally easier,
a little bit mechanically easier,
or more so that we're making being at range a little bit more mechanically difficult.
All right.
From your perspective,
what are the top three to five gameplay improvements from season one to season two?
Ah,
oof.
Gameplay.
Um,
the weaver's tree.
Number one.
Um,
controllers,
controller functionality,
just in general,
how you,
how you control,
I'll put movement controls in one thing.
So controller and was the options.
Um,
biggest things.
I'm kind of,
I'm,
I'm batching too broad of stuff together.
I think,
uh,
the,
can't say that one.
Uh,
what can I say?
Can I say?
There's,
there's just like two that we haven't like really talked about yet that I want to say,
but I can't.
Um,
and then I just get fixated on those in my brain and I can't think of other things.
probably the improvements to,
uh,
I,
I think it's the improvements to some of the faction stuff.
I think that'd be the next big thing.
But like individual skill things is,
is probably the main thing,
like specific skills that had functionality issues or new conversions that need,
that got added in.
Um,
just like better targeting in general.
Health.
Lovely.
Right.
It's not over.
I want my stuff when you get back.
Uh,
right.
As a casual player data too,
I tend to play COF.
What improvements have I made to make a viable versus SSF?
Uh,
um,
what improvements have been made to make this viable versus SSF?
Well,
you,
you can play COF as SSF.
So I think,
uh,
it was meant to be versus merchant skill possibly.
Um,
merchant skill is,
I mean,
unless we,
unless we take COF and we're like,
all right,
gear rains from the sky and you can just like pick your gear from a dropdown menu.
Like it's merchant skill is almost always going to be,
I think inherently stronger.
And I don't think there's a way we can make COF feel good to play and have it be,
uh,
directly competing power wise with merchant skill to the same degree.
We can get close.
We can get very close,
I think.
And we are,
um,
we are working to improve that to get it closer.
Um,
and I think the big thing is,
um,
the,
we're,
we're relieving some of the pressure on lenses.
Um,
because there's a few lenses people just like,
well,
we,
you have to play with this lens or else it just sucks.
And so we're like,
okay,
well,
if it just sucks to not play with that lens,
we're just going to make that lens exist all the time.
Um,
and so we're,
we're relieving some pressure with lenses.
I think that's going to be the biggest thing.
Um,
also just tweaking some numbers,
just like making things cost a little bit less favor,
uh,
making them drop a few better things.
Um,
and then the way that those interact with the weaver's tree stuff and the new crafting options is going to be a big, big thing as well.
I see.
Well,
we have some kind of socketing mechanism mechanics,
not runeword,
more like some kind of power customization.
Also,
I heard about idol crafting.
Yeah.
So the socketing is a tricky thing.
It's one of the things that we've,
we've,
we love socketings,
the,
the theming and the feel and the vibe behind socketing.
Like it's fantastic.
I was not,
I haven't coughed in like two days and like stream started.
I'm like,
all right,
time to start coughing.
All right.
Our crafting system,
like here's an empty socket.
I'm gonna put something in that socket.
I probably should have put something better next.
It's actually kind of decent boost to start with.
Oh,
well,
um,
we've considered socketing in a few different ways.
And I actually regret putting that in.
Oh God.
No.
All right.
Vitality,
leave it.
Um,
let's try and seal something.
Let's seal,
let's,
let's try and seal the vitality.
All right,
good.
Great.
Oh,
we ran out of 40 potential.
That's fine.
Um,
my point is that this,
the,
the socketing,
um,
our current crafting system is very similar to the socketing as a system.
Um,
and it's tricky to kind of separate the two and,
and,
and have them work,
side by side,
side by side.
Um,
I think there's room for a socketing system in the future.
I think it would be kind of its own system.
And the things that would fit in there would be unique to that system.
So it would,
um,
I,
I don't,
I don't know what sort of things,
but they would be,
I think the things that would go in a socket system would need to be,
uh,
distinct from the affix system.
So it would have to be like,
I don't know.
Okay.
Here's kind of the style of thing.
We're not,
obviously not doing this,
but similar to how,
um,
Peewee one puts the skill gems as sockets into the gear where those are separate from the
affixes themselves for the most part.
And I,
I think that that would be the style of thing that we'd be more interested in putting in a
socketing system than,
uh,
more of a classic,
like a Ruby gives you fire damage type socketing system.
Also,
I heard about idle crafting.
Yes.
Um,
there is a,
one of the rewards for one of the woven echoes.
Uh,
nope.
One of the rewards for,
one of the rewards,
the new content,
uh,
gives you,
or gives you the ability to select,
uh,
enchantments from,
a fixed list for,
uh,
for new,
for new affixes that can be added to idols.
Uh,
they can only be added to set,
or not set,
um,
class specific idols.
Um,
so the,
the three,
uh,
three and four size idols.
And,
um,
so that,
that is re-rollable as well.
So you can just keep going until you get the one you want.
Uh,
but it does cost a memory amber to re-roll more than it would,
uh,
for just the first one.
Um,
we haven't really released a list of what those are going to be yet,
but they're pretty great.
All right.
Hi,
a small question.
Will there be more stuff with portals of the past and future?
Because I like the concept of that.
Yeah.
Um,
there's,
I think it's more of that coming in future,
uh,
future seasons for the most part,
like actually,
uh,
time traveling inside of a zone.
There is a nod to our very first instance of that.
We ever did something like that in,
in season two though.
Uh,
but so back in our Kickstarter,
uh,
the very first time the player time travels,
there was a specific event and there's a reference to that in the new,
in the new season.
So if anyone played the original,
uh,
you'll see it there.
Uh,
will there be new character models to choose from?
In the character creation of season two?
No character models are the same as they were in season one.
Um,
I think there's,
there's a,
there's a few,
uh,
a few tweaks on some of them,
but like 99% the same.
That is still something we're interested in doing though.
Uh,
have you guys ever considered a D2 style rune word crafting,
uh,
to the crafting system?
Uh,
or do you feel the system suffice as it is?
We,
we,
we've considered D2 rune word crafting since day one.
Absolutely.
Um,
I,
D2 is,
is like for several of us,
possibly our most played game ever.
Uh,
I think for me,
it might be,
it's like,
it's a toss up if,
yeah,
it's probably,
it's probably that one,
but you do it's probably my most played game ever.
Um,
so yeah,
everything I do,
I'm like,
is this too much like D2?
Thank you very much.
Uh,
real Ranger K for the five gifted subs.
I appreciate that.
So I hope everyone that,
uh,
got one of those appreciates it too.
Congrats.
Um,
uh,
D2 rune words.
We've,
there's a couple systems we've like put in,
uh,
trying to evoke the feeling of a D2 rune word system.
Um,
and the legendary crafting system is one of those things that we've,
we've kind of tried to pull in some of the vibes and feels from that style of system.
Um,
and the,
the,
the big thing there is that like,
so with the D2 crafting system,
with the D2,
um,
uh,
rune word system,
you're,
you're collecting,
uh,
several disparate pieces of very rare things and you put them all together and you get something awesome.
Um,
and,
and that's kind of the vibe we're going for with the legendary craft.
So you get your,
um,
your like rare exalted item,
you get your rare,
um,
unique item and you slot them together and you make something awesome.
Um,
and I know it's a very,
very like tenuous connection at best.
Um,
but that's like,
that was definitely forefront of thought when we were making legendary system.
Um,
and there's some,
I think there's some important distinctions between the season one legendary system and season two legendary system slash rune word system.
Um,
and we're going to be really excited to talk about those differences in,
uh,
on talking to tries podcast coming up in four days.
28.
Yeah.
Four days.
Um,
so if you want to hear about those tune into that,
because we're talking itemization then very excited to talk about that.
I won't be there for that,
but,
uh,
you'll have carve a Judd and Ross there and they are going to crush it.
Uh,
do you think if there is any possibility to have competitive elements in last epoch or RPG in general on an e-sports level,
if he has any insights on how this could look like,
do you plan to do this?
E-sports are,
hmm,
I don't know of any e-sport level stuff that's not PVP.
Like,
all the e-sports that like come to mind when I think of like a,
the,
like the really popular e-sports,
they're all PVP.
Um,
so I think,
I think you'd kind of have to have a PVP system for it.
And I think,
um,
all the big e-sport games that I think of quickly are,
like,
games that are like,
they,
they may have a campaign mode in the game,
but like,
it's,
it's a PVP game with,
with,
with a campaign.
But it's a PVP game.
You know,
that sort of thing.
And so I,
I think that there's,
um,
I,
I think because we've built the game in so many of the systems from,
uh,
the ground up as a,
like,
not as an e-sport to begin with,
and not as specifically a PVP game with a campaign,
um,
or with an,
with a,
like an end game style system.
I think it's hard to make,
I think it's really hard to make that transition into an e-sport space.
Um,
like you almost have to like split the client and be like,
here's the PVP client and here's the PVE client type of thing.
Um,
I do have some thoughts on,
on different methods you could do there though.
And I would love to,
to try some PVP elements.
Um,
yeah.
Cause,
cause like,
I think it's really easy to look at,
uh,
at last epoch and other RPGs.
And then look at like games like league of legends and Dota and,
and other MOBAs and be like,
you know,
um,
but it's,
I don't think it's quite that straightforward.
Yeah.
Uh,
when is shatter on freeze going to come?
I think that's a season three thing.
Uh,
I know the emphasis is on season two,
but new classes or masters for season three,
maybe I'm,
I'm really,
I don't want to talk about season three's potential stuff.
Um,
mostly cause I don't know much of it.
Cause we haven't decided on much of it.
We're really focused on season two.
There's like some key elements we know are coming for season,
season three and stuff like that.
And there's like a few,
a few projects that are spun up,
but like we're really focusing on season two stuff right now.
Love the game.
Thank you.
Me too.
Uh,
but awesome often feels like the sound effects are either a little hollow.
Are there any changes planned to increase the base or screen shake on large
impacts?
Um,
what we do like,
I don't know.
It's possible that you may not have this,
the,
the screen shake settings cranked up.
If you want more of those,
there is more of that.
Um,
so there's like heavy abilities only and most abilities.
and the screen shake intensity,
you can crank that up pretty high.
Like we,
we can,
I,
uh,
that's,
that's a lot of screen shake.
Um,
we do have,
there's like,
there's always a ton of sound effects updates coming.
Yes.
There's lots of sound effects.
It's coming.
I think now's a good time.
Um,
let's,
I'm sorry.
It took me so long.
Here's,
here's,
here's a good little,
little fun,
little teaser.
So,
uh,
there was a,
a joke post that went out on April fool's day.
Um,
and I'm very pleased to be able to actually confirm one little piece of that as
something that is happening.
We are getting an actual Capybara pet in the game.
That was not a joke.
It is real.
It's coming.
Yeah.
All the posts of like,
ah,
you got to like add it in quickly.
I'm like,
it's already added.
All right.
Uh,
you were talking about sound effects on skills.
any plans to tune down amount of time?
A tune says,
I cannot do that yet.
Is the audio playing for it?
Uh,
it is like,
that's great.
Okay.
We're going to,
we're going to take that down.
Uh,
all right.
love loot lizards.
I understand you are reducing their frequency.
Is it going to be to boost them in the new web?
Yes,
there are several ways to boost them in the new web,
actually.
Oh,
oh heck we're doing,
we're doing back to backs.
He didn't even warn me.
This was coming.
I didn't even,
I didn't even look ahead for it,
but we're doing back to backs.
Here we go.
Uh,
so yes,
there are ways in the weaver's tree in order to boost the number of
loot lizards you will find.
Um,
and,
uh,
they,
they do.
So yes,
while we are reducing the,
um,
the quantity of loot lizards that appear,
and we are also reducing the quantity of items that loot lizards drop at
base.
We are increasing the quality of items that they drop.
So they,
they still drop a lot of stuff and it's still really awesome.
Um,
but it's a little less like,
oh my God,
the screen is full,
uh,
situations.
It can still happen if you get like propagating,
uh,
like when there's a chance when,
when you,
um,
defeat one of them and,
uh,
two more spawn or three more spawn.
And so like that can still happen.
So you can get situations where a lot happens,
uh,
but it's a little less intense than it was before.
All right.
Uh,
so Sentinel's getting a rework.
Is shaman and all the other masters missing their fifth skill going to get
their fifth skill at all?
Um,
yeah.
So we're not,
uh,
yes.
The short answer is,
is yeah,
we're still,
we're still getting skills for other classes.
Um,
hang on.
It's,
it's marksman.
Oh no,
it's marksman's getting it.
It's,
uh,
it's blade dancer,
shaman,
paladin,
and lich.
I think it's those four.
Um,
and we've got,
and then,
uh,
and then also base rogue is missing too,
I think.
Um,
and so we've got some plans for some abilities to go into those spots.
I don't want to,
uh,
spoil which ones are gonna be happening first,
but we are,
uh,
we are working on new abilities to fit into some of those.
Those slots.
And,
uh,
they are gonna be cool.
Primeless can use bows when,
oh,
when my dreams come true.
I don't,
I don't have a,
I don't have a fixed time for that.
I'm sorry.
I really,
I really wish I could say like tomorrow.
Cause that's something I want so bad,
but no,
I don't know.
Uh,
what about dismemberment enemies melt on death,
uh,
when they are poisoned arrows stick to enemies.
Yeah.
Like,
like just more gruesome death effects that are more specific to the situation that they're in.
Um,
that's,
that's all stuff we're working on.
Um,
I don't have any details or specifics on what's actually going to be possible or what's coming,
but that style of stuff is stuff we're working on.
Uh,
right.
How many more acts,
how many acts more when,
how many acts more,
when are we going to see them just for sense of game is finished?
Okay.
So,
um,
just to get a sense of how close we are to finishing the game,
how many more acts are we going to get?
I think is what this question is asking.
Um,
we're going to get three more chapters in the game.
to,
to round out the,
the total chapters in the game.
Uh,
could you share roughly the quantity of new uniques coming season two?
Are we talking 10,
20,
30?
I don't know.
Um,
and even if I did,
I'm not sure I'm allowed to say,
I'll say a,
uh,
sizable chunk in our,
in our listing system,
in our backend listing system is,
is a few pages.
Uh,
how big's a page?
I'll never tell.
All right.
Are there any,
any plans for more events similar to,
uh,
Imperial uprising from last year on a more regular basis?
Um,
I think,
I think we're a little hesitant to,
to do too many more of those.
Um,
it's definitely possible,
but it's not something that I would,
uh,
expect very soon.
Like,
granted,
it was just the first one we'd ever done.
And the,
the,
um,
the response wasn't as,
uh,
like significantly,
like,
like just strictly looking at,
uh,
a numbers perspective of like player counts.
Like you can go,
go look at steam tracks and look at when it came out.
And,
um,
like,
it didn't seem like it resonated to,
to,
uh,
highly.
From that.
I don't actually know the numbers were on like our backend numbers,
but if I'm looking at it from that perspective,
that's where I'm seeing the things.
All right.
Have you thought of a very rare rune that returns stability?
Yes.
Many times.
This gets suggested frequently.
Uh,
it is something we have debated heavily.
It is something that we have very conclusively decided that we are not
interested in doing at this time.
Uh,
perhaps a question a team won't like much.
I love all questions.
That's not true.
I love most questions.
Um,
what has been done about performance from 1.1 to 1.2?
A ton of stuff.
Uh,
it's been the same unreliable experience for all my friends,
really unstable FPS and mono as well.
I will say that,
um,
the vast majority of players that we've heard feedback from the frame rates in
general and stability in general and performance has improved very
significantly.
Um,
over the course of the time we've,
we've had this up and,
um,
like I am not running this on a super powerful computer.
I'm running it on fairly high specs,
uh,
the game while streaming it.
And this is not,
uh,
this is,
this is not a crazy computer that I'm running this on at all.
This is a,
I don't know if I can bring this up without showing some extra info that I
don't want to show,
but like,
this is a,
like an I seven,
uh,
12 something,
12,
700 K or something.
Uh,
and like,
I think I'm running,
it's a 40,
60.
I think it's a 40,
Um,
no,
it's a 30,
60.
It's not even a 40,
It's a 30,
60.
Yeah.
Like this,
this is,
this is not a,
I'm going to bring this up here.
30,
60 TI.
Um,
and like,
we are butter smooth here.
I don't know.
I,
I never noticed issues like that.
And so I don't,
um,
I think from,
from,
like,
anecdotal answers of like,
Hey,
it works really well for me.
Aren't useful.
And so I'm not trying to suggest that,
but I'm just trying to suggest that it's,
um,
we are working very heavily.
Performance is one of the most important things for us.
Uh,
multiplayer performance,
server stability,
uh,
game integrity,
just like FPS in general.
Like those,
these,
these are the main things when we're,
when we're deciding like what's the most important stuff to work on,
where are we going to put the people who are really,
uh,
tackling the tough issues going to go like that.
That's where,
that's where it all happens.
So it's extremely,
extremely important.
Um,
and I guess what I'm just trying to say is that I think we've really
improved a lot in that category over the last few years.
Um,
and it's just going to get better and better and better.
Uh,
every chance we get to,
to reclaim some frames wherever we can,
we take them.
get him out of the corner.
Um,
it might be okay.
Alright, will we ever have the final slam craft like Orb of Corruption in PoE?
Yeah, that's the sort of thing we have looked at a few times.
I mean, creating a legendary kind of is that, right?
Can we sustain through this?
Yes!
With Berserk going, we definitely can!
Go Berserk, go!
God's emperors are nothing possible!
Got him!
Am I free?
Sure.
But yeah, sorry, I had to focus there a little bit to actually do that.
As far as an extra slam craft thing like that, like a universal object that can be slammed into anything,
you've run out of forging potential and you're like, one more try.
Boom, does something random and wild.
Yeah, that's something that we are considering as an option, not season two.
Will champion affixes be applied to items randomly or with some class restriction?
I ask because the tease video, Rogue Helmet appeared to have a champion affix of plus one for companions, for example.
Yeah, that was, there were some conflicting things in the video that will not be conflicting when the game launches.
So yeah, if it doesn't make sense in that video, it won't be there in the end.
We fixed all those.
Will stash tabs ever be able to carry over between seasons like actual stash themselves, not the items?
I think it's unlikely.
I think it's possible that we could carry over the layouts and you still have to buy new ones, but they'd auto-pocket the layouts.
That's what I really wanted to do. That would be my goal for the next thing for stashes is to be able to move the layouts over.
So that when you like, you start the next one up and you're like, okay, buy a new tab.
And it just auto goes and says, okay, I know this tab was going to be the, my set item tab or whatever.
And you've already got the labels there or have them be there, but have them be non-functional until you buy them.
So like the tabs exist, but they're like a phantom mode.
And then you're like, okay, well, I need my unique tabs.
You buy your unique tab and it like it's already in place and everything like that.
But you can't use it until you buy that specific tab.
That might, that would probably be the best way to do it.
I hadn't even considered that until right now.
How do you feel about the stability of the market in season two?
I think it's going to be a lot better.
It's gonna be a lot better.
I think we're going to see less inflation.
Yeah, because of reasons.
I'm definitely allowed to say right now, but I'm just choosing.
No, I'm not allowed to say.
I'm sorry.
Anyway, any chance we will see prophecies give more than just one LP items getting the occasional two or three rare LP prophecy would be fantastic.
I'm not sure if we've changed this, but I will say that there are new things that will make getting one LP rewards feel a lot better.
And tune in to talk to tries podcast on the eighth to find out more information about that in four days.
Any chance you will officially support Linux at some point?
We do officially support Linux.
And I realize as I'm saying that there's probably a technicality that I don't understand that means we don't actually officially support Linux question mark.
But I'm pretty sure we have a Linux client.
Question mark.
Oh, we don't.
Okay.
Oh, sorry.
I forgot.
Thank you.
I forgot we switched to the proton only version.
I have no idea if it's coming back.
We used to have, we used to have a Linux specific client, right?
I forgot we switched over to proton.
Uh, I think that was done because we were just getting so much better performance out of the proton version on Linux.
But, um...
I'm not sure.
If there's a really good reason to, I'd say it's a reasonable thing to ask for.
Um...
Like if we can get better performance out of it, that's, I'd be looking forward to that.
We got more subs!
Lone Star McFluffin has come with a rating party.
Welcome.
Oh, I missed a sub a while ago.
7.04.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate you.
Appreciate you subbing.
Welcome everyone from Lone Star Stream.
I was gonna, I was gonna raid you after this.
That was my plan.
I saw you streaming.
I was gonna, I was gonna raid you.
But I guess you're done.
I'm sorry.
Um...
Any information on API webhook integrations for developers?
I really can't wait to get a hold of that stuff.
Um, I don't have any updates for you.
I think there's, there's sort of a couple things that people are really hoping for.
Like, oh, I can't wait to get my hands on the API to do this.
And I'm like, the API doesn't do that.
Um, so just to be clear, the API that we do have, that is, is currently in like an early access
state for people to test out for us.
Um, there's, there's no like item information.
So you can't be like, hey API, tell me all of the tiers of values for all the tiers of
intelligence that can go on items.
It just won't.
That information is just not there.
So like the game data itself doesn't exist on it.
So if you're waiting for it for that, don't hold your breath on that one.
Oh, the new spires.
I can't wait for the new spires.
There's, there's the answer to that question earlier about the new mechanical gameplay stuff
that changes the new spires.
That's my answer.
So much better.
So much more fun.
Oh, and the procedural content generation.
Oh my God.
How did I forget about that?
Do you actually know who the very first person was that downloaded your game?
No, not even sure if you can find that out.
I don't know who it was.
I'm sorry.
We probably could find out who the first person to back us on Kickstarter was, who would be the
first person to like pay for the game that we could probably figure out.
I could probably figure that out on my own.
Oh, that's a lot of messages there.
Oh, yeah.
I'm streaming, bud.
I'm sorry.
I'm not answering you right now.
All right.
I am really far.
I'm an hour behind in questions.
Oh my goodness.
Okay.
Here's what we're doing.
We are.
We're going to put a little teaser out.
It's flashy and I'm going to answer a bunch of questions.
Here is a new cosmetic for Frostclaw.
And we're going to rapid fire some questions here so we can get some of these out of the way.
So we're going to do quick answers only.
Any changes to Nemesis Egg System, like more rare affixes more easily to get not able to find them in
every echo.
No major changes there.
Why do I need to kill Harbinger to get the boss timeline item reward?
Why not get the rewards after each kill?
It needs to so you don't leave halfway through, I guess.
All right.
Is there any private leagues planned for the future?
Vaguely, maybe nothing specific.
For COF, what are your thoughts on increasing the quality of items?
Quality of items, more crafting potential, higher LP chances.
And reducing the quantity to make it easier to manage stash wise.
I mean...
I think this is kind of a like...
Like tighten up the loot filter is the answer.
It's not the great answer there.
There's definitely some...
I think there's more...
Given the new crafting item options available, there's going to be new items that you're going to be
interested in picking up that you're going to want to see.
That you're not going to want us to take away.
But you'll be actually like processing them.
And when they either succeed or fail, you'll be getting rid of them, I think.
Hey again, Mike.
Hello.
Welcome back.
Would it be possible to reveal or speak a bit more about that system you guys hinted at in Reddit for
not having to feel bad when missing LP slams that are very rare to get?
Tune in.
Talk to Tri's podcast on the 8th.
We'll be talking about it there.
All these itemization questions that we're saving for that podcast and it's going to be
juicy ones.
I'm really excited for it.
All right.
Hey, Mike and the team.
Hello.
Is there anything among the leaks that you have prepared for the season two that the
players are kind of overlooking when you thought we'd be super hyped about or anything that we
are fixating too much on?
Well, you thought it wouldn't be too much of a deal.
I think the response has been pretty appropriate, especially the one thing that I would say that
I had said the answer to this question before was the imprinting in the in the weaver tree.
So here's something interesting we can actually see now.
You can see all six of the nodes.
The picture is tiny on my screen.
You can see all six of the nodes that all six of the imprint slots that are there.
So there are six imprint slots that you can see.
That's something that I thought people were kind of sleeping on, but it was so there was no information
on it.
It was kind of like a vaguely what is this?
And so I think I think this is going to be a really big.
It's going to be really cool.
And there's different there's different conditions to be met for different imprinting slots.
So some of them will I don't want to give away what all of them are right now, but there are
there's different ways that the imprinting can trigger and different conditions on what you can
imprint in each of those slots as well.
And you'll notice that some of the different physical sizes that will tell you a little bit about
the type of things can go in those slots more.
All right.
I took a look at the pebble set since you mentioned it, and I think I can make an epic build, but I think
you should add an incentive like maybe featuring a Terra monthly thoughts.
Ah, you want me you want us to tell you we're going to feature the build in a Terra monthly.
I mean, send us the build and we're always we're always looking out for cool builds there.
If you've got a sweet one that is a little out of the box and a little a little wacky,
those those fit in there very nicely.
Uh, hi.
Hello.
What do you think about a player retention for season one?
And what do you think it'll be the same for season two lower better and why I think we'd be much better
because we've got a lot more end game content and a lot.
I think a lot better.
Uh, curve for
uh, fun, a little fun curve.
I don't know how to how to describe that, but I think there's just there's better.
There's there's more steps along the way where you can really
like incentivize specific things.
Yeah.
All right.
When balancing the campaign, do you balance for homebrew builds or is the balance around the net
meta builds?
I think we expect with the campaign, we expect meta builds to push significantly above their
um, their level.
So we, when we're, when we're looking at the campaign balancing, we're like, okay,
if this is a level 10 zone and there's 11 level 10 player here with a homebrew build and a level
five player here with a meta build, um, it's going to make a lot of sense.
And so that's kind of how we look at it.
I think.
Uh, hello, Mike.
Will there be cosmetics offline?
Possibly.
I not in season two though.
Uh, can you explain how the woven echoes items like X snapshot nodes work more specifically when it procs?
Does it always drop items exactly like the snapshot
it showed a note or does it create a subset of base plus affixes and you need to get lucky with a well-rolled item?
Um, yeah, so it
it's got a lot of different.
It's almost, almost never exactly the same.
It is technically possible for it to drop exactly the same, but I, the odds are astronomical.
Um, so it's going to be similar.
So there's, um, sometimes it'll be as simple as just like one affix basically gets chaos.
Or, uh, it might be a simple, it might be like, um, like the base type actually changes or like
basically anything on the item can change.
Um, but it tries to keep them relatively similar.
So you'll see, I think what you'll be wanting to do is you'll be like, okay,
here's an item that's like really close to what I'm looking for, but it's not quite right.
It's like, it's pretty sweet, but like, I want something a little bit better.
And you put that in there and then, um, it, it procs a few times and you're getting items that are really similar and you get one that's just like, that's similar.
And it's got what you want, uh, everything that was good about the old one, but then it's even better in some other way.
And you, so you switch that into the new one that you're, that you're imprinting.
And then it's finding things that are even closer to what you're after.
And you find something that's a little bit better and you imprint that one.
And you just like keep upgrading the imprint a little bit to just keep getting better and better and better and better and better,
better, better stuff in that same category that is really similar to it.
And then you're like, okay, I've got what I'm looking for.
This is like the one that I really wanted.
And you can put something else new in there, maybe.
Or you just get really lucky from a drop somewhere else and you can slap something new in there.
All right.
Uh, can open every note on Weaver Tree or will there be limited points to spend?
There are limited points to spend.
You cannot get every single note.
Uh, what means completed 29 of 50?
Can we get 50 points to spend?
I believe so.
Maybe.
Um.
Let's get this in a spot that I can zoom in.
Look at what you're looking at.
Uh, yes, yes, yes, that's what that is.
All right.
Any plans for being able to pre-download the patch for season two?
No.
Um, Aaron, you know that.
Uh, like this.
Did you guys consider making the woven tree look like a spider's web?
Yes.
Um.
It kind of restricted the layout, I think, a little bit too much.
It made it a little messy behind it.
Uh, can you save one version of the Weaver's Tree and change it later for having two plus versions?
No.
You want to respec it, you can respec it.
Cost Memory Amber to respec.
Uh, around which level or game progression are we expected to interact with Woven Echoes?
Is that as soon as you start finishing, start the first model of timeline or a different point?
You'll find, um,
You'll, you'll, you'll find your first tomb.
Tomb of, you'll find your very first tomb of the race in Fall of the Outcasts.
At level 58 or earlier.
Uh, when you're going through this one, that's when you will find your first tomb.
Uh, and in that tomb, you will very likely collect your first Woven Echo.
Um, item that drops.
Um, and so you'll be able to interact with Woven Echoes in your very first normal
Paul the Outcast monolith.
Um, I'd suggest that you'll likely, and I'm realizing that I was doing that with the
tree up, but I apologize.
Uh, this is what I was showing.
You'll find that in your very first, um,
say that again.
You'll find your very first tomb in Fall of the Outcasts.
On normal at level 58 or earlier.
Uh, and so this is like, this is the, what you'll find it.
It'll be one of these.
It'll just like randomly be, be one of these in your web.
It'll just like populate.
Boom.
There it is.
And given how far I've explored this tree right here, I think you're likely to find
a tomb with this many nodes exposed.
One of like in, in, in season two, like this is how far you'll have to go to find one.
Likely.
I think maybe a little bit farther, maybe, maybe one or two more, but not much.
Like it's, it'll happen pretty quick.
All right.
Um.
Yeah.
So you'll be, I guess the point is you'll be, you'll be integrating into the new systems
very early in end game.
All right.
Is still target farming a good and a thing?
Is, is still target farming.
I'm going to go with yes.
All right.
If I choose to focus on arena in monos, will I still have tombs and cemeteries pop up?
Are they their own echo?
Um, tombs and cemeteries are still their own echoes.
Um, so you'll, you'll need to like go into tombs and cemeteries as an echo.
Are there any plans to remove sounds from items that do not show up in the loot filter?
Uh, I don't think in season two.
Uh, why you guys are streaming Q and A during PoE two league launch.
You know, this is our usual, our usual time slot.
And if I'm, if I'm going to be honest, the reason why I'm streaming today is because I
wanted to show this off.
I was kind of on the fence and, uh, this arrived and I'm like, I'm not going to be on
talking to tries podcast on the eighth.
Uh, and I really wanted to show it off.
So that's why I'm here is to show this off.
This is a wonderful sign.
Uh, this incredible sign that was sent in.
Um, and I, I still can't believe it's huge.
It is so solid.
Uh, it's all like carved out of wood and the, like, there's a light in there.
That's right.
It's like go like if you haven't watched it yet on our, um, uh, our, our, our
channel monthly posts, we've got links to the YouTube channel for, uh, the, like the
making of for this and it's unbelievably incredible.
I just can't, it's, it's just, wow.
That's why, that's why I'm here today.
Uh, I have to leave earlier.
So you may have talked about this.
Uh, I had to leave earlier.
What is your thoughts on arrangement?
The options I did, uh, or mainly options like whips, yo-yos, chain sites, and those kinds
of things became very, very close to putting, uh, something like that in kind of like, um,
uh, like the, the Kratos chain swords, things like that.
Like we, we, we came very close to putting something like that in.
Um, there was a game kingdoms of Amalur reckoning, uh, that had a super fun, uh, weapon type that
I really want to recreate at some point.
That's like, um, that that's like weapons spinning, flailing around so much cool stuff
with that.
Like the, that was the most fun I had playing that game was, was whipping around with
those, um, was it chakrams?
Maybe it was chakrams I'm thinking of in that.
It was a ton of fun.
I really liked it.
Oh, we are, we are stopping taking questions pretty soon here.
Um, we're gonna, we're gonna stop taking questions in five minutes.
So if you've got a question you want to get in, um, you got five minutes to get that
question posted and I'm gonna stop taking questions.
Um,
All right.
Will we see our cosmetics in the character selection screen?
Yes.
Are you planning to add the cold conversion cosmetic for someone wolf skill?
You already have it for here up boss fight summons.
Maybe I would say it's, uh, for as a cosmetic, I would say much more likely than as a mechanical thing.
Uh, at least I can actually play a little bit, can't I?
I'll just sit around talking, yapping.
We're in the arena.
I can just stand still and just attack stuff.
Love it.
All right.
Will you delay the release of Uber Abaroth until the first season killed Abaroth like season one?
No, because there's, um, there's less of a mechanical learn the fight requirement for this.
So like, if you want to learn, if you want to practice Uber Abaroth, you can go do it right now.
Practicing Abaroth will be, um, not one-to-one perfectly.
There are mechanical differences, but, uh, the vast majority of what you want to know,
what you want to learn and what you want to practice will be available for, um, uh,
to try right now, um, on, on Abaroth.
Like it's, it's one of the main reasons we did that was so you couldn't practice the fight
on an existing OP character.
Um, but because it's, it's so similar now anyways, it's, it's kind of less of a,
a need for that.
All right.
With the addition of Wazzy, any chance we can get a sixth skill now that the left mouse will be available?
No.
Uh, will the last Shaman skill be coming in season two or season three?
And will it be Fire Totem?
No information available at all.
I'm sorry.
Uh, will we ever get, oh, here's the, uh, the only answer I can say is it will not be coming in season two.
Um, we have announced all the new skills coming in season two, uh, and it is not one of them.
Uh, will we ever get zombie pets similar like skeletons, but zombies with swords and bows?
Um, I'd say unlikely, but maybe.
I think the theming overlap is not great.
Um, and we do already have a zombie skill that, um,
doesn't really fit mechanically or thematically with it.
Uh, what are you going to season start on?
I'm going to play Heart Seeker to start with because I've worked on it a bunch and I love it.
And Ryxan's my favorite and it's great.
All right.
Even though season two hasn't released yet, are you planning to do seasons more frequently?
Yes.
I'm so excited.
Pick up your set items.
Um,
I was playing the game and I stumbled upon a void squirrel.
Any chance we might be allowed to actually have void squirrels?
Um, maybe at some point, possibly.
Uh, it doesn't fit the theming currently that very well.
So, I mean, maybe.
Uh, will the pickup range increase for items for new season?
Yes, we actually just, that was asking for one of the things we did in the last little bit before the,
the, the delay.
That's something we did actually.
We increased pickup radius for everything.
I think, uh, gold, maybe not potions.
I don't know if we increase the potion pickup radius.
I think that'd be the only thing we left where it was.
Or if we did, we increase it less than the other increases.
But yeah, we increased the pickup radius for, for basically everything.
Uh, there's also now an option in the settings where you can say, don't auto pick up potions.
If you're, uh, or don't like auto heal with potions.
If you are below your, if you're at, sorry, if you're at max potions, um, and are injured.
So you're at max potions and not max health.
Don't pick up a potion and auto use it.
Because right now, if you're, uh, if you're hurt and you're at max potions and you walk
over a potion, it'll just like auto use it like a, like a health orb from D3.
And, um, you can turn that off because that was messing up a lot of low life builds.
So that's in the settings.
We've, we spoiled that previously, but.
I realized that I have one more teaser to share.
We're actually going to slap it at the top so that I can see my face still.
A little, little sneak peek at, uh, some footprint cosmetic effects that are coming in to season
two.
So new style effects.
I don't know if we've used footprints before.
Have we?
All right.
What do you think about certain affixes being near mandatory on certain slots?
Like for example, movement speed on boots.
Yeah.
This is a tricky one.
And we put movement speed as an implicit on boots already specifically because of this.
Um, oh, we are cutting off questions here.
No more questions.
Cause I still have a couple of pages of questions.
I have three pages of questions to get through.
So I'm going to try and get those, uh, all answered here.
Thank you very much for the rating party.
Welcome everyone from that stream.
Hope you're having a good time.
Hope you're having fun.
Um, where are we here?
More questions.
I will answer them all.
Uh, affixes being near mandatory.
Yeah.
It's, it's something that we've debated a few times and movement speed is the quintessential
example of this.
Um, it's just so thematically appropriate on boots.
Um, and there are builds that don't need it.
Um, that we've kind of been, that we've been okay with it so far.
Um, it's on the radar.
It's something that gets debated a fair bit.
Uh, if it becomes any much more mandatory than it is, um, I think it'll be, we'll probably take some
steps like dialing the values down a little bit.
Um, and like probably like dying the values of the affix down and upping the values of the
implicit at the same time.
So like the maximum potential stays the same, but the necessity miss, it's a word.
Now it is of the affix would go down.
Um, something like that probably.
Uh, how's Kyle doing yesterday?
I watched the old lore stream.
Consoling great.
I would love to get Kyle on for the lore stream.
Um, definitely before the next season comes out for season three, well, I, I will be pushing
hard for that.
Uh, all right.
Is there a chance that last epoch will release on consoles?
Oh yeah, there's a chance.
It was a good chance.
Eventually.
Um, I don't have any specifics, which consoles, ETAs, any of those sorts of things,
but it is something that we are interested in doing.
Um, and there's lots of stuff we are doing now to prepare for that in the future.
Uh, yeah.
Uh, whose idea was the Joth bear?
Brilliant.
Yes.
Uh, that was, I think that was Holly.
Um, so if you saw, you saw Holly, uh, was on the, um, the first of our tour of the race
podcast, uh, I think that was her, uh, her idea to do.
Um, yeah, it's, if anyone doesn't know.
There are bears in last epoch that, um, can teleport and they're, they're called a
Joth bear and a Joth bear is a reference to the Diablo two rune word Joth or Joth bear,
depending on how you pronounce it.
Um, which is, gives you the ability to teleport makes the enigma room word,
which I know almost everyone here is like, of course, Mike, we know that.
Why are you explaining it to us?
Yes.
All right.
How many coworkers mysteriously became sick today?
You should definitely not go play the game that just launched.
Uh, I don't know.
I mean, very few, if any.
Oh, the heroes, here's a little bit more details on.
Uh, on this that I'll tell you right now.
Um, so we were talking about the, the number at the bottom of the screen here, this number down here.
Um, yeah, this is the, uh, how many of these points you've unlocked.
Uh, 13 of them come from ranks in the Weaver's faction and 37 of them come from,
as rewards from completing specific woven echoes.
Just like, leave that up.
Uh, I feel like if I do all of the videos at once, the audio is going to be terrible.
Uh,
there we go.
All the teasers.
All right.
How much does COF ranks interact with new Weaver tree stuff?
For example, in the, is the Weaver know where it drops a pile of similar loot.
The imprint item is affected by COF ranks at 25% chance to upgrade rare.
Is all that, yeah, they affect just like any other normal drops do.
Uh, thank you for the sub.
Oh, that's one that's got it.
That's got capitalizations.
It doesn't, uh, Robin Nakalaki.
Robin Nalaki.
Robin Nalak Lee.
You got close.
I appreciate the sub that is always appreciated.
All right.
Uh, when the team talks about new classes, can you mention one or two that are no longer being considered?
No.
Sorry.
I don't, I don't think anything's been like fully ruled out.
That's like been suggested.
Uh, in coming season two, will the COF MG harbinger faction ranks benefit be changed or improved?
Uh, there are some light adjustments to some of those.
Minimal though.
Are we still going to be forced into doing the campaign or can do arena at level one for alternate leveling?
Um, you, if, if you aren't playing multiplayer and, uh, you don't have anyone that you can teleport to,
to, to jump and skip stuff that way.
Uh, the default flow for a single player experience is through the campaign, uh, exclusively still.
Uh, will there be more than five skills in each mastery?
Quite possibly.
Yes.
That is not set in stone at all.
Uh, will we get, like, we very intentionally left space for more skills in each one of the masteries.
Uh, will we get dwarf slash blacksmith faction in the future for better crafting mechanics?
That's possible.
That's, that's, I would say a solid option that we haven't really delved too deeply into yet.
Uh, that didn't cause any problems.
I think we're good still.
Um, hey, love the game.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
10 minutes left.
I got to rattle through these, but there's one thing that's always bothered me a little bit.
Oh no.
Uh, it's to do with walking animation.
It feels a bit floaty to me.
Am I alone in that?
Keep it up.
Um, yeah, there was, um, there's, especially if you're like, you can't see what I'm doing right
now, but especially if you like click really close to your character, it definitely starts
to feel a little floaty.
Um, there's some animation adjustments and some acceleration adjustments that we've talked
about doing for improving the, the, the walking animation stuff that's happened.
I don't know if, uh, specifically what ended up happening there, but it's not,
uh, I've seen feedback similar to this in the past.
So that I guess, uh, I don't know if it's already answered already.
It's okay.
Do you plan on changing how the ward bar works during the boss phases?
Um, the, the functional, the mechanics of it are, we're very pleased with the actual mechanics
of it and that is sticking around.
Um, there are very, very few bosses that have the word bar now, especially compared to what
it was in season one.
Um, so season two, we're removing the word bar from most sources that had it.
So, uh, the only times you'll see it now are in, um, like, uh, timeline bosses, uh, very specific,
uh, like pinnacle bosses, things like that.
Like, like we're talking end game bosses, um, or like big chapter bosses, like when it's a
really important fight, that's, that's when we'll have those up to just, because we really,
we really want it to be easier for, uh, for homebrew builds.
We want homebrew builds to be functional and actually have a place in the game.
Uh, and it's, it's really to support those builds.
Like this, this is a system that makes those builds much more functional and popular and
possible in the game to work.
And so you're not having to follow a meta build quite as much.
I know it might not feel that way.
Um, but I promise you, that's what it's doing.
Uh, will we get those fancy armor from the solar units, uh, for the Paladin?
Possibly.
I can see that being cool MTX to have.
We, we were reluctant to give cosmetic effects to the player that are the same as enemies.
Um, we'd want to tweak them usually just so that you don't blend in too much.
Uh, will there be any resonance, uh, changes on resonance drop rates?
My friend is too stubborn to craft his, her own gear.
Uh, yeah, we, we are adjusting some of those a little bit.
Uh, right.
Uh, only 40 minutes behind.
What is, what's a procedural content procedural content?
Um, random map generation.
So we'll say like, um, here's, here's, here's the, the short version of the most straightforward,
uh, simple version of what procedural content generation means.
Is this is behind everything?
Oh my goodness.
That's not gonna work.
Um,
if you have, you, you end up with like, you create, uh,
uh, so you're creating a, uh, a system of corridors and hallways in a, in a big castle.
And you say like, here's a straight through path.
Here's a T intersection.
Here's a cross intersection.
Here's a left turn.
Here's a right turn.
And, uh, you like, you print them all out onto pieces of paper and tiles and you shuffle those
tiles around and you start slapping them down like a board game that builds itself as you play.
Like, uh, if you ever played like a betrayal at house on the hill or like zombies or a bajillion
other procedural generated board games where you like place tiles down as you're, as you're playing
the game, you come to like a door and it like, you pick a new tile off the top of the deck and
you put the tile down and it like makes the room.
And, um, so that's like the, the baseline for procedural content generation.
Um, where it's like, it's random in a set of rules where it like makes content on the fly.
Uh, so it's not the same.
So you don't memorize it.
That sort of thing.
Um, and the place we're leveraging that is in, um, our tombs and cemeteries to start with.
And we're going to expand that out to other parts of the game.
Once we are confident and happy that that is working and people are happy playing with it.
All right.
Hi, uh, how, and so far the feedback has been really positive.
So I'm, we've already started working on putting it into new places.
Um, how did the unity engine upgrade go?
Great.
Does it change anything for you as a dev?
It changes a few little things.
Um, there's like new features in the backend stuff that we can do, uh, makes things a little
bit smoother.
That sort of stuff.
You've actually, if you, if you're playing live right now, you're playing on the updated version.
All right.
What is the feature you're most excited for players to experience the new patch?
Probably the, uh, the, um, probably, I think probably just interacting with the woven echoes
and the weaver tree, all that new, the whole new end game system is so huge.
Um, some of the new boss fights are pretty cool though, too.
Yeah.
All right.
1500 hours.
Since playing beta, since beta, that's pretty sweet.
Uh, there's a step, there's a steep difficulty from mono level 90, uh, compared to empowered
model level 100.
I usually will reach first empowered at level 80.
Why not corruption?
Zero to a hundred on normal monos.
Yeah.
This is something we've talked about.
It's, I think it's really good to have some, some difficulty jumps, like a few thresholds.
The jump there is too big right now.
And, uh, we are leveraging things in the woven echoes to, to help with that.
Um, yeah, I, I agree that there's, that there's some, that that jumps too big and we are shrinking it a little bit.
Um, but we don't want to, we don't want to cut it off completely.
Cause it's good that there's some jumps, but maybe you make them hops, not jumps, you know?
All right.
Does the tombs give stability?
Yes.
The tombs are normal echoes as well.
Uh, have you guys considered doing a display collab or something similar?
Yeah.
I, I, I've thought about that.
I think it'd be sweet.
Uh, since you don't have your own merch store yet, I would love to do display collab.
That'd be sweet.
Um, I've considered getting it a few times.
Um,
I, I, uh, I play a lot of magic and play a lot of magic.
I would like to play a lot of magic.
Um, and so yeah, I, a lot of, uh, magic creators, content creators, um, like streamers and YouTubers,
they, uh, um, they, they get displayed sponsorships a lot.
So I see them a lot.
I'm like, I've come very close to getting displayed stuff quite a few times, but this is so much better,
which you can't really see completely.
Cause I've blocked it.
What blasphemy is this?
Cause this is so much better.
Uh, all right.
Here's where I'm learning.
My monitor is not level.
Uh, the webcam is resting on the monitor.
All right.
Uh, will we ever get something like divination cards and Pwee?
Possibly.
Um, probably want to put our own twist on it more so, but, um, I do really like the system.
It's that, it's that incremental buildup towards like, I found a piece of something amazing.
I found a piece of something amazing.
And that, uh, that style of system is really strong.
This is kind of a similar thing to what we were talking about with rune words earlier.
When you found a piece of something you find, you find a jaw rune and you're like, okay,
I've found one third of a, of an enigma.
Um, assuming the, not kidding.
The if is the third, I'm counting the, the armor base plate, the perfect base is the third of it.
Um, and I think that's a really powerful, um, feeling.
So I, I'd love to add something like that.
We don't have something specific plan though.
Uh, do you guys ever plan to add mounts with larger maps?
Um, probably we don't have any specific plans for it right now.
Uh, there are some really cool stuff that happens with it, but it is, as you mentioned in the question as
well, the maps we've all made are really not designed to have mounts in them.
So no plans at the moment.
Uh, I really like the player's threshold defense system that gives damage resist at 35%.
How did that come about?
Um, that was actually, that's, that's funny.
We were trying to find ways to, this is really early.
This is like, um, this is in alpha.
So pre, pre beta.
So we're not even like online yet.
I don't think.
And we were trying to find ways to have people almost die, like come really close to dying
and just like, just, just hold on with like a sliver of health left.
Um, and so we built this endurance system into the health bar and didn't tell anyone it was,
it was a completely hidden system.
There was no way to interact with it.
The game didn't tell you it was happening, but it would like protect the last, I think it was 10%
of that time, maybe 20% of your health significantly more than it would protect the rest of your health.
It's just naturally just to be like, oh, you held on by it.
Just, just the thread.
Um, and it was, it was cool.
And it was, it was, it was there and people were like asking for it and we're like, it's already
there.
Like we just didn't tell you about it, but it is there.
Um, and so we decided to like integrate it into a proper system and we were, because we were looking
for new defensive mechanics to integrate into the game and ways to scale your defenses that would
synergize well with health builds and not be ward centric as much.
Um, and so it got, that's, it got converted from a secret system to a real system then.
Uh, and that was early online days and those in beta phase.
I think that's when that happened.
I could be wrong.
Endurance is the system we're talking about, by the way.
Speaking of weapons in, uh, to intro in L E.
Oh my gosh.
Uh, I'm not going to pronounce that properly.
Kusari Yagama.
I apologize that I butchered that horribly to whatever region of the world that I butchered
that from, uh,
a chain and ball scythe is what I'm being told.
That sounds cool.
That sounds really cool.
Um, I don't, I don't think, I don't think my body's ready for that.
Something that cool.
Uh, I think it would have to come with a, like a martial arts themed character or
something like that probably, which I would love to do.
All right.
Did you guys thought about adding a premium supported package where a player can submit
a unique idea you guys develop and put their name on it?
Yes, we've done that.
I would pay to have my name in an item inside the game.
Yeah, we've, we've, we, we used to offer this.
Um, we're still working through some of the old ones.
Um, but yes, we have done this before.
We've done it as rewards for things.
We've done it as, um, yeah, the, the problem we had with this was it was too popular and
too many of them got purchased.
Uh, they were a thousand dollars and we had too many of them, uh, get purchased very quickly.
We're like gotten to, it's like a huge backlog of them.
Um, and like, it feels in order to like do that fairly, we'd have to, I think we'd have
to, if we were going to bring it back, I, I don't know if we can bring it back or how
we bring it back, but I think we would have to put some sort of limit on the number that
we did.
Um, and I don't, and we'd have to figure out, find some fair way to do it like a lottery
system.
Cause I don't think that having, I don't love the idea of being like, all right, well in
order to like get it down to the limit of the number that we want to do with these,
we'll just start increasing the price.
And it's like, it's $5,000, it's $10,000.
And that feels weird selling something like that for that much money.
Like there just seems like too much money, but it's like at 1000, which already seemed
insane was too low because people were buying too many of them.
Um, so we, I think we'd have to put some sort of, but just like a first come first serve
feels bad too.
Cause people are just like at work that day or, you know, just the internet's not working as fast
as something.
So like, I feel like there'd need to be some sort of lottery system, um, or tie it to a
reward system or something.
I don't know how exactly we do it, but, um, I'd love to bring it back.
I do.
I love doing supporter uniques.
There's a really cool supporter unique, um, coming for, uh, there's a witch fire unique.
That's a support unique coming in season two that you should keep an eye out for it.
Cause I think it's really awesome.
Not just cause I worked on it.
Um, but that was, uh, I won't say their name, but yes, shout out to the person who suggested that
because I, well, I didn't, it wasn't even on my radar as a style
of thing we could do.
Um, and I'm so happy they suggested it.
Okay.
Uh, any interest on incentivizing multiplayer co-op?
Yes.
Gigantic asterisk there.
Um, I think the way we incentivize multiplayer co-op is just making it more fun.
I think, I think, um, like putting things to do in the game that are interesting and cool,
but, uh, we really want to avoid having mandatory content for multiplayer.
So a boss where it's like, Hey, if you want to fight this, you gotta get, you gotta find
10 friends to fight this boss or something like that.
It's not something we're super interested in doing right now.
Um, but we are getting to the point where they're getting enough content that it doesn't feel like
you're missing out on a huge section of the game by not interacting with it.
So maybe it's, it's more in the cards now than it was a year ago for sure.
Um, but it's not something that we're actively working on right now.
When comes the new season?
It's right around the corner.
It's on the 17th.
Huge hype for that in my world.
Anyways, um, my little bubble, anything that you can say about the cocoon items.
Come on, Mike, drop something huge here.
I don't want to wait till talking to try podcast.
I'm sorry.
You're going to have to wait till talking to try podcast.
We're going, we're doing deep dive on items.
Um, four days from now on the eight.
Uh, we're going to have any, any items questions that you guys have, which there were lots of items
questions, um, today, which were, there was good item questions, but yes, that, that is the day
that we're going to be releasing items.
There's, um,
so, uh, essentially try tries not in the CT program.
Um, so there's, he didn't have, he doesn't have like an, uh, um, like an insider knowledge
of like questions to like steer with.
Uh, and there's a few things that we're, um, and I think, I think that's a good thing that,
that there's, uh, people that we're doing interviews with that weren't in the CT program.
Um, so we're, we're, we're going to be, uh, there's a few things that are being unveiled
there that I'm really excited about.
So check, check that out.
Um, I don't know the time.
I think it's 3 PM.
I think it's the same time as the stream normally is.
Yeah.
There's gonna be tons of awesome stuff there.
We were prepping for that a little bit today.
All right.
That's going to do it for me.
We're all done.
I hope you had fun.
I know I did.
I will be back, uh, actually same time, same place next week, except different place,
same time, different place.
Cause on the 11th.
So next Friday we are doing, uh, our final podcast tour with, uh, Aaron action RPG and
frosty, the Rue, uh, which will be on their channel.
Um, and that's going to be, uh, three more of us from each G on that one.
Uh, can't remember exactly who else is going to be there.
I, Oh, I'm pretty sure it's going to be Judd carving me.
Um, but I could be wrong.
We'll see.
See who it is.
Uh, yeah.
Thanks for stopping by everyone.
Oh, I love doing these streams.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
Find someone to say hi to.
Who's doing cool stuff.
Oh, we were, we were just, we were just talking about him.
Let's go.
Let's go say hi.
Oh, is Perry's podcast starting right now?
Okay.
We're, we're going to be going.
We're next week.
We're doing the full interview with him.
We'll, we'll, we'll go say hi to Perry and, and, and Dred today.
I like these guys.
All right.
Well, have a great time, everyone.
See you next week.
Drink lots of water.