good afternoon everybody and welcome back to another last epoch devstream as usual
i'm your host mike hello how's it going everybody we're feeling good we're having fun we're uh
we're just gonna we're gonna hang out and play some last epoch and answer some questions
who's got who's got questions for me huh about where we're at all right
yeah so we have a little little chill time hanging out in the uh the monolith killing some bosses
right at the top or the top of the stream we've got a couple little housekeeping things as usual
we do stream for charity our charity is right above my head right here so all the everything goes to
that um second thing if you have a question please feel free to ask it i'll be happy to answer it
please put at last epoch game in the chat um we pulled questions from twitch and from youtube so
uh wherever you are we've got you covered um and i'll i'll get those and i'll be happy to answer
them um we do have if anyone case anyone missed it i assume that most people that are here have
probably heard but we are um moving our release date for season two to april 17th um gonna be a
fantastic launch looking forward to it very much um we do we are moving the twitch drops um
that we're gonna be happening alongside the launch to the new launch window as well so those
happen between april 17th and april 21st the same same time window everything's the exact same just
shifting it uh so that it's makes sense um and the new we are also uh we are also moving the the date
that the old supporter packs are going to be vanishing from the shop um so that's these supporter packs
they are being replaced with new ones um but they are going to coexist with the new ones for a little
while uh after um after the patch launches so we're going to be those are going to be sticking
around until april or may 2nd sorry so you'll have you'll have a couple weeks to to have both of those
side by side and make a decision which one you like the best um and the last two dates on our
um podcast tour around the world uh with with with try and uh the second one with aaron and frosty
uh those have been moved to april 8th and april 11th respectively so a bunch of bunch of numbers
bunch of dates lots of those all available up on our uh news channels on discord on our forums
there's a post on reddit i believe you know so we put it out to all the places of this post if you
want to review that again check out one of those places um but we're pushing everything back about
two weeks and all everything's being adjusted to be um respectively the same time hope that all makes
sense i think i might need to pick a little bit harder content for this character because it's a
little bit better than this i'm kind of just cruising through not even using my abilities
except this guy's got some beef to him
there we go
all right uh let's start with some questions let's get let's get it going
oh all right any downside to forge guard uh the two-handed weapon plus shield passive yes there is i don't know
what it is off the top of my head i think it might be attack speed
either damage or attack speed i think
i can't remember what it is i'm sorry
or possibly both
um we'll we'll get we'll get the details of that for uh actual numbers because i don't it's not a huge
uh huge downside
all right can we get patch notes sooner than later so we can theorycraft builds
i just a little aside i just learned um i just learned where the term theorycraft comes from
and i i had no idea so i thought it was cool this is um i saw a little day nine short and he was
explaining this um i i feel it's the sort of thing that uh he's an expert on but uh feel free to fact
check this um it was that people were playing like when early days of starcraft one there was people
who were not actively playing uh starcraft but were theorizing on the best way to play starcraft
and as sort of like uh uh like i don't like a jab like an internet like like uh that's not that's not
the right way to do things it was all you're just playing theorycraft um
i i i i had no idea it was like a bad term initially which i thought was was pretty cool
which doesn't really matter or mean anything but uh whatever uh as far as the question with patch notes
uh patch notes i don't have a specific date but the patch notes are also getting pushed back
a similar amount of time so it's going to be um uh you know closer to the launch date still
um and we won't be pushing them out early i'm sorry uh hey mike i was wondering if there's a
possibility we'll see mirror image support for mage kind of cool skill node with no support
yeah i i maybe not in season two um it's one of those it's one of those nodes that's interesting
because it is i think the only minion support at all in mage um it is it is way
off on an island and when we were originally designing
uh runemaster we considered making runemaster a minion based mastery um ultimately we didn't
and i'm very pleased with the direction we ended up going with it
we kind of made the decision that mage would be a non-minion class um so i think it's pretty
unlikely that we'll see much in the way of mirror images getting uh any sort of buff hey look at that
there's something you don't see every day if you haven't seen that before uh it's a little easter
egg um potion health potions have a chance to drop as beer um and they have exactly the same
stats it doesn't mean anything it's just a little like hey it's funny um if you can't pick it up you
have to use one first there you go it says plus on potion
all right what do you plan on doing during those two extra weeks pre-launch uh there's a like there's
a few little things we're gonna we're gonna sneak in there's stuff that we had um there's stuff that
we had planned for early hot fixes so like we when we're leading up to a patch we we get to a point
where we're like okay this build is like it's functional there's no major bugs it's solid it's
really good we're we're confident in its its stability and its qualities there um and we're
gonna this is what we're gonna launch with and so we we actually already had gotten to that point
where uh we're like okay we're done adding new stuff for this build now and um we decided to push a
little bit the uh we kind of opened that up and said okay the things that we're gonna go in hot
fixes we're now gonna put into the main build and we'll do more stuff into hot fixes after the after
the um after the season drops so it's gonna be there's gonna be some little things mostly just
minor bug fixing um some little quality of life stuff uh something that just here here's something
that just got put in today that i'm very pleased about that wouldn't have been in um otherwise so
you can you can you can thank the delay for this this screen this probably would have come in like
a hot fix on like day one or two or something like that so it's not really that big of a deal but
um this screen there's now a little label that shows up here that tells you your um the timeline
corruption so all of them all all of the timelines have like a little like like 4 000 um that says
the timeline corruption there so you can you can track your timeline corruption from the screen and
see it uh bigger you know like like little things like we're just doing more polish um looking at like
little feel things um so like uh picking up pick up radius for items we were evaluating revaluating
that today um just just little things like that that are sort of like um as we as we play test more
we get a better feel for things and we um just catch a little minor changes so you know it's
there's always there's always room for more stuff to make it in and uh we're trying to do
low risk high reward things because we just don't have the uh the time for for big testing on major
features
i should drop some of this stuff i really don't need most of it i'm pretty sure we're just we're
just gonna start chucking stuff on the ground it's happening oh my gosh what is he doing crazy person
i just can't help but pick things up is the problem so we're just gonna drop it all in the ground
don't crafty materials having those go directly to your crafting material stash is so nice okay we're
just gonna we're just gonna share this node wholesale i think so the um i'm doing this the wrong way
we're doing it this way because here you go first unplanned impromptu spoiler
uh so it is
uh less damage uh and less attack and cast speed um and haste grants added block chance
here we go
all right are there any plans for further improvements to the graphics engine of the game
not necessarily oh that jumped a lot not necessarily soon just at some point oh yeah definitely um we're
always we're always cooking on the um on the graphics like there's sometimes it's engine based
and like uh more of like a high level thing that a high level change that affects things like a
shader change that can affect all sorts of things in the game that's i think that's something that
a lot of people would associate as like an engine update or engine improvement as it affects everything
um but then we're also doing things where like we just make the vfx for something look better because
we did a better job the second time around you know um so all both those things are on the list
and we're doing them
all right is there a reason why the gamblers take so much time between gambles
um yes do i remember exactly what that is no um i think part of it was that the
just didn't want to incentivize spamming gambling which i think once we took away the ability to get
really good items from the gold gambling um kind of removed the need for it
all right oh some cool little stuff there
yes glorious
free freezing haven't been here in a while welcome back um are more skins coming with the
update oh yes oh yes um we've got new categories of uh of mtx coming we've got new um new stuff for
existing categories new sets new packs new individual pieces um skills
uh i don't know if we've teased every yeah yeah we showed we showed a preview of the footsteps in the um
as one of the twitch drops
uh there's a few things this this ui this ui here got a bit of a bit of a facelift as well it's
like these things got pushed up to the side and the skills things takes up more space because you
can equip like a whole bunch of different skills all at once not just five for triggered abilities and
things like that um
yeah it's great
oh what do we got here i i've i've been missing things i'm how did i miss these things
vulcan or vellum vellum 1112 thank you very much for the sub i can read so good
and welcome to the party everyone from big madive
uh cog ratchet and nex morris thank you for the subs as well that's 14 months there cog ratchet wow
that's a lot of months that's a lot of months much appreciated
all right
hello mike nice to hear from you yes i got a question sentinel one is rebuke getting some love
this season uh no oh he okay yes do i know what it is off the top of my head no
um basically every sentinel skill got touched in some way
like there's an idol that ref one of the island chance that references rebuke
it's one of those problems of like i don't remember exactly what got in
get back here thank you oh no not that far
all right did i i for i totally forgot to transfer my
uh stash i think
did that already
sweet
we've done that already
having these go direct is so nice
uh
any chance we will see timeline bosses turned into uber bosses later down the line it's possible
it's fully possible
um
i think i think taking existing bosses and and like putting twists on them a little bit maybe
a little bit more advanced functionality and a little bit extra stats is is like that's one of
those low effort high reward things that we love to do um not that we don't love high effort things as
well but uh good bang for your buck on development time is always nice
sometimes you get you get stuck though in the constraints of old old design then you start
reworking the original one then the scope balloons a bit yeah
are you guys going to try and squeeze in some extra stuff now that you've delayed a bit would be
nice to get a little more stuff but i'll get if you're focusing on polish yeah i mean we're
we're squeezing in some more polish stuff basically
uh can we have the cosmetics character in menu my drew looks like poop uh yeah sure sounds good
um in a previous roadmap transmog and dies were slated for 1.4 in the latest roadmap no time is
specified is there any update time for this and does the team have an updated stance regarding character gender selection
um
a few things in there i'm happy to answer them and not die at the same time
and thanks for oh you gotta resub
jarzul six months thank you very much glad to have you here
um as for uh dies transmog and character customization i don't have any timeline on any of that for you
um whether that's next season whether it's the season after that whether the season after that i i i just i just don't know
um i would um
the state the state none of the stances on this has have changed like it's all stuff we want to do
um i don't know when we're going to be able to do it uh it's sort of like as soon as possible
but it's you know it's quite a large thing to add so we have to decide if it's like when it's worth it to
do it the best i pretty well everything's a value proposition so that's a lot of move speed
haste effect move speed that's nice
it's actually really nice
what are we using those are these
all right i gotta pick up your sets where they here they are give me my sets
what does this one have
one of the really cool things with the set affixes that we were able to do is that a lot of set items
have mods on those slots that you can't get anywhere else um so a lot of the set affixes even if you're
not using them for the set bonus themselves just having that affix available on that slot in general
is kind of a nice little thing to work into a build sometimes so like um i don't know i was seeing
some some like single set items even being uh functional on their own now
when when made into a like a reforged that i don't
train whistle
oh pumping bees we got more and tahariel 47 months oh my goodness that's so many
i don't know where i don't know where the train whistle is it might be might be my closet that's
right there but it is like there's stuff i'm still in the process of getting my office all set up oh
i almost forgot if you haven't seen it yet there is a um there's there's a post that went up showing the
uh the the piece that's gonna go on my wall it's gonna go right here
um so excited for it um oh i don't have a link if anyone has a link for that post it in chat
uh there's there's a video of like how it's made it's a big sign says last epoch
it's all backlit it's all hand carved it's amazing uh yeah it's incredible
those guys ran away at the exact wrong time
okay more stuff's happening there's there's there's just stuff everywhere i love it um will
the new uh will the new patch include was the controls yes the new patch will include was the
controls um it is a it is a beta implementation of was the controls so it is there's there's a lot
of new things to to add to it still um it is very much a work in progress please give us your feedback
on it we want to hear what it does well what it doesn't do well uh things you'd like to see it
doing all sorts of stuff uh we have feedback channels set up on our discord um in uh in game
uh you know all these places you can communicate to us specifically for things like that that we like
place we put hey give us feedback here um be great and vaulting thanks for the sub
all sorts of people coming today sounds great since it's crazy
all right
will champion enemies have uh ward health shields no champions do not have the ward health shield
um all of the like the nemesis that i just fought this uh exiled mage that's in this rune prison
uh the champions um all all of these like mini bosses um or like elites that show up in uh in in
the just in the middle of an echo things like that none of those have um none of those have shields
anymore the shields getting removed from all of those things they're being reserved for major major
bosses such as timeline bosses uh pinnacle bosses uh or shade of orbus um you know things like that
like it is it is big big boy bosses only oh steel mage that's a that's a four digit raid right there
that is a 1 000 person raid welcome everyone from steel mage chat that is
glad to have you with us
welcome on in we're we're talking about last epoch if you have questions for me put out last epoch game
in the chat i'll get funneled to me i've got four pages of them to get through right now and i should
be going faster um i almost want to just like the trailer up for a second so i can just answer
questions let's put a teaser up and i'll do i'll do a question batch here uh here's a little uh
here's here's a little void nay passive sure that's not with that uh how many bug fixes are coming to 1.2
season two how many bug fixes are coming to season two um there's some bugs that haven't been fixed since
like 0.8 and i'm wondering what's the priority with old bugs um so the priority is basically just
it's the same as always been it's it's how um how big of an impact does this have uh how hard is it
to fix um and it's it's all these things get worked in together to decide what the order of any individual
bug is there's tons of work that's been done on um on bug fixing all over the place and we are doing more
as well um got any teasers and leaks for us after the guys assume cars still employed at ehg yes car
is still happily employed at ehg he received no backlash from that endeavor uh uh uh uh any teaser
yeah i got i got teases i got two ones one right here yeah this one this is our second one actually
from the stream maybe even third one because you know i think i leaked something else earlier by mistake
because i'm just being told um when you craft the set shards on two and i know it i skipped one
oh my goodness uh in one of the interviews you mentioned changes to the ward system is it mostly just
that it's going not going to be on everything instead of just on the most important mobs yes
essentially uh there's some there's some number tweaks as well but if not huge changes to the
system itself uh when you craft the set shards onto items does it only carry over the set bonuses
or is it also the stats and conversions for instance meteor is lightning so when you let's
let's talk about this briefly for a second just to get the details out of the way so let's say the
last bear's fury is the set we are shadowing we shadow this and we get the last bear's fury
set shard uh thank you uh side knee appreciate the sub uh welcome and so you got the last bear's fury set
shard um that one is going to have oh it's not working really great cool managed to make it work um
okay that one is going we're gonna so there's these four affixes here and we have picked two of these
four affixes to be the two affixes that the f that the shard has um and then and it's always
and we've picked two of these affixes thank thank you kane sorry uh we've picked two of these affixes to
be the um to be the affixes that are the last bear's fury set shard um so i i'm not gonna tell you which
two of these four we've picked but we've picked two of them and that those are the two that that
shard gives and that shard will always give those two and because it is something that has seven
tiers it can go all the way it can be exalted um you have to do that a little indirectly with some
of the new crafting materials but you can get exalted set shards set affixes um we've we've often picked
ones that are thematically uh strong so things that really feel thematic to that weapon so like um
um or that that item that really brings forth the feeling of it so that when you put it on an item
it still feels like the same item or a similar item usually um things that are exciting things that
aren't normally found on that slot stuff like that and things that do scale nicely with seven tiers of
affixes so something that's just like it's like plus one strength um that doesn't that's not on any
of them but it doesn't scale great because you can have decimals of strength um that's a bad example
because we can just put more on the on the affix chart but i'm trying to go quick uh and then if
you have multiple items of the same set whether that includes the base set items so i can have uh
like the last bear's helmet and chest piece and then a reforged last bear's gloves and i would get
the three set bonus because i would have three pieces of the set when you put a shard from a set
item onto uh an exalted item and make a reforged version of that set item for all intents and purposes
that item is a set item in that set um so you it counts towards the set bonuses and it has some
set affixes on it
whoo
all right let's take this down so i don't forget
all right keep going uh when you guys that uh when doing gold monolith would be possible to buff the
gold pickup range but would it be possible to buff the gold pickup range just for that mono so we
can actually pick up all the gold that drops um we are looking at pickup range in general not just
for specific situations because i think it's a little too small uh are you considering any changes
in the game's ui more specifically the skill bar and health resource orbs um not huge changes there's
some minor adjustments here and there but for the most part we're very very pleased with it
uh i wanted to ask if you do have any suggestions please feel free to head over to our suggestions
channels i'm not gonna say that every time uh but it's sort of implied i wanted to ask if there was
any thought to adding hideouts yeah we we've we've definitely thought about adding hideouts several
times um the short version is is that we don't love the idea of pulling people out of communal spaces if
we can avoid it um but having places that you're already going to with friends to show off your
hideout and uh customize location is something that we really love the idea of
it's not coming in season two sorry
stop picking stuff up mike i know it's pretty but just stop picking it up like come on you can do it
restrain yourself glorious experience hey we leveled up at least the abilities did this yeah uh damage
and lead sure i don't really know what the build was doing but it was working fine before and it's
gonna work fine afterwards yeah i love that one
all right
uh is someone bear getting improvements for the new season uh it's getting some better swipe
uh functionality so um yes not nothing gigantic
uh since we are expecting some changes to life is it going to be both recovery and increased amount
or is there some new life dependent mechanic um i would say more in that there's better availability
and synergy in skill trees for classes that really thematically like to have non-war defenses
earlier on so you're gonna start you're gonna you're gonna see um things that maybe scale off or
synergize well with life appearing earlier in passives um and on on in stronger amounts on some items for
health regen in particular uh hey mike are there any changes coming to cof or prophecies this season
that you can talk about that you can change how we can target specific uniques um there's not a ton
happening there a lot of that's happening in the uh uh in the weaver tree instead and uh but there's
some there's some little things there's like a couple new prophecies i think um
oh crap i can't remember the exact thing we're like removing the need for one of the lenses
so you'll have more less less pressure on your lenses so you'll be able to customize better there
um something else we don't do this is a few minor tweaks nothing gigantic
all right hey mike oh iron's net are you playing cof or merchant skill that launch of tombs i'm i i
don't know i think i'm probably gonna play cof i played merchant skill last time uh in the in the
like in my free time i did really enjoy it but uh i don't know i'm i i really like cof
i so frequently play ssf in general anyways it's kind of like it's always has been
yep back here i shoved it the wrong way
yeah we did it and leveled up too all right
i have a question i like last epoch but i think the movement is a bit slow do you think about
adding items to speed up the movement a bit well we are adding one item in season two that just
gives you perma haste so uh if you want to go fast there you go
um overall though we are pretty pleased with the the general speed of most things in the game
um i can't i can't see there being huge shifts in the like the overalls meta of speed
i have no idea what we have that we'd want to even take
what would you even take here i thought i had another category in here
let's try and slap some stuff on that why not
i can't wait for tries uh podcast for for this there's so many things i want to talk about
i i almost just spoiled one of them right there and i was like
nope not allowed to say it all right uh any updates on bringing new mtx into offline play i
have no info on this i'm sorry uh will there be a revamp of the necromancer mastery yes not
not in season two though um we're gonna be focusing on uh some some new stuff for
uh like lich and some stuff for necromancer like so acolyte will be a bigger focus in our uh um next
season after this one there was uh at one point uh planned to be a a new lich skill coming for season
two uh and that got shoved to the next season and so i think i think we'll see like a a bit of
uh necromancer stuff at the same time there it feels it feels right putting them together
all right uh with the addition of set shards have there been more sets added to the game for example
there is zero set items and any set bows at the moment uh we haven't added more set items to the
game in season two but assuming that the news the revamp to the set system goes well which i am
extremely confident in going well at this point um we are we're going to start adding set items
again it's been a while since we've added a set item to the game and we kind of wanted to make sure
that the change to the set system that we had planned was was solid and we were happy with it
before we really started uh expanding that as well
ellie is um is also predestined to be played on on the go on steam deck will there be further
improvements from your side regarding le performance on steam deck or are you concentrating on the pc yes
we are we are adding more stuff for steam deck um there's more features coming for steam deck there's
um so controller updates are so nice for what's what's happening on steam deck for gameplay right now
um we are looking at performance as well we're also looking at um uh ui scaling options so you're
gonna have multiple options in the settings for uh for ui scaling uh i think it's around here
something like that there's like uh you can use small medium large gigantic tiny i think there's
like five or six options for for ui scale um so much stuff happening my goodness oh it's a huge it's
a huge gift pack oh that's a lot so is that 10 wow i am sam thank you very much that's fantastic
some other ones before that too didn't we that i missed mind bombing thanks for the sub appreciate
you this is great and salmon so also subbed oh this sub's all over the place it's just i'm just
gonna turn this off soon it's just just keeps ringing you still hear me though right
all right i don't know how to turn it down slightly heavy 46 months whoa whoa feels good thanks buddy
your uh jug survived the move
i'm quite pleased about all right it was like one of the four things i wrapped up nicely
all right i know comparisons are always a bit difficult it's okay we do them all the time but
still what's something you think peewee does better than le and one where you're better oh
that's that's that's uh i i really don't like answering questions like this but i will
because there's one thing that have the peewee 2 has that uh that we don't have that is so awesome
and i would love to have um and and it's it's being able to uh lock a tooltip on screen and have it be
like its own window that you can move that window around and like anchor a tooltip and actually have
it be a a window properly you know like like you have in windows um oh my god oh my god that one that's
so bad uh the the way our tooltip system works for things like items anyways uh most things
actually is it's only one object that the contents the object gets changed when it opens so like this
tooltip is the same as this tooltip as like the game object in the behind the scenes it's just when
it closes it goes it just turns off and then when you mouse over this in that like one frame that it's
turning on there's actually one frame delay before it turns on it it changes everything in it to look
different and then it turns on and that's the same for everything so like um uh like skill tooltips
same thing like all this is all one object that just keeps getting moved around and change the
contents of so we'd have to change fundamentally how our tooltips work uh and one where you're better
i like our crafting system better i do um i i don't think it's a controversial thing to say that you
enjoy one or the other more um and i think a lot of it comes down to preference there so i don't know if
oh yeah does he say do better i don't know if it's actually better i enjoy it more
uh any chance we get a new look at new uniques coming i don't think i have any new uniques prep
today i got i got some other cool stuff i got some very cool stuff for you don't worry i started slow
on the teasers all right uh when will the new supporter packs be available or get sneak peeks the
new they'll be available uh within the patch drops so not before the patch drops um
they will
i i i don't know if we'll show them off early i hope we'll show them off early
alask
all right avalanche is my nemesis
avalanche is the one ability that will like always somehow kill me i don't know how i survived
that do i have a ton of cold res no no i'm even undercapped on cold res okay cool
uh any chance the acolyte gets another melee skill uh she's still missing a lich skill yes
um that's what i was just just talking about a minute ago i know this question was asked before
i said that but yes we are uh looking to post season two for another lich um lich melee skill
um we hate we did no details other than that i don't know what it's going to be we've we got like
10 percent into the like ideation of the base functionality and then we're like
uh we don't have time for this
maybe a little farther than that but not much
all right have there been uh have there been made any improvements in the audio department for
the next patch yes i don't dislike the audio in the game but i feel like it lacks a bit more punch
yeah so we're doing there's there's there's new times when audio can be played more there's there's
new functionality for control over when certain clips get played when um uh like repeating sounds
happen and frequency and volume and um yeah there's there's new tools we've added in and new sounds
we've added in and you know like sometimes uh the the the the skill mtx the skill cosmetic changes for
abilities have they come with audio changes as well um and some of the new audio is really nice too
all right in terms of unique items how they look on characters have you been able to include more
3d art for uniques to match the 2d there are more yes um percentage wise i think it's actually going
down because we're adding more uniques faster than we're adding the uh 3d models for them but
yes there there are more uh 3d models that do properly represent their 2d item art than before
um it's just so much faster to like the code to chain to add a unique like to just make those
things on screen work is so much faster than making the models
i heard you get customizable item sets will legendary affixes be extracted and be customizable
um so i uh reference you back to earlier in the stream this question was probably asked before i
explain the whole thing but the really short version in case you're new uh because you've
shown up since then the really short version is you can pull uh predetermined fixed affixes from
a set item and place them on a non-unique item uh and that item then becomes the set that the affix
came from in the first place uh so you can make your own set items and set items reforge set items as
we call them behave just like the set items they came from and have the same restrictions and same uh
bonuses
like set bonuses uh just some data when are you planning to release a new list of legendary items in uh lp tools
oh um before that um oh that's that second actually so when are you planning to list new
legendary items in uh last epoch tools i think that's what supposed to be um the third party tools
cannot update their tools until the patch is live um so like you can put yeah basically those those tools
i i don't know so we we are in contact with the people who make those tools and they do a fantastic
job on them it's really incredible um but as far as i know they're not allowed to put the content for
season two up on those until season two releases
assuming they have access to it through like ct programs and stuff like that
all right uh as far as the supporter packs we are going to show off the super porter packs early
um before the patch launches i don't know how early or when exactly but um you will see them before 17.
i mean i would assume at least by patch notes time right
all right uh for those of us who are mage mains and it helps assuage some concerns with the ward hit
what ward int nerf uh did mage and its masters receive any love in season two anything you want to
tease show us uh do i have anything here for that i don't have any specific mage stuff but yeah every
every every class every class got a bunch of uh new new cool toys to play with and um a lot of what
the targeting is about is is targeting the the curve that you gain access to those things on um
so you know maybe we we took away some like early game more retention but we then looked at it and said
okay well maybe there's some spot we could put like some a little bit more on like a rare item or something
like that or you know like where it's not always about the total amount of power that any individual
build has access to in some cases it is but it's not always that in some in some cases it's just the
um the the rate at which you get them in the leveling and character advancement process that's
the that's the big issue but yes there's there's definitely buffs too um even without them like it's
really not the end even even if we weren't buffing stuff at the same time uh the sky's not falling
uh there are still powerful board based builds you don't need to worry about that
are there any plans to give the arena champions some love so they have complexity
uh same they have the complexity of other bosses um there's not much being done there uh this patch
but i would love to expand that i'd love to uh that's one of those things that it's kind of like a
a fledgling version of the system i think where i'd love to have um like a reflection of builds that
that placed high on previous ladders show up as the arena bosses for subsequent seasons that's like
that's sort of the thing we've sort of internally been like oh wouldn't it be cool if one day we could
do this type thing i still i still hold out hope for one day that being a thing
chuck some stuff on the ground here because i'm a terrible hoarder
oh let's do let's do a sushi without sushi
oh this this uh display only shows empowered corruption doesn't show normal corruption just fyi
it's not a good thing i'm gonna do it
my face i wanted that
keep frenzy keep frenzy or berserk what's it called berserk yeah lost it it's okay
oh we got siphon at one lp oh my god huge drop oh my god
i'm sure everyone who does shade has a bajillion of those
six corruption ah all right our forge weapon living skins coming uh not for season two but that is
something that i would love to do more of uh what are your thoughts on changing or mixing up the idle
grid love it it's something that we so the the idle grid actually does have these spots um those the
five blocked off spots in the idle grid actually do exist in the code um like there's there's there's
there's hidden spots right here
um and we can we can block off different spots really easily um it's basically just just changing
the ui there's there's actually like just sprites that are just sitting there's there's there's five
images that are just sitting here over the grid that block it off visually um and some code to be like
don't use those spots but yes there's uh we can just change the visuals here and change which are the
blocked off spots in the uh in the code in the back end and it changes the layout there and that's
something that we have when we set this up originally that's something that we're like
okay we want to be able to change this in the future so we set it up to be changeable in the future
um love to
uh will the set bonuses apply to an exalted item as an affix or it won't be like on set items
um the set bonus will apply just like every other set item set bonus applies um like it it is the set
item
oh my goodness
lagan is gonna squish me like a bug this isn't lagan's timeline
the emperor of course is gonna switch me like a bug
if i make it to him
okay
let's do more questions because we're now at seven pages okay we're gonna do this
this and uh is it this this this oh no what is it there we go oh it doesn't get rid of those
oh we already had ui scale stuff here there's more of it coming
uh enemies allies where is it minions there it is
bye bye ui oh my hump names are whatever we're gonna answer some questions i'm just looking at me
uh right now what will be inside season two will also be available in legacy yes is there any plans
to make specific mechanics that will only be inside a season that could be added to legacy
after the season yeah that's that is the sort of thing that we that we're open to and we've done
short-term versions of that with aberroth release originally last season um it's not something we're
explicitly saying yes or no to but it is something that we are interested if the if it makes sense
for the mechanic and we're kind of getting to the point we have enough content that it's not as big
of a deal to do that to something with with uh with legacy uh any plans to make the one-shot chest
item mod shards farmable no because you can't use them afterwards they're sealed anyways uh getting
unity to work uh in kubernetes cluster is magic all its own do you think you could do a back-end engineer
qa share in a future dev stream uh probably not uh but maybe toss that in the suggestions channel and
then i'll get to someone who knows uh able to decide that uh hey pets pick up gold when uh hey
pets pick up gold when hey looking good hyped for new patch yeah uh not season two i'll tell you that
much uh with champions set affixes other potential filtering options will there be more than 75 rules
available no we're not expanding the number of rules in the loot filter it'll still be 75 it's already a
stretch we did make a couple changes that will allow you to combine some rules that were multiple
rules in the past so you'll have access to a little bit more space uh if you were using some of
those rules before uh any primalist changes coming ever yes there's lots every patch uh to me it
feels like a class that's a melee sorcerer totem summoning minion summoning skill triggering class
no identity i i feel like beast masters has has a clear identity in the uh in their companions and
druid has their clear identity in their uh transformations um and then uh shaman struggles
a little bit to bring the the totem theming through um but it gets that elemental damage uh focus
from from just about everywhere that that that earth uh sorry physical with earth theming um
lightning weather and cold weather we try and keep it as like the nature weather theming for
for shaman there uh will we be able to get shards from the champion affixes uh yes no uh champion affixes are sealed no shards
yes champion affixes are sealed no shards um
uh i know this patch is focused on end game but did anything get changed in the campaign like area
tweaks or boss buffs yes um there's there's there's changes in the campaign not huge ones but there are
some changes here and they're sprinkled in um some of them are just like little mechanical things some of
them are adding a little bit of quality of life stuff some of them are just smoothing out the process a
little bit some of them are um the champions do appear in the campaign as well so there's an
extra added challenge there that makes things a little more interesting as well all right i prefer
to play offline uh for the fast af loading times is there any chance for online to have loading parity
with offline or is as fast as it's going to get already i mean we're always doing whatever we can to
improve the performance of online and get those loading times down as fast as we can
um i i don't see a world where it can be the same as offline i just don't see how it's possible
um i i i don't know enough about the uh the back end of how loading happens to know if that is possible
or not i want to say something that i noticed from every podcast you've been in and it's something
quite unique but your smile happiness whenever you talk about elise contagious and it's amazing thank
you very much appreciate that i'm probably smiling a little bit less right now because i'm talking so
much but uh i wanted to say something oh it's that uh will we be able to cast and move with wasd
controls if the ability is instant cast yes wasd does not give you any new functionality that you
don't have already so anything that you can do now you'll still be able to with wasd but it doesn't open
up new uh functionality for uh casting abilities if an ability has a cast duration which almost or the
vast majority of them do this still will with wasd uh will the nurse to ward generation and retention
can you give us any more details on the types of nodes that were hit um most of the ones that say
like that trigger on on hit on crit um things that are like uh there's there's some rings some some
set and unique rings that have like ward on hit or chance to ward on hit or ward on crit things like
that um lots of them are given more per hit or crit and a capped frequency or just one of those things
um last epoch on ps5 please i love last epoch i can't always fire up my pc yeah we'd love to come
to console we don't have any info on when uh or anything like that or which consoles it'll be or
anything like that but yeah that's that is something we're still we're still hopeful for
i'm still working on uh after season two what's the next top priority you'll be working on still
in game or something else um i think let's focus on season two for now and we can get into post season
two stuff later um i'm i've just yeah i've been working on something for post season two for a
while now that is going to be awesome but i don't know if it's the top priority uh probably not um
all right items are reworked yeah they are set shards so awesome the actual items themselves didn't
change much there were a couple items that we adjusted a little bit here and there while we were
going through and picking out which affix to put on each item um we we kind of were like oh this
this this could use a buffer oh maybe this can use a little change in what it's doing to make
it more thematic like there's a few minor changes that happen with a few sets but nothing major
oh you know what let's put something up on on screen because i'm just talking here and this
is boring to look at here we go there's something else um sorry if anyone asked before last time i
remember it being i could just make myself bigger too if you want to see that that's not a big deal
um remember being asked not entirely clear did the team get to improve further on controller support
oh yeah so the big thing controller uh the big issue controller has right now and i know i'm blocking
myself uh do i have projectile abilities i can show this off with you
no none of these are gonna work nice anyways okay so with with controller support
sorry i just shrink this over there with controller support
currently because my character is facing this direction if i use fireball fireball will fire in
that direction period so if i'm running in this direction i'm facing this direction and if i use
fireball while i'm running it will shoot forward um the new controller support because um
say there was say there was a mob over here and brownie face i'm angry little evil goatee
spiky spiky hair yeah that's enough um because there's an enemy over there because the context
is there's an enemy nearby if you are running this direction with controller and use fireball you'll
stop for a brief you would stop anyways for a brief moment turn around uh and shoot fireball in this
direction and then keep moving immediately afterwards so you get a proper stutter step with proper smart
targeting that happens because the context is there that this is the enemy you want to hit
um now we also have uh specialization specific targeting as well so uh if we can use ballista as
an example ballista has a node in its tree which says um like it if you're near it it gets a buff
i think is what the node is um so you want to cast ballista right beside you
my bad ballista um so you want to cast ballista directly beside you so that it gets the buff
but say you take the ballista node that says uh when it dies it explodes you actually want to put
that ballista near an enemy um so that's the specialization specific part of it so it's context
and specialization specific because it will um it will see hey there's an enemy over here and i've
taken the specialization that says i want to put it near enemies so i'm going to put it near enemies
even if you're facing this direction so there's context and specialization specific
targeting for every ability on controller um that wasn't there before
all right any new ancient era stuff in season two you would be my toddler's favorite person if you put a
new in new dinosaurs um i think technically there are new dinosaurs dinosaur
technically i can say yes but not really no i'm sorry not yet um ancient era stuff's gonna be the
focus of a future patch um yeah
uh learn to make filters in for game 1.0 is there anything that we need to have to do for our filters
with the new patch there's a couple things that you'll want to update with filters nothing nothing
gigantically mega different um but updating them will be useful because there's new types of items
there's a couple new things you can do with them uh stuff like that uh any plans to add new skills
for current classes or will those only come with a whole new class fingers crossed for new skills
straight from uh let's just straight from d3 um we will be adding new skills to existing classes
for example um d2 guided arrow pre-nerf is getting added into last epoch in the form of heart seeker
which is the one you skill this ability this this um the season for marksman um next season at least
lich will be getting one new melee skill um we haven't said anything else but that will be happening
there as well that's the plan currently you know everything can change uh but that's the current plan
i should do the boss or not uh was adding different class supporting mercenaries ever a consideration
absolutely yeah uh we've talked about a few there's there's a nod to mercenaries in the game there's a
relic that you can get that gives you a crossbow mercenary that's kind of a nod to that um i'd still
love to do i still love to have like a class that that's the thing is they have a mercenary and they
build it out now the um the the forge guards manifest armor kind of plays that role a little
bit because you can summon it gets a copy of gear things like that but it's not quite the same
need more water why is my camera auto focusing thought i turned that off
okay uh was adding different class supporting or instead uh gosh
this is not gonna go well
i shouldn't be doing this because i need to answer questions but i like fighting this boss
times that one i'm half an hour behind oh no okay can the set shards only be used on those item types
the set was or can it be used last bear's fury used on boots or helmet no the uh base item type must
remain the same um the base base item category must remain the same um so you may put the last bear's
fury the gloves make sure that right the gloves can go on any gloves um
um they do uh they do cause uh class requirements to be taken into account so uh you can't create a
conflicting class requirement um so if it is a specific class required helmet uh it like if the if
the affix would create it to be class required uh you can't put it on a class requirement helmet of a
different class because you can't have conflicting requirements um
your berserk run here we go
come on yeah that's the same icon that's what same working for aldrez uh oh yeah leech we'll do leech
uh any changes coming to characters being stuck when walking into slash through enemies and
i don't know
um i don't know i'm sorry that'll be in the patch notes if it is off the top of my head i do not
remember i'm sorry uh right thoughts on higher monster density i think that in certain situations
it is awesome and very much uh interested in doing it uh there's some there's some fairly high monster
density in a few situations in some tombs that you'll you'll see um has an option to increase
cursor size been added yet so yola mass isn't required no unfortunately we do not have the
functionality available to us to do that um once we are able to do it we will but uh there's no
sign of it happening anytime soon i apologize it is something that we are very interested in but
it's just not it's not like oh we just don't feel like doing it or we don't want to do it it's a
it just doesn't work right now
uh can we still upgrade normal affixes after we turn a rare exalted item into a set piece yes
um so reforge set items can still be crafted like regular items um it's kind of required to be
able to put multiple set items set set tiers of the same set affix on so you'll still want to be
um ramping that up to five or using runes in order to shuffle exalted around to get it into seven
uh any thoughts to making the ui editable yeah would be great
um move move stuff around if the answer is no is there a reason for it uh it is it's it's a
it would be nice to do uh and i think once we're done doing more standard updates to the ui that's
something we'll we'll try to to look forward to look towards um but we just don't have the bandwidth
to do it right now there's more important things to be doing in ui work at the moment
all right are we getting overleach or something cool like that uh
i don't i don't think so
oh this is one of those things it was it was a topic like a while ago almost happened
and i don't think it did
okay we're gonna take a little bit of break from gameplay and uh just crush through some more
questions because i'm so far behind still and uh so here's a node from the weaver tree to chew on
while i'm doing this um so this is uh an example of one of the styles of nodes that can appear in the
weaver tree so just getting a little more info there there's there's lots of nodes in there um
and this is an example of one of those styles
okay
uh i wanted to hop on my character to play around some but it's been moved to standard
and we can't wear half our items anymore because i don't have the cof any thoughts
um intentionals or an oversight yes so when you go to your stash there's a button on the top right
that lets you merge your stash contents which includes your uh faction ranks so click that
and you'll be able to use them no problem um i think the oversight is not making that obvious
enough i think it may have told you in like a pop-up but it's like it's one of those pop-ups
like stuff's moved to legacy and then you just like you're like okay uh and it it gets glossed
over or it wasn't in there at all one of the two
uh hey hey just curious about what we can expect from the central rework and what made you guys decide to
do so the biggest thing is that the cat there's a lot more um we went into this pretty in depth
recently on um on gazzy's podcast that we did so deep more details there i think um but as for like
what brought up this about was i mean you go look at the the current characters the current sentinels
that are being played and like the use of volatile reversal is like 99 for anything that's even remotely
competitive because it just did so so so much work but we were getting a lot of feedback people
didn't really like playing with it that much and it was just one of those things where they're like
trying to mitigate the bad play patterns that it has while just getting the most benefit out of it
it was just this like buff button that's kind of janky um so we wanted to turn it into a fun to use
ability that you were taking because you like the functionality and it was also powerful not that you
were taking because it buffed other things and because it was so far reaching it affected every
other ability in uh sentinel and so they all needed a huge some of them just number changes but some of
them functionality changes and um it caused a bit of a knock-on effect and we reworked like sigils is now
symbols and um there's there's some updates there as well to make less less busy work we're kind of
we're targeting the like the the fit and finish the play the feel that stuff a lot while um we'll
also try to make it a little bit stronger especially in game stuff uh hey mike i was wondering what's
your take uh what's your take about preparation time activities between echoes to specify a little
bit my question currently there are currently no break between echoes aside from crafting
which is quite light once end game is reached for example for me i like to blast for a couple hours
then having some kind of 15 to 30 minute break juicing content changing activities crafting yeah i think
we're we're starting to get a little bit more of that and i think there's there's there's a point
where that's there's like too much of that that we're trying to be careful about approaching too
quickly um but we're pretty far away from that still and um we're starting to get a little bit more
of that with the a little a few more options uh in crafting um and a little few more options in
planning with the the new uh woven echoes that's going to the monolith system so we're we're
i'd say we're leaning a little bit towards a little bit more of that but not a ton
all right have you touched upon loot dropping off screen it's difficult to play dot and turret builds
um nothing specific really to share uh
oh i miss peasant dev peasant dev you subbed like 20 minutes ago i apologize thank you very much um
um as far as loot dropping off screen there's we are trying to address some instances of uh of loot
being missed in certain situations um but i don't have anything specific for like minions killing
stuff off screen right now for you uh do you fix the memory leak on scene change as far as i know there
are no current memory leaks in the uh development builds that are being used to prepare for season
two um i haven't personally experienced a memory leak in years um so i i i don't know if the specific
one you're talking about that was happening for you has uh been changed or not but as far as i'm
aware there are no active memory leaks in uh in the builds that we are testing uh do you at ishi plans
to come to gamescom and columbia game this year i don't think we are i would love to it was that was
i that was one of the most fun times i've had doing anything um i don't think we're coming um
because i haven't heard anything about it yet i feel like we were already planning it this far out last time
uh we talked about an epoch con some time ago jokingly when can we come and visit you well we're so
spread out that we use conventions as kind of like a meetup for the team um but i i'd love to
i'd love to i just want to do more conventions in general there's so much fun exhausting so much fun
uh how many people do you have working at each at the moment i don't know it is a triple digit
number a low triple digit number uh it it changes there's it's also it's tricky to nail down as well
because you have people who are like a company gets contracted in to come do a specific thing
now they might be contracted for like four years and they feel like part of the team they basically
are part of the team but technically aren't um so like they're or they're part of the team but not
working for 11th hour games they're contracted to work with us so it's um it's tricky to define
sometimes the exact number of people but the number of people that are like their day jobs is working on
last epoch it's a low triple digit number uh will you guys one day add falcon skins oh yes
oh yes if like of the i think the fastest selling cosmetic we could possibly make would be like a
phoenix falcon skin like that would just be like 100 adoption day one all right
uh hey mike can't wait for season start any chance the running all over the screen when surfing through
years uh surfing through your stash has been addressed uh yeah there's that's that was
something we were looking at recently uh how do you feel about not having a sense of completion on
last epoch's end game sometimes gonna catch them all maps something how do you feel about not having a
sense of completion on last epoch's end game something like a gonna catch them all like maps but for monoliths
like like like like having having something like this where it like talks about the monoliths completion
um or like
uh
i think i think they're having having like an achievement system would be really good for this
and we don't have that right now and yes kane i know it's still open see i can see you typing
all right ellie is my favorite aribg and i will definitely be buying new supporter packs
uh to support you guys however i do think cosmetics will be improved is there a consent
consensus consensus effort to improve them yes
oh uh we i uh okay look going back a little bit the weaver i was i was wrong it was cheeky
and i can't just tell me something else uh the weaver the weaver echoes do track your completion
for the weaver maps so there is that which is great um the new the new supporter packs the new
cosmetics in general i think that the the art team has really stepped up their game for these ones
uh some of them are kind of like oh my god really it's that good um so yeah i i'm excited to show
those off uh hey mike is it possible that minions persist between game sessions uh like when i exit le
i have minions last time i get auto summoned i maybe season two won't have it i'm sorry
all right control scroll wheel to navigate stash tabs that's a good idea
go put that in the suggestion channel it is not currently like that
all right would druid get some changes in season two or is it more next season thing
um i mean like every class gets changes to every season so yes and yes
oh fandom grip it's cool ring
if i can pick it up which there's improvements coming to that we just did yesterday all right
uh is there any plans to have skill icons on your board change color depending on what damage type
they do red for physical green for poison etc um we don't that's something that we've talked about
that we're like yeah we should really do that we should do that yeah yeah okay let's do that and uh
gotta find time to do that
in the past we've been hesitant to do it but i think we're coming around at least i have doesn't mean much
all right do you have plans to revamp the skill system no we love the skill system as it stands now
at least the number of specialization skills is limited since the ui can only show about four or
five um yeah it's it's the the the limit is not because the ui is set up that way the ui is set up
that way because of the limit um and we really enjoy that limit uh how expensive is it to make the 3d
models for items i don't know but it's i know it takes longer than what it costs to make the
functionality for them um what about infinite forging potential items something you can craft perfectly with
long enough time invested we're not interested in doing that we've actually been very careful not
to introduce those but yeah you know everything has the possibility nothing's set in stone forever
but uh unless something changes we we don't have plans for that at the moment
excuse me our reforge items not sure if that's official name yep perfect
classed as items or rare items can you slam them into unique with lp for example they are
kind of halfway between both so they are uh rare items in the sense that you can still craft on them
but they are set items in the sense that you cannot slam them onto legendaries
until you need to make a legendary with them
and there's other systems too that kind of rely on them not really being either and it treats them a
little bit differently i'll actually show you one of those in like 10 minutes i'll explain what i'm
talking about yeah
we'll come back to that uh will there be changes to timeline blessings or timelines area options um
there's there's some minor changes to some blessings but for the most part that's
pretty similar um like like there's some some some number scaling a few new a few new ones that were
in some and some got removed from some you know like some minor little things but no no big changes
no systematic changes there
uh hello mike happy friday happy friday glad to be here having fun this is a question heavy stream and
they are good questions today you guys are doing a great job so keep it up
um thank you very much for the sub like oh like rainy party welcome stay a while and listen or
talk you know whatever you want to do chatting is good um hello mike happy friday with the reduction
in dot we take an end game will there also be any changes to how much damage reduction we can get
four dots like on a passive unit items there's a little bit i think somewhere but not really it's
pretty it's pretty scarce still we didn't the reason we're doing this is because we don't want to put
uh too much more pressure on the other systems because we could have just put it in those places
in general but we want to keep we don't want this to be adding too much of a new defensive layer that
you're required to heavily invest in as much which is why we're doing it globally
oh well we're at 145 times so it's we are a little over half an hour behind in questions so i'm if you're
not if you're not seeing me answer your current questions because i'm half hour behind all right
will there be an uber avaroth race love the last one i really hope so um keep an eye on the news
uh with the addition of heart seeker uh have other skills been updated to add interactions for it
um it's more that heart seeker got interactions with other skills the because the style of ability
it is it doesn't fit great to be triggered by other things but it does well triggering other things
um so like for example it can trigger puncture um and it has it has a couple little integrations
here and there but not heavy heavy brogue's a tricky one with that in general uh all right
there's a couple items i think how about we have a new community item event a set created by the
community that would be really cool it'd be really cool um wouldn't be for season two
uh is fissure going to finally convert with smite conversions
oh i want to go check this so bad i think so i think it did
i do not remember
i'm pretty sure there's a wait wait for patch notes on that one sorry
all right if arena champions will be there oh um
speaking of arena champions will there be a way to target farm a specific boss instead of
keep retrying the arena over and over hopes of getting one specific arena boss um i don't i
these are good questions and i don't know the answers all of them i'm i want to say that there
might be a weaver tree node that that affects this or if they're not that's where i would put it
maybe that's the thing for a future patch for weaver nodes if it's not there yet
that's that's the sort of thing that would fit really well in a weaver tree node
uh is there going to be a battle pass type of things on the season always love that grind kind
of stuff um it's the style of thing that i think can be done well i think there's uh you know like
like a season's journey um and like depends on how you depends on how you frame it and present it
and uh depends on like if there's if there are paid versions of it uh like depending like really
strictly that you can't buy um more power in those sort of things you know like there's
there's there's a whole minefield of of all sorts of issues but i think that it does
give more than it takes um so it's something that i'd be interested in doing um but we don't have any
for season two uh anton eight and i always have to check a little squint a little bit thank you very
much for the sub that is that is 21 months we're getting close to two years there that is that's so
cool you see these huge numbers that pop up there's a 47 a 46 it's just wild so i really appreciate you
guys thank you um will there be improvements to bizarre price check less npcs not yet uh price
checks one of those things that is um you know it's like if we could wave a magic wand and it goes in the
game it would be in the game uh it's not something that we have the access to at the moment i apologize for that one
uh right will we be able to somehow use singularity unique idol at last please i mean you can yeah
like just will it be strong enough to use uh you'll have to find that out yourself i don't know if it's uh
like you can definitely use it already but i understand the sentiment being that the build
this builds that aren't strong enough to go with it uh will every class can use any skill
will every class can use any skill no uh like using outside the class no it is a strongly classed
game uh unequipping a weaver's will item and the way it unallocates the skill points is highly
frustrating as it can pull points from other allocated skills uh is this by design or are there
any changes to the way this works um it is by design um you can preempt it if you want by pulling
four points out and then re-leveling it those four points first uh forcing it to do the specific ones
you want which i know is not really the same thing um but it is it is it's not random it is specific
i know you didn't say random but it is uh not something that we're planning on changing right now
all right is mike on live or is this season two this is the live version of the game this is not
season two right now i'm sorry yeah after after carve went rogue last time i was given strict
instructions i had to delete it off my knife i wanted to focus on being able to answer questions and uh
worrying about if i was showing uh leaking anything extra was not worth the stress for me
but you know i think it is time for
i think it's time to show this one that i'm excited for
nope come on mike figure
there we go that's what i want to do okay so these nodes that we've that you in the trailer you can see
yeah kane sounds good um we're gonna stop taking questions at in seven minutes
or in 17 minutes so at 20 minutes before the stream ends um in 17 minutes from now we are going
to stop taking new questions so if you want to get a question to be answered because i have
seven pages of questions still to answer here uh we're gonna stop taking new questions and i'm
gonna try and barrel through these as fast as possible and i do apologize that i'm not gonna
get through them all i'll go a little over time probably um yeah so this is a node in the weaver's
tree um that when you when you put a point in the node so you put one point in uh in this node right
here and this slot up here opens up becomes unlocked you can then place any weapon or jewelry i think
yep that's the weapon or jewelry slot um you can place any weapon or jewelry in that slot
and whoa heavy 10 gifted subs the channel thank you very much that is that's congrats everyone got one
of those that's great thank you um yeah this is sweet this is this is this is really hype so it um
will then drop items that are similar to the item you imprint in the slot so when when i say you place
the item in the slot you um you put it in the slot but it doesn't it doesn't it's not removed from your
inventory so you have to keep the item in your inventory and uh it just takes a snapshot of what that item looks like
at that time so you can you you can put the item you can imprint the item into the tree
it takes a snapshot of the item you can craft on it some more if you want you can break the item you
can forge it onto something doesn't matter um the imprint stays where it is and uh and then
you get a chance to drop similar items to it thus specializing the type of gear you're finding so
you can be like i really want to find items like this item basically um so i was mentioning earlier
about set items if you put a reforge set item in this slot um it will most of the time
uh most of the time it will treat it like as as this as though that set affix just didn't exist
um and it'll just it'll just chaos that set affix instead um but sometimes it'll also treat it as the
set item the base set item so this doesn't let you duplicate reforge set items to get more set shards
super super quickly um but it does uh it does work with set that shard items reforge set items as
well well okay more questions let's go well this is all this is up there uh have you played the poe
freesia league uh and is there anything you would want to add from that into le i've been way too busy
haven't touched it yet at all um i don't think i will this time but maybe we'll see i do really like
it just so busy right now uh any plans on raising the minimum skill level i feel you hit max level
too early and then you lose big driving factor for motivation uh not for season two uh any is there
any plans during season two or after season two for more of a push for clan guild-esque system yeah
i think post season two there's a bit more of a push for a clan guild-esque system uh one thing to
be clear on this it wouldn't almost certainly not include a guild stash um or if it did it would be
regular trade rules for it uh last epoch i remember a bit back uh there was a reddit thread asking for
feedback on pet builds did this influence forge master forge guard i assume changes and what
takeaways came from that feedback oh i'm sure it influenced it i do not remember what got taken
specifically from it another sub uh vi gapped i put this capitalization that makes it easier to read
but thank you very much the sub ah vega pt yeah see there's there's capitalization that gets stripped
when it goes into the notifications window all right thank you very much
uh i know that the game works on photo proton uh will there be any plans to develop a native linux
version i know it was dropped a long time ago i don't know what the status of this is i really hope
so but uh i think it's basically just whichever one works the best hey rhymer thanks for highlighting
that one there hey bud hi glad to hear from you hope you're doing great
uh there was there was separate stories at start for each character yeah the intro intro videos um
completely shifted out or there'll be something in future like an act zero um i think i'd like to see
more videos like that tied to like side things you could investigate where you could like find like
a lore tidbit and it would like show up if you wanted it like you went to hunt those things you
could find them um they just didn't play with how we reworked the start of the game
any plans to have an have experience gained on max level characters be rewarding i mean it's like
one of the most rewarding things you can get at endgame so probably no more than it is already
uh not in the form of power creep maybe crafting mats gold gear could be endgame blessing tree
possibility um i mean it's what generates favor so uh you want as much as you can right now i don't i
don't think we're adding it in a second secondary scaling system uh will be element attack immune to
mobs will be element attack immune to mobs or always capped at 75 basically will mobs be some immune to
some elements like fire dragon should be immune to fire as an example i understand what you're talking
about yes we're adding more of this stuff uh some champions you'll see will show up and they'll be
like extremely resistant to fire that sort of thing it'll stay on them and they'll be like a fire
themed mob and that sort of stuff so yeah we are we're adding a little bit more of this on uh really
specific situations but just walking into endgame and zombies immune to cold and a goblins immune to fire
um is is not something we're interested in doing
uh where was uh any chance of getting the tab priority function work for whole categories
so you know to make separate rule for each of the tabs in the category
tab priority function oh i see what you're saying in the stash yes um oh that's a cool idea i don't
think we've we've we've tried that so not for season two uh did you guys remove the lagon safe spot i
sure hope so i don't know i don't actually know i would assume so if not i'll i'll i'll try and look
for that in hotfix i wish affix cards auto picked up when you walked over them especially with all the
ground effects you have to dodge in this game not unusual feedback it's not something we're planning for
season two uh is there any plans to allow casting and moving with wasd not specifically um
it it's something that we might consider um yeah so the rest of the question is spells locking you
with was he feels really clunky and for the most part defeats the purpose we we there was no way we
could have done that for season two that just there's no way um with when we decided to put it in and when
season two was scheduled to launch there was having that functionality to change to every single skill
at that point development was uh a fool's errand um it we would it would require us reworking the casting
and functionality of every single ability and so so many nodes that affect the functionality there as
well that it's it's um we'd have to be really 100 certain that we wanted to do because it is
every ability that's been created in the game has been created with this understanding that that's not a
thing you can do um and adding that in now is such a mammoth change that it's uh daunting to say the
least all right uh hey mike i'm really thrilled with the play the new season i understood uh class
specific idols will be craftable is this the case yes you say yes i want my adorned aftershock idols
unless my aftershock wearbear will be stronger yes um class specific idols are the only idols that are
enchantable i'm like sorry if this has been asked recently that's quite all right but is there any
new info on the ability to select specific uniques with the loot filter the current requirement level
base is very limiting um i thought it this is where i'm like i didn't do that already
i guess i guess obviously doesn't
maybe i'm thinking of uh
i might be thinking of um in the in the in the in the bizarre
i can picture a list of picking and picking uniques out of a list i might be picturing the
bizarre list i'm sorry 50 50 on that one um i hope so i'm back to making the same question
lol mocks at 200 hoped hopped on my game server months ago and said i'm down for dragon class
uh you guys want to actually play a dragon yes uh is this something you guys talked about since then
and yes i still have the proof yeah keep that proof hold on to it
um i i don't have any info on potential upcoming classes in the future anything like that
um i would love to i think it's super cool um yeah i think there's i think there's clear precedent
for this being just fun you know and we love adding fun things to the game so uh who knows what the future
will bring but i i keep pushing for it because i'd love to see it uh how much of a dps boost
uh just having a nice beer to give you it's it's more of a defensive boost than anything it's some
extra padding
okay there's the there's the still 33 minutes behind mark oof uh will we be able to filter by
roles within the range of a tier for an affix or any way to filter within a specific unique uh
uh i should have looked up you know i will look up filter changes for either tries or aaron's podcast
and uh we will uh we'll get some more details on filter specifics for those
um or maybe i'll see if i can find them out for next week but i don't i don't know the details of
what's changed for filters well enough to talk about them right now i'm sorry i didn't work on that this
patch a quick question about heart seeker will only the first arrow have a chance to inflict
ailments or can each subsequent hit inflict ailments each hit can still inflict ailments just the same
as the first one um it goes nutty uh any plans to change stash tabs reset feels so much worse to buy
dozens of them every time than permitted paid stash tabs in the permanent paid stash tabs in poe
we're we're not currently interested in having uh a paid system for this what i'd really like to see
is a this is not something season two but something that i will be pushing for um i think it's getting
suggested enough that it's a possibility is a um a template where you can as you buy new tabs it'll
be like auto add to the template and it'll just like auto pick the next one in in your list of templated
tabs and it'll just populate as you buy them
um since symbols of hope was shown could you show how the legendary ring related to his sigils is now
also how does idle with sigils duration change um
i don't know how the idol changed the the ring is still it's basically it's the same thematics but just
going about it a different way so it uh it's more auto casting i think it changes the interval between
auto casts um and increased effect or something like that it's it's like the two nodes that don't
make any sense in that ring anymore the two mods on that ring that don't make any sense anymore are
just like tweaked versions of the same thing um i can't remember exactly how they were cheap tweet but
it's it's it's it's more conditional infrequent automation just like the ring was before
all right do you have any plans for blade dancer in the future yep uh not huge changes i think it's on
the list for a new ability um i think it's still missing one
i'd love to see a little a little a little touch of two-handed support in there that's my that's my
dream there uh can we see any changes to the visual cap for debuffs like bleed or poison some builds
uh canon will go above a thousand stacks and right now we can't see if any change
to the build has made a difference um
i don't think we've changed that i think it's i think that's more of a like why why have we let
a thousand stacks of something go up more than anything else but um
maybe i think that was done we're like no one can get above a thousand uh so maybe
putting it to four digits probably wouldn't it wouldn't break anything horribly i'm pretty sure
it's just like the ui is just it doesn't look great at four digits so we just capped it at three
type thing uh all right any plans for fourth mastery for regular classes yes not in season two uh what will
happen to double health stout idols in my stash once the patch hits and double health affix is no
longer possible one of the flat added health on that will change to a different affix i don't
know if it's health regen or stun avoidance or something like that like it's a different similar
themed affix but it'll change
a new character stats ui when i remember you mentioning it being worked on no eta but yes it
is still being worked on slowly very slowly uh hey mike it's already been mentioned that the new
weaver stuff interacts with cof is the only cof rank perks or is that there are also some added
synergy with prophecies too it's that like when the weaver drops items when when the weaver's
will tree drops items like for example with the node that i'm showing right there
that one um the if you have something on your uh circle of fortune that interacts with drops it
interacts with those new drops as well so if it's like you get more drops you get more drops
uh old volatile reversal was fun with a lot of skill expression but it wasn't a buff wasn't a buff button
yes is there any plans to bring back old vr in some other form
the i would say the new vr has room to play the way you want it to play um
there's there's room for the new vr to to have a high skill ceiling and how you play with it
uh all right any plans to allow arena from okay we're cutting off questions uh so no new questions
so if you you you have like uh if you have like 10 seconds to slap any new questions you want in
here um but other than that we're going to stop taking questions here so i can just try and get
through most of these um one that just got posted that doesn't have a tag that i just answered
uh all right uh any plans to allow arena from level one as an alternate level in quick action
not really no uh aspiring game deliver what skills do i need to build work to build to work for ehg um
it depends like we've gotten to the point now where you need to be fairly specialized
um in a specific field to to to work at ehg um so getting uh really good at a specific skill would be
my would be my advice um a general like all around dev is something we do higher um but usually you need
a fair bit of experience now to uh to have a shot because even when we post like not senior roles we get
people applying that have so much experience and it's unbelievable how good these people are is crazy
um there's there's there's been some some people have done interviews that i'm like
how how can we only hire one of these people i think um so yeah it's it's quite competitive um which is
great and it's uh
uh i i would say yeah pick pick us pick a specialty and and try and focus on that um
and if you if you're completely if you're working on projects try and complete projects
um if someone's like i've got these six different prototypes that each do something cool that i want
to show you i'm like someone's like here's a link to a game i released i'm like oh cool let me look at
that so yeah my two pieces of advice uh different take on the stash tabs is there any way to change
the price for different factions uh because you can change factions it doesn't really work great
because you could just build up on one switch and then buy them all um yeah you mentioned tagging them
as well so only using that faction again the complexity is a little high for i don't think that
the cost is for what most people are using are in in almost all situations there's some outlying
exceptions here but in almost every situation i think the cost is low enough that um reasonably
playing cof there's not really a big need to have 200 stash tabs and and if you are playing to the
point where you're getting that need you've got the gold for it anyways so uh
i i it's not something we're currently looking at very hard uh there's a lot of empty space in the
character creation screen are there any new base classes cooking behind the scenes are all the devs
working on refining and adding current class masteries um the like the big thing with a class
pipeline there's there's two main categories in the class pipelines it's the like the the art side of
things so the visuals the animations the models all that sort of stuff um and then there's the like
the functionality stuff where like the skills and all that sort of stuff i can tell you i because i
work on the skills side of things um there's no work actively being done on new classes for
uh for new master like new skills for new masteries right now where we are still focusing on existing
ones and new or new classes um but that doesn't mean focus can't change
all right hi mike will will be the glitch during the lagoon fight when the tentacle blocks the
minions companions other players outside fixed for the new season i i sure hope so um
you may you may i i don't know i have the last time i tried it
uh was last time i fought lagoon was on live last several times i fought lagoon was on live actually
at least with a pet i've been playing a lot of marxon so it doesn't matter
uh heart secret is great any chance we can get a tool tips added to minion abilities
lets us know what it scales off of and the internal cooldowns for these moves um
uh i'll tell you this they they they don't scale off attributes the they get the stats from the
minion themselves so you don't worry about the attribute scaling um as far as getting cooldowns and
stuff some of them have that if you hold alt on the nodes that they're affected by some of them
get that actually uh like this oh
people should i agree let's do that let's get it done
uh i was really hoping that would just show the tool tip there if i held if i held all there didn't
do it played myself uh do you consider the possible i'd love to i think do you consider the
possibility to end prophecies manually outside of the monos to not skip slash lose drops we've got
something for this
all right check it out here's some here's some gameplay playing playing the new heart seeker build
he's been off a little too much that he can chew oh no he's formed he's going he's can he survive he
he's pulling out oh he died look at all that great gear on the ground he's lost it all it's just gone he died
oh wait never mind it's fine there it is all good
yay um
so we're we're not uh we're not completely fixing the problem yet um but we're we're putting a band-aid on it
uh this is actually pretty sweet it works it works it works well uh it handles most of the really
pain point situations um but it is uh it's it's not i the question is specifically asking about prophecies
and huge huge drops and all sorts of stuff um so it doesn't quite fix the problem because um
you know you kind of what you have to do is hide all the all the tags of the prophecies
issues so we are going to keep looking at that it's still something we're keeping an eye on
um here i'll see if i can restart it somehow can i do this if i
show it again um there's also another leak in there too if you find it but
uh would you guys ever add pre-made basic loot filters yeah uh this is something that i would
love to do um i i really want it this is i i keep i keep mentioning this and talking about i really want
to add a loot filter um like share like share and sort search share and sort search share and sort
yeah uh functionality to that in game so you can just like find ones that other people have made in
the community because frankly the community made ones always end up being better than the dev made ones
in just about every game situation like this so um yeah i i'd i think having uh in-game sharing
system for them would be the ideal way to do it ways off from that though uh hey mike any teasers today
or in later streams for the remaining sentinel skill buffs uh we can talk about i think i think i put a
little bit of stuff in here today but not much we can uh we can we can play some other stuff later
i think i've shown all of the teasers for this one now
just gonna
there you go there's there's there's a bunch of stuff on screen while i finish these questions
we've got 15 minutes left and i'm gonna try and power through these last only three pages three
pages only of questions we have we have stopped taking new questions from from chat i apologize
um just because we are flooded with awesome questions um and i don't want to be here till midnight
um but i am really enjoying this right now because you guys have great questions today
uh
any plans to add branches to existing skill trees yes um not in season two so much apart from some select
skills um are there any new forms of meta progression for players who'd like to play
exclusively hardcore kind of like a roguelike um i mean yeah the uh the weaver tree progression
is a huge part of this of this patch um it's it's a huge meta progression system that's tons of fun
and lets you customize your end game experience um there's lots of drops lots of changes in the
content you're gonna be playing with it uh you'll you'll progress as you go through and get higher
tier woven echoes as well so like you'll notice the ui for the woven echoes is broken up into four
columns the ones on the right are much rarer and much harder to get and are much harder to
complete much better rewards as well um and so you'll be uh progressing through those as you get
more of them and get farther into it i would call that a meta progression because you can use them
on multiple characters as well those are shared the echoes the woven echoes are shared in your stash so
like they're not they're not physically located in your stash when we say shared in your stash
it's that all characters that share a stash have access to the same ones
um that was a raining party i missed thank you very much appreciate y'all uh would you love seeing
would you really love seeing ui mtx's like different designs and themes uh this is something we've gone
back and forth on so many times uh i'm currently on the side of yes i would love to see that um
um do i think it's gonna happen anytime soon probably not uh love your loot filter creator any
uh any improvements coming its way label size sound effects mini map icons you not much there's
some little things you can uh you can change the size of all of the labels on the ground with the ui
scaling because it is a global ui scaling i'd love to get that split out but right now it is all all
together all right hi can you add dps meter so the puppets buy the arena no sorry uh can an item
have multiple set shards added no single set shard per item once it becomes a reforged set item by
adding a set shard to the item it is no longer eligible to receive set shard affixes uh for
example a belt with pebbles pockmarked sash and isidora's binding tomb binding uh if so does it count as
both sets no it does not it does not work you can only have one set shard on any item and to be
clear um the uh the two rings that are part of a single set static touch and something else that i
can't remember that couch is a good one um also getting nerfed uh rate limited on the uh on the
ward gain i think it gains more ward but it's rate limited that's what it is anyways um you you
cannot put both of those on a single ring either it's just one set affix per item and each set item
has one fixed set affix that it always gives all right are there any plans to add special stash tabs
like unique or set vague plans i would say um this is something i was talking about in the past with the
new um i've talked about this i said there's something coming for uh i kind of teased this before
there's something coming for uh the weaver system that's going to allow us to do like a unique tab
easier this is this imprinting thing that i've been talking about so by allowing us to like imprint
items into the into the slots but still keeping that item usable um this lets us uh i just saw a
question i'm not taking new questions i swear but i just thought i'm gonna answer anyways does the
imprint node work with uniques yes it does work with uniques and set items um they do have a chance to
no longer be set they have a chance to like re-roll into uh non-unique items when they do drop those
so like they don't always drop as uniques but can drop as uniques um so yeah this is that this is what
i was talking about with being able to uh have new tech to to do a unique stash tab better this is this
is what i think we can leverage that with uh will the lizards be staying or going staying there'll be
fewer lizards and they will drop fewer items however they will drop higher quality items
um so they'll still be uh like big hype explosions all sort of stuff um but a little bit less crazy
with a little bit better items um just kind of tweaking them into ranges but yes they're sticking
around they're happy to be here and ain't going anywhere uh do you have plans to look at uniques
that are underused or have too limited use cases yeah we do we touch on those every once in a while
um sometimes sometimes it's just like a new skill gets added and suddenly unique becomes amazing or
you know there's there's things that have incidental knock-on effects a lot especially with uniques
um and and we have touched some of them we kind of go back and update a few of them every time
uh the goal is not to have every single unique in the game have a top tier end game build that goes
with it that's that's never going to happen there's too many uniques and too few builds that'll be top
tier so there's we do like having them have a clear use case and sometimes that's like okay this is an
amazing leveling like fire starter torch no one's putting that in an end game build not really unless
it's like a challenge or something like that um but leveling as a leveling item it's the go-to leveling
item for so many classes um and so like even though it doesn't have this like place in the end game
it has a really clear place in the game and so we're um i think we're trying to get more items
to have their own place in the game but uh not necessarily all of them as super powerful end game
options the the legendary system in general is supposed to encourage that a little bit more i
think it does a pretty decent job at it uh is there any changes to movement skills uh as just like
sweeping changes overall not hugely um i'm sure lots of them got tweaks uh how difficult do you
you think the new uber is compared to the hardest challenge currently in last epoch
this is a really tricky question to answer because technically the hardest challenge in last epochs is
one google corruption um just one followed by 100 zeros but or whatever the highest number we can
physically put in there based on the data type it is it's probably an integer
um and so it's it's it's probably less difficult than that but of like compared to seriously
completable things or fixed difficulty contents it's significantly harder
all right circle but at the same time we are like raising the floor on what characters will be
so like i think more characters will have the shot at taking him down um but it will be extremely hard
like in unless you're like unless you have current abroth like on farm you're not gonna have a shot at
beating uber abroth i think unless you're willing to buckle down
uh forgot to ask circle of fortune changes prophecies are nice but lenses have a bit uh leave a bit to be
desired particularly around targeting item bases and specific affixes yeah so there's um
there i can't remember exactly which lens type we took out but we've we've alleviated some of the
pressure that lenses have and restructured some of the the rates on uh like costs for certain prophecies
and what they get out of them so like we've we've tweaked some numbers and um pulled some pressure
off a few of the spots and system but nothing major sweeping changes uh are you open to drastically
change the weaver's tree each season to give it new flavor or is it mostly set in stone i it's not set
in stone especially not the first version of it i think maybe if we're like 10 seasons down the road
and um like the weaver's trees in a great spot uh you'd probably see very small changes each patch but
it's one of those things that it's it's prime for changes it's the way it's set up it loves it loves
being adjusted uh will we have better quality of life for cof prophecy re uh re-rolls especially the
animation of re-roll takes a long time when you spend 300 000 favor at once i don't know um
i think it's a good i think it's a really good idea i think it's a really good suggestion especially
speeding up those those animations um but i don't know i'm sorry we're only 26 minutes behind we're
catching up all right oh we're almost actually at the end of the uh i guess we stopped taking
questions about 20 minutes left in this chat so there's only six more minutes of questions
i love the room master and unique design in the whole arpg genre are there any bigger changes planned
for that class uh i wouldn't say massive changes we're nearly 13 thank you very much for the sub
appreciate it appreciate it uh that's pretty great that's really um i remaster is still pretty fresh
compared to some of the other things out there so i don't think we are targeting it heavily right now
um but i mean everything's on the list it's just where it sits on that list i think there's i think
there's other things that are higher on that list like i'd say lich necromancer uh most of primalist
is probably higher on that list right now um yeah
uh what are the inherent advantages of abilities that deal multiple types of damage like smelter's wrath
and disintegrate um well as as we start to add finally start to add um enemies that have really
specifically high defenses to specific to to individual um element types those will um have a better time
in that situation uh will the merophage sword gain set champion affixes uh no because you can't you
can't shatter champion affixes off of a uh because they're sealed affixes and you don't get the shards
from sealed affixes so it'll never shatter one of them for merophage and the set ones uh just don't
work you you just can't put set you can't make a unique into a set uh like a unique set legendary
doesn't exist so it will not pull that uh that mod it'll just ignore it because when yeah
also i also i think when you shatter a reforge set item you don't get the when you use a shatter
stone on it you don't get the set shards that way anyways either you only get them when you
shatter them via the mechanic at the end of the tombs
all right will pets be able to pick up gold not in season two
we are coming we're coming right down to the end of stream here i think this is where we start this
that's all the questions i have recorded um at near the end of the stream i do
want to uh go a little bit a little bit of housekeeping if you stick with me for a minute
here uh new release date april 17th
uh twitch drops and supporter creator are moved to april 17th to 21st so they're shifted so it makes
sense with the launch um last season supporter packs also being shifted so it makes sense for
the launch still so you got a couple weeks of overlap before they're removed um so may 2nd last season
supporter packs will be uh going bye-bye um the last two tour dates for our podcasts with um
with try and aaron slash frosty have been moved to april 8th and april 11th respectively um so we're
kind of just pushing everything back about two weeks from where it was uh not exactly perfectly two weeks
on all of them but yeah so um new release date 17th twitch drops 17th to 21st
old supporter packs going may 2nd uh podcasts on the 8th and 11th of april
well tons of awesome stuff there we are at time and this has been a wonderful stream i know i didn't
actually play much i don't think anyone here wants to actually see me play i think we want to hear me
talk and so i think this went well um if you if i did not answer one of your questions and you would
like me to answer it i do apologize it was not intentional um we we do have a discord channel that
ask the devs channel that i hang out in a lot uh we have some great community members in there as
well that will answer the questions that have been answered before um so please head on over there to
ask questions um we're also pretty active on our socials so like reddit our forums um random youtube
comments i'll pop into sometimes for fun uh yeah
whoo i think that's about it i knew anyone got anything cool they want me to say before our
sentence um i had a great time i hope you did too i'll be back same time same place next week so i
got one more stream with all y'all next week uh i'm not sure we're doing on the fourth we'll see
uh something else i think is happening on the fourth that uh i don't know i don't know we'll
come to that when we come to it but next next week i'll be streaming as well um yeah i had a great time
let's let's go see if there's someone we can go say hi to who's who's out there streaming right now
oh there's someone i haven't seen in a while
a ton of people streaming last epoch right now this is so awesome
so cool i love it i love seeing people streaming last epoch it's i don't know what it is
i do know what it is i'm just crazy biased
uh yeah we'll be back next week hope you enjoyed yourselves everybody
drink lots of water have a great time bye