I'm going to go to the next room.
I'm going to go to the next rooms.
I'm going to the next room.
wizards!
The police have returned a notch!
But my choice from a tornadoes test hiding it through someone's Emergency!
because I couldn't complete a phone number...
I'm dying a thousand times of wasting time very soon than I thought Iên had started bagging the weekend.
The disease andえば patch will be the biggest update we've ever made.
This update we have ever made to Diablo IV since it has launched.
Our focus on season 4 is to really make a lot of evergreen updates to the core systems
of Diablo IV.
In season 4, we're ramping the intensity across the seasonal and eternal realms through
a collection of new activities aimed at ensuring the moment to moment gameplay experience is
as exciting and rewarding when how it comes to sanctuary.
Season 4, item changes are some of the biggest changes we've made to Diablo IV thus far.
We've never done anything like this.
We are fundamentally changing how you engage with items, how you upgrade them, and along
the way, solving a lot of things that we've seen continually from our community, we agree
with our pain points of our existing item system right now.
So in this new itemization system, we're focusing on narrowing down the scope of the base
affixes.
They're going to be a lot simpler, they're going to be fewer in number, so you can much
more easily parse whether this item is useful for you, and if it is, then you can take it
and further upgrade it and customize it to your own specific build.
Tempering is a new system that allows you to really customize the gear that you find.
In order to temper, you will need to go to the blacksmith and then choose the recipe that
you wish temper from, and then a random affix from that recipe will be attached onto your
gear.
These recipes can be found from almost all of the content throughout sanctuaries.
So you will actually be looking for tempering recipes that go directly with what you're
envisioning, maybe you're thinking, I'm going to play a frost sorceress.
There are also going to be recipes that are more generic and maybe are just generally
good for the sorceress, but you'll be able to choose which one you think is going to be
most powerful with the build you're making for your class.
You're making a pretty radical change to the codex of power in this season based again
on the feedback that has been coming from our players.
Now every single legendary in the game will be entered into your codex of power so that
you can continually imprint the best possible version of that legendary onto your gear.
So going forward, there will no longer be carrying around all of these aspect crystals
in your inventory.
It's all going to be in the codex of power.
So part of the final system that we have is going to be greater affixes.
Well, it's a greater affix.
Well we want to keep it compelling that there are some drops that are even better than
the others when you're trying to get the perfect build at endgame.
Because of this in World Tier 4 and only in World Tier 4, when an ancestral legendary item
drops, there's a chance the affixes on it can roll as greater affixes.
These will roll with bigger values that are normally available for that affix.
Greater affixes are fairly rare, but they're not impossible to find.
While leveling up, you're going to be able to find upgrades much more easily with this
new system.
Another part of itemization is going to be master working.
Now this is something really intended for that very high endgame, again, World Tier 4.
This is where a player is going to take an item.
He has the affixes that they won on it, but now they go through a process of upgrading
those affixes, getting even higher values on them.
Master working really starts at level 100.
Once you've already completed your build and found some of the best items, you're going
to be able to test your build against the powerful enemies of the pit.
The pit is a new endgame system that has been added in this season that is going to challenge
players that feel that they have largely maximized their build.
By pushing into more difficult tiers of the pit, you're going to be able to unlock
rare crafting materials to master work your gear even further.
You're going to have to play some of the hardest content in the game, but once you do,
if you're successful, you can go and make those affixes even stronger.
In season 4, we're ramping the intensity of the health tides through the inclusion of
a variety of new activities, the first of which is a doubling down and rise of the cultist's
presence throughout the tide.
We're going to be running through the health tides, saying the cultist is conjuring
up swarms and swarms of demons, adding to that sense of manic and chaos that they're
pretty well known for.
The other archetype that we're adding is the presence of the Doomsayers, who were unfortunate
enough to be caught out into tide and basically just lost their minds to all of the mania going
on around them.
And lastly, rounding out the new activities are just the inclusion of the iron wolves.
They're finally joined the fight.
It could no longer stand in the sidelines, seeing the health tides and the health forces
intensify their assault on sanctuary.
As season 4 players engage and progress through the cult of the wolves, seasonal activity,
they'll earn honor with the iron wolves, unlocking access to a vast assortment of rewards to
accompany and empower your season 4 journeys.
In the updated health tide for players who are able to stay alive long enough, they'll
be paid a visit by the Hellborne.
Former heroes of sanctuary who have aligned with the forces of Hell to attack the allies
they once aligned with.
Players who are able to take down the Hellborne will be acquiring the materials they need
to engage with the new premier Haltide activity, the accursed rituals.
Located in the Haltide, these accursed rituals are pretty much just botched rituals from the
cultist that players will be kickstarting for themselves, drawing the intention of all
the nearby Haltide monsters in this kind of all-out battle.
One of my favorite themes for these ambushes is the Hellworm.
It's literally a giant hell slug beast that emerges from the ground, but it spews out a
whole bunch of mobs at you.
If you're able to survive that, you'll be paid a visit from the Blood Maiden, our brand
new Haltide mini-boss and one of the ultimate challenges in the new experience.
So I think I'm actually most excited about this season because of what you're able to
do with your old characters, how they can integrate with this new item game and take
them to new levels of power with this system.
I think that the best part of this update is that you're going to be really empowered
to build the character that you want to play.
You're going to be able to pick custom affixes and enhance your character in a lot of new
and interesting ways.
Happy Friday Diablo Community.
Welcome to another Diablo IV, Campfire Chat.
I am Adam Fletcher.
I'm joined here by a very familiar face, Mr. Adam Jackson.
Hello, hello.
The atoms have invaded.
We've taken over.
We have taken over.
We actually are joined by one additional person and this person is tuning in, patching in.
I don't know what they're phoning in.
I don't know.
From Albany, Blizzard Albany.
That's Mr. Dan Tangue.
Dan, would you like to introduce yourself?
Yeah, sure thing.
Hi, I'm Dan Tangue and I'm one of the lead seasons designers for Diablo IV and we've
got a lot of exciting stuff to share with you.
Awesome.
Great to hear from Dan.
Dan is kind of like melting in Albany.
I believe it's very, very warm up.
It's actually warmer there than California, which is kind of crazy.
It is.
Look at this.
Adam and Adam.
Ooh, I love it.
We did it.
No more Joes.
Jo is where is Jo by four, not here.
He's actually on vacation.
That's the reason why he's not here.
We have a lot to talk about today.
We are actually going to be talking about season five in the PTR and we do want to, there's
been a lot going on with Diablo IV over the last couple of months.
Obviously season four is launched.
We had our midseason update last week.
We introduced pets, which is really cool.
Adam, would you say that?
No one expected it, but we did introduce pets within season four.
And at the same time, we also had our release state announcement for Vessel of Hatred, which
is October 8th.
So lots and lots and lots of cool stuff that's going on with Diablo IV.
And we have more to share today, but of course with PTR, we do need to talk a little bit
of the housekeeping stuff to make sure that players are aware of it and when it's going
to start.
We have season five PTR actually starting next Tuesday and that is on the 25th.
It will run for one week similar to the season four PTR.
It is PC Battlenet only again.
It is just easier for us to be able to get builds up and get things out and get feedback
in really quickly when we have it on PC Battlenet.
So that will be going live next Tuesday.
Everything that we're talking about today will be in a blog that will go live after the
stream.
And as well as patch notes will be going live after the stream and they're pretty beefy
and themselves are in it.
I don't know.
It's Friday, you guys.
So we haven't done a Friday stream in a while.
It's been a long while.
For feedback though, we will be opening up our PTR forums for players to actually be able
to submit feedback.
So the Diablo IV forums will have a special section for PTR.
And then separately, if you do want to leave feedback on other avenues such as Reddit
or the community sanctuary discord, places like that, we most definitely end up combing
through all the various ways of players being able to provide feedback specifically from
that end.
For this PTR, we will note that this one will be a little different than season four in
regards to how you can start off characters.
There will still be character boosts like what we had with the season four PTR.
I believe it's actually moved to a different city.
I can't recall.
I think we had it in Kyovashod before and I believe it's in a different city and I don't
recall which city it is.
It's in the blog though.
But all that information will be there after the stream.
Separately, we did incorporate a character copy feature, but we initiated this character
copy already.
No one knows this, but as of yesterday, characters were copied from your accounts over to PTR.
So it gives you a little bit of a variety of being able to take over some of those characters
that you've already built out.
Or if you want to, you can still use the character boost.
I will note, we do want players to be experiencing in a variety of ways like whether using your
current characters that we're copying over or if you're using some of the character
boosts, we do recommend, or if you want to level up, level one too.
That's another option as well.
It allows us to get feedback from all different aspects.
So we do recommend trying it out in different ways and providing feedback of how things
feel, how things flow within the PTR itself.
So that is all the general housekeeping notes that we do have.
Oh, and I will say that I believe we actually did correct that codec's a power reset thing
as well.
Yeah, I remember that was that was a plaguing some people last season.
We did correct that.
So I won't reset.
I believe every single time you end up like creating a new character or boosting a new
character, I believe.
And then separately on the forums, we will have a known issues list because they're, you
know, it's PTR.
It's an early build.
So we want to make sure that people are aware of that.
And with PTR, you know, when we take in feedback, it's great for players to be able to
like write all various forms of feedback.
I will say by the time season five launches, we will try our best to get as much of that
feedback in.
If it's something that's like a massive like, oh, like a huge overhaul or something like
that, I wouldn't expect it in season five, but it is good to hear that feedback because
it might be something that we end up incorporating maybe in the future for like a future season
from that end.
Yeah, it's very useful.
So that helps us drive future decisions and even we did a lot of reaction to PTR feedback
in season four.
I remember right.
We did like a whole lot on our team at least and I expect the same for season five.
Exactly.
It's send it in.
It's very useful.
And then one last thing I do want to note is because players have probably seen when
season four is ending, which is currently in early August, you can see that kind of like
on your character select screen when you're jumping into the game.
I will note that season five is a little bit shorter of a season than what we've had
beforehand.
Season five itself will run until that October 8th date with Vessel of Hatred because Vessel
of Hatred is actually the start of season six.
So we did want to at least clarify, make sure because we've heard a lot of those questions
of like, hey, is like, is Vessel of Hatred hitting the middle of season five, things like
that.
So we did want to note that from that end.
And now for the housekeeping notes, I know a lot of players want to hear about season
five in itself.
And so Mr. Dan Tangway from the sweltering city that made some of the Albany will be
walking us through season five.
Yeah, absolutely.
So yeah, let's dive into the new features on PTR for season five.
Just to give you a little bit of context, you know, we did some early brainstorming
for season five and we knew that, you know, we needed to build out the end game.
So end game, you know, we've heard y'all that end game is very important.
And season four, we added the pit into the end game and some people have been playing
a helltides into the end game, but we still want to expand the end game a bit more, right?
So if it's an end game activity, we definitely need something that's for awarding and very
replayable.
We also wanted to make something with a lot of monsters.
I mean, monster density and just entering that feeling of flow states really important
for players.
We needed something that had stakes and we wanted players to push their luck.
And finally, we really wanted to return to hell, you know, previous Diablo games let
you return to hell after you defeat the big boss, but Diablo four hadn't done that yet.
And so with all those goals in mind, let me introduce you to the infernal awards.
Now, let me give you a quick summary of what the infernal hordes is.
It's a wave-based gameplay mode with survivor-like choices in between the waves and it'll
culminate with an all new boss encounter.
And then the rewards build on top of itemization 2.0 that came in season four.
So now how do you go about confronting the internal hordes?
How do you get back to hell?
I think we can queue up some footage and then I'll talk you through some of the ways you
get back to hell.
All right, first off, you're going to unlock, you know, the activity for hell with a
brisk eternal quest line starting at World Tier 3 in Zarbonzett.
That's where you need to go in the PTR.
Now, you need a new type of key called a compass, which you can see down in the inventory
below here.
And like Nightmare Dungeons, the compasses all have a starting monster difficulty and a
number of revives.
And there are eight levels of difficulty with escalating challenge and rewards.
You can see it's a very Nightmare Dungeon-like flow here.
And then compasses can be upgraded to higher tiers with all new consumables called Abyssal
Scrolls.
So you'll get a chance to play with all these new features when you're in the PTR.
But let's really talk about the gameplay itself.
And I think we've got some footage of the wave-based play that we can show off here.
First off, going to have a lot of monsters.
Now you have one monster here.
This is the start of wave 1.
And so you defeat this Aether Fiend.
And it's going to drop something called Burning Aether, which is a new currency.
This new currency is specific to health.
And you use it to unlock the spoils of hell at the end of a run.
And at the end of each wave, there's going to be what's called the infernal offer.
So let's get through this wave and we'll take a look at the infernal offer.
Now you see these hands reaching out from hell itself.
And they're tempting you with a choice.
You're going to choose the form of your destructor.
You're going to pick a boon and a bane that impacts the rest of your run.
And so now you've chosen a boon and a bane.
And that's going to modify the gameplay that comes up next.
And so here, you're jumping into one of the new activities that also unlocks Aether in
this.
And this is a soul spire.
It's pretty similar to a hell spire that you'd see in Hell Tide.
And you have to kill a number of enemies within that ring in order to be able to earn an
Aether.
And you can upgrade soul spires from the infernal offer as well, if you like.
And then finally, what you need to do is complete the number of waves in order to be able
to confront the boss.
And so you see in this particular run, you're at five of five waves.
So you are just about ready once you defeat this wave to go confront the new bosses for
the infernal hordes.
So we'll finish collecting our Aether here.
And our last number of enemies.
And I think we're good.
I think we're ready to go.
So let's take a look at our new bosses.
I think we've got some cool art to share here.
So these are the fell council.
They're going to be some familiar faces for Diablo 2 players.
They are resurrected versions of the council members from Diablo 2.
For those of you who didn't play Diablo 2, the council members were former high priest
of the Zachary room.
And they had promised to basically take care of Mephisto after he'd been trapped in the
soul stone.
And he'd been hidden down and harassed and tribuncle.
And of course, as it happens, Mephisto corrupted them both in mind first and then their bodies.
And they became demons who are just zealous and serve him without question.
And so we thought it was going to be really cool to be able to resurrect them and bring
them back for Diablo 4 and they fit great in hell.
We had to tweak their power sets a little bit to fit the D4 combat system.
So we gave them new titles and new looks to really reflect their combat specialties.
It's incredibly awesome to see these guys come back.
It's giving very nostalgic vibes of doing a bunch of, you know,
Durance of Hate runs for Mephisto and doing Meph runs and everything like that.
So it's really awesome to see them back in season 5.
Yeah, I agree.
Diablo 2 is certainly near and dear to our hearts here out in New York.
And yeah, we're really glad to have them back and we hope to see hopefully more returning
new faces in the future too.
So let's take a look at that boss encounter now.
So I showed you a number of members of the Fell Council here.
We've actually built five of them in total.
But you're only going to fight three at a time.
Now we keep two in the hopper basically and we do that because we want to have a whole
bunch of replay associated with this boss fight.
And because we're only using three of the five, there's actually ten variations of this
boss fight.
You can fight randomly as you do your infernal run.
And so we're going to basically kill them off.
And once you defeat one, the fight will actually escalate.
Actually probably escalates even if you just take down a certain amount of health, if I
remember correctly.
And it escalates basically their attacks become more powerful.
And then they start really getting even more powerful kind of room clearing attacks towards
the end.
But we've defeated them here.
And this is the reward moment I actually wanted to talk through with you because this is
something that really ties in the itemization 2.0.
You've got several chests here.
And you've got a choice of the rewards you get at the end of your infernal run.
You can choose from a chest that contains all new legendaries and new uniques.
You can choose from a chest that contains all sorts of crafting materials including master
working materials.
So you don't need to go to the pit any more exclusively to get master working materials.
You've got a chest that allows you just to get a whole bunch of gold.
I know people out there are really asking for gold and this is going to be a good source
of it.
And finally, even though it wasn't shown here, you have a chest that guarantees a single
item with a greater effects on it.
And so we thought we'd want to try this out and see how people respond to it.
And we thought it would be pretty exciting, certainly, in season 4.
I'm really trying to get some more greater effects.
So I'd love to have this in season 5.
So yeah, let's take a closer look at some of the uniques you can farm from the infernal
run.
Since we're talking about rewards already.
So we're going to queue up some footage here.
So first up, we've got the basilisk.
And so this is going to be a new unique staff for druids.
And so when you hit an enemy with a nerf skill, it'll petrify them and deal physical damage.
So turning the monsters to stone, always cool.
But it's also cool that you can see see your target and boost your initial attack here.
So this one's pretty exciting for your druid players out there.
All right, next up, we've got the third blade.
Now, this is a unique sword for barbarians.
This one makes your weapon mastery skills be treated as core skills that cost fury.
Even though they deal a little reduced damage, this one's pretty exciting because now you
can start making all sorts of new builds that you've never seen before.
So we're really interested to see what the community comes up with here.
All right, next up, we've got the morta crux.
Now, the morta crux is a new unique dagger for Necro.
So when you consume a corpse, there's a chance that you'll create a skeletal simulacrum
that seeks out enemies.
And when it dies, it explodes.
So essentially, you're making a scally bomb when you consume corpses.
And so that's just going to seek out targets and explode.
I think that'd be pretty handy for my Necro this season.
So I'm looking forward to that one too.
Next up, we have the umba crux.
The umba crux is a new unique dagger for rogues.
So if you use a set or huge skill, you'll create a totem.
And if you hit that totem with an attack, it replicates any of the damage it takes.
It all nearby enemies.
And so it's a great way for essentially replicating and doubling down on the damage that you're
dealing in a particular area.
All right, next up, we've got the vox omnium.
Now, the vox omnium is a new unique staff for sorks.
And so when you cast a core skill, it's going to cast an additional two basic projectiles
based on the previous elements used.
And so this allows you to really start comboing your core and basic skills together.
And if you decide to have different elements associated with those core and basic skills,
now you can start casting fire and lightning and cold all at the same time.
So we're pretty excited about this one too.
And the final one we're going to share out here is actually a new set of boots that's
available for all classes.
And these are called raconoth's wake.
And so whenever you use an ability with a cooldown, you'll trigger a tongue twister, trigger
an explosion, deal in fire damage.
And so really, it's pretty straightforward.
You're going to bathe your enemies and flames whenever you use a cooldown skill.
So maybe I'm going to dust off my whirlwind barb here and slap them on and see how it
does.
So yeah, these are some of the uniques and legendaries that are going in to the infernal
hordes.
I think there are 10 uniques overall and over 20 legendaries that you can farm from the
infernal hordes.
So there's going to be a lot to chase down in there.
That's awesome.
Thank you, Dan, for like sharing going through all that stuff.
I know with players jumping in on PTR, especially for and trying out infernal hordes and everything,
what's kind of like the top things that you really want them to like kind of hone in on,
give feedback on, check on for PTR.
Yeah, absolutely.
We definitely need feedback on the PTR.
It's super critical to ensuring that the infernal hordes and all the rewards feel great
for when the season launches.
So here are some of the topics that we could use some help on.
First off, just how is the infernal hordes gameplay?
How do the boons and veins feel?
Which ones do you like the most or the least?
These are types of things that will help us fine tune that experience.
Similarly, how is it acquiring compasses?
Do you have too much to few?
How do you feel about upgrading them?
That could help us really dial in kind of the access to the infernal hordes.
We're also interested in learning how you feel about the difficulty and the gameplay
linked to the different tiers.
Like I said at the top, we've got eight different tiers of difficulty.
And so we have the ability to dial those in a little bit.
We want to make sure that players can really replay this over and over again as they push
into the end game much like the pit.
And then finally, of course, how are the rewards?
Which do you like the most or the least?
We can certainly make tweaks on the rewards to make sure there is enticing as possible.
Awesome.
And I know with the infernal hordes, this is another alternative because as you mentioned,
you can jump into it starting with World Tier 3.
So if you're actually leveling a new character, you can actually jump into infernal hordes.
And you're able to earn experience in here.
So you actually have the opportunity of jumping into Hell Tides if you want to.
You can jump into infernal hordes.
When you get to 85 or something like that, you can jump into pits.
So there's now more or nine dungeons, obviously, when you're upgrading your glyphs and everything.
So there's a lot of different variety now for being able to level up a character, especially
as you're going to that mid to late game.
The phase of your character's journey, you could say.
Yeah, something else to bring up for the rewards for the infernal hordes as well that I want
to clarify.
So Dan mentioned about, there's going to be uniques that are there that you can target
farming the infernal hordes.
There's actually going to be a group of uniques and legendaries that you're able to target
farm in that piece of content in the infernal hordes.
So you're also kind of somewhere out in the normal game works, you know, how you can target
farming unique from a boss, but you can find anywhere else in the world.
It's the same way here where you can get these new uniques and legendaries anywhere, but
you have a better chance, you know, if you're targeting them in the infernal hordes.
And this is the first time that we're doing this with a group of legendaries as well.
We have legendary powers that are actually able to be target-formed in the infernal hordes,
which is actually something a little bit new to the game.
So I just wanted to clarify that.
And in addition to that, we're also adding new uniques and legendaries to the rest of the
game as well in addition to this.
So there's actually a very large group of uniques.
I think this is over 50 or something.
Yeah, wait, there's over 50 new uniques and legendaries coming in to season five.
So we have a lot of coming.
It's pretty extensive.
A lot more to talk about there too.
Yeah, wait, this was just kind of a small preview of what people were looking at here.
And they'll be able to jump in more and actually check it out on PTR because all of them
will be present there.
And I know Adam is actually going to talk through a few additional ones here later.
But yeah, Dan, this is awesome.
Can't wait for players to jump in.
I appreciate you informing and providing all the new updates and everything.
It's exciting.
Yep.
From the sweltering heat of all the, I mean, I'm going to keep bringing it up.
They can't go school up there.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
I'm like, that's absolutely insane.
But we will be seeing Dan again here later, especially when we get into Q&A at the end.
But Dan, thank you again.
I think we're welcome.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Appreciate it.
We're going to jump into a little bit of some balance and class updates with the
chemistry out of Jackson.
So yeah, let's get to it.
We have a lot to talk about.
I think we have.
Yeah.
So the topic's going to be covering today.
We've got unique items.
We're going to be talking quite a bit about that.
We've got some updates to mythic uniques that are very exciting and near and dear to my
heart.
And then we've got your standard class updates.
A lot of stuff coming in season five.
One thing to clarify here is that we are going to be releasing the patch notes soon.
I'm not going to be going over every single class update because there's a ton of them.
Similar to season four, I'm really only going to highlight just one major thing for each
class on the stream today.
But you'll be able to see all the things that we're doing in the patch notes.
There's a lot.
So first, unique.
So we have some quality of life updates here, really targeting how you get unique.
That I'm pretty pumped about to announce here today.
So you can now target farm uniques from three additional sources.
You can target them from oval vendors, helltide chests and whisper caches.
These places where you've always been able to target farm certain gear slots and not
being able to get unique.
And you're wondering, well, why are you going to do that?
That's things.
Well, now you can.
And it's awesome.
I love it.
So here, just to give some more detail into how this works is basically when you open,
like, I'm just going to use helltide chests as an example.
If you want a specific unique weapon, let's say, you can just simply target the weapon
helltide chests and you'll be able to have a chance to get only unique weapons for your
class from those chests.
So when you're targeting a specific thing, you just go to the place that has that slot,
whether it's the oval vendor the helltide chest or the whisper cache, and you'll have
a chance to get unique that are targeted for that slot.
So it kind of adds, while you're doing your normal grind of doing the boss ladder, killing
the boss, you can also be collecting ovals, doing the helltides, doing the whispers,
and having a chance to target and get that unique as well from that content.
And in addition to that, this is also true for mythic uniques.
So I'll just give an example here of exactly how this works.
Let's say that you want to get, you know, Harlow can crest a shaco or and Arielle's
visage.
You don't want to target those helms.
You could be targeting helms from helltide, targeting helms, and, you know, when you
turn in your ovals to the oval vendor.
And every time if you get a mythic unique, you will get one of those two from that source.
Now also to clarify, let's say that you are targeting gloves for some reason.
You know, we don't have any mythic unique gloves yet.
Then if you were to get a mythic unique, you still can.
It'll just give you a random one instead, since you know, you can't target one in that
slot.
So a pretty exciting way to target kind of the things that you want while you're far
made.
Yeah, it's going to be amazing.
Yeah.
I know.
I know we've heard a lot of players going like, hey, you know, we do the end game boss
is a whole lot.
We're trying to, and you can actually find them just in the open world as well.
We've actually seen a lot of cases, especially with this past season where the players
are jumping into helltide and they're actually finding them there.
But now it's an additional, or additional options for players, which I think will be a
lot better for just overall finding some of the gear that everyone has.
As someone who for the last three seasons, my uniques have always come from the beast
and ice.
I am very selfishly invested in getting into the game.
Yes.
All right, let's talk about other unique updates here.
We're going to make a whole lot of updates to our unique items.
So I'm going to be covering a lot today.
We've heard your feedback and we're going to be doing some updates here to clarify before
I go into what the updates are.
You are going to be seeing these updates to like the way that we think about in our philosophy
are unique and how they work.
You're going to be seen on the PTR for the new uniques coming into season five.
Between the PTR and the launch, you'll be seen in the season five launch.
These updates to all the existing uniques in the game.
So in season five comes out, basically all the uniques will get these updates done about
to talk about.
But in the PTR, you're only going to really see this in the new uniques coming into the
game.
Yeah, there.
So now we can go on to the next part.
All right.
So the teams are talking a lot.
As many of you probably know in season four, we did our organization 2.0.
We didn't really update the uniques almost at all in the game, right?
We didn't do like a big pass, like cover, how they exist in tempering or anything like
that.
The teams been talking a lot about what is the role of uniques in Diablo 4?
How are they different from legendary items?
Because they're similar in that they both give you a legendary power that's really strong.
But how are they different?
And what do we want them to be long term?
And we've kind of landed on a few things here that I'm going to talk about.
The first one is that they're powerful and exciting items that kind of direct players
to builds, right?
So imagine you're a fireball sort.
We've got two uniques for you.
They really target you.
You're going to feel a lot better playing with fireball when you take them.
We want you to take these things and kind of level up your build.
There are moments of like very large incremental power where you feel like you're feeling in
your fantasy as a class.
The next one is that they're kind of pick up and play, right?
They're easy to evaluate the moment that you pick up the unique.
You know, you know whether it's a good one or a bad one.
We want this to be a little bit different from legendary powers where you know you pick
it up and you kind of go on a journey where you know you make it into something that's
really good.
A unique you know when you pick it up whether or not it's one that you want to keep or
one that you don't.
And then the last one, pretty obvious, but we're saying you know they're kind of more
rare chase items that players don't see very often.
You know when you're going through the end game you're seeing legendary powers a lot
because you know we have a lot of reasons to give you a lot of you want to upgrade your
codex.
They are the way that you can you know get greater affixes and temper and master work
them.
So there's a reason why you want to churn and look through a lot of them.
Uniques you do want to get a good one obviously, but not nearly as often as like a legendary
power.
So that aspect of their design.
So they are more rare they're harder to get but when you get it it's kind of like a more
exciting moment like did I get the perfect one and then if not you go and try and get
the next one.
So let's talk a little about our goals for the update that we're going to be doing here.
One of the things that we come to a lot that we talk about the team is this idea we I like
this quote of like players build their legendaries and players build around their unique
right.
Your legendary power is is very or your legendary items are very malleable.
You know the moment you get it you don't know yet if it's going to be the best in slot
item but it has a chance to be but they're also like able to fit in a lot of different
ways.
You can manipulate your their stats via you know enchanting via tempering and master working
and so there's a lot that you can do with the item once you've gotten it whereas unique
there are a lot more static right the the stats on them can't change.
You can't really manipulate them very much and sometimes they have maybe qualities to
them or stats are a little bit inconvenient and you got to figure out like how do I overcome
this this this little detriment or make my build into where it's a plus instead of a
detriment right like it's a fixed thing that you have to build around which is very different
than a legendary.
Also ideally we want players to run two to four unique in their build you know one of
the the difficult parts of this and I think we're going to be continuing to work on with
the balance and design of unique is that you know we want you to run some but we don't
want you to run all of them in your build right.
It's very easy to go one way or the other I can very easily make you run no unique and
I can very easily make you run like every slot is a unique by making the really really
crazy right.
We want these to fit in such a way that you're running some of them the ones that are applicable
to your build or maybe some spicy ones here or there that you try and you know like making
a special way to work with you but not all of them I would say right now like on live
in season four players are ready more like zero to two in their build so it's not as much
as we want which means that we want to update them to make them a little bit more attractive.
And another one is we kind of want to move away from these generic fits all build styles
of unique right.
One thing I know a lot players talked about in the past that we've had is that some of
our unique are just so generically good and this is particularly scary for us when it's
like what we call generic unique which is when we're every class can use it and so like
if every class can use it and every build can use it and it's better than like the build
specific or class specific stuff then it just becomes best and slot for everybody and
we've taken away your agency and your choice because you're just going to target this
item and ignore everything else right.
The only items in the game that we really want to to fit that role are like mythic uniques
where they're across all classes and they're so good but they're also extremely rare
so you're very excited to see them whenever you see one but all the other regular uniques
we don't want to fit that design space.
So we're going to be trying to move away from these ones and readjust them and redesign
them a little bit where they fit into all kinds of builds and kind of target something
that they're really good at or that's a little bit more unique about them and make them
really good at that and less generically good at everything.
It's funny because everyone's in the chat going like oh, Rip, Shaco, Rip, Shaco but
we just literally not.
We just, we just, we just, we just, we just, not, mythics is not what I'm there.
Different beasts here.
I'm talking about all your regular ones.
Yeah, yeah.
Shaco's still going to be just as good if not better honestly.
All right, so enough free-amble.
All right, what are we actually doing?
So we're going to be doing two big updates to Uniques.
The first one is we're going to be increasing the upper power of the unique effects and the
role range.
We're going to be doing an increase in the range from an average of 10 to 20 roles, which
I'll explain in a second.
And then we're also going to be increasing the upper power of like how much you can get
from the roles.
This is really just buffing pretty much most Uniques across the board to compete with
the new world of legendary powers that we live in since you know, they got extra power
juice to them.
Now Uniques are catching up.
So as an example here, I gave, you know, if an older unique like one on live gave you
around 40 to 80% multiplicative damage, that's going to go up to like 40, 100, maybe
120, maybe even higher.
Really, the mandate is as high as we can get away with without breaking things.
And then we're also going to be increasing the role range.
This is like the number of possible roles it can do from an average of 10 to 20.
So it'll be a little bit harder to get basically what we're targeting here is the discrepancies
out inside of the unique is a little bit wider where the difference of like a low role
in a high role is a little bit bigger, but the high roles are way better than they were
before.
So they're more exciting when you get them really good, but it's a little bit harder to
get there.
And the next one is going to be updating the affixes, the actual stats on the Uniques.
We're doing a pass on all of them and this is kind of what we're doing.
The first thing is we're changing their stats to fit with the season four updates, right?
We're doing the things like we did before, of simplifying stats, you know, getting rid
of super conditional things, making them as more generically understood and good.
We're also going to be adding tempering stats, we're open to really adding whatever we
want that makes the unique fit the fantasy.
So as an example here, you know, a lot of two-hand weapon Uniques have a problem where they're
all basically competing against bonus projectiles as an affix because you can just temper that
onto your weapons, right?
So when it comes to those kind of situations, we'll just slap the bonus projectiles on
that unique and now, you know, it's no longer competing in that way where we have to kind
of dance around it.
We can just put it.
We're also open to the idea by the way of breaking slot restrictions, kind of like we didn't
season two, so you can have bonus projectiles or other things on other slots, you know,
like Uniques are where we get to play a little bit and just really make something thematic
and cool and build the finding and so they have lesser restrictions than everything else.
And the other one is we're updating the stat power levels and the effects.
So the idea here that we're thinking, and this is particularly nuanced when it comes to
generic Uniques, but stats that kind of fit the theme or the fantasy of Unique, we're
going to be like way stronger than your normal stats, right?
So as an example, if you have a Unique that's targeting fire damage, maybe it's like a meteor
or firewall and the sorcerer, whatever it may be, you know, that plus fire damage can
be juiced up to be really, really high.
But stats that are more like generically good, like, you know, I don't know, attack speed,
max life, resist all, those ones aren't going to be juiced unless it fits the theme of
the Unique really well, right?
So we have an example here of one that has been a problem for us in the past, like kind
of want to go through how we would think about it.
I'm not going to say exactly what we're going to do here to Tvultzwill, but kind of give
you our thought process, right?
So Tvultzwill, as many of you know in previous seasons, was kind of a problem where it just
became best in slot for almost every build.
You know, the famous line we say is they was damage on pants, which was, you know, impossible
to get almost anywhere else in the game.
And turn out damage on pants was really, really good, right?
And also gave you damage reduction, one of the best stats in the game.
And then it also gave you a bunch of, it also sold resources in many ways for you as well,
right?
It gave you a bunch of resources when everybody became unstoppable, which wasn't too
hard to do.
So it was doing a lot of things at once.
It gave you a very unique effect with putting damage on a slot that you don't get it.
It also gave you resource, which is something that every class wants, you know, very heavily.
And Adam, it gave you three extra promotions.
And three extra post-shirts, yes.
Now that one, yeah.
That's all right.
But yeah, so, you know, the way that we would tackle this one to give you an idea is like,
you know, the, we either would kind of pick, you know, do we want to focus this on the
damage aspect, that it's damage on a non-damage slot?
Or maybe we focus on the resource aspect and like double down on that and make that really
powerful and really cool.
Or we do like a little bit of both, but if we do both, and it's not going to give you
the defenses that another pant slot would give, right?
Basically, in our mind, we'd be like, we want to give the minimum amount of defense, where
it's not just like a trash item because it has nothing.
But then after that, not so much, and you're going to have to solve your defenses in other
slots or somewhere else to justify getting the damage on this slot is how we would think
about it, right?
And so we're having a lot of conversations now.
I don't think we're going to nail every single item perfectly in this first pass.
So we're really looking for feedback when you, you know, jump into season five and beyond
and we'll be adjusting them.
But I kind of want to give you an idea of what we're doing and kind of what we're thinking
and targeting with this.
I think we can move on.
So Mythic Uniques are getting the facelift here.
So lots of updates here.
Mythic Uniques are now going to be truly mythic.
They're getting a new color beam when they drop on the ground.
They're coming out with an awesome new sound that you're going to hear in a little bit.
You've got new item UI that you can see.
So they have a different color.
They really are going to look and feel like the special items that they are.
And we have a video here to show you the sound and what it looks like on the ground.
So you can see here this beam looks, you know, very different than anything else.
Isn't that sound echoey sound?
I love it.
Sounds like a, it sounds like a, you're murdering a bunch of like church organs or something.
Yeah, it's crazy.
Yeah, so you know, with this thing drops, you're definitely going to know when you got one,
no more like sifting through your Uniques to see if it's actually one of the mythics.
You'll know right away.
So we're really excited about this.
Super happy it was able to get in.
All right.
And last but not least, let's talk about class updates.
So I'm going to cover some generic things across all classes and then go through a little
bit of each one.
Again, this is not going to be nearly close to everything that we're doing.
Just a little taste to teaser for what you can expect to see.
Let's start with things across all classes.
Once systemic update we're doing to the game is invulnerability skills are now going
to start their cool down when the invulnerability ends instead of when the skill begins.
This is really to prevent things like infinite invulnerability and really to open up design
space for us on the team because now we can be more comfortable adding things like, you
know, invulnerable duration to skills or cool down reduction more liberally and things
like that where we don't have to worry about this.
This is very similar to like, you know, what our previous games have done and some other
games do and we do think it'll be a good fit here.
The idea isn't really to like make it that you can't be invulnerable very often.
It's just to prevent like 100% uptime where you actually break down the combat of the
game and you're not interacting with enemies anymore.
The next one is we reviewed monster CC and we generally reduce the CC duration and
frequency across the board.
So you know, if you were frustrated by getting frozen for a million years and then dying,
that'll happen much less often.
And also to help with this, potions can be used while CC'd even while you're stunned.
So you know, while you're frozen standing there and everybody's around you trying to kill
you, you can at least spam potion a little bit and maybe survive sometimes.
Next one we've got some bug fixes.
These are some of the notable ones.
We do have more coming in but these are the ones I wanted to call out.
Rogue victimize is no longer going to be double dipping on X damage, which was resulting
in a lot more multi-puket or a lot more damage really than it was supposed to have.
Damage over time effects were getting double the amount of percent damage that they were
supposed to and skeleton reapers were getting both book of the dead bonuses when the second
option was selected.
And again, this is you know, just a little bit of a preview but we have other bug fixes
coming but these are some of the bigger ones we want to call out.
All right, now let's get to the classes.
So barbarian, they have a new unique coming in.
This is the unbroken chain.
This is for you support barbarians or really just more defensively oriented ones.
Basically what this is going to do is create a connection between steel grass and binary
maelstrom where you'll be able to cast iron maelstrom a lot more often as you use steel
grass.
And also enemies damage by our maelstrom are going to be doing less damage for a little
while.
So the idea here is you could debuff enemies debuff those bosses and make them do less
damage to you so you can survive better.
And next the rogue, Flurry is going to be getting a lot of big updates.
We updated the enhancement and both of their upgrades.
So you'll be able to see kind of a theme here going on before you know you would damage
a crowd control or vulnerable enemy for the enhancement then you would heal.
Now when Flurry hits an enemy you can just make them vulnerable.
So actually Flurry becomes a vulnerable generator here which is pretty exciting.
And it'll also deal more damage as you hit vulnerable enemies.
Stacks up really high.
So the idea here is with Flurry builds you want to make everything vulnerable and then
just keep walking them with Flurry and gain a bunch of damage.
And now improved Flurry is changing before it was about vulnerable spreading but now
baseline you can just generate vulnerable so we don't need that anymore.
So now improved Flurry is going to actually give you a dash.
So now similar to things like the shred on the druid you can kind of dash to your target
and also every time you cast Flurry now it's going to heal you.
So it's going to be a lot more mobile, a lot more awesome, very cool.
And the last one not least to compete with a dash what could we do with advanced Flurry?
Well we can just add a stupid amount of damage and resource cost reduction.
So before you had to evade through an enemy and then do damage with one cast and stun
enemies.
Now as you spam Flurry it'll basically get a big damage bonus and it's energy cost will
go down which will let you be able to spam it even more often.
So the idea here is you just want to be using over and over and over again and it'll
get stronger and stronger and ramp up pretty heavily as you go.
I'm excited for Flurry Rugs.
Very excited.
Yeah, there are going to be a lot more words around bouncing around and it's going to
be great.
Yeah, ironically I'm playing Flurry this season.
I'm always off by one.
I always play the thing and then like, oh, we're going to massively make it better next
time.
But it's fine.
Everything's fine.
Next, Druid Shepard's aspect.
We've gotten feedback from players now for a while now about how Shepard's aspect kind
of dominates the meta for Druids because you're basically both, it's both not great from
a design and a balanced perspective on the design side.
You know, we're telling you to put companions on your bar and then they're actually just
buffing you.
So you make this companion build fantasy, but it's actually just making the player better.
And then on the power side, you're basically just slotting three skills on your bar with
your companions and then not really caring about buffing them or using them because they're
just kind of there as proxies to make you better.
So we've changed it now where basically it's going to be about the companions.
So your companion skills are just going to deal damage for every companion that you have.
So the bigger your zoo, the better your zoo is going to perform.
And to compensate players, we're doing some pretty massive buffs to Druid skills baseline
to compensate.
So you know, your skills are just going to be getting that damage baseline and in many
cases a little bit more.
So you can check that out when you see the PTR notes or the PTR patch notes after this,
but we basically just buffed everything across the board and made it so that Shepard's
isn't required anymore.
Next for the source service.
This is Axiocon to it.
I'm really excited about this unique.
This is your chain lightning unique.
So chain lightning builds.
I know how unique that really talks to you.
And you can see here kind of our stats and that new philosophy I told you about.
You have a chance to double cast chain lightning on pants instead of just a weapon.
So that's pretty cool.
So basically the way that this works, we're going to have a video about how to explain to
you how this works because it actually changes your skill pretty significantly.
So now when you cast chain lightning, the way it's going to work is it's going to cast
and bounce on enemies just like before, but then it's going to come back to you and orbit
you a little bit.
And then it's going to go out and hit another enemy and then come back to you and orbit
and then come out and then go out and do another enemy and come back.
It's a good do that back and forth a few times.
And every time it comes back to you, it's going to drain some of your mana.
And after I drain so much mana after coming back 10 times, the bolt is actually going to
explode for a ridiculous amount of lightning damage on enemies.
So there's a mini game here where basically, oh and by the way, you can cast multiple chain
lightnings when this is out.
You're basically going to be like running a gambit here and the mini game is you want to
stack as much resource regeneration as you can so that your lightning bolts can survive
being drained over and over and bouncing everywhere so they can last to their explosion
and do a ton of damage to enemies.
One thing I want to call out here also is that because it drains mana, resource cost reduction
won't work on that drain.
You're actually going to want to focus on gaining resource, which is a little bit different
and kind of makes us build a little special I think and unique compared to other resource
builds based around resource.
So I'm going to see you in action here.
So you'll see what one cast looks like and then I'll think we'll see what it looks like
when you spam it.
So you can see here circles, you go in his enemies, circles, you go in his enemies and
then does a big explosion at the end that we've tuned the damage to be pretty high.
See there?
So then it explodes.
So oh wait, oh do we have one more cast a bunch of times?
Maybe we don't.
Oh there we go.
There we go.
So see here, you can see that as you go and keep going, going, going to explode a bunch
of times.
But another thing I want to point out is if you're hugging enemies at melee range, as
it's circling you, it will also hit enemies.
So you now have a way to like really maximize your damage by hugging bosses as such, the damage
goes way up.
So next last but not least, the Necromancer.
So we got some feedback.
We've had this for a while and felt this on the team where you know, the goal of them,
we really love, you know, we love our goal of our goal of them boys.
And you know, but sometimes it can be frustrating where you tell the goal of them to go somewhere
and then you kind of take a while to lug his butt over there and do a slam or a shout
or whatever and you know, things can get in the way.
And so we've kind of upgraded them a little bit.
I'll let the video speak for himself here.
But so now you can see your goal and the Hulk smash and just jump on enemies and slam
them down.
So this will work with all of your goal types by the way, not just the iron goal but
now your goal is going to leap to the area that you tell them to go and then castix ability.
So we're really excited about this.
Shout out to Charles Dunn who got this change in and our animators who helped us out.
We're really pumped for it.
It looks amazing.
Yeah.
So those were the class and balance changes.
I know.
We jumped to slide there.
How dare you production.
No, but we are, as they wave to me like, I'm sorry.
We do want to go into some quality of life updates.
We do have a significant amount of quality of life updates that we do want to go through
that will be available in season five.
And you guys will actually be able to check this out in the PTR.
So now we can go to the next slide where we do want to talk about some hell tide and whisper
updates specifically.
So I know this has been kind of at least has been a pain point for me and I've heard it's
been a pain point for others is that as you guys are going through hell tide, there are
whisper objectives within there to help you with your progression on your whisper bar.
But the issue with the ones in hell tide is that it's sometimes take quite a while to
do.
And you know, you sometimes players would have to leave the hell tide to go to another
area to complete some of these whisper objectives.
So we are optimizing this to ensure that they don't take nearly as much time.
The ideal goal is to get a bunch of value within those 15 minutes and to potentially end
up getting a full entire whisper at 10 point bar within 15 minutes on in one hell tide.
So it will be a huge help because I know at least for me, I've always had to leave a
hell tide and try to knock some of that out.
Especially help for players that are looking for additional gold because whisper catches
that have always been great sources of gold.
And now as Adam mentioned, you can also use whisper catches to target fire.
Yeah, so maybe it's keeping things more optimized for players, which we know will be
way better there.
The next thing we do want to talk about is also Bainful Hearts.
I know in this may not sound like a huge quality of life thing or a buff of any sort, but we
have noticed that and players have had a lot of Bainful Hearts within their inventory.
We do want to make these a little bit more valuable so they won't drop ass frequently.
We know that players will still have a significant amount, but maybe not hundreds and hundreds
where some people have within their inventory, but players should not have any type of issues
regarding having a ton of these Bainful Hearts, but we are tweaking the drop rate because
they were dropping a little too much there.
The very broad up topic, well, and like, people are talking about that.
So it's pretty popular.
Yeah, so I want to take a minute to talk about tempering and how the design team sees it
and what we're happy with, what we think could be better, and some adjustments will be
making in season five.
So first high level, how we see tempering, we really think that it's important that items
have an endpoint where players know kind of that the item is done and that they're not
hoarding lots of them forever on the chance that they can all be good, right?
One of the big key goals of season four was that we didn't want you saving a million items
in your stash space.
And while we know that breaking an item never feels great, we do need that to be something
that's possible to do in the game so that you know when the journey is done and you're
not just holding on to an item forever.
So that part we actually think is working very well where you know an item is done and
you try and go get another one.
And so you're always interested in items and trying to you know to have that game loop
go for in the game indefinitely or until you feel like your character is max sound power.
But we do agree with players that you know the RNG right now is like completely out of their
hands which doesn't really feel great.
You know you get you get so many tries basically to roll and then that's kind of it and you're
done and it doesn't feel great.
So we're looking at ways in the future for players that more control over that RNG so
that you know you have more ways to maybe manipulate the tempering or get the odds in
your favor and do other things like that.
One update that's going to be coming in season five.
It won't be in the PTR but we're targeting for launch is that you know we've got a lot
of feedback that it feels so bad when you know you get that like triple greater aficz
and it has the same number of rolls and then you you you brick it and then you have to try
and go get another one.
So in season five to help with this you know as your item gets better basically that you
find you're going to have more chances to temper it so a much better chance to get the
one that you want.
Basically what I work is you're going to basically get one extra roll per greater aficz
that you have.
So you know we have one greater aficz, one roll, three, three rolls.
And again just to clarify this is not in the PTR but it will be in for the launch of
season five in itself and I again just to reiterate we are still looking at ways to
to help out that experience within tempering as we've noted we agree with players that
it doesn't always feel great and so you guys should expect to hear more updates to tempering
after we get their season five for sure.
Yeah.
Alright next up weapons.
Yeah so I'll talk about this one a little bit.
We took a little bit.
This chart.
Yeah this chart.
We took a look at inherent aficz on weapons and we found that you know a lot of inherent
aficz is like damage to distant or some other ones were a little too conditional and didn't
get the update you know in season four that we wanted.
So we went back and made them a little bit more generically useful and better across
more builds.
So we have a little chart here but you can see kind of this is going to be the new inherent
aficz on all the different weapon types so we made quite a few adjustments here.
You know as an example you know vulnerable damage is on bows and thought damage is on
axes which I believe vulnerable on bows is new.
But yeah so we made quite a few updates we basically just looked at the matrices of everything
and kind of adjusted it to see what makes sense.
So basically you're just going to have you know things that actually impact your builds
much more often on the weapons that that you want.
And as another result of this update we are also looking at what weapons classes can
use and we updated them a little bit to try and you know let more classes use more
weapons.
We want players to be able to create interesting builds play the way that we want and
so we want to open up these things as much as we can in our designs.
So now Druids is going to be able to use two hand poems one hand swords and daggers
sorceresses are going to be able to use one hand swords and maces and necromancers are
going to be able to use and these maces and axes actually.
Yeah despite this necromancer picture right here that is not using it.
Well it's using a two handed sword but you can already use a two handed sword but not
using a and yeah and the necromancer here I know it's supposed to say all maces and
axes as opposed to all swords.
So basically we are going to be opening up these classes to use more weapon types.
And then also some of the unique are going to be updated for the classes as well so the
butcher's cleaver can now be used for necromancers and sorcerers can use doom brainer and
azure wrath now.
Yeah sorcerers can use azure wrath kind of like D2.
Yep fits their theme very well too so I think that will be pretty cool.
Some additional quality of life updates.
Now we're going to talk about some end game bosses as I have experienced as Adam is
this experience earlier as he mentioned in the stream we are making changes to the beast
and ice.
You guys will no longer have to make a sigil to summon the beast and ice which is a huge
quality of life update.
The beast will now live in a standard dungeon.
The crawl to get to the beast and ice is much much shorter now it's going to be more similar
to what we've seen with some of the other end game bosses.
And then at the same time eternal players that have maybe already built out some of these
sigils we made sure to keep you in mind so you can still use the sigils to fight the boss
you won't need some new materials you can just use the sigil right there in the boss room
in itself.
And there's no longer required sigil to actually summon the beast and ice.
So some big changes to the beast and ice to help out that whole entire feel especially
when you're really target farming the beast and ice.
Sometimes it was kind of brutal to have to go through the whole entire dungeon each
and every time.
So many times.
Yeah.
So next we have Varshan.
Varshan, the body parts are pretty much being reduced to one.
I know it was eating up a lot of inventory space.
It was kind of hard to manage at times and everything so we're optimizing this, making
this better.
Now you'll just need one body part two essentially summon Varshan going forward starting with season
five.
And one big thing that we're going to call out here before and this is kind of like
the cherry on top.
We should let's actually just play the clip and see if people actually notice it and
if not then we'll call it out.
What could be different this time?
Poor Durel.
Yeah, mythic unique maybe.
Oh.
No, that's not it.
Good gear though.
Yeah.
But something that is interesting here is the cold dream has reappeared.
You can just resummon it.
And there's the altar right there.
You can now resummon all the end game bosses without needing to run out of the dungeon and
reset the dungeon.
And reset the dungeon.
So this will help a whole lot.
We'll make things way better in terms of like optimizing when you're for time and everything.
Yeah.
Especially when you're a party and you're like everyone leave the dungeon so I can reset
and stuff like that.
Now you'll be able to do that immediately for all the end game bosses which is a huge
feature.
I know that players have been asking for.
So that will be also incorporated into season five.
So lots and lots of changes for season five.
One other thing I did want to call out regarding tempering because just to clarify because
we've got some people going like I don't understand like the greater afic stuff like in terms
of additional roles.
If you have a one star greater afic you'll get one additional role.
If you have like a three star or four stars something you would get three or four ending
the amount of stars that you actually specifically have on your item.
Yeah.
I think those are the three.
Three.
Sorry.
Four is unique.
Yeah.
If it was a greater afic like a three star greater afic or something like that you will end up getting those three additional
roles afterwards.
So that will appear after these changes actually are implemented with the start of season five.
It'll just be on your internal character obviously because your seasonal character will
move to eternal as I fix my earpiece.
That's like falling out.
No.
But one other thing I did want to call out is well for season five.
We have some really big like accessibility options that are being added to the actual
game and we really really need some testing on this in the season five PTR.
This is actually called out in our blog.
We'd really love if players can actually check them out, test them out, provide feedback.
I will note we aren't planning.
Despite it being in the season five PTR we aren't planning on these features actually launching
with season five.
We really want to take the feedback, make them better for when they are ready and right
now I think that the plan would be that they would be ready for season six but it's important
for us to be able to get that feedback.
So we really need people to actually test out these specific features.
We have like an auto pin feature.
We have a compass feature and then we have like an audio navigation assistance feature
that is coming within some of these accessibility features for season five.
So really important for people to kind of like jump in, check it out, give us feedback
and then you'll see those in season six after the PTR is kind of over.
But that is kind of like a huge wrap up of all the stuff that is coming for the season
five PTR and even a little bit more of even even some of the stuff for season five.
We do want to take some questions and we still have Dan on the line from the burning
house of Albany to answer any questions that we may have.
But I know we have a question specifically teed up.
So if you have questions please ask them in Twitch chat which is where we have live chat
going on right now and we will try to get through as many as possible.
Cool.
But first question I believe we have is because I teed up this question.
There are any new class buffs coming to season five specifically if Adam can answer
Druid and Sorceress because I know we hear you and everyone about Druid and Sorceress.
I know we talked a little bit about it here but if you can like expand on it a little bit.
Yes, there are new class buffs coming to season five covered a little bit.
I think when they call out that people talk a lot about right now is how barbarians in
particular are pretty strong and then the classes that can't get as far as they can in the
pit feels kind of bad.
There's a lot to chew on there but I think the short answer is yes we hear you and we're
going to be looking to beef these things up.
We do have some specific ways that we want to be targeting these things and there's a
lot of history to it.
Barbarians in particular are tougher to balance.
I think I'm talked about this on stream a little bit before of because of their arsenal
system they have more items.
Anytime that we mess with and we've mess with like the underlying systems of the game
very heavily in the last year right season two we updated all the combat math which
of course impacts items which impacts character power.
We've updated in season four all of itemization which obviously directly impacts the arsenal
system very heavily.
When we do these large shakeups it's way more it's a lot more difficult in the short
amount of time to get everything exactly perfect of how the common of the works of those
effects are going to impact classes.
Last one end of it another end is what we're trying to do and we started with this in
season four is we were looking at the other class mechanics and we want to kind of be
flum up and give them the treatment that we kind of gave with the necromancer in the book
of the dead.
In season four we actually wanted to try this as an experiment but like hey the book of
the dead the minions the sacrifice bonuses they're what really make necromancer feel really
cool and special and unique.
We're going to try and catch that up so to speak to the arsenal system on the Barbarian
and not only just increase the numbers right is just increase the numbers is kind of
easy we even did that in the mid season patch if you look at the jurid boons you know
we increase them by 50% double them in any cases but we think to really help solve that
on the fantasy and even just a design perspective we want to like overhaul and really look at
these mechanics and make them way better and more thematic to classes.
So we don't have anything to announce today for season five but that's something more
long term that we're doing to help that problem in the future.
In the short term we are you know looking at you know fixing the issues with these various
classes buffing them up in different ways you know making different builds and other things
viable and trying to keep that parity.
We're also looking at you know bringing down the outliers of power with the Barbarian
in different ways to make sure that they have more parity with other classes as well
but that's kind of our short and long term vision of where we want this to be.
Awesome.
I know we have a question specifically and this is something I've seen a few times regarding
season five for Dan because in front of Horace people are seeing this gameplay and they're
hearing about like okay like I can play it can I play this on eternal and seasonal can
I play this is this like an ongoing thing going forward like what what players expect Dan.
Sure yeah so with season five we wanted to build out the end game and because we're
building out the end game we wanted to make sure that any of the end game things we're
putting in are on both seasonal and eternal and so in this PTR you'll be able to test out
the eternal version of infernal Horace and so any of the rewards you get from it all that's
eternal so all players are going to benefit from it.
Awesome.
Yeah so all players will benefit from it and it's and as Dan mentioned it's a it's a new
end game feature so it's like something that will be you know continuous beyond you know
even season five is what we're looking at so yeah players can expect to jump in infernal
Horace going forward which is pretty cool yeah and yeah the feedback is going to be incredibly
important during this PTR as Dan mentioned beforehand all the specific items that were really
hoping to get you know feedback on regarding you know how the boons feel how the the rewards
feel how the the combat feels and the waves and stuff like that will be really important
for us during this specific moment.
What is the this another season five question and hopefully you might be able to answer
this Dan what is this from Lucky Luciano shout out Diablo partner what is the equivalent
pit level of the eighth difficulty of like the infernal Horace pit level I guess or nine
married dungeon or or monster level yeah you're making me do math here yeah we just
ingested pit level yeah so tier tier eight tier eight of the infernal Horace is going to
be equivalent to about monster level I think it's 180 to 200 so it goes up pretty high
that's pretty late okay nice nice so a difficult challenge for sure which is good to hear
we have a question from Zapadass and you all need easier names I swear do you foresee changes
in grouping in the pit to allow a group play to be more efficient there will be changes
it won't be something present in PTR we'll talk more about it at the season five launch
but the team is very aware of it because we've heard about like hey it's kind of not great
to feel like I'm getting only 50% of you know the rewards associated when I'm in a group
within a pit if I'm not the party leader specifically so it's something that the team's taking
in and we will have an update for players before season five and it will be live whatever
change we have live in season five so a question from let's see oh this one's easy okay
robot jomo what's the team's philosophy on rate of power gain it seems that the tempering
especially players gain too much power too quickly really removing the tension from leveling
up experience any chance to add more friction to tempering materials costs etc yeah we have
seen a little bit of this and heard this feedback ourselves it's kind of going in two different
ways here so the leveling experience then how tempering messes with it right the leveling
experience as people probably have seen has been sped up quite a bit right we do want people
to be able to kind of level quickly and get to the fun of the game as quickly as possible
so we do want them you know we don't want there to be a ton of friction like you know we first
launch the game we we had the idea that like getting to level 100 alone was a big accomplishment right
and we've learned that you know players really want to like fulfill their power fantasies get to
the part where they're actually like incrementally increasing their characters power and finding
things don't use that power against and so they they enjoy that end game a lot and we want to
get them there in a reasonable amount of time so that's the part that is like you know hey you know
it's fine level quicker it's good right but then the other part is like tempering and kind of
the tuning of the affixes we have heard the feedback and kind of agree with it that you know
the early tempering recipes are really really strong right that was by design when we launched
season four one of the big kind of mandates to the team that we felt was important was we wanted
before season four we constantly got the feedback and knew it was true that you know your item stats
weren't interesting enough and didn't matter enough and we're very impactful and just didn't feel
good right and so we we very much like juice them up to be very strong and then this new tempering
system that manipulates them we made a very strong so the out the gate our goal was that when you
temper an item you can really feel the damage it wasn't like this incremental my damage goes up in
like 10 different places here and there and now I'm strong it was like no this one thing happened
and you felt it and it was good and so we're gonna you know try and walk that line we're gonna
probably go a little more in between here where you know we do agree that the tempering is
working the early game experience too much to the point that it's like you pick up an item and
you don't care about the stats because you just temper something on and it's like way better right
so we don't want that but we do still want them to feel and be really impactful so we have
heard the feedback I don't remember don't think we have huge adjustments in season five right away
but we are going to be looking at that leveling process and streaming and lining that quite a bit
we're having time to actually talk about that right now with various members of the team so
it will be looked at not tons will change in season five though awesome question from
razzle dazzle dazzle darris dazzle dazzle darris it's a long name to log in on did you say we
can temper unique are you open to letting us imprint affixes I had this thought we can imprint
a unique but only once yeah going back that was kind of what I talked about with the unique section
we right now know I'm not going to say never in the future it's definitely the obvious thing that
we could do like it has just had tempering the unique of course but we we want them to have an
identity that is very different from legendaries one of the concerns with that is that the more that
you give you unique manipulation the more that they just turn into legendaries with a different
item color when they drop on the ground right like they're actually not different in how they work
if we were able to manipulate manipulate stats add stats all those things so we do want them to
have a different identity in the game so we're not doing it now but you know in the future we've
talked about it we're open to the idea but we do want to try this first of like double down you
know what makes a unique unique and that you build around it except whether there's a little bit of
friction rather than just turning it into the item that you want every time yeah question from
Barric is hey Adam or Adams I have a question for the Q&A how is the dev team feeling about the
reception of season four is that making them rethink any plans for future seasons I mean I think
one thing that we can most definitely call out here is like obviously season four has been really
great like we've been hearing a lot of great feedback from players and you know we're very well
aware of like you know how everyone's been enjoying it I think one huge thing that's helped with
that as well was like the idea that we had a PTR for season four and now we're seeing that again
for season five so like we know like having that moment where players can actually jump in provide
feedback give us some some notes on specific things is really beneficial especially when we have
like new huge features like what we did for season four which was you know obviously tempering
master working the pit all new health times there's a ton of new features and then of course
with season five you know players are now going to be able to run through the infernal horde
tons of new gear and and legendary aspects for them so it's just like a ton of stuff that we know
that we can most definitely take feedback on having those moments has really helped us with some
of those decisions yeah I would say on the design team side I know like the people on team are
very happy with how season four went it couldn't have gone better really in our eyes PTR was a huge
deal helped us a lot especially on the balance and design side to you know get things into a better
place another thing I may call out with season four is that uh and you have a phrase it like
you know there's been a lot of disruption to the game right and so it's when there's that much
disruption of like you know we update all the core math and all the items and everything it
looks very difficult to get things into a fine-tuned state right and you know without giving anything
away we have big updates coming in the future with you know expansion and other things but one of
the things that we're we're looking forward to try to get as a team is when we've kind of uh
settled down a little bit on the big disruptions like overall you know I did all of itemization
and things like that because um you know it becomes a lot more difficult to fine-tune things like
balance or even on the design side like designs and making sure that they work and that we're like
iterating and upgrading things versus you know changing things around in huge ways so while we
think it was really successful and we're happy with how itemization 2.0 turned out um the team is
looking forward to like making the things as they are and make them work better and more do fine-tuning
work and so I think you can expect in the future as a player um you know after we've done some more
destruction and made the game like in a really good place we're very happy with it which we're really
close to now I think um that you're you know you off tighter class balance tighter designs tighter
roles for things and just you know the one of the things that excites me and excited the team
about season 4 was like the tons of quality of life improvements and how much of an impact that
makes on players which I think we knew but hit home in season 4 right like just the codex of power
how that changed and how that completely fixed you know the hoarding of items and things like that
I think are what really jazz us a lot because it just makes that flow experience better like the boss
ladder you know being able to reset bosses stuff like that I think is actually really impactful um
and good for for the longevity of the game so we're excited to do more things like that
all right uh last question that we have here uh is uh say
well it's just saydens oh say saydens with the z and six six six afterwards very very
the all over yeah very diablo theme is specifically asking uh what is the seasonal theme um
are we like holding back any information right now regarding that and stuff uh
Dan I don't know if you want to clarify here or if you want me to you can
all right so um we haven't announced the name for the season yet as far as I know but the the
seasonal theme seems I guess fairly obvious um you know we're going back to hell and so uh the theme
is pretty much returning to hell and while the infernal hordes is uh just one part of that uh the
rewards are another part and uh when we have our our season five live stream uh we'll go into
all of the rest of the things that we have planned for season five exactly yeah we have uh we have
some yeah we have some we have some additional stuff uh yeah to to talk about when we we do actually
have our season five live stream we're just uh right now the biggest focus for this stream is for
people to hear about the content that they're going to be able to play and ptr um and we want people
to really hone in and focus in on that uh so we can actually get that feedback uh for the team here
and we can make any changes that we may need to yeah um but yeah that is kind of a gonna wrap this
up for today for for Q and A um I I'm gonna lightening round like a few quick things
sure sure chat will kill me if I don't call it out sure now we're getting a lot of questions
about loadouts uh it is again still something that we are very well aware of and we we still plan
on it's just takes a lot of time it's a huge huge uh amount of uh overhaul changes and everything
from that end uh separately uh we uh uh this isn't coming up a lot auction house there are currently
no plans right now for for something like that but uh we we hear you guys we we we feedback things
like that let us know um but right now those are those are the two big things I I've been seeing a
ton in chat I just want to address them before people go like you're not reading chat what you're
you're in some like alternate universe chat or something like that um but uh ptr again just to
remind everyone starts next Tuesday uh runs for one week it's on pc battle net only please
provide feedback on our forums reddit social media our community discord things like that uh we're
always looking around uh we really are we really value the feedback that we get during these ptr
processes and of course uh at the same time we patch notes on the blog or live immediately after
this stream so check out diablo4.com and those do get up uh next time you guys see us next time we
stream is July 18th it's the spirit born reveal oh yeah everyone gets to check out the uh the
the spirit born so we'll be back live on stream on July 18th we'll be revealing the brand new class
coming to diablo4 uh that will be part of vessel of hatred so we're really excited about that and uh
yeah I think that wraps it up I want to give a huge shout out to Dan and Albany yeah thank you Dan
yeah enjoy the AC I'm the birdie fire under him yeah not exactly uh and uh thank you again Adam
Jackson and from everyone on the diablo4 team we wish you a wonderful weekend and we'll see you in
ptr next week thank you everybody see you guys
mmm