Just getting music on here.
Justango, how are we doing, buddy?
I'm good, guys.
Can I ask you guys a question?
Do you guys ever wake up in the morning and ask yourselves,
why am I not playing Elden Ring?
Every morning.
He's locked in, chat.
Two bits.
How are we doing, buddy?
You weren't a fan of Elden Ring?
Really?
Right.
Could see you ever 다음, buddy.
Yeah.
Thank you.
We're on here.
We have fun.
Thank you.
I'll give you all the answers.
It's on our radar.
No, I want to get inside the minds of the devs.
I want to know their approach to things.
I don't want to know.
I'm not going to ask yes or no questions.
When can we save builds?
I think they already answered that.
They said that they like the idea of an armory.
They like the idea of an armory.
And...
It just wasn't the top priority for them to get into the game.
But maybe I can reiterate that it was the top question.
Okay, let's not use the ats because that's stupid.
Okay.
What is it?
CP max 205 or something?
And then Sergeant Turtle 3 3.
Every single one of these questions I already had on my list except this one.
Are there questions related to endgame improvement?
Yeah, so I guess I can walk you guys through my questions that I have so far.
You would be shocked.
I actually spent a lot of time on this.
I'm trying to be as prepared as possible.
I'm going to need to clean this up and potentially grab more questions from you guys.
Okay.
Actually, let me change my mind.
Let me do a little bit more work here and then I'll ask you guys because it's not quite
complete yet.
Okay.
So they talked about set items yesterday.
They said that set items are a fan favorite.
They said that there is, if you think about a character's power, it's a slice of pizza.
A slice goes to skills and paragon and uniques and aspects and the affixes and whatever.
If sets come into the game, then it's going to take up a slice of the pizza.
So, how much of the pizza should it take is what they were talking about.
So, one thing that they said is there's no point to implement set items if they're too
weak.
And I strongly agree here.
Look at the super shitty sets.
I love pizza.
That's what I took it from as well.
That's what I took from it as well.
So, if you look at like Last Epoch, for example, they released sets.
Most of them are completely worthless.
I actually just filter out set items in my loot filter.
I just filter them out.
A lot of them in Diablo 2, you find a lot of low level set items.
They're useless.
You just go into the Black Marsh, you get your, what's it called?
Your stealth.
Then you make your two spirit items.
And we ain't got no time for any of these sets.
But they also said Diablo 3, too strong.
And I agree.
So, the thing that I wanted to ask them about is.
If set items come into the game.
Where do they feel.
Is the right amount of power.
And item slots taken.
And I can give them three examples of sets that I think worked beautifully.
So, in Diablo 3, a good example of a set is maybe Captain Crimson's.
All guilds.
And, uh, Guardians.
They barely take up any slots.
And they're.
They have different use cases.
So, Guardians is for early game.
Crap and Crimson's is if you want cooldown.
And all guilds is if you want damage.
And another really good example, in my opinion.
Is Diablo 2's Tal Rasha set.
And the reason why is it's.
It's an end game godly set.
But not game breaking.
And two pieces are.
Very rare, but not impossible to find the amulet and the chest.
The chest is super difficult.
But the amulet is very accessible.
The.
This is my example of the three best sets I've ever seen in a game.
Do you guys agree that these sets would.
These sets are well designed.
Don't break the game and add some flavor to the game.
Can you move away from turning D4 into D2 and D3 questions?
DF.
I got four pages of questions here.
I got four pages.
I'm asking questions about Diablo 4.
The questions are about Diablo 4.
But I will draw analogies to many other games.
I even have a question about Diablo 4 specific unique ideas.
I've put in a shitload of effort into this document, man.
Trust me.
I'm not talking about the other games.
But we can bring up tons of analogies to other games.
The interview.
There was an interview yesterday from Riker.
We're going to.
We're going to talk about.
We're going to talk about that.
Okay.
Here's my question on rumors.
They said yesterday.
They like rune words and they see a future.
See a future in D4.
They are.
They initially had rune words coming in.
But they didn't have time to finish them.
But here's the problem.
Here's the thing for.
Here's the thing for me about rune words.
Rune words to me again is an iconic system.
Iconic system of D2.
But the announcement that they had for rune words.
Wasn't rune words.
It was like.
It was like a prefix and a suffix.
And it was like.
A totally.
New system.
With the same name.
So my question is.
When the team talks about.
The work that you've already done on rune words.
You.
And.
I don't have a specific kind of statement.
I'm going to try it Pavlik.
More人民.
Which has a specificAttackgebra and a way.
Do you try critically.
But if.
And.
The.
Can it.
You.
Your privilege.
Thanks.
The other main meta monesses.
The.
You tá.
Open Up.
The.
For BIOS platform.
이쪽.
This.
Um.
The IP.
On.
Your hac.
with a different direction.
Because this is the thing that threw off the community the most
when they initially announced this.
They said, RuneWords are coming to Diablo 4,
and then they showed us what it looked like,
and it wasn't RuneWords at all.
It wasn't.
So I want to know,
it sounds like it may be coming sometime in the future.
If it comes in the future,
are you starting with kind of Diablo 2's base of that system
and expanding upon it and changing it and making it
work in the Diablo 4 universe?
Or are you actually going to give us something different?
The interview's in one hour exactly.
Okay.
On Riker's interview,
they took 15 minutes answering each question.
Yeah, I watched Riker's interview three times over.
I watched it three times.
I'm pretty, I would like to think,
hopefully this is true.
I'd like to think I'm pretty prepared today.
I watched it three times.
That's why the title of this is
CJ's Questions in the Beginning.
I want to,
and I messaged Blizzard.
I said,
I would like to continue some of the conversations
that you guys had.
The interview's in one hour, guys.
One hour.
They did,
they talked about all of these.
They talked about all of these
in Riker's interviews, guys.
I know.
I watched it three times.
I have a different question.
Riker asked,
are Rune words coming in Diablo 4?
And their answer was,
they like Rune words
and they see a future in Diablo 4.
That's not my question.
My question is,
when Rune words come to Diablo 4,
are they going to be Rune words
or are they going to be something different?
Because when they initially announced it,
it was something different.
That's why I want to talk about it, Karaman.
That's why,
that's why it's my first question.
That's exactly why it's up here.
They talked about aspirational
and pinnacle content
like three different times.
So,
so,
yeah,
both.
It would be both.
Okay,
charms.
Let's say
last epoch
we get our,
so,
PoE
D3
don't have them.
D2
has them
no in,
with no
dedicated
inventory.
Last epoch
has them
with a dedicated
inventory.
Will they
ever
come to
D4?
If yes,
would they have
a dedicated
inventory?
I already
have that
as a question,
Luna.
When is Diablo
coming to Diablo
for?
if Joe is smart,
he would be,
he would be in the chat
taking notes
to prepare.
there.
So,
let me,
let me clarify
this situation
here,
guys.
never actually,
like,
individually or
one-on-one
too much,
but I have
been talking
to more
Joe than
Adam,
but some
Adam as
well.
I've been
talking to
them for a
long time.
Me,
Joe,
and Adam
had a
lengthy
conversation
about how
great
Elden Ring
is and
how all
great
all the
Souls games
are.
By the way,
I think both
Joe and
Adam beat
every single
Souls game.
Bloodborne,
all three of
the Dark Souls,
and Elden Ring.
So,
they're gamers,
right?
I am not
going into
this interview
with a
machine gun
looking for
blood,
right?
I'm not
looking to
embarrass them.
I'm not
looking to
put,
you know,
uneasy
pressure on
them.
What I want
to do is
I would just
like to get
some answers
for the
public on
the most
pressing
questions,
right?
I want to
know,
what is
in their
minds and
on the
team's
minds for
the future
of the
game.
So,
that way,
we can
estimate
what we
are going
to be
getting out
of Diablo
4.
Honestly,
I think
this interview
might have
some impact
for some
people on
whether they
buy the
expansion or
not.
Because if
people like
what they're
hearing about
the future
of Diablo
4,
maybe they
will have
more confidence
in purchasing
the expansion.
You know
what I
mean?
So,
this interview
is not
my personal
opportunity to
get answers to
these questions.
This interview
is to go
out in
public with
a bunch of
lovely people
like yourselves
and ask
them some
deep questions
and see so
everyone else
can hear all
the answers.
I'm not
going in
here for
looking for
blood
necessarily.
You lost
10 million
runes today.
Can't you
just go pick
them up
though?
No.
Maybe just
some bruising.
Any question
regarding
PvP?
No.
Let's put
this in
here.
could ask
that.
Give me a
second here.
Rob sent
me a message
and said,
Rax,
if you can
squeeze these
two questions
and get
them in.
so let's
try to
ask them.
Yeah.
So,
okay,
let's go
up here
for a
second.
Okay.
Let's go
up here
for a
second.
Okay.
Let's go
up here
for a second.
Okay.
Oh,
then,
I have
Ru application
of the
name.
You.
Right here.
Got five questions in.
Well, I have one, two, three, four, five, six.
I have six, well, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
I have seven questions that came directly from CJ's interview follow ups to questions that
CJ asked.
And then I have two other additional things.
And then I have many, many.
Here's another five questions.
I really want to know this.
A lot of people in the community say Blizzard never tests anything that they, that they do.
They just throw stuff into the game.
We're the beta testers, dah, dah, dah, dah, dah.
And I think we, I think people deep down know that that is not true.
So I would like to know how does testing work for Blizzard?
You have an idea for something.
Oh, we're going to do the avatar.
Fine.
You put together like the monsters and the layouts and maybe you get it into like a testing phase.
Then like what, what happens?
What is the internal process for testing?
What's that?
Another question that I wanted to ask at some point.
I can delete all of this.
Another question I wanted to ask is Microsoft's impact.
I don't really know, though, because the problem with this kind of a question,
the impact on game development, here's the problem, though.
I don't know if we're ever going to get an answer here.
Because if Microsoft negatively impacted their development, they would never say it.
They're either going to say, Microsoft is great, we love them,
or that's not true and they're not going to answer it.
I guess we could ask it a different way, though, that's not offensive.
Maybe we could say the Microsoft takeover.
And then I guess we could ask them, have they mostly been hands-on,
helping you guys, providing resources, providing guidance,
guidance, or are they very hands-off, letting you guys do your thing,
they trust you, or is it kind of like a mixture?
See, there's two people.
They already said the Microsoft impact is positive.
They already said that Microsoft is hands-off.
Not even the internet can agree.
Okay.
Hey, CJ, can I call you?
CJ is here.
Wait a minute.
Can I, uh, do you want to chat on Discord for a second?
I watched your interview three times, by the way.
Okay.
You call me, CJ.
You call me.
Okay.
CJ is here.
Let me turn off the music, guys.
Remind me to turn it on.
CJ is Riker.
Let me message him.
Hmm.
This will also give me a good chance to, uh, test my Discord audio here.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Hey, Ryan.
How you doing?
Yo, can you get, okay.
He's got to be too low, right?
I turned him way up.
Can you give me another one here, CJ?
Check one, two testing one, two.
How's the volume there guys up down or perfect?
Okay.
I I'm, I'm actually getting every answer.
Uh, okay.
Let's go up slightly more.
Last try one more time.
Check one, two.
It could also be, maybe I'm a little on the low side.
How's that?
Yeah.
Okay.
We're good.
Hey man, I watched your interview yesterday.
I don't know, man.
You have like, you have like a flow, like it, you've done this before.
You have like a flow to the conversation that, uh, I don't think I'm going to be able to match, man.
I'm just rough around the edges.
I'm just, I'm just diving right in, man.
Now you're going to have a different style and I think it's going to, it's going to be really good that we're each going to have like different kinds of interviews that are going to get different kinds of answers.
Like there are some questions that, um, cause we did like, I kind of what you got, what you're doing here.
We're getting some questions from the audience and I'm like, that's a racks question.
You guys can go ask that tomorrow where I know it's like, it's a bit more granular.
It's a bit more, uh, on point.
So yeah, no, I think, uh, I I'm excited to see, uh, what you, cause you also have Adam Jackson, right?
They're bringing in, they know, they know what to expect from you to cover those, those really specific, uh, you know, class, uh, uh, talking points.
Oh God.
I don't even want to know what that means, but, uh, um, yeah.
So I watched your interview.
I really liked it again.
I added another page and a half of followup questions to your questions.
Your, your questions were good, but yeah, like, I guess, I guess with my questions, like listening to how you brought them up, I have some like very, very pointed questions.
Like, how do you feel about this?
Um, I guess two questions for you.
How did you feel about, uh, the interview in general?
And was there any really pressing thing that you wanted to get out of your interview that you didn't have time for that you want me to revisit today?
Oh, that's a great question.
Uh, I mean, I got through maybe half of the questions.
I was like triaging them as I was going through them.
Um, uh, just cause I was, I was happy with the interview overall.
I, I recognized, uh, that I asked some big questions, especially upfront that necessitated very long answers.
And that's something I need to think about going forward is being able to maybe pepper in the smaller questions, uh, upfront that can give smaller answers just to get more in there.
Like I would have loved to, you know, have hours to talk with Joe, uh, and get through everything and also ask those followup questions and stuff.
But, uh, I know the Microsoft one was something that was high up on the list.
I don't know.
Like I, I was hearing your concerns and I had those, I was going through that same theory crafting of what can they answer?
What are they going to answer?
So yeah, possibly one way of framing it would be what if anything has the deal with Microsoft allowed you guys to do now that you couldn't do before.
Cause obviously they're not going to crap talk Microsoft.
Uh, but it's kind of one way to see if their day to day is being impacted, uh, at all by this kind of stuff.
Okay.
Uh, keep going.
What, what else, what else would you have asked?
This is good.
Oh, let's see.
Um, one answer that would have been a big, I skipped it.
Cause it would have been another big answer would have been, well, what's like the most challenging part or what has been the most challenging part, uh, to what I'm doing.
I'm doing a big part, uh, to work on a D four to date that can help give insight.
Like I like to ask questions that get insight into.
Their process.
Cause sometimes, you know, they'll do something and we'll react to it and be like, it'll be obvious on our end or it'll seem straightforward on our end.
But it's cause we don't understand the thinking that went in, went into something.
So I like to ask questions that make me understand what they're thinking.
So sometimes things that seem simple and easy for us to do, like, well, you know, this was easy.
Why don't you just do this?
It's like, Oh, actually that was really challenging to, you know, put together, which could also shed insight into, well, going forward.
Why don't they just do this?
It's just a flipping a switch.
Right.
It's like, well, actually, you know, this and that.
You know, I actually, I actually agree with you.
So a lot of, a lot of people, well, actually not a lot of people, that's not the right way to phrase it.
But some people think that when we have the opportunity, and this is like a rare thing, I don't think I've ever been able to speak to Blizzard freely, openly.
And they're just like, you know, throw whatever you got at us.
And you can look at a snapshot of Diablo four at any point in time and say, I like this.
I don't like this.
Will you buff this build?
Won't you buff this build?
This balance is off.
Da da da da da.
But that doesn't help me project how I think the game will be in the future.
The thing that will help me do that is, what do you guys think over there when you're in your chair?
We can see all the Reddit threads of what people think you think.
But what I want to know is, what do you actually think?
And then all of a sudden we can start to figure some things out that will actually happen in Diablo four rather than focusing on a snapshot in time.
That's a great way of framing it.
Yeah.
I also like to avoid any questions that are just basically thinly veiled suggestions, because we have our ways to pass our suggestions onto them, right?
We have platforms.
We can make a video with suggestions.
The devs see that.
They hear that.
An interview is kind of like wasting time basically passing along a suggestion when we know we can get that feedback to them.
Yeah.
You know, I actually watched your interview multiple times.
I watched a little bit of your follow up conversation as well.
One of the first things that I was going to ask them, you actually touched this multiple times in different areas in your interview.
But talking about kind of like the really end game, the aspirational content.
I heard them say Lilith is was mechanical mastery.
It wasn't based on gear and that it, you know, I agree that most people thought that that wasn't fun.
But I don't know if it wasn't fun because of the hit boxes of the waves or because it was just challenging.
But then later on, they talked about again, you ask them again about the aspirational or the pinnacle content.
And you said, well, they can make players weaker.
They can make monsters hit harder.
They can have more health.
But in general, for it to feel like an ARPG, the decisions that you make before you go into a fight should matter more than in the fight itself.
Because otherwise you're playing like a souls like game.
But they did mention that when they do have aspirational or pinnacle content, if they properly label it to the community, then the backlash actually really isn't there as long as it's properly advertised.
But I would say like, again, my my follow up question to that whole idea there is what about skill, though, because the Uber Lilith was the moment in the game where I feel like I actually triumphed over a tremendous challenge, a peak ahead of me in my Diablo four journey that I finally overcame that I didn't just win because I found a shackle or I got a perfect role.
I actually had to learn some mechanics, play well and win.
I wanted to ask them, is there any plans for stuff like that in the future?
It doesn't have to be a one shot, crazy hitbox, things like that.
But it sounded to me like they were kind of moving away from that entirely.
And that that honestly makes me sad.
I think that's definitely worth asking.
Yeah.
Whether they're planning to add any skill based end game or pinnacle content.
One question that I didn't have a chance to ask was, what is your philosophy towards adding new end game activities to kind of get an idea of what kind of new stuff we can expect to come?
Or if even say, like, yeah, no, we're done.
You know, it's this kind of we think we're in a good place now with it.
And, you know, I don't think that's the case, but to try to see where their minds add with regards to what more they're going to add.
Did you see the update from last epoch a few days ago about their one year roadmap?
I I wish I had a chance to.
I'm definitely going to dive into that before the weekend.
I've just been slammed.
Yeah.
Um, so it is a spoiler alert if I tell you a little bit about it right now.
Go ahead.
Please do.
So it in every single quarter, they're making significant improvements to the end game.
Like my title, my title is like, uh, last last epoch update.
And my thumbnail was end game, end game, end game.
There's this every quarter end game, end game, end game, end game, changing this, adding this, this new thing, dah, dah, dah, dah.
And again, I'm, I'm not trying to ask like question, like put a gun to their head or whatever, but I wanted to, I don't know if it would be rude to draw an analogy to that and be like, we just saw last epochs update.
And it looks like there's a tidal wave of many end game updates coming in their future roadmap.
And it, it looks good.
I mean, that's, that makes me happy as a player because like they talked about in your interview, there's a huge difference between what's fun to do one time and what's fun to do repeated times.
Hmm.
And a lot of people rip through the campaign and do a couple of echoes.
It's like, okay, then what?
I think these constant updates to end game are going to, are going to do well over there.
And I want to ask them, is there ever going to be a roadmap for Diablo four that looks like that end game, end game, end game, every single time end game, end game, end game.
But yeah, one of my questions would have been, do you guys plan to do a roadmap?
Yeah.
Give it to me straight because let's be honest.
Let's be honest.
You're the, you're the voice of reason.
You're the sweet little angel.
Everyone loves you.
And I'm like, you know, like on the shoulders and I'm like the devil with the pitchfork.
Is it, is it very rude if I ask a question like that?
Okay.
So I don't know.
My mic might've cut up there for a moment, but I, I actually did want to ask if they were going to do a roadmap.
Um, I don't think they will.
And I think the reason is they don't want to pigeonhole themselves.
They might've even touched upon this in the past.
I think I anticipate the answer to be that if they're not going to do a roadmap, it's because they don't want to, uh, pigeonhole themselves into a specific path.
And then if something else comes up, right.
And some other fire they have to put out, they got to rearrange the roadmap.
And now they're going to piss people off because they have to push things off.
I think that will be the reason they would not want to do a roadmap, but I still, it was a question I did want to ask.
I don't think it necessitates, uh, you know, framing in the context of another game.
If you want to, you could.
Um, but odds are they probably haven't seen that video either.
Um, but I mean, roadmaps in general, I think is, is totally fair play to ask.
Okay.
I'm going to ask it maybe in a, in a quote unquote softer, softer way.
Um, okay.
What else?
What, what other pressing topics are we missing?
I mean, I have four pages here.
I don't think, uh, this is ever going to happen, but, um,
I, for sure.
I forgot if I managed to ask this, but I want to ask whether the, the scope and size of, uh, seasons we've seen in two and three is about what we can expect going forward.
Uh, also whether the vision for what seasons are has changed since launch.
Okay.
Uh, without being able to find the question specifically.
Uh, so I'm going to kind of ramble here, the question, but basically we've seen in the past couple of seasons, uh, there's the season launch.
Uh, there's the season launch.
And then there's like maybe one or two things that happened during the season.
It's either like, uh, the abattoir of zeer or, uh, like a mid summer or sorry, mid whatever mid winter event.
Or there's like a couple points that happened throughout a season that I guess is intended to bring people back.
Uh, just I'm wondering like, what is their intended cadence of, I guess, content rollout?
Like, is it again, is what we have seen sort of what we can expect going forward?
Or do they plan on having more content beats throughout a season or fewer, uh, kind of what they're thinking there.
Actually, I want to know what your thought is.
What, what do you want to see in a season?
Do you like everything happens on day one and then nothing changes for the rest of the season?
Or do you like to see some other little content drop, you know, two weeks in a month in, or what would you like as someone who, you know, plays these games a lot?
Uh, well, I, but let me tell you something, CJ, that happens to me a lot.
I don't know if this happens to you, but one thing that I get spammed all the time on the internet is.
Rax's opinion doesn't reflect the community's opinion because he plays the game all day.
So Rax doesn't speak for us and whatever he says can be taken with a grain of salt and is not going to help the community.
I hear this shit.
Um, and I've on every platform, every single time.
Um, so what the mid season events have been are fun, little, very low time required, very low effort cutie patootie things to get into.
And get some cosmetics.
That's what they have been.
Um, and I think that the majority of the people that play casually, which is, I understand is 95% of the people that play the game.
Um, probably really like that.
And that event probably kind of aligns with what they're looking for.
So does, does a mid season event need to change from their perspective?
Maybe not.
The, the thing for me about what has not drawn me to them is the events and mostly the rewards have not seemed very great.
Like for example, if, if I got to, if I did the, the, the winter event and I'd let me transmog as a snowman, like I'm actually a snowman on my horse.
I would have done that because I mean, I can be a snowman, but what they currently have doesn't entice me to log in and complete the event.
For me personally, and it's not because I just play in them.
People say, Oh, well, it's because racks plays them.
I like events that are timed and have some kind of a little competition to them.
It doesn't even have to take a lot of skill.
Um, it could be, Oh, I don't know who finds the most, the most, the most, uh, Rudolph, the red nose reindeer things in the snow for the, for the event.
And you win a prize and maybe there's a cap on how many noses you can find per day.
So that way the casuals don't miss out, but I love what POE does.
Like POE takes their game, gives you a completely different version of the game and has a little bit of a race to it, bro.
I'm never going to win those events ever.
I'm never going to win any prizes.
And I think that that's way more fun than the season events that Diablo four is doing.
So that's a complicated answer in that what they're doing right now is probably fine for the masses.
But if you want my answer, I haven't been enticed to play them at all for those reasons.
How do you feel about it?
Um, yeah. So, I mean, I guess if we're speaking about what, what things we have gotten, I would say for the most part, they're, they're okay.
Like the, I don't love the season events. I don't hate them.
Like it's something to do. It doesn't take particularly long. It's not exactly thrilling.
It comes in at a point in the season where we're pretty much already kind of done.
And it's just sort of maybe giving us a couple more hours of play time.
Um, on top of that. So we, we've had that, and we've also had Avatar of Zeer that also released later in the season.
That was in season two, season three, we had the gauntlet come in later on.
Uh, in both those cases, that was content also not for me.
So it's not something that I engaged in for, for very long either.
Um, I do, I do like that there is stuff to come back for.
Um, but I think I'm like you in that I, I would like it to be something that I guess I personally would be more invested in.
So what, what would make you more invested in them?
That's a great question. And I think, I don't know how familiar you are with Helldivers.
And I know anytime I bring this up, people are like, it's an entirely different game.
It's an entirely different genre. Okay, sure.
But to me, it is like the perfect example of live service done perfectly.
Because it's a game that cannot exist without it being a live service.
It justifies in every way it being a live service.
Their content rolls.
And I'm, so I'm not saying that this is what they should do in, in ARPGs, but just to frame what they do in Helldivers too.
They have a patch.
Uh, they have a patch once a week.
Uh, with, um, generally there's, there's new content that rolls out on a pretty regular basis.
Um, and they have stuff in their patch notes, but they also have stuff that's not in the patch notes.
And that tends to be like, like balance changes towards their weapons and stuff.
That's definitely in the patch notes, but then new enemies popping up that just sort of people discover it while they're playing the game.
And they sort of like have little teasers going up to it like a week before, like, oh, on this planet, I saw a mech and I could get in the mech guys.
I'm actually driving a mech. What the hell? They added mechs in the game.
And then like two weeks later, they give us this major mission to actually unlock the mechs for everyone.
So they sort of tease it in the game. First, people are like discovering stuff in the game and say, oh, what's this cool stuff?
And so the game is changing and evolving over time. And it's not all just like one patch where they say this is everything that's coming.
And now there's nothing left to get excited about and discover. So for me, I've been loving Helldivers.
Like I don't really play games outside of stream and I've been playing a ton of Helldivers with my friends and having a blast.
So I don't know. I really like the way Helldivers is doing things.
I wonder if there's any way to integrate that kind of stuff or something of that into an ARPG.
So you like the main thing for you is the element of surprise and discovery.
You don't quite know what you're getting into. And you have a feeling that when you're playing, you might uncover, you know, a little diamond in the rough kind of thing.
Yeah, that's definitely a part of it. And I think in the ARPG sense, we don't want to be changing builds because in an ARPG, you are investing heavily into creating your build.
So it's not like, oh, this new weapon. And now I need to like redo all my character or whatever.
But like if it's content that we're doing, like a dungeon or an enemy type or a raid or, you know, whatever.
Sorry, raid is not the word. You know, some kind of boss or an Uber, like new things to engage with as opposed to things that are changing our build.
Right. Like we want to stick with the same build that we're building up because we're investing time into it.
If the game, you know, if we're getting a balance change every week, then it's like, well, why am I even bothering to grind up all this gear?
It's going to get nerfed next week. But I do think there's places, especially with this big open world of Diablo 4, justify the open world.
Make things happen that attract us to different places to go there, you know, check out whatever dungeon that is or whatever pit runner. I don't know.
Yeah, the I'm trying to think of analogies in Diablo 4. I have been surprised a few times. I didn't know. I remember in the vampire theme, I didn't know how the ambushes that the ambushes were going to happen. I almost died.
Yeah, that was cool. And I was testing on the PTR and I ran into a goblin pack. They didn't put that in the patch notes. I don't think. Oh yeah.
So that so that but those are probably kind of like maybe too small in scope for what you're talking about. You're looking for something a little bit bigger than that. But I mean, as someone who degenerately blasts the game, you definitely you definitely notice those things.
I'm surprised they didn't put other kinds of goblins in the game. Maybe that's another thing I could ask them about.
Um, I'd imagine maybe over time that something we'll, we'll do. Yeah. You want to know another thing that I really enjoy in games? It's in, it's in like all the different games. It's in POE. It's in Elden ring. It's, it's in Diablo 3.
I forget when you're playing the game and there's a, like a very rare chance or like a secret that opens a portal somewhere entirely different. And it asks you the question, do, would you like to go in here instead and see what's in here? And when it's like, you know, it's challenging or it's rewarding, then it can be really fun. Like when the vault spawns or the POE side areas, when I went through the campaign as a beginner, you know, you see the side area, you really want to go do it.
It looks fun. You know, you find out later, oh, you just skip everything and just run through it. But the idea of it is there. Elden ring, you open a chest and it teleports you to an end game zone. And there's like a big dragon in front of you. It's like, ah, should I really go fight him? Probably not. But if I kill him, he might drop me like his tooth or something. And then I can kill everybody. Um, I wonder if that would be another kind of thing that you're describing. Can you give a, like, imagine we're running nightmare, you're running nightmare dungeons in season four. And on your 40th one, it just drops a gold.
Portal. And it just says leads to a place that does not exist. It doesn't have to be the cow level, but anything. And you'd be like, holy shit, what is this? I have never seen this. Okay, let's go in. Let's, let's see what we have here.
I think that'd be absolutely amazing. And I guess so question for you and for, you know, chat as well, because I know some people they want everything to be launching at the start of the season. But what if that happened like a month in like no, no announcement from Blizzard, but one month in to the new season, racks is playing and suddenly a portal opens and no one knows what the hell this is. Everyone is seeing this for the first time on racks is stream. And he goes in and it takes him to the cow level, for instance, or whatever, something else.
And now all of a sudden people are like, well, there's this new level and people are going to start logging people who like they were done with the season. Now they're going to start logging back in to try to find this, this new secret level.
Oh, data miners. I didn't think of data miners.
Ooh.
The thing about data, the interesting thing about data mining is, um, so there's a massive push to, you know, find the cow level and we have like, I think we've progressed as far as we can into the, into the quest or whatever.
And, but the thing is, is with data mining is there is no data mine for an area called the cow level or anything with a mysterious name or mysterious mobs.
Like they've looked at it very, very thoroughly and it's just not there.
So it's kind of hard to, I don't, I don't know how you hide anything from the internet anymore.
They did this already with sellers.
I would say yes on a very, I wouldn't say on a minor level sellers are cool, but you kind of have to, the thing about sellers is you gotta, again, uh, when I see a seller nowadays, now that I played the game for a while, I'm not dying to dive into that seller.
I got bigger fish to fry the surprise that could be waiting in the seller is usually not worth the time invested to check it.
It's it. That's why I don't, I don't know when you see a seller, CJ, if you're doing hell tide, if you're trying to get some boss mats, if you're leveling up your nightmare dungeons, do you get on your pony and ride over to a seller to go check it out for a surprise that might be in there?
Sell lar? What, what is this?
The, the little, the little random, the, I'm trolling you. Yeah, no, I, I don't, I don't care at all about sellers. Yeah.
Okay.
You got me on that one. I was like, what?
What?
Oh, yeah, no, I think that's a great point where like, if, if they are going to add these, these transformative things, they, they need to be significant enough that we would care about them. Right? Like if, if, you know, a, a month into the season, they add like a flower in a town, like it's not something that's big and exciting.
Yeah, exactly. Okay. Um, before I let you go, are there any final things? Cause I got one thing I have to do before we start here is I have to organize these probably by order of importance. Cause I don't think I will get through like, I don't know, like any of this, but I'll try. Um, is there any other critical question that you would like to get an answer on that didn't get to yesterday that we haven't already covered?
Uh, I'm going to think on that a moment longer, but I will also say, uh, I ordered my questions in order of importance and I realized I should have also kept in mind.
How long each of these questions would take to answer. Cause I had to start triaging throughout the interview and skipping some of my important ones, just cause I knew that they would be really big answers. And so I was jumping down to still important, but very shorter questions. So something just to bear in mind, I guess, as you're also, uh,
uh, asking those, um, I don't know if, I don't think I got to ask about map overlay. I know some people still care about that. It's probably going to be a shorter answer.
Um, Oh, PVP again, not a super priority thing, but I did kind of want to ask, are you guys happy with where PVP is now? Uh, or do you have any plans to expand on in the future?
Uh, trade you've opened up trade in season four. Any plans to give us some tools or something to increase the quality of life of trade? So don't have to go to external websites.
I have a, that's my number three. I will get to that is social features, trading group finder clans. Um, and, uh, asking about, you know, trying to avoid third party sites.
Beautiful.
Yep. I have that. Um, so I can do like quick hits here. Um, so the quick hits I have are how do they feel about loot filter? How do they feel about PVP? How do they feel about SSF? Um, how do they feel about offline mode?
How do they feel about ladders? Uh, we can put, here's one question I wanted to ask. I mean, it's kind of low priority, but I wanted to ask them.
Mike Ybarra, before he left, tweeted that Diablo five will come much faster than Diablo four. Do you think I would ever get an answer to the question of, um, have you guys already started to work on Diablo five?
Or plans about what Diablo five would be? I mean, even if the answer is yes, do you think that we'll ever, do you think I'll even get a yes or a no answer out of them for that or no?
They wouldn't say whether they started to work on Diablo five. Um, they might start, they might say they've been thinking about it, which I mean, honestly, whether they've started working on it or not, like it's an easy answer to say, well, sure.
We've thought about, you know, Diablo five. Um, you might want to ask, um, like bring up the Ybarra quote specifically and ask what they think about that or what they think he meant about that might be a way to allow them to say something on the topic.
I'm just going to delete it. Let's just get rid of it. I, I ain't got no time for any wishy-washy questions that aren't going to get, they aren't going to get an answer.
Um, another thing that I saw a lot of people, uh, another thing that I saw a lot of people
ask about was the campaign. So a lot of people liked the campaign, probably like the most polished, polished experience that Diablo four delivered.
And the campaign is one and done. Now people don't, there's some people despise the thought of doing the campaign again.
Especially like the escort quest with the camel or whatever that that was pretty brutal.
But I wonder if Diablo four could be a game where you could actually choose and it would be a legitimate choice where you could benchmark.
Okay. What is leveling up in hell tide in the overworld look like after you spend three hours doing it, you are essentially at this level with this kind of gear.
And then you time a campaign run for three hours and you, you expedite, you know, the, the camel quest or whatever, make it, you know, get rid of a lot of the stuff that no one wants to do a second time.
But for the most part, just keep the whole campaign intact. And then after you get done with that, you're at about the same spot and let people choose. Do you want to do the campaign or do you want to do the overworld? Cause right now, if you do the campaign, you're just a million years behind.
That's actually a really clever way of, um, of doing it. Cause yeah, my first thought upon hearing like the campaign is exactly what you said. I'm like, Oh God, like don't make us have to do the campaign again.
But that's actually a really clever way of, um, yeah, working it in where it's still more efficient to, you know, just slam the health heads. But for those who want to do it, you're not going to be terribly far behind.
All right, man. Well, I appreciate you as a person. I appreciate your professionalism in the interview. I think you cracked the egg and got into actually a lot, a lot of, um, really good topics. I know a lot of people are big fans of yours. You've been doing this for a long time. So big respect, man. I'll, uh, try to do round two of this and see if we can get, uh, see if we can get some more questions answered here.
Love you, Rex. Appreciate you. I look forward to your interview. Best of luck. You're going to kill it. And, uh, I'll be watching.
All right, man. Guys round of applause for CJ. Here we go with a round two of the interview for blizzard. Thanks, man.
Take care.
Okay.
I need, okay. So a lot of these questions up here, I think are important. What I need your, I don't think I have my, I'm only have 16 more minutes, not even 16.
Um, so I have the top questions for you. The, the, the, the, the important thing here is the order. I'm going to ask these questions first. I'm just follow up to CJ's interview. So I'm gonna, I'm gonna ask these questions first.
Um, um, actually don't really care about this. I, I'm not gonna have time. Let me just delete it. Um, the top questions for YouTube. I'm asking the social features is way too important. I must ask it. Here's the, um,
um, this is supposed to be here. Social features is going to get asked a hundred percent. I already asked this question. I can delete it.
Um, this is really not that important. Just delete it.
Maybe I can put it down here. Let me organize this for a second. Give me a moment.
Um, okay.
Let me look at this.
This is probably lower priority. I'm going to put this lower. I don't really care about how Microsoft,
I don't need this question anymore. Let's put this here and delete this.
I really want to, I really want to talk about this. I really want to talk about the target audience of Diablo 4,
if they are willing to talk to me about it.
I'm going to move this lower.
Maybe here.
Let's go, uh, let's go like that. Okay.
Maybe we can go here.
It's actually a way.
I want to know when Uber Tomb Lord is coming out.
Did I put the campaign somewhere else?
Um,
got another question that we need to ask a map overlay. Another question that we need to ask.
Is.
Something about balance.
This is kind of a, like a generic question.
We can keep it, but maybe I put it.
Much lower.
Let's cut this out.
This, I think is a very, this is a very good question.
I really want, I really want to ask about, I, I must ask about this.
I'm going to put it, I just, I'm going to press this out.
Okay.
Um.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to set a timer for 40 minutes.
And then when I get to 40 minutes, I'm going to go to the quick hits and I'm going to ask all of them.
Just real quick knee-jerk reaction to what do they think about these things.
So let's set it for 40 minutes.
And then I'm going to ask all of them.
What time is the interview?
In 11 minutes.
Okay.
I think this is important.
I already asked all of these, so I'm consolidating my list significantly.
Social features.
I need this to go here.
This needs to be tabbed over.
All right.
Okay.
Man, dude.
So let's look at the order here that I have and let's see if this is pretty good or not.
So the first thing I want to talk to them about is pinnacle content.
I'm going to ask this first.
They talked about it a lot in CJ's interview.
I want to ask them, is there ever going to be skill involved in the end game or is it all going to be about gear?
Along with that, let's ask for a roadmap.
Is there a main focus in the end game?
That's the thing I care about probably the most.
I think I can delete this question.
I don't need to ask that.
They always say that they deeply care about feedback.
And one super mysterious thing about Blizzard is how do you actually receive the feedback?
Do you guys have meetings about it?
Can you walk me through, like, does someone, is Adam, is Adam, God, how many Adams are there?
There's Adam Jackson.
There's Adam Fletcher.
How many Adams and Joes are there?
Does he gather, is there a team that gathers it all and then you look at it and then you have a meeting about it?
I want to know how do they process feedback and how do they test things.
I want to hear from them how they do it.
The State of Nightmare Dungeons, they made them better.
You can teleport to them.
You buffed Glyph XP.
They're putting more things to do in them, like events.
You lowered the cast time to 0.75 seconds.
And they said that, they said in CJ's interview that they want to iterate on Nightmare Dungeons.
So, I want to ask them, have they considered more qualitative ideas, not only with the current state of Nightmare Dungeons, but in the future?
For example, can we carry multiple objects?
If you have two rocks and two pedestals, if you go rock, rock, you're already guaranteed to backtrack, right?
Stuff like that.
Is there any reason why we can't reduce the cast time further?
You miss 100% of the shots you don't take.
It's not necessarily that I mind freeing prisoners.
It's I mind freeing seven prisoners.
Why is there seven of them?
How about like three where I just click them and they're free?
And then the slay all with one monster behind.
I know that there was a fix for little things to follow you, but that doesn't work all the time.
And it bricked some of our Nightmare Dungeons.
Don't get into drama questions.
Right.
I don't think any of this has any drama to it.
What?
There's no drama here.
Okay.
There's no ghost anyone who can do this.
But it seems to have someism in the for your business.
Okay.
You don't have anyuge今日.
I'm done.
So they're setting up and their Discord is broken.
Their Discord is broken, so we're going to do it in Zoom.
So they're going to send me a Zoom link.
There's something wrong with Discord.
So we're going to Zoom.
Okay.
They're not trying to back out.
No, they're not trying to back out.
Okay.
Yeah, M3X did, Seattle.
All right.
Okay.
Let's see how Zoom is going to go.
All right.
Let me...
I guess we're going to join now.
Let me switch my screen real quick and see if I can join the Zoom link.
Be right back.
All righty.
Click on this.
Open the Zoom meeting.
Here we go.
Join.
That should work.
Let's try that.
Okay.
I'm in.
But let me see.
I think I have to start virtual camera on OBS.
Let me start the...
There we go.
Does that work?
There.
Well, kind of.
I'm about to move my...
Let me move this down, maybe.
There.
That actually kind of worked.
Okay.
All right.
It was a mic issue that was disable Adam Jackson's mic.
I'm flexible, man.
I am flexible.
We do whatever.
Whatever works.
I'm big chilling over here.
Big chilling over here.
All right.
Yeah.
I'm just sitting here.
Let's see if Adam and Joe can come in here.
All right.
Well, while we're waiting here,
I guess there's...
I guess there's no issue in me.
Coming back here, right?
Okay.
Let me see here.
Let me get rid of this webcam, maybe.
Let me get rid of this.
All right.
What's up?
And I wonder if I can show...
Hey, what's going on, man?
What is up?
All right.
Can you...
We're doing it.
It's happening.
Can you guys hear him fine?
Is he fine up or down?
How is it sounding, guys?
Can you talk for a second, Joe?
Just testing the ups and downs.
You know, what's up?
How do I sound, chat?
Okay.
I can see it's way too low.
I'm going to turn you way higher.
Let's try again.
I can just start screaming.
Hey, how do I sound right now?
Okay.
Is that better, guys?
Up more.
Okay.
We're going...
I have you at 100.
Okay.
Oh, man.
This is dangerous.
I'm going to...
This is going to get dangerous when I get excited about something.
So we got to watch out for that.
Apologizing in advance.
Hey, thanks so much for coming on here, man.
I'm really excited.
Yeah.
This is going to be a blast.
I'm looking forward to the conversation.
Hell yeah.
Yeah.
Where's my partner in crime?
Where's Adam Z.
Jackson?
You want to know what?
He's faking all of these technical issues and he's just like, you want to know what?
I'm going to call in sick and I'm just going to have Joe solo this.
Yeah, it's fine.
Let's do it.
Let's just sign him up for a whole bunch of stuff.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do here, tried my best to be as prepared as possible.
Cool.
But of course, I'm probably not prepared at all.
So that's just the way life goes.
No, no, no.
It's all good.
Hey, and one thing up front, right off the top here is like, I have a lot of things I
want to say, but it's okay if you want to interject.
So it's not rude.
I'm not going to take it as being rude.
So if there's the things you want to chat through or things you want clarification on,
please interrupt me.
It's all good.
I feel like I want to give that preface to everybody I talk to now on stream, right?
I would never interrupt that sweet, angelic, mellow fluous voice.
Speaking of that, Adam Jackson is here.
Let's take four questions.
Can people hear me okay?
I've spent the last 45 minutes troubleshooting my mic and it's been the worst.
It's okay?
Okay.
Dude, is that a paper towel roller by your bed?
How do I get one of those?
I have kids.
They're very messy.
It's part of the life.
Dude, that is, that's the most ingenious thing I've ever seen.
We're pretty creative over here.
You can hear me okay though.
I'm very concerned about this.
It's fine.
Okay.
Thank God.
I mean, I can hear you.
Chat, can you hear them?
Sounds perfect for me.
How is it for you guys?
All right, cool.
Because I changed, I fucked with all my computer settings and now everything's terrible.
But as long as it works, I'm happy.
All right.
Okay.
I'm starting a 40 minute timer.
Then we'll do rapid fire at the end to try to hit as many as possible.
That sounds good.
Sounds good to me.
Thank you so much for being here, guys.
All right.
Yesterday, CJ Riker did an interview with them.
So he asked a bunch of great questions.
I want to do some follow-ups to some of the questions that you guys talked about.
So one thing, the topic that I think you guys probably covered the most in the interview
yesterday at different parts was about aspirational and pinnacle content.
Some of the things that you said that was uber Lilith at the start of the Diablo 4 was
all mechanical mastery.
If you don't dodge the waves, you're dead.
There's pretty much nothing you can do about that.
And a lot of players didn't have fun just, you know, getting crushed by her waves.
Talked about there's different lovers to pull on the difficulty.
You can make players weaker like Nightmare Dungeon Sigils.
You can make monsters hit harder.
You can give them more health, more crowd control.
And I heard you say that the decisions that you make before you go into the encounter should
matter more because it's an ARPG.
It's about hunting loot.
It's about getting powerful.
And then you go in and you have a big advantage and you finally overcome the difficulty.
And another thing that I heard you guys say is when you guys introduce very difficult
events like the Avatar of Zier, for example, when you properly advertise it as something that's
very difficult, you didn't get any negative backlash or too much negative backlash for
the difficulty of it because it was properly labeled.
So with that huge preface in mind, my question is, is do you guys have plans in the future
of Diablo 4 to build in these very, very difficult encounters that do require skill, that do require
you to go in with an event or with a boss, learn their mechanics, and that is going to be
another supplement besides getting gear to winning.
Thoughts on that?
Yeah, sure.
So I can just kind of, I'll start off.
So yeah, everything we talked about yesterday, you just did a good job of covering again.
I appreciate that.
But when we think about what the future of aspirational content needs to look like in
the game, we do want to leave opportunities for this kind of mechanically complex content
for players to engage with.
And we experiment with it a few different ways.
So I don't think that, like the Echo Lulith encounter, it's a really good example of
like, you know, us like diving really, really hard into mechanical mastery where we expect
players to really have to be very, very active in terms of their dodges in order to survive.
But we do want to continue to experiment with these ideas and try more things, particularly
when they are advertised in the appropriate place.
Adam, do you have thoughts on this?
Yeah, originally I did.
And it was like a very long winded answer.
But I don't want to take up too much time on this.
I guess what I'll say is, you know, everything kind of exists on a spectrum when we're talking
about things like difficulty or a lot of game design topics and ideas.
Because like in this spectrum, in my mind, it's like, you know, how hard should the fame
be versus how much should your gear going into it matter, right?
I think we're still trying to find out what the best answer is for the things that are
really, really hard, like Uber Lilith or these crazy, difficult fights.
One of the things that we're doing in season four that we started doing in Beyond that one
of our encounter designers came up with a great idea was adding this.
I think you've probably seen our array racks, but that second debuff idea where, you know,
you can screw up getting hit by a wave a couple of times, but then after that, you're
probably just going to get one shot and die.
And so that gives us this kind of happy medium between pure one shot mechanics and things
where you have to be perfect in your dexterity versus, you know, the other way where you
can just like outgear everything.
There's some other things that can go into of like, you know, the difference of the most
powerful and least power or mid powerful builds and how we do difficulty.
Maybe we'll give that a different answer, but that's the TLDR.
I think we're still trying to figure out what is best for our game and what our players
like.
You know, in my heart of hearts, I'm more like you racks.
I love the very, very crazy hard things.
I don't mind one shots personally in my games, but I don't think it's best for this game.
Yeah.
It's not millennia.
We have play it.
Yeah.
I don't think that it's best long term, but having a little bit of that kind of stuff
sometimes I think is okay.
I think it's more how much and how we introduce it and how we frame it to people.
That's the simple answer.
Okay.
So kind of like one thing that you guys are liking is kind of like the soft enrages where
over time, eventually it gets to get so difficult that you're eventually going to lose.
Yeah.
Fancy 14 does a good job with this as well.
Like they have this idea, like, you know, if you mess up a mechanic, you're going to
get stacking deep off and it can escalate and get worse and worse as the fight goes
on.
It's an interesting way to allow for some mistakes or current for some learning to happen,
but really like, and to punish you, but not immediately spike you and end the encounter.
Awesome.
So one thing that see some other games doing is they release roadmaps of kind of like in
the same topic of end game of things that, Kali, stop it.
Sit down.
Sorry about that.
Um, so for Diablo four, will we ever see roadmaps come out kind of showing like detailing what
might be coming in the next six months to a year?
I know that there's some challenges with that.
Like if you guys change your mind, then like the community gets really mad at you.
What are your thoughts on that?
I think it's important that community knows that we are identifying problems, you know,
and that we, we are listening as I've said before.
And I think that a roadmap does a good job of like expressing some of this information,
but it does, to your point, does lock us into a schedule.
So I think that we're, we're kind of like thinking about how we want to approach, like
explaining these sorts of things.
Like you'll recall back in like season two, I mentioned at the very end of, of actually
between when we were wrapping up season two and AOZ was out and we were getting ready to
begin talking about season three, I mentioned that we had identified a lot of itemization
issues and things that we wanted to make like upgrades to and make updates, which turned
into the season of Loot Reborn and season four.
Now I want to make it clear that we identified a lot of the issues that the players have been
talking to us about for a while, but we weren't able to like immediately resolve those sorts
of things.
So I don't want, one thing I, when I, I occasionally see from players when they see a long roadmap is
they'll see something that they care deeply about it, like really, really towards the end
of a year and they'll ask them like, well, do they not think this is important?
Do they not care about this?
And I, I think that there's a way for us to talk about these things that players feel
that they, they, they, that they have confidence, like that we are looking at these problems
and we do have plans.
So I think we're just working through exactly the way that we want to approach this.
Yeah, I think I'll chime in a little bit.
One of the things that you're going to hear is a constant theme from me and other designers
say this with different words, but there's this idea that there's, there's rarely really
perfect solutions.
There's really only trade-offs in the world.
And this actually comes from an economic term that says that there's never solutions, only
trade-offs.
But, you know, when you ask us things like, you know, why don't you do X or Y, or why
don't you provide roadmaps?
The way that our brains immediately go is, well, there's pros and cons and which decision
is best trying to get the most pros that we can with the least cons that we can, right?
It's a simple example of roadmaps is the pro of roadmap is everybody's on the
same page.
We show that, hey, we care about these things and the community knows what to expect, right?
Obviously, that is a desirable thing to do.
But there's big cons that maybe we have that you don't see.
And this is where most design discussions end up of people asking us, well, what do you
think as developers?
Is that we try to explain the cons to you so that you understand the full picture.
You know, the cons of a roadmap is we're locked in now.
We've promised things to you that we may not be able to do for whatever reason when things
end up changing down the road, right?
Life has a way of screwing with your plans, especially when you try to plan things more
long term.
This isn't just true with game design, but anything.
So we try to make promises and keep promises.
Like one of my things I'm really passionate about as a designer is when it comes to interacting
with the community, making promises and then keeping them.
So I'm extremely careful of the promises.
I mean, this is just my strategy of how to build trust with people and the community and
just life in general is I'm very careful of what promises I make.
And then I make damn sure when I do that I keep them.
And so to do that, the longer our roadmap goes out, the higher chance we're not going to
keep those promises.
Some things, for example, that we've seeded in the past.
I remember it was either our season one or season two campfire chat.
I made a list of things that our team wants to do longer term.
One of those things on those lists was making scaling mechanics for legendaries that kind
of suck.
And we finally were doing that in season four, right?
You know, your earthquake legendaries, all of those.
We finally made them scale with your weapon to make the damage go up.
I also talked about at the time, and we haven't delivered on this yet, in my opinion, but making
ultimates meaningful and scale in a similar way.
It's on our radar.
It's something I want to do.
Haven't done it yet.
I didn't give a date because I don't know when the date is because our timelines and
schedules and priorities change quite a bit based on community feedback.
You know, if I had made the promise like, hey, we're definitely fixing ultimates, then
Loot Reborn wouldn't have happened because I have to spend my team's time on doing that
other thing.
But this other thing came up that I think is way more important for the game.
And that's just kind of how the nature of our job goes.
Thank you for the super detailed answer.
And that is a perfect segue into my next question.
It's kind of like an addition of Mythbusters, kind of.
So a lot of people in the community, a lot of the people that are angry in the community
about, you know, whatever it is they're angry about at the time, they say that they're passionate
about something.
Passionate.
Very passionate.
That's the word we're looking for.
Constructively passionate.
Yeah.
So one thing that I they have, like the meme video of you guys saying feedback, feedback,
feedback.
And then on the Internet from a bunch of different angles, they say Blizzard doesn't listen to
They don't do anything.
They don't even test their game where their beta testers.
So I wanted to ask you guys, could you give us some insights into how your team actually
processes and internalizes feedback?
Is it like concatenated for you and you guys have a meeting and you discuss it like that?
How do you guys go about testing things internally to kind of debunk all of these myths that you
guys are just working by yourselves and never listening to anything?
We know it's not true.
You want to go first, Joe?
Yeah, I think we both probably have different things you want to say about this.
So I think that the point on feedback, I think that's being brought up, there's like kind of two
things.
Like one, are the designers in a corner entirely by themselves, like just making decisions with
no information being good to them?
And the other version is like, is the team listening to the community?
Right.
And then how do we process these sorts of things?
So the starting from the does the team listen to the community like side of this thing,
you know, we are always reading everything on that's getting posted on Reddit.
We're getting everything that's posted on the forums.
We're going through our socials on a regular basis.
We have teams and people like like Adam Fletcher, you know, the community director,
he's going through and like kind of gathering a lot of this information for us.
And in places where we don't like I personally can't read every thread in every social media
site.
You can't?
I can't because there's other things I also do as part of my job.
But I do read a lot of stuff.
Right.
And a lot of things get sent to me.
So a lot of that stuff can get like kind of pulled together for like reporting purposes
and brought to us.
Right.
And I think that's really, really useful.
We also have a lot of internal feedback that we get from the from the team.
Like so when we start working on something, we were able to like kind of give a presentation
to the overall dev team to get an idea of what we're trying to do.
We have regular play tests where like a large group of people all get a chance to kind
of give us feedback on a regular basis.
And we can keep checking in with them as time goes on.
So that's I think that's a starting point for these things.
But it's it's really important to us that we are like hearing things from the community
because that's kind of telling us like are the like are the changes that we're making
right now?
Are they effective?
Like are people having a good time with these things?
Because we can look at all kinds of data to determine things.
But like here when people talk about it is also really, really important when they have
when players have needs that aren't met.
You know, it's our job to find ways to kind of like bridge the gap there and make sure
that they're being heard.
And the game is going to be more fun for them.
But what do you want to talk about?
Yeah.
So firstly, I would say different game companies, different teams and even different teams
within a bigger team have different cultures and ideas and ways that they process feedback.
So I'll tell you what I do on my team and kind of what D4 kind of does as a larger team.
Right.
So on the live team, we are probably the most interactive with feedback because we're doing
the live changes.
We have to be very connected to the game to make good decisions.
So I give this speech a lot to the people on in my group of your job as a designer is
to go and find the problems with the game.
And then you are the filter when the community comes in and brings up things, whether it's
a streamer giving things.
I post things all the time from streamers.
I post things all the time from Reddit threads.
I post things all the time from our forums.
And anywhere that you can go out and go.
And also personal play experience.
Nothing replaces that as well.
So we actually dedicate every day at least some amount of time that everybody in my group
is either playing an internal build of future things coming out in the game, which I'm playing
through season five right now and I'm really far in it.
Or they're playing their live character in the live game because you need to understand
the game and understand the problems.
And the way that I do things and what I've been trying to tell my team and I think we're
pretty good at is while you are parsing all this feedback and playing the game yourself,
you keep a running list of notes of crap that sucks that you want to make better or ideas
that other people had that you think are good ideas that you want to make better.
Now, of course, not every idea is equal, right?
You don't copy every Reddit thread and every single thing that someone says.
We are the filter of trying to figure out.
Remember, I talked about those no perfect solutions, only trade-offs.
This is where we're like, hey, they brought up an idea and we think it's good.
Now we need to explore if that can actually work in the game.
And this is where we come up with our list of things and priorities that we're going
to do.
That's a starting point.
That's one of a few starting points.
The first starting point is community feedback, our own play experience.
Another one is telemetry.
That's just a fancy word for data.
We have the ability to see data all over the game of how many people are equipping different
legendary aspects, how many people are engaging with certain types of content.
We can see what's working, what's not working, what people are actually doing versus what
they say.
Usually what they say will match with what people are doing, but there's a mismatch.
Then we have to have a discussion of like, hey, how important is this actually?
And then another way is internal testing tools.
Again, we have groups that give us presentations and people who their job is to look through
data and do focus sessions and all kinds of other fancy tricks to come up with stories
and understanding the different types of players we have and what they're doing and how they
work.
And they give us presentations on different topics that we're interested in, or they
find their own topics of things that maybe we didn't think of that we may have missed.
And then last but not least, we have internal people.
You know, we have a big team of people working on this game and we have certain feedback avenues
via emails or channels that we give feedback to each other because on new stuff, we can't
rely on telemetry or the community or all those other things.
And that's where things are a lot harder.
I think Joe went into this yesterday a little more deeper, so I'll just gloss over it.
But this idea that Diablo is a freaking huge game that takes forever to play and really
truly understand because our systems are so interconnected.
So there is no substitute for actually going through that 80 plus hour experience and playing
everything.
The part that makes that really hard and where I think the community gives us a hard time
sometimes, I think a little bit of it is warranted, but it's a cursed problem is what I call
it, which is another concept I'll go into later.
Is that to really test our game, you need to spend your life playing our game in many
ways or a lot of time, more times, more hours than what you normally would expect someone
to work at a job, right?
So we can't tell people, hey, you must spend all your life playing this game, but also,
by the way, you have to design and create the new things too, right?
So that means that internally, it is really hard to play test the full amount of our game
as a designer.
We have to rely on, we have people in QA and other play testers that do play this content.
We either direct them of things we want to test and play, or they just find things on
their own that they think, hey, they bring it up to us, like, hey, we think this is a
problem and we have to parse that.
But there isn't enough time for a single designer or every designer to play the game fully all
the time, but we do still play it a good amount and we use those internal feedback mechanisms
to make things the best that they can.
And this is where I think there is that little disconnect sometimes with the community where,
yeah, we would love to polish things and play it.
Now, I would love to play season five 200 hours before it comes out.
I only get it for, you know, 50 hours, right?
And we have to use our guts and existing ideas and telemetry to figure out if the decisions
we make are right.
And then we use, after we launch the game, to really fine tune and make it perfect, right?
And that's kind of the overall process of how things work.
Yeah.
One last thing I want to add here too, is that even when we're just thinking about like
a feature, like we're talking about adding one thing, like something like the pit,
for example.
Good example, because it's going to be new coming out in season four.
If you sit down, you play the pit for an hour, one day, you're going to feel a certain way
about your experience playing the pit.
You're going to feel differently if you play that for two hours a day, five days straight,
you know, and you experience it through that entire process.
You're going to have a different relationship with the content at that point.
And players are going to go, you know, 10, 20 X that number by the time they're done
playing in season potentially.
So like, it's really, really important that we get the reps in on these features to make
sure that they're, they're really resonating and they're singing, they're doing everything
they need to do.
Right.
So I think if there's a, there's a lot of truth, everything that Adam's talking about, everything is a lot
of trade-offs, there's a lot of things we need to do.
And this, this kind of links to the PTR, the PTR feedback for season four was hugely valuable
because now suddenly we're able to like, take, take what we already know about the season
and then multiply that like 10, 20, 50 fold as we get tons of players going in, checking
things out, not just from the telemetry, but also just in the feedback we're getting
from content creators, from players themselves.
Like we've got a lot of really good data for that.
So it's been, it's been very useful for the same reasons that Adam talks about.
Yeah.
I mean, go ahead.
Sorry.
No, go ahead.
One last real quick thing is this is where you get things that seem obvious to players
that were bad ideas, but sounded like really good ideas when we're sitting in a room talking
about it.
That simple example I'll give in season four is when you temper your items or things and
there's like a really nice thing that plays and you can see it, it's visual, but you can't
skip it easily.
Right.
That kind of stuff is where sometimes things fall through the cracks of, hey, doing this
2000 times is actually terrible because you've got to wait forever versus, well, we want
to have a moment of celebration and for the cool thing to be cool.
Balancing these things is what can be harder to do internally.
We're obviously we've messed up enough times and this is true for every game company, so
I'm not afraid to admit it.
But like, you know, we've made that mistake enough times that we're now we're very cognizant
of it.
Like we make a new feature or a new activity.
Like, hey, how does this feel if you're doing it for 200 hours?
Is this still going to be something that people want to go through?
Right.
That's a question now that we ask all the time.
But even then, there are times where we have to kill otherwise good ideas or we have to
flex a little bit because we do need some presentation or some tutorialization or some
other thing to balance that, even if it makes the 2000 times experience a little bit worse.
Right.
The answer is not always so obvious, I guess.
But we are receptive to like when the community tells us clearly, hey, no, we want it to be this
way.
We're going to do it that way.
I mean, it was a lot of great points.
I mean, the I'm very glad that I asked that question because the thing that is refreshing
to me, the thing that I wanted to hear more than anything is that you guys have a chance
to actually play through the game and not only to hear that you guys play the game as almost
part of the job description, but it sounds like you actually put a big effort into that.
That I mean, that makes me feel that makes me feel great.
Honestly, that's that's so great to hear.
I'm so glad that's part of the process.
Talking about some of the current modes in the game.
Let's talk about you talked about yesterday, the state of nightmare dungeon.
CJ did a ton of iteration on it.
Now we can teleport to them.
You just buffed glyph XP.
You said that you'd like to add more fun things to do to them in the future.
You guys made events better.
Now I saw goblin packs, I think on the PTR when you put the vampire ambushes.
That was good.
You reduce the cast time down to 0.75 seconds.
So we're going to have new things coming out for it.
My question is, is going forward, it looks like you guys made a ton of qualitative changes
to it.
Like you just make it a little bit easier to access all of these different things rather
than riding around on your pony to every single thing and everything takes forever.
When you are designing future things, is that kind of at the front of your mind with things
like, oh, maybe at nightmare dungeons we can carry multiple objects?
Because if there's two rocks and two pedestals, if you go rock, rock, you're guaranteed to
backtrack.
I mean, I have two hands.
And then have you thought about reducing the cast time even further?
I know that one comment was if the cast time is so low, then people may not even see that
they interacted with something, but maybe that could be updated via like a little quest
thing.
Oh, quest, pick up two rocks.
Oh, it highlights.
Oh, now pick up one rock.
And another part of it was, it's not just that I have a problem freeing prisoners.
I have a problem going to Dead Man's Dredge and the quest objective is I have to free seven
prisoners.
Like how many people got caught here?
Is qualitative stuff still at the front of your mind when you're iterating on these things
and in the future events that you're going to make?
So I think that there's a couple different pieces to pick apart here, right?
So with Nightmare Dungeons, they're building upon the dungeons we had in Diablo 4, right?
And these were supposed to be these really like kind of interesting little content things
you could find all over the world.
They all had little bits of like environmental storytelling, objective-based storytelling, some
side quest points to these dungeons as well.
And we want players to feel like they're kind of, they're going on a little bit of adventure
when they go into these.
We didn't, we didn't initially make the content in these spaces to feel like there was like
blast corridors, if that makes sense, right?
So I think that as we, as we think about what different players are looking for and what,
what we can do to improve the experience for everybody, we don't want to lose the kind
of like the contextual and like fantasy underpinnings of what players are doing to go into
these spaces.
To your point, like, you know, it's not that you hate freeing prisoners.
No, but you don't like that it might take, you know, 0.75 seconds to do it is one question
maybe.
And then there's another one where it's like, well, you don't want to free seven.
So you kind of want it to be like a faster, more punchy experience, but it's not that
you don't like having to click those objects as part of your experience going through a
dungeon.
I think that like there's, I think there's an expectation when players are like doing some
of these actions that there is a response.
So having just a, like a quest tick for some things, I'm not saying that this is where
we would only ever make this decision and a quest tick for things like freeing a prisoner.
It is, it is feedback.
Is it as impactful as having the moment where you get to see your character on bind that
on the binds?
I'm not so sure, you know, but in the end is that value, it's to Adam's point earlier
about like, you know, it's about making trade-offs.
Is the, is the idea for the player who does care, does care about like kind of going slowly
through the space and trying to find the collectibles and trying to do all these things for that
player.
Is it, is it going to be a big miss for them if they click on stuff and just kind of like
has a quick update, doesn't feel like anything really changed.
So it's sort of like where we want to optimize things.
I think when you look at content, like the, like the pit, you know, and a lot of things
we did in Helltide as well, you know, we've made a lot of attempts to try to make sure
that the content feels like there is less friction, you know, as you're going through.
So like when you get into a flow state that you're, that you're happy with, uh, that you
can kind of maintain that, that, that pace.
So, and we made a number of changes we already called out to Nightmare Dungeons to also kind
of support this.
So I think it's a question of like how much further do we want to go within Nightmare
Dungeons specifically, right?
Because I think we've already said that we're looking at this for other, other pieces of content.
Um, I don't know where we're going to fall necessarily for the, uh, for the, the channel
time for clicking on, uh, objects and freeing them.
It could be that it comes out a little bit lower.
It could be that we decide we want to make changes to make it more, more instantaneous.
We haven't really made a decision.
You know, we'll continue to be looking at feedback as we play.
And also from like different players, like players who are just playing Diablo 4 for the
first time, want to kind of hear what their experience is like as well.
Awesome.
Uh, so here's kind of like a, here's kind of like maybe a huge question, but it asks very
directly.
Um, so what is kind of the future of the overworld in Diablo 4?
When we first released, it was kind of the main thing you used to do everything.
And kind of the first experience was that 50 to 100 grind.
Now one to 100 is much easier.
And the focus is probably, you know, having, enjoying that journey, going to the pit and
anything in the future that you're going to release.
A lot of the things that seem to come out though, the abattoir and the challenge riff thing
and the pit, they're all instanced things.
Are there big plans for the overworld?
Is that still like the defining characteristic of Diablo 4?
Or are we moving away from that?
So we, you know, Diablo 4 and the fact that we have this like big contiguous sanctuary is
still a really big part of Diablo 4.
Now, uh, I think that we want to continue to expand the, uh, the landmass and the areas
where players can explore.
That's still an important part of things.
But in terms of how players are engaging with the experience overall, we do expect that,
um, one of the, one of the downsides of the, uh, of the, the open world, uh, is that it
is a, it's a fixed layout, right?
So if we think about like the sorts of things that players like to play in a, in a, in a,
in a, like a replayable content fashion, right?
It's not normally in place where you like really want to keep running through exactly the
same, uh, glade in the fracture piece or exactly the same area, you know, of Keteristan.
Like it's, it's, it's usually, you're trying to like find like different things to kind
of go engage with.
And like our dungeon systems are places where you can really do a lot more of that.
I think we push it really well within Helltides.
You know, there's lots of things happening in Helltides.
Uh, they're pretty procedural in terms of how things respond in and like what sorts of events
you might find as you're kind of wandering around.
Uh, but in terms of like having a lot more like flexibility to create different experiences,
we have that really more in other systems.
But I think for, this is like, uh, going back to some things I talked about the other day.
But there's sort of like the experience that a player has, Diablo is a, is a, is a big
game, right?
And, uh, and I don't say that to suggest that any, any, anyone's needs are less important,
just that there are a lot of different needs.
Different players have different expectations.
So when some players come into Diablo, like they're here because they want to go through
like this epic story.
They want to play their, they really want to play a sorceress and they want to like see
what happens to Lola if they want to go explore all, they want to find all the things
in all the zones and they want to get really, really powerful.
And then they're going to, they're going to take a break until the expansion comes out.
That's just the way that they sort of play these games.
It's how they, that's how they play, right?
For those players, these moments as they explore the world, it's really, really important because
that's their experience with Diablo.
It's like their exploration of the overworld, them going and finding all these side quests,
talking to all these characters, and that's their relationship with the game.
For players who play seasonally, you know, they, it's, it's once you've kind of like uncovered
all the applications, since you've found all these things and done this stuff, you don't,
there's not usually a lot of reasons why you want to go and have that same moment of discovery
again.
You can't really recreate it.
We talked for a while about like moving little statues around season to season.
So you'd have to collect them again.
It's, it's, it's another, another one of my brilliant ideas.
So we didn't, we didn't do it of course.
Right.
But like we had the idea of like every season we'd move where the little statues could
be found.
So players have to go find them again.
But then the next conversation is immediately like, well, okay, so people are going to go
on to maximum or whatever, and they're going to go immediately see where the node map
is for the next set of ultra little.
Then that's now their new homework they have to do at the beginning of every season.
They have to run around on their horse and go collect every single one of these.
And it's like, is that fun?
No, clearly not for that, for that player.
It, but it wasn't, it was necessarily horrible.
The first time players do this, like that's, that's part of the fun of like, almost like
an open world game.
Anyway, it's kind of like exploration and finding things.
So I know that I'm, I'm, I'm getting to go long, but so I think that the, the, the
underpinning point here is that the, the overworld of Diablo four is so really, really important.
As we think about how to make the best use of it for like replayable content, you know,
hell tide is a good example of this.
Blood harvest is really, really, really, really helpful for kind of giving us some like
ideas of what players are really excited about things that we could do better.
Like the like kind of light social gameplay of summoning creatures and things.
And I think we have other ideas we continue to explore in that direction.
I think Legion events and boss events are things we continue to like kind of iterate
on and think more about, you know, but, uh, I think that in terms of creating like, like
really compelling replayable content, I think it's going to end up being in more of the
space where you have like more procedural control over how like the dungeon is formulated or like
what players can expect to encounter as opposed to these, uh, these more fixed outdoor locations.
Does that answer your question?
Yeah.
So I guess laughing at me, I didn't answer the question.
No, no.
Boy, these are such in-depth answers.
I'm, I'm just scared.
I'm looking over at my questions.
I'm, I'm never going to, I'm trying to figure out how to skip around for all of them.
So I guess I'm so sorry.
No, no, no.
So the main takeaway that I'm getting there is the overworld is a super important part
of it.
Like a first player's experience discovering everything, but then it's hard to recreate that
magic for the people that comes season to season to season.
And that's why it goes more to instance stuff is kind of, I guess the summary of,
the summary of it.
Yeah.
That's reasonable.
And I think we're also just on a regular basis looking for new ways to engage with the, uh,
with the open world in ways that are going to be fun for seasonal players as well.
Like, so we're, we're, we're continuing to find like just experimenting with things,
see what makes it like fun and new for players.
Okay.
I promised I would ask this.
So there, uh, maybe there might be a player out there that you guys have heard of and
have maybe added, I don't know, hundreds of hours of overtime to the team, Rob and Rob.
You're familiar.
Just a little familiar.
Yeah.
So he had a,
Rob, love Rob.
He is a good guy.
He had a two questions about the pit.
These are probably a little bit more straightforward, but, um, I guess for, for end game activities
is do you guys ever think about or worry about, I guess, fishing?
So like it gets to a point in the pit where, oh, you're fishing for the right mob type or
you're fishing for the right boss or, and then you just leave kind of like what happened in
Diablo three or, oh, I'm going to go get a very on and hopefully that it procs the,
the amazing shrine for me.
So then I can finally win.
And do you guys off the top of your head know about how much the health in the pit
was buffed by?
And I, I'm guessing that the main idea for there is not only to add difficulty, but to
actually, because the, when you were going through the pit, the bills are so strong that
you delete the, the rift part of it in two minutes, like clockwork every time.
And the monsters don't even get to do anything.
So I assume like the part of the reason for buffing it is to actually even let them get
a hit on you and see what they even do.
Yeah.
I can take the first part of the question at least.
I mean, I can take both too.
Joe wants to take the other part.
So talking about fishing.
Yes.
Fishing for stuff keeps me up at night and I hate the problem.
And it's a really hard problem to solve.
Remember that no salute, you know, rarely perfect solutions, only trade offs thing.
Right.
So this very much applies to this type of problem.
A core thing that we want in our game is, and when it comes to combat and effects and
legendary powers and unique powers and whatever, is we want to push the elbow, make cool shit.
Right.
So on one end of the spectrum, you need to make cool stuff.
And that involves doing things that aren't necessarily completely deterministic because
I think completely deterministic things after a while get kind of boring.
Right.
When you know that you're going to get this effect or it's up all the time, or you do this
and get this, like we do it a lot, by the way.
So I'm not saying that's not a good design, but just.
You need to have some spiciness, some really cool, crazy things.
Right.
And that, that unique, uh, uber unique power is one of those.
Um, on the flip side though, it means that when you make really hard content, uh, doing
things like wanting to make cool stuff, uh, fishing gets in the way of that a lot of times,
especially in randomly generated content, which is what, you know, the pit is in many ways.
So that is why we have to do things that we, that by the way, we as designers don't like,
like removing the fun shrines or the things that are going to break, because then you
just find the shrines that, you know, break the game in whatever way.
And that's all that you're doing.
And that becomes the game.
Um, this is a core thing about ARPGs that I, in my opinion, after working on it now for
years, and I've been involved in pretty much every game genre extensively as a player and
many as a designer.
Um, I think ARPGs are one of the hardest, if not the hardest genre to design for.
Uh, MMOs are really high up there too.
Um, there's a lot of other genres I think are very difficult, but ARPGs are a special
slice of, of awfulness when it comes to trying to make things fun and also make them interesting.
Um, and this is one of the reasons why.
So as far as like this exact design of the spear, uh, we're keeping it in for now.
Um, I would be very sad if we had to redesign it because it's the only way to get through
high pit tiers.
That would make me personally sad, but because that is the most difficult thing to do, uh,
we may have to make a tweak to it, but we're not doing it yet.
We're going to see how it plays out.
Um, but I think that the conversation is more interesting of conceptually, like, you know,
is this a problem?
Yes, absolutely.
Does it mean that we can't do things that would otherwise be cool and awesome for your
average player?
Yes, absolutely.
But we also think it's best for the game because I think fishing for the right tile set,
the right mob, like restarting a thing over and over to be able to progress is not
fun.
Um, and therefore we have to design the rest of our game knowing that that is a pain.
Um, yeah, just adding to that too, like, I think that, you know, we definitely see fishing
as a problem so much so that we built the gauntlet, you know, for the trials feature with fishing
specifically as the thing we're trying to account for.
Where we said, all right, if we, if we have a competitive content feature players going
to engage with and it's randomized, then players aren't really competing until they find
exactly the right seed that they managed to roll to compete against.
Cause that's the actual optimal seed that they need to compete on, compete on.
It's only against this monster family or only with this dungeon tile layout or only with
this, like these set of shrines or whatever it is.
So instead what we did is we made a highly deterministic content type that changed it
every week.
Like, and players went to it and said like, well, why is it so fixed?
Like, this is boring.
Like I want, I want something like, I want something that's, that's different and changes
every time.
But then you kind of fall back to that same point that I brought up about like curse,
like these, the trade-offs for all the problems that we have.
Then we, we have to decide like, all right, so we okay with the idea that like players
are going to go into a, like a gauntlet run and they're gonna have a wildly disparate
experience potentially between person A and person B.
And they're just continually running the, the content over and over again in the hopes
they eventually get a good seed.
And that might be the way that they're able to place because the difference could potentially
be vast between one thing and the next.
So it's a, you know, it's a complicated space.
Something we definitely think about.
The other part of your question was what, what did we do about the, what did we do about
like health scaling in the pit?
The HP, how much did it go up by?
Yeah.
So we did make some big changes there.
So basically what was happening in the PTR is that monster scaling, monster health scaling was
pretty mild in the pit going through the first hundred levels.
It was basically virtually nil, you know, from level 100 on more or less.
Right.
So we ended up putting it in a place where like the tier 200 pit is like, okay.
So like, like around tier 150 pit is like close to where AOZ was, you know, for like tier
25 AOZ runs and tier 200 goes beyond that.
So it's pretty, it's pretty considerable.
The scaling has been increased.
We still want it to be gradual as you're kind of progressing through.
Because we want you to feel that you have a place to push.
It's not like, so like, because AOZ was 25 tiers, extremely, extremely chunky.
When you went from tier to tier, as you got deeper and deeper inside here, it's a little
more gradual as you go further and further.
And we think that that's going to be good experience overall.
Because it's ultimately a lot of the materials you really want from the pit, you can gain
by the time you're like doing like tier 60s.
You start to get like little bits of the deeth iron that you need to kind of start finishing
off your masterwork items.
And then that gets more and more efficient as you go deeper and deeper, you know, but there's
the, but we do want to have these like really, really difficult challenges.
We made a, we made a decision at the launch period of the game where we took nightmare
dungeons difficulty.
We kind of scaled it in a different way, you know, whereas like initially they were
extremely challenging going up to tier 100 and we ended up making a reduction in their
difficulty going into season one where we basically rebalanced things such that like
the tier 75 old nightmare dungeon was the new tier 100 nightmare dungeon.
And players no longer had that, like that measuring stick, that really, really difficult content
anymore because we kind of took it away.
We want that to still be there in the pit.
I mean, I think if tier 200 is far beyond abattoir of 025, especially with some of like
the balancing and the bug fixes to a lot of different builds, I actually, I don't know,
maybe I'm wrong, but I expect that to be pretty challenging.
I don't think people are going to do that as a cakewalk.
Okay.
So we have eight minutes left.
I already cut off my timer.
There's no way I can get to 99% of these questions.
So how do we feel about maybe doing a little rapid fire?
Let's do it.
Okay.
Sure.
Yeah.
This was talked about yesterday.
If I remember correctly, this was the, so these are the top, top questions from YouTube.
So I promised I would ask them.
So here we go.
This was the number one question by far, and it was touched on a little bit yesterday.
Is there an armory coming?
I heard yesterday, I think if I quote you correctly, you said that armory is great.
The team, the team likes it, had to prioritize some things.
Will an armory be coming to Diablo 4 so we can save our builds?
If you can answer it.
Yeah.
I mean, this is a problem that I think that the players have.
I think I've already mentioned that we're like, we're in the business of trying to
like solve player problems.
It's a thing we're really excited about.
It's a thing we, it's a thing we would like to do.
And that's all I can say right now.
They're excited about it guys.
Okay.
There's lots of different ways to expand the game.
And as Joe put it yesterday, different slices of, of the pizza to give you power.
Again, from YouTube, it seems like the most requested way that people would like to expand
power or change their builds is to have this skill tree expanded.
Is that something that we can look forward to at some point coming to Diablo 4?
Is the team passionate about expanding the skill tree in multiple ways?
Maybe you'll even give us an ultimate button so we can get another skill.
You never know.
Yeah.
I'll, I'll take this one, I guess.
Unless you want to say some more.
I would say I have, we have nothing to announce about big updates to the skill tree.
It is a little bit more of a complicated problem because we want the skill tree to remain as
an easy gateway for new players and returning players to come back and kind of know what
that is.
And we didn't want the complexity and heft of our game to be there.
So it comes with some nasty trade-offs that I'm not sure that we're willing to make, but
we are open to the idea of adding some more depth to the skill tree, but we don't want
it to be super complicated.
It's not going to be the POE encyclopedia.
We don't, we don't want that.
At least not for our game.
We want it to be in crafting in other places.
Yeah.
If I could show like the, like seeing how different players, like, again, there's a lot of people
who like, this is their first Diablo game.
Like seeing what players did with the skill tree in testing.
Yeah.
I think it would be very surprising to you and your audience.
They take, they take all the generators and max them to five.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And other things like that.
Um, it's, it's a tougher problem.
I think a lot of people give it credit for, and I don't know that the juice is worth the
squeeze if we go too far, but hearing that people want more, we've heard that loud and
clear, but nothing to announce in the near, in the immediate future.
Okay.
The next one for repeated and summoning content now and in the future of the game, are there
plans to let people just resummon these bosses without resetting the instance?
Cause that eats up a lot of time for the people that do want to farm up a bunch of things and
kill some bosses.
Yeah.
This is a really, this is a really good idea.
Um, there's a lot of things that get cleaned up.
Uh, when a plate, when players were set a dungeon that makes it a lot easier for us to do this
in the first place.
Uh, let me take that back to the team.
I don't, I don't know that we've talked deeply about like exactly when we could deliver something
like this, but we definitely see it as a, we definitely see it as a, something that
you can improve.
So yeah, we'll, we'll, we'll take that back.
All right.
Um, last one from YouTube here, will the campaign receive further attention?
So, um, we'll, well, first of all, obviously probably the story continues with the expansion,
but, um, uh, another way is currently when you start up a new season of Diablo, you can,
you can go through the campaign again, if you want, or you can probably now go farm in
helltide and the helltide is going to level you a million times faster for a million, million
more rewards.
It's not close at all.
And some games let you force you to do the campaign.
Some games in Diablo 4, you don't have to.
Have you guys thought about maybe editing the campaign slightly for a replay, maybe taking
out like the camel escort for, for example, and maybe benchmarking, oh, how long does it
take to do a campaign?
Just normally playing.
What is it?
Three hours for us.
I don't know what it would be.
And then benchmarking what it would be to do it in helltide and kind of have them at
the same point at the end of those journeys, um, to allow players a real choice in how they
want to start out their new season, because the campaign was such a fan favorite on the
launch and it was very well done.
Sure.
So I think if there is a, uh, like the quest team has a lot of really cool ideas of things
that you want to do to allow for players to like replay the campaign or to make it, um,
to kind of edit it a little bit in some ways that you suggest.
I think that, uh, it's a thing that we're thinking about as we go.
Uh, but the, we know that we want to make sure that we are prioritizing the piece of
the game that need work first.
If that makes sense.
Like, I think that the idea of being able to replay campaign is very, very exciting.
Uh, and I think there's really neat things we can do.
And we do have plans in the future for, uh, for this stuff as well.
I don't want to like make it sound like we're not committing to anything here.
We kind of do, we want to do something like this.
It's just that there's a lot of other like replay features like helltide, for example,
that we thought are, we're in a great position to like lift up and make feel like more exciting
for players.
So that's been a, more of a priority for us, but I do think that there's opportunities
there for sure.
Something there I want to point out, and this would help when the community is discussing
things or when you even are with us is this idea of opportunity cost.
I don't know if you know what, are you familiar with that term racks?
Yeah.
Economics.
Give up something to gain something else.
Cool.
Then, then I don't have to explain it, but yeah, the opportunity cost comes very heavy
into play.
When we talk about features and suggestions and things from players, I think a lot of times
it can be frustrating as a member of a community because I'm a member of gaming communities
too.
So I know how it is.
I'm like, Hey, you know, this thing, we obviously, it sounds like a good idea and we
all agree.
It's a good idea.
Why don't the devs do it right away?
And most of the time when that is true, it's because of opportunity costs.
It's that the excited opportunity costs are something that you didn't realize makes it
harder than it seems.
But opportunity costs, you know, here it's like, do we do loot reborn?
Do we redo how all the loot works in the game and your, your entire leveling experience
with our updates to helltide?
Or do we make the campaign have parody with not doing campaign to level up?
Right now, having campaign have parody to the non campaign obviously is a good thing,
but I would argue very heavily that loop being better in a loop based game is more important
and impacts more people in a better way, in a more long-term way.
And then the list goes long and long, forever, forever of the things that you could do versus
what you have to decide to do.
And then the other part, kind of alluding to your last question about resummoning bosses
is that I would say in that one, like, yeah, obviously good idea, better player experience
in there.
I would say the reason why we're not doing it, just knowing how the game works a little
bit more is Excel.
Our game wasn't structured that way.
And we have to do a lot of things to make it structured that way.
And the answer to actually do it is harder than most people would think.
And that is why both of these things are obviously good ideas that we would want.
There's different reasons why we haven't done them yet.
Doesn't mean they won't happen, but it means that it's why they're not happening now or yet.
And that's a better way to frame it when people are talking to each other.
It's like, hey, what should the Diablo X4 team do first or now?
Or, hey, you know, maybe this is a little bit harder.
Could you explain why it's harder would be a good question for an interviewer, for example,
right?
Because then you're going to get actual insight into why rather than just complaining that
it's not happening.
Are you providing Rack's feedback on this?
I mean, I might be giving feedback on feedback.
That's part of my job too.
But I like productive conversations is why.
And I think the community would rather have more productive conversations than their only
avenue is to complain and not know why things aren't working the way that they want.
I think people want to know how things work.
I think that makes sense.
I think they want to know how things work.
I want to educate people so that we can have better conversations about games.
I mean, I'm a loser, guys.
I'm always here if you guys ever want to talk, which we're actually at time.
Want to ask one more?
All right.
I mean, probably the one that I'm just going to ask a 15-part question then to abuse the
one more.
I love it.
Gamer at heart.
Probably the most important one that's still left on the list is about social features.
So I have three main topics.
I can't believe how many questions I put here.
That was so stupid of me.
I mean, there's no chance at all.
Anyway, social features.
So there's three main things.
Trading, group finder, clans.
So with trading, what are your guys' thoughts on putting an auction house-esque type of thing
just to allow trading and to avoid third-party sites?
Obviously, not a real money auction house.
People are begging for a group finder.
I don't know why.
People have cooties.
I rather play by myself.
But I guess people want it.
And then clans, I understand there's a big difficulty with clans.
Not just implementing them.
They were implemented in Diablo 3.
But Diablo 3 clans mean absolutely nothing.
It's just a second friends list.
There's no achievements to do.
There's nothing to unlock.
There's nothing to work toward.
But then if you put that in the game, opportunity costs, the thing that the economic principle
we keep talking about, then if you build that in the game, then people have to belong
to a clan.
And otherwise, they feel left out, which then leads me to another one of my million questions
about SSF.
But whatever.
So for social features, trading, group finder, clans, what are your guys' thoughts on those
three for Diablo 4?
Let's get going.
So for trading, okay, trading in Season 4, players can trade Legendaries and Uniques.
They're still going to have to go and actually meet up to do those trades.
There's not going to be an automated trading function.
There are things we're talking about with regards to the Trade Chat channel to make it
a little bit easier to navigate.
In terms of creating an actual auction house user interface, it's a thing a team has discussed.
It's not a thing we've landed on.
We really want to see what the reaction is from players in Season 4 and what the experience
is broadly for players in Season 4.
How many players are actually trading?
Because I imagine it'll be different for different types of players, right?
But I think there could potentially be room for an investment there.
Because we don't want to just push players just to third-party sites.
But we're at a point where we're like, well, do we really want to go and make a whole...
Opportunity Cost would be a big investment to go make an auction house for Diablo 4, for
example, without knowing exactly what the desire for it is going to be.
And we didn't want to wait to let some of these things be tradable in the meantime.
So that's the HALA version.
We're not opposed to it.
We want to see how things go in Season 4.
With regards to the group finder, I think is the way that you call it, we do want to
make sure that there are easier systems for players to use to find parties of players
who are doing things that interest them.
We do have a social team on Diablo 4.
They've been thinking about clan stuff.
Things like this.
Things that make socialization more easy between players.
I think there'll be exciting stuff to share in the future.
So there's things we're thinking about.
And then with regards to...
What's the last one?
Clans.
Of course, clans.
We also have ideas of things we want to do to update parts of the clan functionality
to make it just a little more engaging to give more purpose to parts of clans.
You know, this is a thing that we have designs for and things we're thinking about.
I can't announce anything today.
Just to say that we recognize there's some parts of social features in Diablo 4 that can
be leveled up, made better.
And there's process we see players going through as part of regular play in seasons that we
want to make easier, more streamlined for them.
Well, I got to be honest.
It was actually an honor to have you guys come here.
I really like you guys.
I love the Diablo franchise since I was a kid.
This actually meant a lot to me.
I have a million more questions, but I know we're out of time.
I want to be respectful of that.
Thank you guys.
Thank you guys for coming here and speaking so open and honestly.
I'm a loser.
I'm always here.
If you guys want to go again, I mean, you guys got three free hours.
I got a lot more questions, but I guess, is DM going next or I can just pass along a million
more?
I'm sure.
I believe so.
Yeah.
I'm on with him tomorrow.
You guys, right?
Yeah.
All right.
It's been a blast.
It's been super fun.
Thank you, Rex.
Really appreciate it.
I will say we're trying to get in front of the community a little bit more and talk about
these things.
It's something that I really like doing and I'm pretty passionate about and I'm looking
forward to doing more.
So thank you guys for being here.
Talk to us.
Hell yeah.
Let's do it again.
Thank you guys.
Everybody in chat, say goodbye to the lovely people at Blizzard and I guess we'll see you
in season four.
Thank you all.
See you folks.
Thanks guys.
All right.
Coming back.
Okay.
How do I, how do I like this?
Boom.
All right.
I'm back.
Dude.
I can't even explain to you how many questions I had to skip, man.
Yo, dude.
I had so many more questions.
Like, oh man, dude.
Look at all the questions I missed.
First of all, I missed all of these, almost all of these.
And I missed loot filter, SSF, PVP, offline mode, ladders, how did the PTR go?
Map overlay.
We kind of talked about this.
Charms, Uber, Tomb Lord, the cow level.
Why isn't Diablo and Diablo 4?
What are the toughest challenges of your job?
How did the Microsoft takeover impact you guys?
What are the scope of your seasons and the mid-season events?
Can you make community goals and events?
Why are world bosses loot pinatas?
What about pets and followers?
Who is the target audience for Diablo 4?
I wanted to talk to them about, I just had, I don't know, man.
I don't know, man.
I was, I was pretty disheartened, man.
I had so many more questions.
Ugh.
I had so many more questions, man.
I feel like, I feel like I spent too much time talking.
Like I spent too much time maybe phrasing the question, maybe.
Then I could have gotten a couple more in.
And I, I purposely didn't, I purposely didn't, like, I wanted to have a conversation with them about every topic.
But if I have a conversation with them about every topic, I only get to ask two questions.
You know?
Hmm.
Man, dude.
I wanted to ask them so many more questions.
Man.
I, I super over prepared for that, I guess.
Well, did you, did you guys enjoy the conversation?
I'll tell you the most shocking thing to me.
I literally said it in the interview.
They block out time for the developers to play the game because they said the only way you're ever going to know anything is by playing the game.
I thought that was pretty good, man.
What's the cliff note version?
No.
Well.
Okay.
So, oh, shit.
I closed it.
One second.
Okay.
Yeah.
A TLDR version? Okay.
So the TLDR of Pinnacle content and will skill ever play a factor is,
I think the way I would summarize their answer is yes, there will,
but they're still trying to find out what the right level is.
Roadmap, they said, has a lot of pros and cons.
The pros have to outweigh the cons, but they feel committed to giving the community promises that they keep.
When I ask them, how do you actually, how do you, how do you, by the way,
there's so many people subbing and doing super chats and somebody gifted 50 subs.
Mr. G Point gifted 50 subs.
Thank you.
And so many people are subbing and stuff.
I actually, I don't know how this happened, but it actually got,
I actually closed the notifications somehow.
That was an accident.
Let me reopen this.
Thank you guys.
Sorry.
I was, well, I was just a thousand percent focused on trying to,
trying to suck blood from a mummy,
trying to get everything I could out of that.
There's a, there's a million people that subbed with prime and 56 month resub from Maxim.
That's crazy.
So there's so many of them.
Thank you guys.
Make sure I didn't miss anything crazy.
Sucking blood from a mummy.
Never heard of that.
Like a mosquito sucking blood from a mummy.
Extracting water from a stone.
Same analogy.
Okay.
You sure sucked them hard racks.
Thanks, man.
I sure sucked them.
All right.
Um, the, I thought, I thought that I almost threw this question out.
I actually thought this was the best question I asked them because they did say,
we read the Reddit threads.
We watch the streams.
We watch the YouTube videos.
We read the comment sections.
We go to the forums and they said, we play the game.
That's the only way you will ever really know to play the damn game.
I thought that was, I thought that was the best part.
Um,
uh, on nightmare dungeons.
I essentially just cried and asked them, stop making me free seven prisoners and reduce the time further and let me carry multiple objects.
And I think the answer was maybe.
Overworld's future.
Um, this, this is maybe the answer that kind of surprised me a little bit.
I was kind of, I mean, what they said made perfect sense.
They said the overworld is super fun.
Kind of the first time through afterward, you can't really recreate the magic.
We need to just get you to the events that you want to do.
Like, I can't argue with that logic.
That makes sense.
But I did kind of expect them to, I guess I expected Diablo four to dot double down on the overworld's future kind of more than what I heard.
I was actually kind of, this is probably the most surprising answer to me that.
The overworld in general is not, not, not totally a one and done, but that's, that's what I got out of their answer.
You think you want it, but you don't.
Well, I just got done playing 130 hours of Elden Ring.
And all I did was roam around in the overworld.
And all I ever think about in my life is when am I going to play Elden Ring again?
And when am I going to do new game plus and 30 more playthroughs of it?
I understand it's a different kind of game.
This is an ARPG.
You don't have to tell me I played a trillion different games, but my point is World of Warcraft.
One of my fun is, one of my favorite things, World of Warcraft, get on the pony and ride around and go see what we can discover.
And there's, you know, there's so many things to go do.
I wouldn't say that overworld is.
I think I want it, but I don't.
In fact, I think one of the most fun game modes in the game is in the overworld, Helltide.
I think Helltide is more fun than Nightmare Dungeons.
It might be more fun than the pit, but probably not.
The pit is probably more fun currently, but it's way more fun than world bosses.
And it's way more fun than challenge rifts.
So, I don't know.
I don't think they should abandon the overworld.
That is not how I feel about it.
These were Rob's questions.
I wanted to ask them.
They actually said this in CJ's interview.
They said this.
That the Diablo 3 had some cool things that they could borrow from and some things that they didn't like.
So, they actually kind of pseudo-admitted that it is kind of like Diablo 3.
But I wanted to ask them, do they often take inspiration from the past games?
And they said yesterday on CJ's stream that there will be new things that are, and this is a quote,
distinctly Diablo 4, fresh and exciting.
I wanted to ask them about this.
I wanted to ask them, are you actually innovating on ARPGs?
Distinctly Diablo 4, fresh and exciting.
Do you actually, are you actually planning to release new things that really the ARPG world has not seen?
Because that would be exciting.
Yeah.
I wanted to talk to them about said items.
They talked about it yesterday on CJ's stream.
I had more questions, man.
I wanted to talk to them about RuneWords.
They said that they like RuneWords.
They were working on it, and they're going to come in Diablo 4.
But I still have questions.
I wanted to talk about charms.
I asked all the questions from YouTube.
I forgot to write their, I forgot to say their names.
I should have said their names.
I forgot.
God, I'm stupid.
I should have said their names.
The interview is over, yeah.
Saying names adds time.
And then I was out of time.
And then I said, well, probably the next best thing I could ask is about social features.
It didn't sound like they have anything coming for trading anytime soon.
It sounded like they actually, I was surprised.
They actually sounded like they had something for clans coming.
And they didn't sound like they had anything for trading.
What did they say about group finder?
What did I think about the interview?
Well, I liked the, Callie literally just walked up to me and farted.
Thanks for that, Callie.
Thank you.
Did you see Callie trying to crawl on me the whole interview?
No, it's not even a drive-by.
She runs up, farts, and then she sits there and wags her tail.
She doesn't go anywhere.
Okay.
Nothing to announce, but it's being discussed.
What is my overall opinion about their answers in the interview?
It's kind of, it's hard to judge because it's hard to judge like being in the moment.
I'd probably have to go back and rewatch it to get the, to get the full, to absorb the full amount of information.
But it felt like they were being very honest.
I don't know.
I thought that they were giving good answers to the questions that I asked.
What Adam Jackson said at the end was exactly how I feel where he said,
it's not really that valuable for you to ask me like a yes or no question and I give you the answer and you post it somewhere and no one ever knows the why behind anything.
So what would be much more helpful is having in-depth conversations about opportunity costs.
Um, I'm glad that I studied economics in college because they were actually talking about a lot of economic principles.
He's like, do you know what an opportunity cost is?
Yes.
I love economics.
I love math.
So that, that helped.
Um, one time, the one time college actually pays off.
Um,
um,
they were talking about their problems,
their problems,
but that's exactly,
but that's exactly their problems by,
by transitivity become our problems.
If blizzard has a problem,
it's going to become our problem.
If blizzard has a problem implementing something,
it will become our problem as players.
Someone has a super chat here.
Never call yourself a loser.
Ryan,
you are awesome.
Thanks for saying that,
man.
I mean,
I am a loser.
I just sit around and play games all day,
but I appreciate the sentiment.
What did I major in in college?
Math.
I have a,
I almost got a,
I almost got a triple major.
I almost triple majored in math,
stats,
and economics.
I also went pretty far into psychology as well.
I like,
I like school.
I always,
uh,
my corporate job for 10 years always gave tuition reimbursement.
So I always went to school.
So I got my bachelor's in math and then I had,
I put a huge emphasis on stats,
economics,
and psychology.
I got my,
uh,
first master's in PNC insurance,
the CPCU.
And then I actually went for a second master's.
I'm about a third of the way done with it with an MBA.
I just like school.
A lot of people hate school.
I loved it.
I like to go and I like to go and learn not from MIT,
from the university of Nebraska.
You got a triple major math,
computer science,
and drugs.
Well,
one of them will make you way more money than the other.
Just watch breaking bad.
I'm a corn Husker.
Yeah,
we have the,
uh,
we used to have the best,
football team ever in the history of football.
And now we have the worst team ever.
And we're garbage.
We don't,
we don't,
uh,
we don't talk about the current day.
Don't,
didn't we get the number one pick though?
We got the,
got like the top court.
We have like,
now we have like the godliest quarterback ever.
And we have the rest of our team sucks.
You graduated with your cybersecurity degree this December.
Hell yeah.
I didn't go to high school.
I went to school high.
Yeah,
we have Riola.
So we have,
we have Nebraska has racks.
That's a,
uh,
y equals MX plus B.
Good old algebra.
Yeah.
Did you hear what they said?
You should hear how most players built.
You should see the data on how most players built a skill tree.
I was like,
what's the dumbest thing that they could do?
What did they do?
Put five points in every generator.
And Joe was like,
yes.
I was like,
Jesus Christ,
guys.
Max roll.
GG.
What is wrong with you guys?
So yeah,
if you guys like college football,
the Nebraska corn Huskers are going to be super interesting to watch next year
because we have the greatest quarterback ever.
And our,
the rest of our team is absolute YMCA rejects.
So how far can one God quarterback take a team of losers?
It's going to be like space jam.
It's going to be like space jam,
but for a football.
I'm sorry to say racks,
but ever since you stopped making barb guides,
you stopped following Maxwell.
If I don't write the guide,
you don't want to read it.
Uh,
I can tell you,
uh,
the people that write the barb guides over there,
like,
uh,
snail.
And is it sloth master and snail?
Dude,
they,
they put a lot of effort into those guides,
man.
They put a lot of effort into those guides.
You can snail is a many,
many,
many time rank one Diablo three player on almost every single class.
He's one of the greatest players ever.
You,
you can read a guide from snail and fruit feel good about it,
man.
He's,
he's one of the greatest Diablo players of all time.
It doesn't have to be me.
Who writes the sorcerer builds.
You ever heard of a guy named North war,
North war,
every,
everybody follows North wars builds.
He is,
uh,
nobody does more,
more math in Diablo four than North war.
Nobody.
He is the best sorcerer guide writer.
In the,
in the world by,
by a huge margin.
It's not even close at all.
There I am.
There's no way.
It's not even close.
Rob's the math guy to Rob's the math guy.
Guys,
remember Rob was on Maxwell for three years.
Rob's the math guy too.
Okay.
What changes are coming.
I didn't catch the stream.
It wasn't really an interview about,
it wasn't really an interview about changes.
Really.
It,
it's not like a spoiler thing where they can like announce a bunch of new
things on the stream.
It's kind of understanding how do the,
how are they going to make the game?
So kind of the,
the high level takeaways are challenging content will be in the game,
but it's never going to be all skill based again.
I don't think mechanical mastery is out and your gear is going to be a huge
portion of you winning is what I took from that.
Um,
they're really unsure about roadmaps,
but they have no problem making certain promises and keeping them kind of
sounded like a no to me from the roadmaps.
That's how I interpreted the answer.
They said that they block out time for the team to play the game.
So he said like,
for example,
he already,
he's going to have about 50 hours in season five.
He said that that's by far the best way for the team to be able to play
the game.
I,
I don't think there's any other way you could in,
there's no other way to approach the question.
The only way you will learn is by playing the game.
You will never learn by sitting in an ivory tower,
theorizing about the game.
So that this was very refreshing to hear.
Uh,
this was just me essentially just complaining and I want more qualitative stuff.
And they said kind of like,
maybe,
this was just me bitching about everything.
Um,
the overworld future was surprising to me.
This is the most surprising answer.
So the,
they essentially said the overworld is really fun to explore the first time or
two.
And then people want to get to their events.
I mean,
that's probably true,
but I mean,
we have a big overworld here.
There's gotta be something we can do with it.
Right?
You're coping.
They said no to Insta interactions.
Well,
I don't know if they said no.
They said that they thought that they could bring it down further.
I thought pretty sure they said that,
right?
That they'd look into bringing it down further.
Well,
no guys,
it's not that it's not that the overworld is not going to expand.
Right?
I mean,
it's very logical that with the expansion,
there will be new zones and things to ride around in.
It's not that the overworld is never going to get bigger.
What I was asking them is,
is the overworld going to be a defining feature of the future of the game?
Are we going to be spending a lot of time in the overworld for future
activities?
And what they said was,
is the overworld is kind of a one or two time thing where it's interesting.
And then people want to get to where they want to go.
So certainly the overworld will be expanded upon,
but that's not the same as,
is it a defining feature?
So.
We're going to wait to,
We will put it on the other side.
And then people want to open it up here.
So you can adjust them down to the other side.
We're going to click here.
See you next time.
Bye.
We will not hit the endlich button,
but you can adjust those first icons to the target.
?
We have to go through or see how something happens.
Have to go out and see how something happens.
And the first thing we can do is,
that's going to have to go through it.
We have to work with our traumas
and theThree days and the other side,
how,
let's focus on testing this sequence?
Or testя,
okay let's do some poll let's do that's a good idea let's do some polls about the
how you guys felt who cares what i think let's see what you guys think
how did you feel about the interview everything about it
how it was done the questions and the answers just everything as a whole
you thought it was godly you thought it was great you thought it was meh
you thought it was terrible you thought it was horrendous create the poll
let's paste the poll if you want to vote
there it is i pasted it a million times results let's see how did you guys feel about it
the the whole entirety of it how it was everything about it me alt blizzard everything lumped into one
all right
it's pretty good i'll take that
it was that was that's what i was going to ask from you guys what
banned the 22 people i wouldn't give them uh i wouldn't ban somebody for having an opinion
that didn't align with mine as long if people state their opinions and they're different than mine
as long as they aren't being toxic about it uh i don't have any problem with them it's when people
voice opinions to me and they're being toxic about it that i swap them away
okay um
okay so
what feedback do you guys have about how it could have been better either i mean it's really not up to
them to do better it's up to me to do better so it could have been a longer interview what can i do better
um
i need to ask questions quicker
not be a simp
i was being a simp for diablo 4 you know i hear some content creators get called this
some content creators get called a simp i actually don't get that too much
i'm kind of surprised to hear that
it's usually just not feedback that i get very often
joe needs to talk less but
here's the thing though
i it's kind of like adam said kind of at the end of the thing
i think it is much more helpful
to have insights and deep dives into conversations than to do the rapid fire in your i could have asked
50 questions if i would have done it will there be charms in diablo 4
will there be set items in diablo 4 but
last epoch has set items and they're terrible
diablo 3's entire game is based on overpowered sets and it pretty much ruined the game
diablo 2 has some godly sets and some of them are completely useless even after the repass of what
they did of them so
when you tell me set if they would say yes sets are coming into the game that doesn't tell me anything
what i want to know is what do you think about sets let's have a conversation about what works about sets and what doesn't that's the
that's that's the important thing to me
so when you say joe talks too much
i would not coach him to talk less because i want to have conversations about it
one hour is too short of a time to ask detailed questions
most of the segments should be rapid fire otherwise you don't cover anything if you had
two or three hours it would have been a different story barely any questions were covered
yeah i think that's the i think that's the main point of feedback is more time
well one of the questions well some of the questions that i started off with which i thought were the
most important they already discussed it yesterday and i cannot assume that people watched
rikers interview like i did so i had to i wanted to start off with here's what you guys said already
okay here's what you said yesterday now here's my question here's the part that
i'm missing here
yeah i mean again if i could have had a conversation about things when adam jackson was talking about
balancing the campaign i mean i have a pretty simple solution which i which i think is i mean again
opportunity cost how long does it take them to do it versus what's the benefit added i can
i can go through um i can go through um hell tide and play for whatever five hours and oh i'm level 65
and i have a full set of basic ancestral gear and i have two or three legendaries that are good for me
that's where i get in five hours or something and then i go play the campaign and the campaign
takes me five hours and when i'm done with it i'm level 43 and i have mostly yellows and two legendaries
and then i say okay if you design redesign the campaign completely with all the new smart loot
and this or that or this or that then it's a huge undertaking right so what about this leave the
campaign as it is forget it just leave it as it is and the only thing that you do is cut out some of the
the ridiculous parts like maybe walking around the snake 300 times or the camel escort quest where you're
sitting there for 20 minutes there's the slowest camel ever following it and then you say all right the
time now is uh four hours or something or whatever it is and then you you benchmark that compared to
about where would you be gear wise and xp wise um at the end of the run you could do it you could do it
very cheaply actually you could just play the campaign you kill uber you kill lilith at whatever level 42
and once you kill lilith you go to level 60 in world tier 4 you just you just ding 60 boom you're 60
you're in world tier 4 and you get a little good lilith drops lilith's goodie bag and she drops you
a decent set of eye level whatever 800 ancestral gear put it on it's about the same
that requires almost no changes in the campaign nothing you didn't change anything and when you
kill lilith you just ding roughly the level and roughly the gear that you would have had
if you would have played in helltide that sounds lame though but that sounds lame to you people love the
the campaign the whole point is to give another choice people who say that's lame that's you
i would personally love that
see
some people in diablo 4 would rather do the campaign again and arrive at the same spot than run 15 helltides
you know to know what let's let's not leave it up to interpretation
no guessing answer let's just ask the question
assuming
reasonable
campaign changes meaning you don't have to wait for the camel for an hour
which is more fun to level if you arrived at the same point for the same amount of time
i don't i don't expect i don't i'm not expecting this poll to be lopsided i'm expecting it to be a balance
helltide blasting or the campaign but let's see if i'm wrong let's let's just see what happens what would
be more fun for you
i spammed it what would you rather do if you arrived at the same point and they made some basic
quality of life changes to the campaign
okay i didn't actually expect the campaign to win but
this is what i i expected it to not have a landslide victory for either of them so
what someone says is stupid to you is way more fun for 420 people kek w
well
i don't think about it
talking about kilowatt com
guys another thing is
this is this if they took this development time other than the opportunity cost of development
time on some other feature this situation is just a win for everybody even if you're just helltide
blasting it does not hurt you for the campaign to be an equally viable option for the people
that want to play this game what's the problem and guys some people say racks your solution is
really lame you just beat the campaign you ding 60 and you get a goodie bag yeah i mean that's
pretty lame that's not as good as them redefining the whole campaign and putting in special loot
drops to align and making it perfect but the entire point of why you wouldn't get this change
is the dev time opportunity cost right it takes a million years to fix that whereas
if they just did a gooey bag and made you ding a certain level then they could implement it maybe
in a day and then they can fix it later right now you're not going to get night now if you do the
campaign you don't get anything you don't get jack shit you don't get any xp and you don't get anything
it's a huge huge not even close to helltide
stop wasting time on meaningless garbage jesus the game has much bigger problems than this
some of you guys
i know fourth grade was hard
it's it's hard to cover a lot of different ideas and aspects of a topic
i know that that can get really complicated for some people
i can see the smoke coming out of some of their ears from all the way over here
that's why i'm saying fussy that's why i i included this portion to expedite the campaign
on a replay a little bit we don't have to walk the camel again
wait there's a fourth grade after fifth grade fourth grade is coming man and for some of the
people in chat it's where their journey ended
you
they should have an uber fight of the camel and you have to walk him across the desert
in it's kind of like
like a mario kart race and the timing is really really precise you need like frame perfect inputs
to get the camel to turn left and right
you
yeah
and there needs to be landmines
and
there needs to be landmines and if you successfully beat it then you unlock a key
to go into the catacombs to fight uber tomb lord and uber tomb lords mount is the camel
the interview is already over yeah if you
if you blinked it's uh
it's already over
rob just sent me a clip i don't know what this is let's just click it
so we ended up putting it in a place where uh like the tier 200 pit is
like okay it's like like around tier 150 pit is like close to where aoz was you know for like tier 25 uh uh a aoz yeah aoz
That is insane.
Oh my god, thank you so much, Ryan.
Yes.
Oh boy.
W.
150 pit is tier 25 Aoz.
Let's go.
We have a real endgame.
Dang.
Suck them harder, Rax.
Finally, guys.
Of the Neath Iron that you need to kind of start finishing off your Masterwork items.
And then that gets more and more efficient as you go deeper and deeper.
You know, but there's a...
But we do want to have these like really, really difficult...
So we ended up putting it in a place where like the tier 200 pit...
If the Barb is happy, then we're happy.
We got a message from Adam Fletcher.
I know that you had a ton of additional stuff.
Maybe we can do this again sooner rather than later.
And we can hit up even more of your questions.
All right.
I mean...
I got questions.
I can come up with another 100 questions.
Adam to save the day.
Rob probably loves the camel.
He better not.
Okay.
Should I call Adam and Joe?
Be like, are you guys free later?
Let's go again.
Part two.
Okay.
I didn't know this.
It's Rob's birthday today.
Five, nine, huh?
It's his birthday.
Okay.
31.
That's one foot in the grave.
Should I just...
When DM's interview starts, should I call them?
Be like, what?
No, you guys got your schedules confused.
This interview was my interview part two.
DM's is later.
They'll be like, oh, okay.
And then DM's going to be like, what the hell?
No, I'm just kidding.
I'll just send DM my questions.
He'll do a good job.
Okay.
Excuse me.
I'm 34.
How are you even alive?
I'm 37, by the way.
There's DM right there.
Please no.
DM.
I'm sure you have a list of questions.
Would you like a...
Would you like another list of questions that I didn't get to get to?
To add to your list?
Dude, 45 minutes, man.
Is not enough time.
Send them your way.
You'll carry the torch.
All right.
I'm going to fix this document.
In fact, I'm going to do it right now.
I already asked this.
Well, let me do it this way.
I already asked about aspirational content.
I already asked them about the roadmap.
I already asked them about feedback.
I already asked them about the state of nightmare dungeons.
I already asked them about the overworld future.
I asked them about the pit.
I didn't ask them this.
So these are all done.
I already asked those.
This was kind of asked already.
I wanted to prod at them deeper, but...
I'm just going to delete this question.
I'm not sure if DM was aware of this.
Maybe this question doesn't make any sense anymore.
I'm just going to delete it.
Charms.
This is a good one.
So that's a good one to ask.
All right.
So I already asked.
I asked all of these.
So this is all.
I already asked this.
Didn't ask that.
I would love.
I want to know this.
I want to know what their target audience is for Diablo 4.
This is already listed above.
Okay.
Yeah, here you go.
Anything in...
Anything in orange I already asked.
CJ had some extra questions as well.
Okay.
So let me share this with DM here.
All right.
There you go, man.
He has it.
There you go.
Yeah.
That's another question I should have asked.
Why is everything red?
I asked about the armory.
And they gave me like a little smile.
And they said,
we like the idea of the armory.
And we know people want it.
That's usually their cutie patootie way of saying that it's probably maybe coming soon.
Like maybe season five.
How am I feeling about the pit difficulty?
Yeah.
Like I said live on the interview,
if tier 25 is 150 and 200 is beyond abattoir tier 25 with the bug fixes and with the balance changes,
that should be in theory extremely difficult.
When will North war release his guides?
I know he has a lot of guides to work on.
I don't know the exact timing,
but I do know that.
Don't know the exact timing,
but I do know that the Maxwell people have been blasting.
So obviously before the season comes out on Tuesday,
the Maxwell team has been blasting to get the D4 guides out.
Please tell me I will not be playing hardcore in Diablo 4.
I'm 1000% going hardcore SSF.
And it is very, very likely that I will die.
Very likely.
I did a couple of practice runs on the PTR with the no cheat death changes.
I did not survive a single run.
I died on every single time.
And I'm,
I know Diablo 4 pretty well.
You want to know another cute thing about me playing hardcore next season?
I have never fought an Uber boss.
I've never fought Uber and Dario.
I've never fought Uber.
Uh,
I don't even know their names.
Lightning man.
I never fought Uber.
Zier.
I've never fought them.
Not even one time to test them.
No,
I,
I fought.
Is there a 200 version of Durial?
As well?
Okay.
I,
I will almost certainly die.
I didn't survive one speed run in the PTR.
I died on every single one.
Um,
um,
I'm probably going to play.
I'm well,
first of all,
I'll,
I'll play every class.
Cause again,
I mean,
I've said this like five times a day,
but I'm a loser.
So I'll play everything except maybe rogue,
but maybe I'll play rogue too.
Um,
I'm probably going to start necro.
I haven't started necro.
I don't know if I've ever started necro and I really want to play with the minions.
I think the minions are going to be fun as hell.
Why not rogue?
Cause rogue didn't get many like exciting changes.
I tried several less speed leveling things and I died on every single one of them.
I hate minions.
It's not that I hate minions.
It's I hate minions where I'm a babysitter and not the commander of the undead.
If my minions are dumb as hell and not,
and I have to do a ton of things to make them do anything,
then yes,
I hate minions.
What time is DM's interview?
I don't know.
Uh,
he tweeted it,
didn't he?
I'm such a Twitter noob.
I don't even know how to look people up here.
Um,
search search.
Darth
micro here.
1 p.m.
Pacific.
So,
exactly 24 hours from now.
I believe.
am I hype for May 14th?
I am.
It's going to be fun.
I,
I'm almost certainly going to die,
but I don't care.
I'll just make another character.
We go again.
I believe.
you watched the interview already a second time.
I was too hard for myself.
My phrasing was well done.
Thanks for saying that,
man.
Appreciate it.
Yeah,
I just,
I just didn't.
Time was the limiting factor there.
Yeah.
Is there any need to keep aspects on old characters to migrate them over to the new system in season four?
Keep in mind,
the,
the new system is very seamless,
right?
You run around,
you pick up legendaries.
Okay.
You take a look.
If it's not better than yours,
essentially,
if it doesn't have a greater ethics,
you just salvage it.
It's just going to chain.
It's just going to start chain upgrading your codex of power seamlessly.
I don't think you need to save stuff and salvage it and anything like that.
I think you just play and your codex is going to get filled out pretty easily.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a good way to phrase it.
The,
one of the biggest values there is the humanizing of the blizzard entity or the Diablo four entity.
You get to speak to the people in plain English.
The,
the,
the real advantage here,
the difference between this and a campfire chat for me is they are willing to just sit there and say,
what is the community want to talk about?
And I tried to make my questions a little bit pointed.
If I leave the question super open ended,
then we can get a very,
very high level glazing of ideas.
But if I say,
I want to talk to you about pinnacle content.
You said,
this didn't work.
this is going to be a bigger factor than X is going to be a bigger factor than Y.
Have you considered Z specifically for this content?
And what does the team think about that?
Then we can start to dig at what are we actually getting at here?
Right.
When you leave it very open,
it's not even like a,
it's not even like a negative,
but when you leave it,
when you leave a topic wide open,
they will respond similarly to how they have always responded.
Right.
If I say,
what did you guys think about the PTR?
They have already said a hundred times.
We really liked the PTR.
We got so much feedback.
Thank you for participating on the PTR.
Okay.
But I could ask them,
what kind of feedback from the PTR seemed to be the most valuable to you?
What,
what kinds of things surprised you when you started to concatenate the data and
start to make some decisions about it?
That's better.
Like we're actually going to learn something out of it.
Racks plays soft course.
You can do community Durial and Endarial runs.
The problem is,
the problem is,
is,
um,
when I,
if I do that,
whenever I have ever done a community run,
I have always required myself to pay my own way.
Unless someone comes into my stream and says,
Racks,
I'm,
I'm literally quitting.
I'm going to go play.
Wow.
Season of discovery.
If you want my 50 mats,
you can take them.
If not,
they're going to rot in my chest.
Okay.
If you're actually quitting,
whatever,
I'll take them.
But in general,
if I just log in,
what you guys will do,
because you guys are so nice,
is you guys will pay for me to run Durial 10,000 times until I have every Uber unique,
because you're very nice.
But if I do that,
I'm missing the most important thing about my stream.
And as a player,
I miss being relatable.
If I just use streamer privilege to just get handed everything,
first of all,
the game is boring because I didn't earn anything.
And the second thing is,
is I'm not relatable.
You guys don't have,
a lot of you don't have a thousand million people that are willing to just hand it.
So when you're trying content and you have a stick and I have Excalibur,
it's not relatable.
So that's why I,
I don't do that.
Or if I participate in community events,
events,
I pay my own way every time.
Am I not trying to be Rob?
Guys,
I'm not,
I'm not needling Rob or people are saying Asmogold.
I'm not giving this answer to disrespect other people or their decisions.
I was asked a question.
I'm responding to the answer for me.
They can do whatever they want.
Interview already happened.
Here's an interesting thing.
Lee just made this.
This is going to be the timestamps of the interview on YouTube.
Let's look,
but this is interesting because let's look at the time spent on each topic.
I mean,
half the problem is,
is this question had a lot of setup.
I spend at least one minute setting up the question from CJ's interview.
So let's say about four,
four minutes on roadmap,
about four minutes on pitical content,
11 minutes on feedback from the community.
Wow.
11 minutes.
We spent one,
we spent one fourth of the time talking about how they process feedback and how they test the game.
Armory,
42 seconds.
This was the rapid fire thing though.
You got to talk faster.
Speed run questions.
I mean,
I was trying,
man.
I was trying.
I wasn't yapping fast enough.
What stood out the most?
Probably,
probably the feedback section.
The fact that they said that they build in time for all the developers to play the game,
to learn the game.
I would say that's,
that was the best news for me out of all of it.
But I,
that,
I think that let's do one more poll.
I don't want to become a poll Andy.
But I,
I do have a question.
Let's,
for those that watch the interview,
let's see.
What was the best information about,
or from the interview?
The devs,
the devs,
play the game every day.
What are some other choices?
The,
the pit actually having difficulty.
Yeah.
Pit actually difficult.
The overworld being dead.
Yeah.
It sounded like an armory is coming.
Armory coming.
We think.
Kind of.
Paper towels next to the bed.
Good.
By.
Both.
Good.
Yeah, they actually feedback listened to from all sources.
I mean, that's good enough.
We don't have to fish for these.
Let's just go with this.
Which of these four did you say was the best news out of these four choices?
I spam the poll in the chat if you care to answer.
All right, so what I'm gathering from this is people are excited about different things.
It's a little bit more balanced than I thought it was going to be.
VPN user voting is not allowed.
I wonder why that is.
Is that because they don't want you to vote a million times because you can just keep
picking different sources or what?
Why would they block that?
It's like to protect the integrity of the poll or something?
devs play the game every day is not a best info that is their obligation
i don't know if every gaming studio blocks out a certain portion of their day every day to just
play the game i wouldn't say that's let's say an obligation is a stretch but i'm glad that they do
it obligation is a is a stretch
well jesse did the did the people actually think that the devs don't play the game
i don't think i think most people thought that the devs play the game but there's a huge difference
between playing the game and your entire dev team as part of their daily job plays 50 hours of the
new season each before releasing it to the public
i think that's not those are not the same thing
i was not expecting that
what is ssf solo self found you mean
all right um there's so many people here i would love to just blast all day but i actually think
i'm gonna relax a little bit i was gonna keep i could stream all day guys but i think i'm gonna
think i'm gonna wrap it up here and i'm gonna raid rob because it's his birthday so let's raid rob
wish him happy birthday and see what see what he thinks really appreciated you guys being here you
guys left a lot of comments i took the top five comments on youtube and i blocked out time to ask
your questions so the the probably the most insulting thing the thing that pisses me off that
people talk shit about me all the time and that's fine you're a streamer that's what's gonna happen
the one thing that pisses me off the most is when people say that i don't care about the community
i don't represent the community in any way i don't give a shit about the casuals i only care about the
blasters it's complete horse shit that's why i let you guys post all of your questions and i when i'm
running out of time i asked every single one of your top five questions i didn't do it as a pr move
i did it to make sure that your questions got answered so that's the thing that if you really
want to piss me off is saying something like that to me one guy no it happens a lot my friend trust me
you wouldn't believe how much people talk shit about me but you're not going to focus on that today was a
great day um but remember this for all the people that say i don't care i asked the top five questions
from youtube and i i didn't have an opportunity to ask many questions
is rob still streaming yeah okay thank you so much guys i appreciate it um tomorrow i'll probably play
diablo 4 i haven't played in a long time i mean i'll be honest with you the the the five-year-old
in me just wants to keep playing elden ring but i'll probably play diablo 4 um might theory craft some
things might look at some max roll builds need to make a tier list
it's it's it's just so hard to say man it's so hard to say that the tier list i'm gonna make it
just because people like the video but it's so hard to say i'll see you tomorrow frosty frosty
hopefully you got some ultimate meme content from that you already know frosty is brewing something
thanks for being here guys by the way there were a million super chat subs flip said hey i am
watching your elden ring playthrough you can only play the game once for the first time thanks to
the creators i can watch someone else experiencing for the first time thank you for uploading it to
youtube and bless you thank you man flip i hope you're here if you're not here i'm gonna private
message you just to make sure sorry i didn't see that until now everybody on youtube thanks for all the
subs thanks for the likes thanks to the super chats thanks for everything sorry i was super tunnel
visioned on the stream today i wasn't even looking at the notifications today i'll do better
um i got to the end of the final fantasy 7 rebirth and then i just stopped playing it i'm literally at
the point where the bad thing happens and uh i'm at the point where the bad thing happens and i just
stopped playing i'm just like i don't know it's just not the same as final fantasy 7 man
have a great night guys see you tomorrow
see what
oh that's to say
here
you