so
I
check check check hello hello this is me talking hello yeah right three two one hello check check
check check all right cool so let me show you the other one check check check check oh stay on yeah
sound this one check check check audio check hello hello hello yeah sounds good took a minute to dial
it in so just remember remember if you do start to hear double feedback or or some popping
just rides bottom two right those two depending on what I want to get there are the main this is the
main main stream audio is coming in stream can hear you well the stream
yeah
small
guys
Thank you.
I can put on my Русço often rehums work, and when I was travails around, my lady had
1950 salmon in pet
A
so
Thank you.
Season 4,
Every single, you know,
better than the others when you're trying to get the perfect build at endgame.
Because of this, in World Tier 4, and only in World Tier 4,
when an Ancestral Legendary item drops,
there's a chance the affixes on it can roll as greater affixes.
These will roll with bigger values that are normally available for that affix.
Greater affixes are fairly rare, but they're not impossible to find.
While leveling up, you're going to be able to find upgrades
much more easily with this new system.
Another part of itemization is going to be Masterworking.
Now, this is something really intended for that very high endgame, again, World Tier 4.
This is where a player is going to take an item,
already has the affixes that they want on it,
but now they go through a process of upgrading those affixes,
getting even higher values on them.
Masterworking really starts at level 100.
Once you've already completed your build and found some of the best items,
you're going to be able to test your build against the powerful enemies of the pit.
The pit is a new endgame system that has been added in this season
that is going to challenge players that feel that they have largely maximized their build.
By pushing into more difficult tiers of the pit,
you're going to be able to unlock rarer crafting materials
to masterwork your gear even further.
You're going to have to play some of the hardest content in the game,
but once you do, if you're successful,
you can go and make those affixes even stronger.
In Season 4, we're ramping the intensity of the Helltides
through the inclusion of a variety of new activities,
the first of which is a doubling down and rise of the Cultists' presence throughout the tide.
You're going to be running through the Helltides,
seeing the Cultists just conjuring up swarms and swarms of demons,
adding to that sense of mannequin chaos that they're pretty well known for.
The other archetype that we're adding is the presence of the Doomsayers,
who were unfortunate enough to be caught out in the tide
and basically just lost their minds to all of the mania going on around them.
And lastly, rounding out the new activities are just the inclusion of the Iron Wolves.
They're finally joining the fight.
They could no longer stand in the sidelines,
seeing the Helltides and Hells forces intensify their assault on Sanctuary.
As Season 4 players engage and progress through the Call of the Wolves seasonal activity,
they'll earn honor with the Iron Wolves,
unlocking access to a vast assortment of rewards
to accompany and empower your Season 4 journeys.
In the update of Helltide,
for players who are able to stay alive long enough,
they'll be paid a visit by the Hellborn,
former heroes of Sanctuary who have aligned with the forces of Hell
to attack the allies they once aligned with.
Players who are able to take down the Hellborn
will be acquiring the materials they need
to engage with the new premier Helltide activity,
the Accursed Rituals.
Located in the Helltide, these Accursed Rituals
are pretty much just botched rituals from the cultists
that players will be kickstarting for themselves,
drawing the intention of all the nearby Helltide monsters
in this kind of all-out battle.
One of my favorite themes for these ambushes is the Hellworm.
It's literally a giant hell slug beast
that emerges from the ground and spews out a whole bunch of mobs at you.
If you're able to survive that,
you'll be paid a visit from the Blood Maiden,
our brand new Helltide mini-boss,
and one of the ultimate challenges in the new experience.
So I think I'm actually most excited about this season
because of what you're able to do with your old characters,
how they can integrate with this new item game
and take them to new levels of power with this system.
I think that the best part of this update
is that you're going to be really empowered
to build the character that you want to play.
You're going to be able to pick custom affixes
and enhance your character in a lot of new and interesting ways.
All right.
We were just watching a video.
Literally just finger-gunning the screen for no reason.
And everyone's like,
what are you doing, Adam?
Hey, guys.
How's it going?
Welcome to another Diablo 4 Developer Update livestream.
My name is Adam Fletcher.
I am the Community Director here for Diablo.
I'm joined by this wonderful panel
plus an additional head,
which we will haul out.
We only have four seats.
We have to swap people around.
We have to do the same thing we did during the PTR stream,
which was like we swapped out Joe Shelley,
and put in Adam Jackson.
That's true.
We did do that.
So we're going to play more magic tricks today.
But do you guys want to do a quick intro
to yourself to the wonderful Diablo community?
Sure.
I'm Joe Paipora.
I'm the Associate Game Director for Diablo 4.
And I'm Adam Jackson,
the Lead Live Class Designer for Diablo 4.
And we have a new face.
Hello.
I'm Colin Feiner.
I'm the Lead Live Game Designer.
Awesome.
And then we're actually going to be joined by Derek.
Who are you?
Oh, well, I already introduced myself.
Oh, sorry.
You just missed it.
I know.
I'm already screwing this up.
Terrible.
It's my first game.
But we actually have Derek who will be joining us as well.
Derek, you just saw in the video prior,
talking about Season 4,
he'll be swapping in to talk a little bit more about Helltides later in this.
But big stream here.
We have Season 4 coming up.
As you guys saw earlier this week,
it is Loot Reborn for Season 4.
And a lot of players actually got to experience it a couple weeks ago with PTR.
PTR, this was our first Diablo 4 PTR.
It was a massive undertaking from the team here,
but it was really, really great to have players jump in early,
check out Season 4 and all the changes,
and actually provide feedback.
And so we have a lot to cover today
based off of feedback that we received from players from PTR itself.
But Joe, I know you wanted to jump into kind of talking a little bit more about Season 4,
how PTR went,
before we jump into all the changes.
Yeah, happy to.
So, okay.
So last time we were on stream,
we were actually talking about a lot of the changes
that players are going to get a chance to check out on the PTR.
So we think that went really, really well.
It was even just having the week of time for players to just jump in
and just crush through all of the content,
check out all of the new features,
and gets a lot of feedback,
find a lot of bugs on the way as well.
It was, again, super valuable.
It's been really, really great for the team.
We'll take a lot of this feedback,
look at the tuning variety of features,
and really make sure that we've got the best version
of the Season 4 experience ready
when we get into the launch today.
So, you know, in terms of, like, our big takeaways,
first of all, really, really valuable across the board.
Season 4, Season of Loot Reborn was,
as I mentioned during the PTR stream originally,
was really our opportunity to go back
and take a lot of the feedback in that we've been looking at
since the launch of the game from 2023.
This art is so good.
I do love the key art for this.
This key art for Season 3 was awesome as well.
It's awesome.
Yeah.
So, yes.
So, looking back at the...
Thanks for disrupting my flow.
I'm sorry.
David Puzar's art is amazing.
So, yeah, looking back at the launch
of the other products in 2023,
we've been getting a lot of really good feedback.
You'll remember back in Season 2, Season of Blood,
we made a big change to vulnerable damage
and the multiplicative damage that comes along with it.
We made a change to the way the elemental resist worked.
And there were a lot of things we had to do
to make those changes really shine through.
There's a lot of Paragon knows it had to get updated.
There were a lot of legendary aspects that had to get changed.
There was a lot of itemization stuff in the background
that we had to do to make those systems work better
and lift up other things around them,
like overpower, for example,
to make that feel like it was in a better spot.
Yeah.
So now that we're looking at,
like, even when we were done
that one big release for Season of Blood,
we knew that there was a lot more that we wanted to do,
again, that we've been thinking about.
But there's a lot of work we need to do,
like make sure that all of these things
really all fit together cohesively.
So, I mean, as people got a chance to see on the PTR,
like the introduction of things like the tempering feature,
which we're going to talk a little bit more in a minute,
where you get to introduce these new affixes into items,
and affixes you can't get on items anymore,
the reduction affix count on items overall.
So it's a lot easier to go and sort through
25 pairs of gloves in your inventory at any given time,
where you don't really have those same situations.
We reduced the number of items that drop
in the game experience overall,
but made sure that the items that are dropping
are just more valuable,
are more likely to be upgrades for you,
or something you could kind of, like,
build into an upgrade.
We introduced the masterworking feature, right?
And Colin helped head a lot of these things up, right,
during working with the teams.
So they introduced the masterworking feature,
where, you know, players can continually upgrade items
and can increase the value of the affixes,
and then, you know, at ranks 4 and 8 and 12,
you get to, like, kind of crit on one of these
and make them even better.
You know, there's a lot of things that were introduced.
We add the new content type in the form of
the Pivvy Artificer.
It's like this new, like, you know,
extremely deep and deadly dungeon dive
players get to go into once they get into the,
like, towards the end game,
when you're getting to, like, you know, 85, 90,
your character level,
you're starting to kind of dip into that space.
And that's where you go to get your masterworking materials,
which feels really, really good.
And we learned a lot of really great lessons
from, like, Greater Rifts and Diablo 3,
because we think there was some really cool content there.
So there's some really, really fun things there.
And then also...
And also the Codex of Power updates.
You no longer have to save all your legendaries all the time.
Codex of Power updates, which I was like,
to be fair, I've been kind of...
I've been so excited about the Codex of Power updates,
I've been teasing it for, like, six live streams.
Yeah.
Like, it's not...
That's so good.
Like, before BlizzCon,
I feel like I tease it at the end of a live stream.
So it's just what it is.
But, again, super excited about the Codex of Power changes.
That is very transformational.
Like, now, when Legendary drops on the ground for you,
you just salvage it, you get that aspect,
put it into your Codex,
add the role that you got,
and you just get to use it in perpetuity.
And we actually have some fun ways,
we'll talk about later,
how we're playing with that a little bit as we go.
So, I mean, all of this stuff and more,
we've made huge, huge changes to Helltide.
I know Derek's been talking about it in a little while,
as he helped lead the team,
did a lot of the work for that.
And we got to introduce the season theme
in the form of, like, Loot Reborn,
and then the reintroduction of the Iron Wolves mercenaries,
the players we're working with
during the course of the release.
I know that we showed a little bit of that off earlier.
And I am just,
personally, I'm just really, really excited
about the release overall,
as this was an opportunity for us to work with, like,
not just the season team,
but also the live team,
and, like, a lot of support from the systems groups.
And there's a lot of things being done for,
you know, the expansion, you know,
that's coming out eventually as well,
like Vessel of Hatred.
So being able to, like, really organize teams
and make sure that we're in a really, really good spot
to, like, provide this really big update for the game
has been very, very exciting.
And the feedback, going back to the feedback,
the feedback from PTR was, again, really, really valuable.
It was great to get players in there
and to get those things taken care of.
And we're going to talk about some of those things today.
I know that some of this information has been, like,
we talked to, like, a few, like, press outlets,
we talked to a few different people,
and, like, some information is getting out there.
But I want to make sure we can provide
a little bit more detail, you know,
because I know this is the audience
that wants to know, like, the real specifics.
We're going to get into it, right?
And we'll also have our Q&A, as we usually do at the end,
where we can, like, answer some more questions
the community might have
as we kind of go through the whole thing.
So, yeah, I mean, that was the,
at a high level, that's what we were feeling about the PTR,
feeling pretty good about it.
I'm happy to, like, maybe jump into itemization,
or how do we want to go?
Yeah, I think the first thing
we probably want to talk about
is, like, the itemization changes
that are in Season 4 that people experience,
which includes, like, the tempering,
the masterworking stuff that changed in Season 4.
And, of course, all the feedback that we got
from both tempering, masterworking,
and what we are planning on doing
based off of that PTR feedback
for the launch of Season 4.
Yeah, we've got a few updates.
Yeah, lots.
Yeah, sure.
So, I guess just starting off, then,
with, like, high level itemization.
Like, let's go back to, like,
some of the goals that we had
when we started, like, down on this,
started some of the work for Season 4.
Now, we want to make sure that,
first, players were having an easier time
comparing items in their inventory.
It was actually one of the first things
we started thinking about
when we began discussing
what we thought needed to change
about itemization.
Because the experience in Season 3
and Season 2 and other seasons
has really been, like, the player,
you know, you'll get into, like, the,
you know, you're running your
high-tier nightmare dungeons,
you're getting lots of drops,
you know, you're sorting through
all of this stuff.
Like, you'll have, like, items that are,
like, you know, this is, like,
a 904 iPower sword,
and this is a 909 iPower sword.
Now, I've got, like, six helmets at all,
or, like, have a wide variety
of affixes on them.
We really wanted to, again,
just to quickly hit this,
we wanted to make sure
that we had a lower number
of affixes overall
that could roll on different item slots,
but those affixes were more, like,
generically useful
and stuff you could really build around.
As opposed to having lots of
really conditional affixes
going back to, like, the,
you know, the Damage on Tuesdays joke,
you know, like, that's...
The shirt that...
Literally wearing it now.
Literally wearing it.
So, huge proponent...
It's always funny.
So, it's, obviously,
because it's a joke, right?
Oh, jokes are always funny.
But the truth is, like,
we wanted to make sure that...
Where we wanted to have
conditional affixes in the game,
we wanted to find places
where players would be able
to opt into them
in a very specific way.
You know, so initially,
we want items that you're, you know,
really dropping for you
to have more generic utility,
just be more valuable
for you overall.
And also, as a result of this,
make it easier
to compare those items.
So, one of the changes
that we made
is we actually reduced
the number of affixes
that can naturally
roll on item slots.
So, like, now, like, you know,
a rare item can roll,
like, two affixes,
a legendary item
can roll three affixes,
but then later on,
there's other systems
you get to introduce...
We'll talk about in a bit.
It lets you introduce
more of those.
And we did that,
so it's just easier
to go through things.
We also made all items
post-level 100, 925.
So, you're no longer
comparing, like,
the designer number
that's, like, 904 to 925.
You're just focusing
on what's cool
about the item,
which is the affixes.
Yeah, which is super important,
because there's a lot
of situations where, like,
if you're level 100,
like, Blood Harvest
might be a lot of fun,
but Blood Harvest
is still dropping, like,
iPower 900 items for you.
And at that point,
why would you want
to keep even Blood Harvest,
which players really love,
like, why would you want
to keep engaging with it
if you can't get
really good endgame items
format?
So now when you're, like,
at level 100
and you're playing
in Helltide
or if you're going
through Nightmare Dungeons
at, like, a regular,
like, a slightly lower tier
and you're fighting
level 100 monsters
or higher,
you're always getting
iPower 925 items.
They might not have
all exactly the stats
or exactly the rolls
that you want,
but you're always getting
stuff you could actually
potentially use.
Yeah, a lot of the things
feel a lot better, too,
like gambling, right?
Like, now gambling
is actually a really
great source
for targeting item slot
because all of those
are 925 at level 100.
That's right.
So, like, the ovals
that you've been sitting on,
where you go and you just
churn through a whole bunch
of these at once.
They didn't have
as much generic value.
Now they're a lot better
because you really can
just, like, say,
I am looking for a helmet.
I am looking for a ring.
And you can just go roll,
you know, 10 iPower 925 rings
in a row.
And you have stuff
to play with then
at that point.
So, yeah, those were
some of the high-level
changes we wanted to make
with items with regards
to, like, making it easier
to compare these things.
Codex hits a lot.
Like, a lot of the inventory
concerns that we'd have
made changes to gems
in previous seasons.
We didn't have as many
of them clogging up
your inventory as well.
So we thought that was
really, really good stuff.
But then we knew
that we wanted to make sure
that it wasn't just about
like, we weren't going to
add another tier
of iPower to items.
That wasn't the way
to make itemization
more interesting for players.
and rewards more interesting.
You know, one of the
core things that we really
want to focus around
was the idea that, like,
items have a journey.
The best items have a journey.
Right?
So when you get
a really good item,
it's about what the
potential of that item is.
You know, what you can do
with this item
to make it really superior.
Right?
Yeah, definitely.
And that's sort of
to jump into tempering.
Yeah.
One of the first features
we had in terms of
taking your item
on a journey
was this idea that
we wanted hundreds
of different affixes
and each one spoke
differently to a build.
We wanted you to be able
to play sort of
whatever class fantasy
or build fantasy
you had in mind
and manifest that
through customization
of your items.
So we actually have
some video, I think,
of what the tempering feature
looks like,
and I can talk through
some of the updates
we've made from the PTR.
So here you have,
you know,
we're adding an offensive
affix to the item.
It's going to land on
increased corpse explosion damage.
It's like, yeah,
that's pretty cool,
especially if you really
like corpse explosion.
We've added a skip button
so you can skip through
the flow if you really
want to blast through this.
We also have a result screen
now that shows you
exactly what affix
it landed on
and what the roll range was.
And then we have
some more exciting affixes
that you're going to see here.
For example,
chance to cast
Bone Spear projectiles twice,
which I know, Adam,
is your favorite
because of all the
balance bomb
that dropped in your lap.
Don't say it like that.
It's so great.
It is cool, though,
because he,
like, being able to, like,
oh, Derek is here.
So, yeah,
we did our swap.
But Joe's still
going to be here
off screen.
We just want to make sure
that Derek up here is here.
Derek is our
lead season's designer.
So he'll be
talking a little bit more
about Helltides later.
Sorry to interject.
Okay.
Go ahead, Joe.
So, yeah,
now I'm off screen.
I think one of the
really cool things
about the tempering
system in general
is that, like,
the manuals
that we're introducing
initially are just,
like, the beginning
of what we can do
with tempering.
It's opportunities
to make, like,
really weird
and interesting new
ethics is to kind of
throw at the player
that we can introduce
in seasons
or in other updates.
So it's something
we can really extend
and do some really
neat stuff with.
Yeah, we absolutely
plan to build a lot
in the future.
Yep.
Awesome.
Yeah, so a bunch
of improvements
to tempering overall.
Yeah, and a lot
of these, again,
these improvements
in tempering
from the skip animations
to the previews
and stuff like that
that players will see
were based off
of feedback
that we actually got
from PTR.
And so, again,
huge shout-out
to the community
for providing
all that feedback
for us
so that we can
actually get that in
before the launch
of Season 4.
But with tempering,
we also have
Masterworking,
which is another
new feature
within Season 4
and permanently
within Diablo 4 itself.
So talk us through
a little bit
about what Masterworking
is and, of course,
the changes as well
that we're going
to be seeing
based off of PTR feedback.
Sure, yeah.
So, you know,
the next step
in your item's journey
is to really take
it to new heights.
You've customized it.
You found some base affixes
you're really into.
And we want it
to give you a way
to essentially
take some of these affixes
to new levels.
So you think about
Helms and CDR
or Cooldown Reduction
or, for example,
that chance to replicate
your Bone Spear.
We want you to be able
to really juice those stats.
So I think we have
a video here
of what that looks like.
You know, overall,
what we've really done
is taken a look
at the feedback.
We got a bunch of feedback
that it was tedious
to upgrade these
over and over.
So we've removed
the animation
from ranks 1 through 3.
We've kept
the critical upgrade.
We have the animation
still there,
but you can skip it.
You know, again,
sort of in the spirit
of blasting
across everything
that we do.
So we can do that
very quickly.
And another piece
of feedback
that we got
was that, you know,
part of the master
working process
allows you to reset this.
And why do you want
to reset this?
It's because you want
to hit that specific affix
you're looking for.
You want to juice
to specific affix.
And sometimes
you might miss, right?
Which means you want
to reset that item.
Yeah.
So part of the resetting
sort of requires you
to get lower tier materials.
You're going to get
these from the pit.
We'll talk about
that a little bit later.
But overall,
we saw a bunch
of feedback
that was really tedious
to create like
a thousand caches
and open up them
in town like
a hundred times, right?
It's super annoying.
The town is lava.
We want to address that.
Right.
So, you know,
we've added multiple scales
of material conversion
to those caches.
This is a short-term solution.
We have something
in the future planned.
It's just not ready yet.
So, you know,
while it's not
the perfect solution,
it does get you there
a little bit quicker.
There's multiple conversion
rates of materials
so you can turn,
you know,
one legendary material
into a much higher
count of materials
based on the tiers
that we have
in that crafting system.
So, again,
not the perfect solution.
We have something
coming in a future update.
Cool.
Awesome.
So, yeah,
a lot of changes
coming for masterworking
based off of feedback.
Masterworking,
of course,
being a brand new
kind of that end tale
of that item journey
that you'll have
even after tempering
and stuff like that.
So, yeah.
I'd say another thing
that was brought to you
was about Veiled Crystals,
right?
Didn't we reduce
the amount that you need
for crafting?
We did.
And I can totally talk
about some of the stuff
we've done just overall
on itemization.
Veiled Crystals
is one of those things.
Yeah,
so I'll talk about...
First,
I want to touch on
rare and magic items.
That was something
we made a change
from Season 3
and Season 4.
Legendary items
are just generally
straight up better
than rare items now.
And part of our goal
there is really
to ensure that players
aren't sifting through sand
looking through thousands
of items.
We want to just call it out,
like legendary items
are legendary.
At the same time,
we acknowledge that
there is some coolness
to knowing that certain
magic and rare items
could have value to you.
We don't have anything
for Season 4 yet,
but the design team
is definitely talking
about ways that we can
bring this rarity back
in a way that doesn't
diminish our overall goal
of trying to reduce
that sort of sifting
through sand feeling.
So in the meantime,
they can be salvaged.
They still have a use
in the endgame,
but we heard a ton
of feedback,
to your point, Adam,
on the Veiled Crystals.
It's just such a bottleneck
and it's like,
goddammit,
I have to pick a bunch
of yellow items up
to do any of the
cool crafting features.
What the hell, Blizzard?
That's an actual
player quote, too.
Yeah, I'm very sure it was.
Yeah, so what we've done
is we've made it
so that legendaries
break down into
equal amounts of
Veiled Crystals,
so you can just not
pick up yellow items.
It's just a bonus now.
We've also made
sacred and ancestral items
break down into
two and three
amounts of salvage.
So sacred items
will break down into
double,
ancestral,
break down,
and triple.
So we're effectively
tripling the output
of a lot of the salvage here.
And I know,
so, one,
that was probably
the most vocal feedback
that we got from players.
Maybe a little bit.
Yeah, but I need
more Veiled Crystals,
so I know that there's
changes coming for that
in Season 4
based off that PTR feedback.
Another,
probably maybe the second,
maybe also the first,
topmost,
our largest feedback piece
that we got
is around greater affixes
and the visibility
related to those.
So there are changes
going into that
for Season 4.
So, Fawn,
do you want to talk
a little bit about that?
Yeah, we wanted,
you know,
the dopamine.
That was a big goal also
of part of itemization
is just like seeing
an item hit the ground
and just be like,
oh, I like that jackpot moment.
Yeah, that's really important.
So we actually have
some video here
to show of what
that actually looks like
on the ground.
So you can see,
here's the weirdly
long named item.
with the greater affix.
I'm yielding commander
sacrificial sickle.
I know, right?
Yeah, yeah.
So we have
one greater affix star.
It'll go up to 3
or 4
if it's a unique item,
which always feels incredible.
So it shows up
on the ground
when it lands.
And then if we can
go to the next video,
we actually have
an indicator now
when it is
in the inventory.
Yeah, so you can see it.
What a zoom.
It's a trade enhance.
I asked this as a joke
and it looks so good.
I'm so happy.
I'm disappointed.
I can't see the pixels.
It's not zoomed in.
So that's been
enormously helpful
and really,
you know,
when you kill like Durial
or one of these
tormented bosses
and they drop a ton
of loot on the ground
to see some of these
have stars on them
and it just
is a feel-great moment.
Yeah.
Kind of goes with the whole
like not sifting
through the sands.
You clearly see that icon
and you know
that it has value to you.
You want to know
what's valuable.
Exactly.
Especially, again,
even on the icon itself.
like in your inventory
you will immediately know
those are my greater
affix items
and long gone
are the days
of the Roman numeral.
Right.
Even like the designers
of the show.
It's funny.
I think internally
we knew like
oh, that's probably
going to be changed.
We had a few jokes
about that.
Sure.
One thing I want to touch on
real quick before I move on
to itemization
if that's okay
is we actually
to touch on the
Veiled Crystals
I think players
are going to want to know
this is we reduced
the imprinting cost
of aspects quite a bit.
That's really going to
help the Veiled Crystals
as well.
I think it went from
like 75 Veiled Crystals
to imprints
on an Ancestral Armor
to 16.
Yeah, that's huge.
It's a pretty huge swing.
You're just getting
way more of your aspects
on here.
It's a lot more flexible.
We really want people
to feel like
and this is kind of
the Codex of Power Updates
in general
which I'm really pumped about
is we want you to feel
like you're able
to re-imprint those aspects
and it's something
that you're not
having a huge cost
or huge barriers
to doing
because as you
upgrade your gear
that should be part
of your process
is like putting on
their favorite affixes.
Yeah.
So a lot of changes
coming with tempering,
masterworking,
itemization
and I know
did we have any other
changes that you wanted
to cover before
we move on
to the next section?
Colin's got this
like this novel
in front of him
and he's like
what am I going to
do you want to re-imprint?
Oh, one I think
is worth mentioning
Colin you may want
to talk about
is the masterworking.
I remember we got
a lot of feedback
about the failchance.
Oh, that's a great point.
Oh yeah, that's true.
Funny enough
that was like
probably the biggest thing
changed.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That was the first bullet
and I somehow missed it.
Yeah, so we
definitely felt like
there's a ton of feedback
that the double random
chance was just
a little bit too much
and we agreed
so we just took it out.
It's just fun now
just to upgrade the item.
We adjusted the material
costs a bit
but the failchance
is no longer there.
Yeah, awesome.
Cool.
Well, thank you Colin
for going through
those changes.
We'll actually be back
to Colin here later
because he still has more
to talk about
from his novel
papers that he has
to be prepared.
But we did want
to jump into
some of the
class balance changes
that are coming
after PTR
of course
with season 4
we have a lot
of class balance changes
that are on top
of all these
itemization changes
and we got a lot
of great feedback
from players
so Mr. Adam Jackson
very much did.
Let's run through these.
Yeah, so basically
The classic
Adam Jackson slides.
Yes, I love my slides.
We have got three categories
of things
that I'm going to be
talking about today.
Again, thanks to everybody
for playing on the PTR
we did get a ton of feedback.
I'm not going to go over
the specifics
of everything that changed
but I'm going to go over
kind of the categories
of things
just because there's
a whole lot of changes.
One of the first big ones
was endgame survivability issues.
So this is kind of
talking about those people
that went really far
into the pit
and this is kind of
something that's been
happening online as well
that we wanted to address
and there's this phenomenon
when you get really deep
into the game
and you're fighting
high level monsters
where you'll hit a point
where the monsters
are kind of easy
and you're able to blow through
with your really powerful builds
and then you kind of get
to a point where
they start one-shotting you
and it can be kind of mysterious
and hard to understand
like what's going on
why did this happen?
We've also had some issues
balancing that kind of
top end survivability
when you get to those
hard monsters in the game.
One of the reasons for this
is that variability
and player defensiveness
has been really high
traditionally.
This is why
when you look at
the new items in the game
in Season 4
you don't see
a damage reduction
very much at all.
It's a very premium stat now
that's really hard to get
and it's to help solve
this problem
of when someone is stacking
all damage reduction
versus someone who has
none of it
their difference
in effective health
and survivability
is really really high
and so it makes it hard
to balance the game.
Another part that we wanted
to hit was really armor.
That armor is kind of
a really confusing stat.
It's not really well
understood how it works
and I'm going to be
going over in a little bit
how it works
and what we're changing
to kind of address
both of these issues
a little bit.
Next is that some stats
can get really high.
We added all these
crazy awesome stats
and you can juice them
with master working
and crit them
and all these things
and it allowed for some
really crazy things
on the PTR
which people love
to post constantly at me
and to be clear
we like crazy things.
It's awesome to get powerful
and have that fantasy.
We do have to take
into account things
like combat clarity
and computer performance
to make sure that
the game can still run
very well for everybody
so we made some changes
there to adjust that.
You mean it's not fun
to just not see
the screen or the ground?
I think it was
for a little while.
It is hilarious I think.
It's funny for a bit
but you can always see
patches of ground
and one player can do that
let alone when you get
four of them in a group.
It's great.
And last but not least
balance changes
and bug fixes
I'll be going over
some of them
but there's way more
than what I'm covering
right now today
but just know
we took a lot of feedback
on balance
a lot of feedback
on bugs
there were a lot of them
that were reported
and we acted on a lot of them
and I'll give an example
of some that we did.
Alright so let's go
into armor.
So brief history
lesson or description
of how armor works today.
This is like when you log in
how armor is functioning.
It's your staff
for physical damage mitigation
so you know how you have
your elemental resistance
that caps at 75
and then can get pushed up
a little bit.
Armor reduces your physical resistance
up to a cap of 85%.
It can't go higher than that
that's the number
but what's confusing
is the amount of armor
that you need
to get to that 85% cap
is actually based on
the level of the monster
that you're fighting
and I gave some examples here
these are the actual numbers
in the game.
So if you have a level 50 monster
that's hitting you
you know whacking you
then you need 5,265 armor
and then you'll be at
that 85% cap
but then at level 100
at every level
you know like 51, 52, 53
that number is going up
of what you need
and at level 100
it's about you know
9,230
and then at level 150 monster
it gets close to 13,000
right?
And so what this ends up
you know kind of creating
is that the player
really never knows
when they're done
with armor right?
That number can scale up forever.
It's kind of a hidden system
under the hood
so when you're fighting
these monsters
and they get way higher level
than you
as you scale into the pit
or nightmare dungeons
or whatever
you don't really know
how much you need
and so this is kind of
really contributing
to that phenomenon
where you're fine
you're at the cap
and then you're
you know
the higher level monsters
just start one-shotting you.
So in season 4
a lot of it's going to be
the same as season 3
it's still going to be
your source of
physical damage mitigation
the cap is still going
to be 85%
and you're still going to need
escalating amounts of armor
as the monster level
gets higher
but what we're changing here
if we go forward a little bit
is that armor is now
going to cap
at that level 100 monster number
so that 9,230
you can write down this number
we're also going to later
get into the tool tip
we couldn't get it in
for the launch of season 4
but we'll have it soon after
but it's kind of going to be
like elemental resistance
where you get to this number
and then you're kind of
done with the system
right?
So armor is just another thing
on your checkbox
of things you want to do
as far as defensive survivability
and once you get it
you're done
you can get it from gear
legendary aspects
and so on
particularly in season 4
I think this will be
a little bit of an easy
number to hit
we're not trying to make
this super difficult
or hard to do
it'll be very achievable
for you
when you're a level 100 player
so here we have a zoom in
on the tool tip
so you can see
this player has
way above that 9,000
amount of armor
that they need
they have close to 16,000
but you can see there
it's capped out
at that 85%
physical resistance
and again
soon after the launch
of season 4
we're going to actually
put the cap that you need
of the number
that you're chasing
because we want you
to know what the goal
is that you're trying to hit
so that means
they have a lot of room
for optimization
correct
yeah
this means that
this player
can actually give up
armor on some of their
tempering or item affixes
and look for other stats
like that's kind of the point
so next
stat caps
so you know
now that we've introduced
a lot of ways
to get really high amounts
of stats in the game
we want to kind of
control for visual clarity
you know
what a player
can put onto their screen
so kind of similar
to some caps
we have already
in the game
like attack speed
or elemental resistance
we're putting some caps
on cooldown reduction
and the increased area size
you know
like it's really fun
to get those giant
frost novas
that cover the screen
but when it goes
like two or three
screenings away
it can get really
noisy and messy
so we still want
these stats to be
really powerful
and impactful
but just control
a little bit
the amount of insanity
that they can bring
and one thing
on this cooldown reduction
cap
to be clear
this is not just
CDR across the entire game
this is just capping
what you can get
from gear
so this is like
the base cooldown reduction
you get when you first
cast a skill
what it's going to be
you can still get
cooldown resets
or additional cooldown effects
from things like
the skill tree
or legendary powers
that just reduce
the cooldown of your skills
as you do certain mechanics
this is just like
the baseline cap
that comes from your gear
I think when we looked
at the cap for area effect
too we tested it
on frost nova
and we were like
pretty meticulous
on what that cap
should be
and it was still massive
no it's huge
yeah
when I say like
making a cap
you're still going
to get to insanity
when it comes to
what's on your screen
it's still going to be awesome
so you can see here
this is just showing you
what the tool tip
looks like now
so we're going to be
showing you
as a player
what those caps are
so you know
when you're evaluating
your gear
on your tool tips
what it is
and then same thing here
you can see here
like the dust level
area effect size bonus
it caps at 100%
next balance updates
so again
like I mentioned before
we made a lot of
balance changes
based on feedback
again thank you
for playing
and giving us
all that feedback
I'm going to go over
some of the things
one of the bigger
categories of things
was again
like I mentioned
those changes
due to combat readability
and balancing player power
a few examples here
of things that we're reducing
are like the amount
of dust levels
that can be on your screen
and fractured winter glass
one of my new favorite
uniques we're bringing in
the amount of
frozen orbs
that could span the screen
is going to be reduced a bit
so I want to prepare you all
for that
again to be clear
you're still going to spawn
a whole lot
it's just not going to be
like insane amounts
where you can't see things anymore
they're still going to be
very powerful
I'm even going to show
a video a little bit later
of kind of the difference
of PTR
to what's going to ship
in the game
some other things
that we're doing
fortify
we wanted to increase
the amount of damage reduction
that you get
this is just fortify
across the board
the base mechanic
that DR is going
from 10 to 15%
and this is because
before when it was at 10%
we had to take into account
that players could get
damage reduction
from a million different sources
throughout the game
now that it's more rare
and more premium
we can actually make
this mechanic in the game
a little bit more impactful
and feel like you're
a tankier player
for opting into this
these kinds of builds
we also made a lot of
tempering affix updates
I'm not going to go
into detail them
but just know
what you saw in PTR
and what's going to ship
you're going to see
a lot of improvements
a lot of balance changes
even some shuffling around
of the affixes
to make them
in ways that make more sense
based on feedback
and then we did do
some class changes as well
I'm only going to give
very few examples here
but just know that
there were quite a few
one is druid players
companion druid players
always harass me
they want that build to work
and I agree
it's really cool
so we increased
the health of druid wolves
by 200%
and we also reduced
the respawn rate
and cut it in half
so we got feedback
basically that
their companions
were really good and fun
and did damage
but in the late game
they just kind of died
and couldn't survive
so we're doing this
to kind of address
that feedback
alright so here's
dust devils as an example
so you can see on the left
this is just one barbarian
by themselves
the amount of dust devils
that they could produce
right
and then on the right
you can see
kind of the same barbarian
you can see like
the dust devils
around the areas
where the enemies are
they're still getting hit
by a ton of them
but it's not covering
the entire screen
right
especially when you get
like three four
many players together
it really becomes insanity
yeah
when you're in a party
of four barbs
or
you know
it's just like
everyone's a barb
and I don't know
where I'm walking
yeah
in other classes
they do that kind of thing too
not just barb
but this was kind of
a good example
so you know
this is kind of
seeing the difference
between PTR and live
and then next
we have another class change
so Scoundrel's Kiss
this is another one
of our new uniques
that Rogue Players
gave us a lot of feedback on
so a quick summary
of how this new unique works
is it kind of changes
your rapid fire skill
from shooting straight
and hitting a single enemy
into kind of a mortar skill
where you shoot up
into the air
and then your arrows
fall on the ground
and explode
it's really really cool
but one of the pieces
of feedback we got
was that when you
launched the arrows
they would kind of
go in a line
and they wouldn't all
hit the same enemy anymore
so if you were trying
to do single target damage
it could actually be a nerf
unless you like
walked right up
to the enemies
and shotgun them
and while there was
a way to play around it
you know
players weren't really happy
that like we transformed
the skill so much
that it went from
a range skill
to kind of a melee skill
so we made an update here
and we have a video
of the before and after
but basically
you can see on the PTR
on the left here
how you know
it goes in a big line
and then the player
has to run right next
to the target dummy
to do the full damage to it
and on the right now
you'll see
basically you target
where those arrows
are going to drop
and they just all
go to that area
so you can hit
a single enemy
but you'll also
hit all the enemies
around it
because the arrows explode
so it should be
a lot more usable
compared to before
can Scandals kiss
ricochet with my rapid fire?
I'm pretty sure
yes it can
so it does all the things
and inherits all the things
that your rapid fire
doesn't say
that's very cool
but can it double projectile?
I'm pretty sure it can
just like everything else
yes
spam everywhere
we love spam
and last but not least
bug fixes
like I mentioned before
there were a whole lot
of bug fixes reported to us
thank you all for getting them
we addressed pretty much
every single one
that was reported
I'm giving some examples here
but again we got a lot more
than what I'm showing
on the screen
one was Druid's Hurricane
was incorrectly scaling damage
basically infinitely
so we fixed that
Ebon Piercer
the extra missiles
from our new unique
they incorrectly
had a 100% lucky hit chance
which is proccing
a lot of crazy stuff
and then Flame Weaver
another one of the new things
we introduced to the game
it's basically an effect
where you can put a firewall
on the ground
and then you shoot firebolts through
and it'll split the firebolts
really cool fantasy
but what happened
in the PTR
was you could stack
a bunch of firewalls
right on top of each other
and they would split
the firebolts multiplicatively
and add more and more
way more than intended
so you could fire
a ridiculous number
of firebolts
which were crashing servers
and things
so it wasn't great
but now we fixed that
so it'll work properly
and again
we're still discovering
and working on other fixes
there were a lot more
that went in
if you reported it
it was very likely fixed
so basically
the build will be
in a much better
stable state
once we launch
and that's really
due to all your feedback
so thanks again
awesome
that's my section
a lot of changes
coming to classes
class balance feedback
we got from PTR
was really really great
able to make
so many different
changes
there
of course
some of the biggest ones
like the readability stuff
that we probably saw
seeing the initial videos
of the dust devils
everywhere
was crazy
also being in a party
I was playing PTR
and being in a party
with two barbs
and another necromancer
I was like
oh okay
what's going on right now
yeah
PTR is
one of those things
you get to see things
in development state
I will say
these kinds of things
are actually pretty common
when we're developing anything
is being able to create
these crazy situations
and we have to fix it
for the game
before it goes live
so that's kind of
the advantage of PTR
is players can find
these things
there's a lot more manpower
being put in
PTR was super great
for us to have
and thanks again
to the community
for the feedback
on all the class balance changes
and thanks Adam
for walking us through that
the next thing
we do want to talk about
is with Derek over here
Derek is actually going to
talk a little bit about
of course all the immense
Helltide changes
probably one of the most
popular features
and changes that we've
introduced in season 4
with PTR
and people being able
to experience it
of course we got feedback
based off of players
jumping into Helltide
and we do want to go
through all that with Derek
and then we also want to
talk a little bit about
the season itself
with Derek
so Derek
want to jump in?
yeah just a few things
to cover
yeah so as you mentioned
the players who joined us
when the PTR
or caught all the various
like blog and video posts
and whatnot
know that with season 4
we're introducing
permanent upgrades
to the Helltide experience
heavy focus on improving
and enhancing I guess
monster density
and activity variety
so there's ton more
things to do in the Helltides
and as a result
there's just ton more
monsters to you know
mow through
in the Helltides
there's also
some explorations
and just to
double back real quick
these are all permanent
across both the seasonal
and eternal realms
so they're not going away
once season 4 ends
this is just how
Helltide works
it's part of the game
kind of like our item updates
too right
this is the new world
we live in
this is sanctuary
but there's also
if you kind of look
at the top right screen
there's a threat system
so the longer you're
fighting in the tides
you're going to be
accumulating threat
which just results
in even more
monsters ambushing you
at higher frequencies
than monster packs
I think the personal favorite
and I think like fan favorite
is the Hellworm
you know this giant demon slug bug
that just pops out
from the ground
and just vomits monsters
all over you
but you know
kind of with all those
the seasons
as we say a lot
are an amazing opportunity
for experimentation
and sometimes
the best results
of those experimentations
are when they can inspire
permanent upgrades
and just enhancements
to the base game
as a whole
so that's where
the Hellborn
and the new
Accursed Ritual
and Blood Maiden
come into play
as part of the new
Helltad experience
yeah look at those
those look great
so the Hellborn
as our season 2 players
might recall
we introduced
the Bloodseekers
and those were
really cool
monsters
based on
class archetypes
so you're kind of like
fighting
the Empiric Shadow
versions of yourself
and we take a look
at that content
and we just love it
from like the team perspective
and just find like
hey we're upgrading
the Helltides
this is a perfect
piece of content
to just include with it
so that's where
the Hellborn
came into play
you know
they're fallen heroes
of Sanctuary
they've been overtaken
by the corruption
from Hell
and you know
kind of turned against you
kind of in line
with that
the Accursed Ritual
and the Blood Maiden
in season 2
with the Bloodlurs
and the Bloodseekers
we introduced this concept
of
I guess calling it
just like
open world
social boss summoning
we followed up
with like the
yeah there's a buzzword
there
yeah it's very very
yeah very catchy
rules right out of time
I love it
again to my designer
speak sometimes
but yeah
and we followed that up
with like the
Malfus spawners
in season 3
and again
looking at these
really successful
experimentations
from previous seasons
we love opportunities
to bring players together
and just add that
extra out layer
to the Helltide experience
so that's where
the Accursed Ritual
comes into play
so as you're
out fighting
against the tides
you'll be collecting
the new material
the Baneful Hearts
that you can bring
to the Accursed Ritual
it takes 3
to summon up
the Blood Maiden
and you can do this
you know
by yourself
or you can partner up
with some buddies
and all
I guess
contribute to the
summoning together
and you know
the Blood Maiden
itself is our new
Helltide mini boss
that she's immensely powerful
but also very very lucrative
and I think the last thing
I forgot to mention
is that this is all
expanding into
World Tiers 1 and 2 as well
and kind of like a
distilled not diluted
so there are
the Helltide and World Tiers 1 and 2
is more specifically tuned
to you know
I guess like meet the leveling needs
or the needs of the leveling player
awesome
on the Blood Maiden
I remember you had talked about
with me before
that
the people that summon the Blood Maiden
actually get bonus
loot drops right?
yeah absolutely
so you can either contribute
just by yourself
to the Blood Maiden
and get some extra loot
for you know
your troubles
we want to you know
make sure that we give you
a little bit extra
because you're sacrificing
up your hearts
but also
every player
that
it doesn't stack
so you're not
you know
stressed to say
hey I just need to be the one
that summons them all
we can all party up
and just deposit our own
Baneful Hearts
and I guess reap the benefits of that
yeah
right
to be clear
so like
so if you put in all three
you get bonus loot right?
correct
but like you, me, and Colin
are in a group
and like I put in two
and you put in one
do I get more loot than you?
no
so you get the same amount of loot
so you know
if Colin has a Baneful Heart
to deposit
and if we all
you know dump them in together
then we all get the
shared benefits of that
but I will touch on a bit later
the PTR updates
and just some of the
enhanced value
that the Blood Maiden
received since PTR
for both contributors
and non-contributors
to the summon
awesome
yeah
so a lot of new stuff
coming in for Helltide
and this is all part of the stuff
that players got to experience
in the PTR
and of course we got learnings
from the PTR
as you just mentioned
many
do you want to
walk us through
some of the changes
that are coming in
with Helltide
for all the
the PTR feedback
that we had
yeah
I think I have a PowerPoint
on my own
there you go
look at that
yeah so
you know as mentioned
tons of sweeping changes
going into the Helltides
and just overall balance
of the game in general
season 4
and kind of with that
sometimes you know
we push a little bit too far
in some regards
so we did get feedback
and also just own
internal kind of
field checks
on the
Cinder drop rates
were feeling a bit slow
in the PTR
so we just went back
reviewed it
and gathered our feedback
and just iterated
on the drop percentage
to hit closer
to the expectations
of how much
we want to be
collecting the Helltides
the Cinders
and interacting
with the tortured gifts
so I think we're
in a much better spot
I know we're in a much
better spot right now
actually
so that was one
of the first
major pieces
coming out
from the PTR
a lot more chess
from this yeah
yeah chess
more loot
more fun
awesome
let's see the next one
yeah so
on the topic of
more is more fun
the Baneful Hearts
we were noticing
that they were
dropping a bit
inconsistently
so you can get
the Baneful Hearts
from opening
tortured gifts
killing the Hellborn
and one of the
Doomsayer variants
one of our new
activity types
but again
we want to get
the Baneful Hearts
in the hands
of the players
with a pretty
steady cadence
so we noticed
with the PTR
that we're just
not gaining them
as frequently
as we wanted to
so we just
went back
iterated and
kind of reviewed
our bad luck
protection
to just ensure
that we
improve the
consistency
that Baneful Hearts
are dropping
and this is all
kind of like
the Blood Maiden
is not meant
to be seen
as like this
highly ambitious
piece of content
that you only
engage with
like once
every 50 levels
we want you
getting the hearts
engaging with
the social boss
summoning
mechanic
and you know
I think it just
adds that extra
layer to the
Helltides
we want you
to engage with
and on the
topic of
the Blood Maiden
overall
like we
touched on
earlier
the Blood Maiden
is just
saving some
overall
rewards
improvements
so as
noticed
or as
mentioned
before
if you
contribute
to the
summon
of the
Blood Maiden
you receive
a bonus
reward
but one
of the
things
was that
you couldn't
really tell
there is a
little icon
that appears
like when
you're buff
bar
but the
effects of
that was
largely
unnoticed
from both
the team
and actually
just the
PTR
players
themselves
so again
taking this
opportunity
to just
review the
overall
value
of the
Blood Maiden
for
contributors
and non-contributors
alike
because again
we wanted
to make sure
that she
has a
clear role
in the
Helltide
experience
so again
overall
Blood Maiden
is just
overall
more valuable
with this
we're dropping
things like
Legendary's
Forgotten
Sold
Lore
and a
percent
chance
for
contributors
at the
end
world
tiers
to
get some
endgame
boss
materials
as well
yeah
so this
is now
like an
additional
opportunity
for players
to get
additional
of the
boss
mats
for the
boss
ladders
yeah
which you
know
we've heard
a lot
about
how
players
were like
hey
we only
really have
one
kind of
method
to get
them
and we
wanted to
expand
that
and bring
into
more
avenues
so players
didn't have
to just
kind of
be like
tunneled
off
into one
area
to get
specific
boss
mats
which
is cool
yeah
variety of
the spice
of life
yes
i like
that the
contribution
encourages you
to actually
use these
in season 2
i just
chain summon
the boss
over and
there would
be this
awkward dance
where someone
would show
up and it's
like i know
you have
yeah
use your
material
yeah that's
why it's
really also
important that
the nuance
is not
nuance is
honestly lost
pretty frequently
when we're
talking about
drops for
different kinds
of creatures
and different
sorts of
situations
like this
like treasure
goblin
we talked
about treasure
goblin a
while ago
a few seasons
ago
and i
remember i
put a poll
out on
x.com
so i put a
poll out
basically asking
players what
they believed
the legendary
drop rate of
treasure goblins
to be and i
had a whole
bunch of
options and
every like i
think like 85%
of the players
were wrong
and because the
drop rate at
that time was
50% players
didn't feel it
because they
didn't see the
treasure goblin
enough to
really notice
that it was
actually that
high so uh
so i think
making sure that
like we were
like buffing up
those moments
where like if i
have my
contribution bonus
a little bit
higher that
helps make
sure that
is felt
yeah absolutely
you know what's
funny is uh
joe talking
off screen
and we're all
looking off
and people are
just staring
us stare
into this
random corner
and stuff
you know what
would be funny
is we all
just actually
looked back
there at
bail
we should
plan that
every time
yeah every
time and
like joe's
turned into
bail
oh oh
so literally
coming out
oh
that's
awkward
that wasn't
part of
the plan
i like the
deep shadows
that's right
he is
i guess the
moments when
i decide to
say something
maybe the
location
like oh
we have
another
camera
awesome
um
cool
so a lot
of a lot
of health
high changes
that we
have uh
coming in
yeah i think
there's actually
one more slide
yeah one more
um so
one thing that
we've kind of
covered a lot
across like just
tempering and
just the masterwork
and just the
spirit of season
four in general
just like
removing friction
points and
just keeping
players in the
flow of
you know
the flow of
fun
people want to
blast
yeah absolutely
so one of
the doomsayer
variants
and again like
the doomsayer's
new activity type
it's kind of
like a kinder
surprise where you
interact with them
they crackle and
pop into something
a variety of
things actually
so one of the
variants that we
had was the
chest of doomsaying
where they would
explode into a
tortured gift that
costs 50 cinders
and gives you a
whole lot of good
stuff we're kind
of reviewing that
and sometimes
what could happen
is you can
encounter one of
these at the
very start of
your helltide
running you
don't have 50
cinders it's not
a lot to get
but it still is
kind of a
stressful
potentially feels
bad moment
so we just
said hey let's
just have it
explode into the
loot directly
you save 50
cinders and you
kind of just keep
going on your
merry way in the
tides so that's
one of the kind
of like efficiency
smoothing outs that
we've done the
next one is also
just we're dumping
a whole bunch of
monsters on you and
it's always a feel
bad moment you get
knocked out of the
interaction you're
trying just to open
up the tortured gift
and you know head
out so we reduce
the channel time to
open tortured gifts
from three seconds to
1.5 seconds I
believe for season
four launch proper
nice that'll help
a lot so and I
think while I
just some feedback
like you know why
don't we just make
it instant right
right right yeah
you know we kind
of do want to
safeguard against like
the accidental clicks
again it's a frenetic
game so you're
clicking a whole
bunch and you know
I think 1.5 seconds
is enough time to
you know let you
make sure that
that's what you
want to commit to
before you open it
and there's also
like because you
guys can talk about
this there there's
changes to like the
channeling like you
you I think with
like dot damage and
stuff like that
but yeah dot damage
that will interrupt
channeling as well
which is a pretty
nice which is good
so especially as
you are in the
frantic areas of
helltide and
everything so yeah
lots of helltide
changes a lot of
good feedback from
players from PTR
Derek thanks for
walking through on
that but you're not
done yet we do
but wait there's
more as you guys
know like there is
this is season four
loot reborn and
part of helltide
includes the iron
wolves and some
people have figured
that out even before
our blog on Tuesday
but we did want to
talk a little bit
about season four
and the iron wolves
participation in that
along with some
cool things that are
specific to seasonal
characters for season
four as well yeah
yeah so again as
mentioned the players
who joined us in the
PTR or again caught
all the various blog
posts will notice that
the iron wolves are
now a permanent part
of the helltides you
know they're fighting
and dying alongside the
players now and
they're here to stay
however for our
seasonal players we
have the call the
wolves seasonal
activity where players
will get to spend a bit
more time with the
iron wolves and go on
a bit of a journey with
them to try and uncover
the potential root cause
behind these rising
tides and uncover this
mysterious phenomenon
that's threatening to
corrupt and consume the
iron wolves from within
in addition to that you
know again the iron wolves
are in the helltides with
you as players are
fighting and dying
alongside the iron wolves
and the helltides you're
also gonna be earning
your way through the
wolves honor reputation
system and this is
saying you progress your
way through a collection
of just super juiced
rewards that are
specifically tuned to
overpower your leveling
journey from level one
to 100 and beyond
the main pillar for this
reputation track was
really pushing the
players powers forward
the player power forward
there you go the
players power forward
and giving them early
access to you know gear
with the juice stats
legendaries materials
boss materials and even
a resplendent spark to
as like a cherry on top
at the end we love the
juice we do you do love
that but you know in the
spirit of weight there's
more you know those are
all like the gameplay
related things but we
also have a couple really
cool cosmetics that you
earn through the collective
call the wolf season
activity so this is the
iron wolf mount trophy
the little iron wolf
banner and oh a little
bit fast but um yeah so
the iron wolf mount
trophy we're doing it
live here um that's
earned from completing
the right there it is
um you can get both of
them um that's earned
through completing the
reputation track and the
blood maiden head is
earned by completing the
associated iron call the
wolf quest line awesome
yeah those look really
great and of course as
you mentioned resplendent
sparks there's and then i
know um there's one
other item that i know
we wanted to talk about
with uh this season
specific because it is
specific for um season
four and yeah yeah
yeah um thanks for the
reminder of that there's
so much to cover
i know derek has like
the the largest list of
items to kind of go
through here so um yeah
so you know as mentioned
before on the seasonal
team we love our
experiments and i don't
think a season would be
one without some level
of experiments so with
that we have the seasonal
item or as kind of like
call it the seasonal toy
and that's the profane
mind cage um yeah so
there it is so the
profane mind cage is
pretty cool in the sense
that it's a guaranteed
drop from the hellborn and
when you consume it i kind
of like to imagine you
just like eating this
demon brain um yeah
when you can when you
consume it uh for the
next 60 minutes the
hell type monsters are
going to be boosted up
to 10 levels depending on
the world tier that you
consumed it in and
you're also going to be
increasing their aberrant
cinder drop rates so
you know again all
tying this back to that
leveling journey and like
tempering and stuff like
this is a really fun
item that lets you kind
of put your build to a
little bit more of a
test in exchange for
maximizing your hell
tight efficiencies
through you know just
one higher monster level
means you know more xp
and stuff like that and
also just aberrant cinder
drops too you know
oh go ahead okay i was
gonna say we reduced the
world tier to three and
four xp so that's great
yeah it ties super well
you can just get to
blast the endgame very
quickly now yep yeah and
with the mine page itself
like uh you know because
everyone's probably going
like well that's a
consumable like how how do
how do people end up like
obtaining additional ones
of those or can you get
more of those throughout
the season and everything
yeah we want to be very
uh generous with those um
so one they're guaranteed
drop from the hellborn
in world tiers three and
four but you can also use
them in world tiers one and
two so if you want to like
boost some level you know
alts and whatnot um you
also get a uh i think like
a bucket of them through
the wolves honor reputation
like we crammed as many
rewards as we could in
there so they will be in
steady stream so don't
again in the spirit of like
use it don't hoard it
definitely experiment and
have fun with this thing
because you know it's it's
a game have fun yeah so
it's great like if you want
a little bit more of a
challenge a little bit better
rewards as well you can of
course use your your mind
cage uh and that is
exclusive for um uh
players in the season so
yeah it's awesome to see
um but yeah thank you
derek for walking us
through all the changes
with helltide and of
course some of the the
new season stuff with the
iron wolves and if you're
a lore nerd uh iron wolves
of course are very familiar
faction within diablo they
are from diablo 2 act 3
you could actually hire
them as uh some of your
your mercenaries they are
one of the mercenary
options though we know a
lot of people went with an
act 2 mercenary in diablo 2
for the aura but yes um
cool thank you so much uh
derek and of course we uh
still have more to talk
about we're actually going
to go back to colin uh and
colin is going to talk us
through a little bit about
the pit um the pit is a
brand new feature within
season four and is now a
permanent feature within
diablo 4 um and uh yeah
do you want to like give
us a breakdown for people who
may have not experienced the
pit or may have not seen the
stream beforehand and then on
top of that uh tell us about
all the improvements that
we're doing to the pit based
off of feedback yeah so you
know something that players
have asked for uh since we
did a bunch of nerfs to the
nightmare dungeons uh if
you recall i forget what
season it was but we made a
tier 100 nightmare dungeons a
lot easier so players can get
through them um one of the
big pieces of feedback we got
was okay well where's my
measuring stick you know the
game is a power fantasy it's
about getting as much raw power
as possible and just
dominating right so if there's
no place to push back then
you know everything is just a
little bit too easy so the pit of
the artificer is our answer to
that measuring stick you're
going to be able to push very
deep into the pit um there's a
lot of levels we were inspired
by abattoir of zir but to be
very clear you know abattoir of
zero was a special case in that
each tier jump was just like
brutal it was like exponential
it was like ridiculously hard
every single tier and it's like
ah you could only get to seven
uh which isn't very heroic or
or powerful right so we've taken a
lot of the learnings from abattoir
of zero um the pit goes uh very
deep there's many more tears it's
much more gradual so you can start
pushing into it um and getting some
of these master working material
rewards um and the pit is all about
you know just blasting through
monsters and the demons of hell right
there's no negative modifiers we're
not cc'ing you a bunch you know this
is really just a test of how powerful
your build is um so from the ptr we
actually got feedback that it was way
too easy um because we added a ton of
a ton of power through tempering um
through the codex of power it's just
much easier to get a lot of that those
aspects online um so we've taken a
look and we've moved some of the
master working material tiers around
previously uh you know the tier one
master working materials only came from
one to twenty we've moved that up uh
ten tiers so tier one will come from
one to twenty nine tier two will come
from thirty to fifty nine and tier three
will be sixty plus and what that does it
it just makes the journey feel a little
bit more rewarding right like we saw in
the ptr that people just like within
the first two hours just blasted through
all of it because they're so powerful
um so we've just adjusted some of the
the rates there so you have to push a
little bit deeper you have to optimize
your build a little bit more so those
armor caps are things to watch out for
right where if you're over the armor
cap it's just a straight optimization to
start thinking about how you want to
replace some of that armor we think that
feels pretty good and overall we've
increased the health and damage or
sorry i should say increase the health on
all monsters post level 100 both in the
pit and nightmare dungeons so the enemy
should be pushing back on you a little
bit more right you care a little bit
more about utility defense outside of just
one-shotting everything right so it sort of
tests you a lot more you know and part of
that feedback though that we've heard is
that well like nightmare dungeons don't
feel very rewarding and the pit doesn't
feel super rewarding post you know that
that sixty tier when you're getting those
master working top-end master working
materials so we've done two major changes
one is we've added obols that scale with
both of these tears so everything past
tier 46 and nightmare dungeons and
everything past tier one in the pit
actually it just always gives you obols you
might ask like but obols are terrible but
you know again why do i want obols call it i
know right a big part of season four was
that you know we made the gambler guarantee
of the p9 25 legendaries at level 100 and
those legendaries can roll greater
affixes so you know if you blow you know a
ton of obols on two-handers for example
those two-handed legendaries are getting
are the same as anywhere else in the game so
it's actually a huge efficiency boost to
getting the items you're looking for
so to be clear you can get like some of the
best items in the game from the obol
vendor now absolutely and and one thing that
is also changing with obols it's like
because you know when people pick up obols
they're like oh i've got my cap and yeah
someone's like typing but calling the
oval cap is fine so you know like we've
increased the oval cap substantially so
the amount of obols you get now is 2500
you can hold up so you can just like go to
the gambler and be like give me everything
and you can just do that a couple of times
so get your obols and hit the tables
yeah yeah exactly and the items are
incredible and just and just to like double
down this for a second too like the like
one of the things that we also did as part
of this like when you're when you use the
enchanting feature in diablo 4 you can't
actually enchant off of an affix into a
greater affix that's right yeah so when a
good item drops for you in the in the
base game you can't you can't try to like
roll for greater affixes off the
enchanting system it's good for getting you
to a stat you really need in a situation
where an item didn't get you what you
wanted but now with the obols vendor like
those items not only are they ipower 925
and they have the chance to be legendary of
course like they are like the obols vendor
always has but you also have a chance to
get greater affixes off those gambled items
yeah so if you are again if you're
looking for a particular pair of gloves
you're looking for a particular helmet
and you're really you're saying i really
want a greater affix version of cooldown
reduction on my helmet right like now
it's okay cool i'm going to take my
2000 obols i'm going to go to the i'm
going to go to the vendor i'm just going
to just gamble gamble gamble gamble and
try to get the try to get that one
helmet yeah like now i have a chance to
really do that and this is a way for
you to like getting more drops and and
and such inside the pit is one thing
but giving you more choice when you get
out of a pit run i think very very
valuable it's going to feel way better
yeah absolutely yeah and another change
we made uh was to glyph xp we got a bunch
of feedback that's like god what the hell
nightmare dungeon so we've increased the
glyph xp by 25 percent which is faster
leveling we've also scaled the amount of
rune shards which is the pit currency to
get into the pit with nightmare dungeon
so you can create sort of a positive
feedback loop if you're really strong
you're really powerful you're hitting
those tier 100s and the nightmare dungeons
you're getting tons of pit keys that you
can then translate into the pit and just
get lots of runs and lots of master
working there yeah so right a lot of
feedback from nightmare dungeons people
were saying like hey um are we planning on
making any changes to that glyph xp and
you know so there there are some we sure
did we we actioned on it for sure so uh and
there's funny enough there's also even in
the um uh the season journey i believe
there's also like a changes to that the
the ashes themselves where you can actually
use that to boost even like yeah like
glyph xp is also part of that um with the
the season journey so very cool um stuff
that we have one more sorry i have this
list but then i don't actually read it but
then she's like a prop yeah sorry um the one
other thing that we did was we heard a
bunch of feedback that uh players were
dying at the end of the pit because we
have this like shadow boss that sometimes
comes in and throws a wrench in what you're
doing um and you know as much as i push for
learn to play you know our encounter
designer
absolutely uh take that hardcore players
surprise yeah yeah isn't it fun to die
after you killed the boss uh yeah so uh our
encounter designer uh did an amazing job
cleaning up a lot of those affixes after
you killed that boss and the arena should
be clear now as chat says get good um but
uh yeah we we we saw that a lot and you
know if you're a hardcore player that would
have been a tragic loss to your character
i prefer the word hilarious
some designers like fist pumping like yes
yeah just watching streams and reactions
from that so awesome so a lot of changes
coming for the pit pit is of course a new
feature within diablo 4 permanently and
you can experience that in eternal and
seasonal realms um and of course we have
some updates to the boss ladder because the
boss ladder itself is changing pretty
pretty significantly we talked a little bit
about like how you can get additional
materials in other places um that derek had
mentioned uh but uh colin has additional um
like points that he wants to bring up about
the boss ladder because we got a lot of
feedback on that and uh there's some new
changes to it with season four
yeah so we added and dariel the best lesser
evil yes yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah he's dunking me yeah yeah he's
dunking me with orbs all day who likes that
yeah so uh and dariel obviously has come
back she's incredibly fun to fight the
encounter design team killed it um and you
know on top of endorial we've added a new
tier to the boss ladder uh called tormented
bosses so these are much higher level than
level 200 bosses um sort of pinnacle aspirational
bosses to take down and what we've done here is
we heard a bunch of feedback that it required
five times the amount of boss materials
including some rare pit material to summon
these and five times the reward um that
didn't really feel like the right amount of
reward efficiency for taking on something
that was challenging so we've nerfed the cost
it's now 3x the amount of boss material and
5x the reward so you get some pretty big
efficiency wins there especially if you're
crushing them in the end game um so that's
feeling pretty good uh we think we also heard a
lot of feedback that it's uh tedious to do the
same activity over and over and over to
summon some of these things right so it's
like i want to summon penitent knight or i
want to do the beast and ice i know you and
i've done that one like yeah every bill i've
chosen in a season requires the beast and
ice and it's like i guess i'm doing another
nightmare dungeon yeah yeah yeah so um yeah
well we made it better um a lot of our
random uh you know monsters and activities
and and things like that so you know elites
whisper caches treasure goblins world
bosses you know hellborn to name a few
are all going to start randomly dropping
um these boss materials so you know you're
not necessarily forced into doing one exact
activity it's still going to be the
absolute best way to get some of this
boss material but as long as you're
blasting you're just going to be getting a
lot of these materials ambiently which you
can trade you can just sort of cash in on
on your heart's desire and we think this
makes the game feel more flexible and just
sort of enables you to play a little bit more
on how you want to play while still keeping
the experience fresh um so we think that's
going to be a pretty big win yeah it's
huge yeah um to jump back into the torment
bosses uh just because i'm going to jump
around a little bit uh we heard a bunch of
feedback uh especially from wadijo uh
hopefully he's watching uh is is there's no
way we just watching right now probably not
yeah it's not very it's not very interesting um
we we did some tuning uh to make sure that
the tormented versions have some more parody
right it was sort of like a in a scenario where like one of the
latter bosses was just like dead easy didn't
really match the difficulty of the rest and that's important because we give
you one guaranteed resplendent spark one
time for defeating any of these so one step closer to getting that uber
unique that's not just a raw drop of your choice
which is pretty awesome and then something else you know speaking of
resplendent sparks we're adding one to uber lilith so the first time you kill
uber lilith you're also going to get another resplendent spark so now that that
brings us to three opportunities of being able to earn yourself a resplendent spark we heard one
from from derek at the end of the the season and the iron wolves you know uh uh board and
and doing that within the season we now have one with uh the echo of lilith and of course one
with your first tormented boss as well so uh additional opportunities to earn resplendent
sparks and of course you can still salvage your uh any uh uber gear that you do happen to find
yeah and you can actually earn a resplendent spark yeah so what that means is if you do all of these
and then you get an uber unique you can actually change that into whatever one you want yes yeah
is really what that means and then something else you know on on the uber uniques is that
i'm just laughing because i i didn't realize this but chat's calling out with our our tool tip
that we showed we had 200 plus resplendent sparks yeah that's what happens when we're just really
lucky we're doing good yeah yeah that's how i get them let me tell you guys about dev tools
yeah that's actually my account online oh yeah yeah nice um so uh on on the uber uniques um you know
we heard a bunch of feedback that it feels like a chore to have to do you know the pendant at night
into varshon into doing durial just for a chance at an uber unique right um and you know we've experienced
that ourselves right it's like god i gotta do all this stuff to to fight the boss that's going to
actually drop something that i care about um you know greater affix has helped that because you know
that there's some variation to the uniques you're going to get but for uber uniques we've actually
added a small chance um a little bit lower than durial to all of the ladder bosses and they're going
to have a chance to drop an uber unique as well so you know while you're grinding through this ladder
every single boss you kill is going to have a chance to drop an uber unique it's not exactly the same
music uh dariel durial and and dariel we should do like a combo a lot of rails um and uh we think
that's going to make it feel a lot better awesome so yeah a lot of changes coming with uh boss ladder
and changes based off of ptr feedback that we saw yeah lots just overall changes for season four that
we were we're planning so that it's um gives more opportunities for players to actually experience
of course the uh the new versions of the bosses themselves and their tormented echo versions so
awesome thank you so much colin of course um and i know we wanted to before we jump into q a because
we we're getting towards the end of our updates for season four um mr adam jackson wants to talk a
little bit about um the season journey this is actually something really cool one last thing um
us over on class designer we're really passionate about this and we're excited for it so the season
journey uh so we really want to kind of juice the rewards and make the season journey
more exciting and so what we went and did was when you're going through the season journey for
every class you're actually going to be getting a preset curated amount of legendaries as you're
going through that are targeted toward a specific build so we chose a build for every class in season
four and we're going to change it around in future seasons please give us feedback on this but
we think it'll be pretty cool but you're basically going to get like close to a completed build when
it comes to opening those caches they're guaranteed targeted legendaries to build a specific
fantasy for every class i think we have a video to show what they're going to be for every class
in season four maybe maybe there so barbarian here you can see uh we're going to be giving you a bunch
of legendaries related to dust doubles uh the druid we're going to be giving you basically a pulverized
build which is pretty cool next is the necromancer of course everybody's going to be playing minions so
we give you a bunch of minion focused legendaries it should be pretty awesome and then next is the
sorceress we actually have a cool new legendary coming into the game for incinerate which you'll
see here it's what's up so we were giving you an incinerate build on the sorceress
and then the rogue uh we're giving you one target toward barrage so again kind of the point of this
is that you know if you don't really know what you want to play or you really want to just go through
a season journey and try out something before you go to a build that you really want to do you have a
foundation of something more complete to start with which we're pretty excited about yeah and with
the codex change now uh you also get to collect all those those items are actually dropping out of the uh
the season journey caches you get to kind of keep those they're all going to your codex you use that
build the entire your leveling process correct yeah awesome so lots of changes coming season
sorry my mic died halfway through there so i had to do a quick mic swap as we were playing also uh
joe pipe or is back um yeah hi joe derek is now over here so uh if people are confused of like what's
going on we are playing musical chairs today that is that is also a new feature our favorite season four
i'm just kidding um but uh yeah so all a lot of changes season four pretty huge is by far the biggest
season um for diablo 4 yet uh and i know we wanted to jump into q a i do want to bring up one thing
as well oh wow which is this is a change that uh will be represented in by the way patch notes are
coming out immediately after this stream so geez okay so that's one thing so yeah people can check
out patch notes immediately after this stream you enjoy reading it as much as we enjoyed writing it
we're writing it and reviewing it and editing it and i wouldn't based off of the size of the patch notes i
wouldn't be surprised if we do have a few things that might be missing that we'll probably like
have to post ad if if uh as we're kind of going through it just because it's massive in terms of
size as people saw from ptr and now it's just even a few different teams like effort trying to lose
too yeah so uh but uh patch notes will be up one thing in the patch notes that i did want to bring up is
and this is a thing that's coming in season four is uh for players that want to change the their their hair
on their characters themselves they can actually go to the wardrobe now and actually be able to do
it which is a nice like good quality of life feature we've heard a lot of people go like hey
i kind of want to you know i made that character a while ago especially like an internal character
or something like that i would like to be able to change that around yeah i now have that flexibility
being able to do so which is actually really cool so um we're going to jump into q a as usual as we
always do um we will start off with a question this is actually something that's been a a popular topic
that a lot of people have been talking about uh since ptr and of course even this week with the
the blog itself but um don't leave me in suspense i know i i i uh that i think we have the question
there it is uh what does this mean for season powers in the future oh just what season four is
like the nature of season four yeah okay sure so yeah season four is a uh season four as i mentioned
before is like an opportunity for us to kind of like lift up a lot of aspects of the game that we
think are really important diablo is a game about killing monsters and getting loot and as i said
before getting loot uh we need to make sure it feels at least as good as killing monsters right
like it's extremely important that this part feels good and uh we took a lot of our development effort
and put it against that that goal as part of this release and there were other parts to gain that we
lifted up at the same time like the various changes that we talked about for for helltide for example
you know the miri new tempering recipes and things like that there's lots of things we did
i think as part of the release just make the base experience of diablo 4 more fun right so i'm
really excited we're able to do that in season four thinking about what the future holds we always
want to make sure that with every season now we are adapting to what we think the game needs at that
time we think it's going to make for a better experience overall we we love the idea of seasonal
powers i we we we've learned a lot of really really great stuff from the days of the barber all the
way through the vampiric powers we got in season two and all the seneschal and construct stuff we
we had in season three uh we have lots of big ideas for the future so but you know you will
you will see seasonal powers again in the future and in different themes and mechanics as we go
that's you know that's kind of our promise to you and with the things we have in terms of like the
iron world's quest line and the various rewards you get changes we made to the season journey for
like getting like all of those themed items uh those like uh those uh those various like kind of aspect
builds together as you kind of progress through we want to keep building upon these mechanical elements
as well at the same time they can continue to help lift up the experience so yeah we will we will we will be
returning to seasonal powers in the future you know but with every season we want to make sure
that we're doing what we think is to be up like lifting the game up uh the most the things that
we think are most important at that time awesome um question from our i'll i'll bounce between some
questions from chat and from our forums because we did have a thread up in our forums about uh okay
specific questions but this one's from the forums this is from avalon um they're asking if uh because you
know season three actually ran longer and season four itself had a ptr will season four actually be a
shortened season or will it still be in a a standard size season they they weren't sure how ptr is
actually affecting the time on it uh so ptr is is not as uh is not as impactful for the timing here we
we we it's i think it's a slightly shorter season i think it's like like one week shorter or something
i need to look at the date yeah and and i i will note like ptr the the reason why season three ran
longer was because we wanted to make sure that we could get that ptr this was our first ptr um so it you
know there's there's a little bit more effort into and needed to get that out for players yeah i
guess i i guess you're you're absolutely right so like i think about like when i'm thinking about
the future and like what ptrs look like we want things to be like we're it's not that like having
a ptr automatically means that everything is going to take longer to deliver it's but there's a lot of
things we had to set up for the first time the ptr for season four and i'm really glad that we did
because as i think you've seen there's a lot of things we learned going through the process and give
us the time to iterate and use the feedback too yeah which we did a lot of things on based on uh question from blake
dark oscs uh will you guys think about maybe a potential different bean color for items with
greater affixes uh so i know we talked about this for a while yeah yeah i think um that's something
we're definitely going to keep an eye on like right now we think that the the little dots or the i should
say huge dots the huge stars on them um are doing a pretty good job but you know that's something that we
we also need to feel out and play and we're super open to feedback and seeing how these new big stars are
going to help yeah um yeah the the change especially the changes in the inventory because like now you
can actually identify them in your inventory and everything is really big these also roll on unique
so there's a little bit of like work that we'll need to figure out um but again yeah it's true yeah
you can get greater affix on unique as well yeah so it's like what yeah the beam color gets a little
confusing there for you so something to that we'll monitor for sure and of course something that we've seen
from players and a lot of people bringing that specifically up um fire dragon dad says that the season four
update's going to retro into existing uh eternal so see everything we talked about today with the
exception of the iron wolves quest line stuff is actually present in the eternal realm so um players
like the codex power changes everything like that will be there i know there are a lot of questions
related to like the codex changes especially for eternal players and just to clarify if you have aspects
in your inventory and your stash you'll take whatever your highest role of that specific aspect and then
that will become your your new best uh uh codex entry uh when season four does start you may need
to log on to specific characters on eternal uh to at least like for us to be able to check your
inventory but the stash i know will automatically move over there um and same thing for for uh i know
we get a lot of questions about like items on eternal those will be marked as like legacy items specifically
um because obviously we we've changed a lot of aspects and everything and those items you can't
you can't craft on those items either at that point like you can't you can't temper those items and
you can't masterwork those items but they'll still retain like the item upgrade state that they have
in the blacksmith exactly so if you if it doesn't mean like when you log on all your gear is suddenly
unusable it's just it's just marked as legacy and you wouldn't you won't be able to use uh tempering
or masterwork it's a great stepping off point to getting some new items it could have greater
affixes and other things that could be making even more powerful yeah yeah um a question that we
have uh actually from uh the forums this is from iggy uh with the itemization reworked is there uh what
is like the next like big thing you guys are actually looking at uh potentially wanting to uh really work
on within the team uh i don't know if we want to play our cards too early yeah i think it's working on
things we're working on all kinds of stuff everybody but no i i think one thing we want to continue to
work on i think you see like as we're thinking more about the the end game experience a lot like
when we when we launched diablo 4 we thought of end game really as a journey from like really from 50
to 100 like the things you're doing along the way and getting off your preparer on glyphs and leveling
those glyphs up and go diving deeper nightmare dungeons and you know going and eventually confronting
low that was what we kind of imagined or thought that end game would feel like and that was a good
thing for us to build on i think we saw that a lot more players were looking for end game like
explicitly at level 100 that was when they wanted a lot more things to open up and we've made a lot of changes
recently to try to like create more gameplay around that part of the experience between
like the optimization changes and the crafting changes and also the introduction of like
tormented bosses and of course uh the uh the pavio artificer yeah so i think that like we know that
there's more opportunities for us to build on these things right like i think you've heard me say this
before but you know a lot of things we're doing in season four specifically really are done to like
build a new framework you know for how end game sort of functions the the things that drive a player
for the things that get them excited that they and and the content that they engage with along
the way as well right we want to make sure that they're having that players are having a really
fun time or rewarding time while they're playing diablo 4 and they can find opportunities to be
appropriately challenged as they go through the experience as well we think there's more
opportunities for us to kind of like grow and expand uh the offerings of things that players
have access to the things they can go experience you know at that stage of the game awesome uh question
from old dudes new games uh and uh i love these names they're so good um what about codex resetting
when swapping characters that was actually just an issue on ptr um like when you when you swapped
characters and stuff like that sorry yeah when you swaps and you use the uh when you use the boost npc
yeah yeah yeah so that that was not a a thing that you will experience with season four uh and so you
that's not a common thing or a normal thing that's supposed to actually happen uh it just was
a bug that we had in ptr um there's a lot of questions here about um uh the mine cage and i
just want to um maybe clarify with the the the players um opus crocus says if you consume more than
one does the mine cage stack or does the timer reset timer reset i think the timer resets timer resets
okay and then uh in regards to again uh this is from optics uh do cage or do mine cages
trigger for a single player or your whole group if you're grouped up single player just a single
player yeah it's a personal thing okay all right so clarity around the mine cage because i know we've
had a lot of people ask specifically and we want feedback on this by the way too so when you get a
chance to play with the mine cage during the season like you know yeah tell us what you think we want
to know um this is from noopu games uh do unique items get a stat slash functionality boost since
tempered legendaries are just straight up better and is it generally not worth it to equip a unique
item after the patch yeah i mean uh i think adam can speak to some of these changes if you wanted to
jump in but we've done a pass on all the unique items we've done things like uh razor plate i think
has four thorns affixes and we changed what the legendary power is yeah by the way that was a big question we
got from people ptr because they were like hey what about razor plate we heard a lot we had to
change razor plate yeah it'll be cool and it's actually in the patch notes um and yeah it's a lot
of thorns razor plates hilarious we still love it it's hilarious i wanted to just have like one so you
can't miss on masterwork yeah but um yeah what i'll say though about the unique to legendary item power
level i suppose is that we knew when we were making these temporary changes and updating those that
we wanted legendaries because they kind of have a like they have kind of different identities right
now in the game and so we're still figuring out what we want to do with uniques long term but the
idea is that like legendary items or items really they have a journey and you know you're you're working
on them and there's a story to them and you know you get it it's not like a one-stop shop you're done
kind of like how they were before uniques a part of our identity is that that like you know you get a
unique and it's freaking awesome and really powerful and very exciting and and you have it and you're done with
it and so we're we're keeping this discrepancy of like what their purposes are in the game for now
um and kind of seeing how it goes we did take a look at some uniques but we didn't like do a whole
pass of like you know every single unique now has five outfixes or something like that like we wanted
them to be a little bit different and different identities so we do kind of expect that uniques may
be less prevalent than they were before we still believe though that a lot of uniques are really key for
various builds and so you're still going to want them but you're not going to want like a unique in
every single slot on your character now because there's clearly always better right sometimes
some builds will want more unique some will want less and we want to kind of see how that plays
first before making sweeping changes um you know some obvious roads we could take is like adding
crafting to uniques what if you could temper them what if you can do these other things right like
we know that that's a thing and we may do that in the future but we're kind of evaluating this world
where it's not clearly always you only get one or the other and we kind of want to see how that goes
first uh before making any big changes yeah and the fixed nature sort of has you consider it's
part of your optimization puzzle yeah like well i'm going to give up some tempering affixes to get
this unique for example in in my chess slot for example we sort of want to see where that goes like
we think that that's that's fun and um we think that the excitement of a unique is is the are those
fixed stats when you see the item on the ground you know like oh okay that's that's the unique i want
i can just equip it i don't even have to work on it yeah it's just like there for me so um awesome
and then i know by the way did we talk about uh master working or not mass working we did talk
we've done it twice on youtube did we talk about groups and uh with the pit i didn't write it down
and i didn't talk about it yeah yeah yeah so we we got a bunch of feedback um that you know it sucks to
help someone with their pit run and just not get any master working material it's like well
why am i here um so what we've done is we've made it so that the person who opens the pit is going to
get 100 of the master working materials previously i think it was uh split maybe across all players
and what we've done now is that the person who opens it gets 100 and then everyone who helps
defeat the pit gets 50 of that target goal so we're trying to walk that line where group play isn't
just like totally overwhelmingly efficient but you're still getting something for helping each
other like go through those pit levels yeah we we heard a lot of feedback about players going like
that feels a little unrewarding to yeah and so there were some changes in general there i think there's
still some tension with how players feel about the efficiency of groups which is the efficiency of
solo play with like boss summons and things like that these are things we're thinking about we have
ideas on but we want to continue to get feedback particularly with these changes and kind of see how
things play out absolutely awesome um we're getting questions about you know hey are there any updates on social
features and and things like that coming to to d4 um don't know if we have anything to share right
now right it's it's something obviously that team is very well you guys ask all the time so we and we're
very very aware of it um and the team is is been looking at it and once we have more to share we'll end up
sharing it with you guys but for right now we don't have any update yeah um it there's questions about it is
is there if there's plans of adding maybe potential leaderboards to the pit or anything or or is that
going to be something that's just exclusively on the gauntlet um i think the idea of adding leaderboards
other types of content over time makes sense could be pretty fun you know but uh right now we really
want to see how the pit plays on its own uh the you know the um trials feature on and challenge ladder
like we really want that to be a place where players can or the other guys really want players to be able
to like go and compete in a very fixed environment a very extremely fair environment which is like the
what we really prioritize part of the release um the pit is pretty variable run to run so that makes
it a little more complicated it doesn't mean that we would never add it i think that there's a clear
indicator that there's it would be pretty fun to have this slightly looser leaderboard associated
with a feature like this yeah yeah but we're gonna see how things play out and we'll be we'll be
thinking about how we can add more competitive features like that to the game over time um question from
elro here and i didn't pronounce that right but uh uh uh when i wrote here i think that is actually yeah nailed it
uh it's like an elven time right now not since not everyone actually experienced ptr because ptr itself
was on pc battle net but uh they're asking when tempering can you keep previous roles can you keep
previous roles oh like the enchanting system oh i see yeah yeah currently right now we don't have the
functionality to let you keep the rule right now if you're going to commit to re-rolling you're going
to lose that you're committing to rolling yeah it's sort of like the blacksmith is hammering on that item
and unlocking different aspects of the weapon you sort of lose what you previously had but we're
open to feedback right it's completely new feature really want to hear how it's playing and then
ultimately what we want is a fun crafting feature so if uh you know that that sort of feedback is really
valuable uh we'll take two more and one is from matt lol is uh temporary going to allow changes for the
skills uh the skill type like maybe lightning hydras or maybe changes to blizzard where it's a rain of fire
or something like that that's pretty cool honestly anything an apex can do yeah it is open season
of things we could potentially do in the future yeah not not in season four but you know possibly in
the future awesome um and i this is actually from a lot of space to grow there is utility is a category
we can yeah there's a lot of things potentially yeah yeah um there's a lot of questions in here about like
additional character customization options and stuff like that coming in the future it is like something
the team is always looking at adding additional things to for players to have more choice of what
they want to do especially as they're creating characters um and of course uh being able to obtain
those like even just some things in season four of being able to get additional you know cosmetic
things for your mount and everything like that is something that uh the the team is most definitely
looking yeah we we actually we care about this a great deal um i think one thing that's very interesting
uh about uh diablo 4 or a problem that we have that's very specific right is um there are actually
quite a few cosmetics for players to earn out on bosses and things like throughout the game like
there's there's lots of things for players to collect cosmetically in the game um but it's really hard to
know that that drops off that thing yeah in diablo 4 like you can go and you could fight like a world
boss 50 times and not have a uh a drop occur for you right like then eventually get your special horse
like oh okay it is here but you have no idea it's kind of like it's harder to know exactly where to grind we're actually
talking about that a bit on the uh on the dev side see if like there's more ways we can kind of like
make it clear where certain things can be found which i think would be really fun yeah uh but i
think that there's work we can do there and also there's still work we can do about just trying to
get more cool looks into the game so we've been talking a lot more with the various teams inside
inside diablo 4 and there's a broad agreement we want to bring more cool stuff to you guys and more
cool stuff for players to find and and pick up and equip and feel like it was really exciting to get that thing
uh one thing we're doing like already is we're like as we develop more uniques we're trying to make sure we have
like more unique appearances to go with all of them we usually have like a lot of really really fun ideas
we have what we have to constantly like wrestle with like all right we we only have like this x x many swords
but like we have like this many ideas for swords and we want to try to get this in the game we want to wait
till we have the artwork for a sword we will usually try to make sure we've got a fun toy to immediately give you
uh but we're going to make sure we're trying to get more of that stuff in game as well so there's just even more
artwork to the unique system for players to collect awesome so that's all the time we got right here
for today um we have we went over all the changes or not actually there's even more changes there's
actually more changes in the patch notes uh we can't go through every single line in the patch notes
over a stream so you guys can actually check out the patch notes uh those will be available on
diablo4.com we always have those listed on our specific patch notes page and those will be live
immediately after this stream season four loot reborn starts on may 14th this is across all
platforms it's on pc xbox playstation and of course if you're an xbox and pc game pass user you can
also uh play diablo 4 now uh via pc battle net or on your xbox so yeah lots of opportunities to play
and of course steam steam can't forget steam steam is also on there for pc that's also a platform that is
also a platform we're everywhere any other platforms you want to shout out uh we're everywhere oh all
right everywhere just everywhere um but uh again thanks to everyone for tuning in uh we're looking
forward to you guys jumping into season four loot reborn uh and uh yeah we'll we'll see you guys um
in in game and thanks again yeah okay guys
sak für
Transcription by CastingWords