I'm going to go to the next room.
You've been saying this whole time that Hell is Gumble.
Now Hell is Here.
Something that's always present in a Diablo title
and we wanted to make sure that 50th Diablo IV
returning to Hell was a special moment.
We referenced the end game cinematic
with Prave and Enorious taking the fight
to Hell at the end of the game.
We really wanted to capture that experience.
that sensation of battling throngs of demons and hell.
In the Infernal Ports, they're going to go into this mode, battle waves of demons,
and be able to kind of change the shape of the game experience as you play.
Those of you who have joined a synth space game and throughout the seasons will have noticed
that we have this phenomenon in the world that's going on called Hell Tides.
Some of you might have noticed that Hell Tides have been getting a lot worse lately,
and now Hell is able to pierce the veil that's holding hell back from fully invading sanctuary
and starting to take root in sanctuary.
And we started by asking ourselves some questions.
What is the state of sanctuary right before the vessel of hatred happens?
How has Hell changed now that Mephisto isn't there anymore?
What are the demons up to?
Where is Mephisto?
Does he have anything to do with this?
Or is this just hell rising of its own accord as the prophecy proclaimed?
And so we thought to ourselves, how can we make things even worse for the people in sanctuary?
In this season, you'll very much get to dive into those mysteries with some unlikely allies
and really get to the bottom of what's happening.
So in this season, we play a lot with the notion of the enemy of my enemy as my friend.
How far would you go to save sanctuary, to save your world?
What price would you pay?
Would you sacrifice your soul for this?
You're going to meet a guy named Lockrin, who at first seems sort of usual,
but you're going to quickly realize that something is off, that something is a little strange with this guy.
So Lockrin and Estelle are your allies, and they're going to help you return to hell.
Both of them are experts and demons, and they're going to use that knowledge to help you return to hell
and become more powerful to be able to battle the infernal hordes.
The infernal hordes is a new endgame activity in Diablo IV.
It's primarily a wave-based activity. You're going to be fighting a wave after wave with demon
forces in hell. So if any of you have ever played wave-based gameplay before, you'll know that things
escalate. We've got meteor strikes and all sorts of things that try to keep you on your toes.
One thing the infernal hordes does differently is the notion of infernal offers.
In between each wave, you'll make a choice. You'll be granted an infernal offer,
and by choosing one of three of these offers, you're going to change the game mode in some way,
a positive and a negative. You can imagine from the depths of hell these hands rise out,
and offer you both a boon and a bane. A kiss and a curse.
And this is a temptation that the Fell Council is making to you. And in this temptation,
you're offered more power, but that power comes at a cost. And so you get to choose, you know,
which temptations you're going to pursue during your infernal run, and then customize your
experience from there. One of the guiding principles of this game mode is replay. It's an in-game
mode that we want to make sure you're playing over and over again. So we really wanted to create
a broad set of enemies for you to fight during this mode. We've got many demons to choose from
and the lexicon of Diablo's monster families, but we're also going to see some other foes you might
not expect. There are going to be certain types of enemies like goat men who have been banished to
hell that have now rallied to Mephisto and fight by his side. And even some unlucky souls that marched
on hell from the cathedral of light have now been revived and hell and fight against you alongside
the demons. Basically, everything that hell has to throw at you, we're throwing it at you this
season. The infernal hordes has been built with multiplayer in mind, but multiplayer is not required.
We want to make sure that solo players still have a very fun experience in the infernal hordes.
Now that said, if you roll in with a party, you're going to have a lot of fun. This game mode is
going to appear in the eternal and in the seasonal realm, and that means that once the season is over,
it's here to stay. The infernal hordes is unlocked at World Tier 3, so really what you need to do
to access it is earn your way up to World Tier 3 and then complete an eternal questline that
takes you back to hell and then unlocks the infernal hordes. For World Tier 1 and 2 players,
we've built out a seasonal progression that will help them become more powerful in order to be
able to confront the infernal hordes. First is you can earn reputation, and that reputation
applies to a reputation track that earns lots of really cool rewards that'll make you more
powerful as you progress onto World Tier 3. The other thing we've built are micro dungeons called
Hell breaches that offer a glimpse at the infernal hordes mechanics, and they give you a chance to
learn the mechanics before you confront the infernal hordes at World Tier 3. The final boss in
this season is the fel council. And the fel council is some familiar faces that you might recognize from
Diablo 2. These were priests of the Zachary Room, holy men who were corrupted and basically became
vessels of hatred in their own right. The council members in Diablo 2 tried to help contain
Mephisto in his soul stone, and of course Mephisto being Mephisto slowly but surely corrupted them,
and eventually they had soul stones pierced into their hands and became super powerful. But eventually
you overcame them and sent them to hell. Through the course of the story resummoned them,
they've been reborn, slightly new powers, but the same animosity toward you. What's interesting
about this boss encounter is there five council members, but you're only going to fight three of them at once.
This allows us to then create many different flavors of the boss fight for the fel council. In fact,
it's about 10 variations at all. And so every time you go into that council fight, there's a very good
chance you're going to have a different fight than the last time you played. We think it's going to
offer a lot of replay for players. What we also introduced during these waves are opportunities for
you to earn ether. Earning ether is the resource that you gather during the infernal hordes,
that you can then spend at the end of the activity. There's going to be a fixed number of waves
you have to defeat, and once you've completed all those waves, then you'll face the fel council to
feed them and collect your treasure. So upon defeating the fel council, the spoils of hell will spawn,
and then you consume your burning ether and opening those chests. Now, the trick is when you are
playing through these waves, that's your opportunity to earn as much ether as you can. Different events
are going to spawn all throughout the waves around the periphery of the arena, and it's your job to
try and defeat as many of those events as possible to try and gather up all the ether you can't.
Really skilled players are going to be able to really maximize that ether so they get the biggest
payout possible at the end after defeating the fel council. So with this burning ether, you'll be
able to get new uniques, you'll be able to get new legendaries, you'll be able to get rare materials,
things you might have scoured the whole sanctuary for in previous seasons are in the base game,
but now we offer it to you here down in the depths of hell. A lot of these new uniques and legendaries
really build on top of this idea that they've been forged in hell, and so they're going to have
unique looks that you can then make into cosmetics to apply wherever you like. They can also have
unique VFX and sound effects to really create the sense that they were forged in hell. One particular
one that I enjoy using a lot are boots. Boots, you say. Well, these boots not only have been forged
in hell, whenever you use a power with a cooldown, they shoot out a ring of fire that hits everyone
around you. That's just one sample of the types of powers we're exploring.
So death in the infernal hordes is quite a big deal. You're returning to the realm of hatred,
where Mephisto is born, like this has to be a big deal. In the infernal hordes, it's a lot like
nightmare dungeons. You only get a fixed number of revives in order to be able to get to the end of
your run. So at lower difficulties in the infernal hordes, you'll get a number of revives shared
between your party. But at higher difficulty levels, the game is going to start taking away those
revives and that increases the stakes that you have. You die too much, you'll be ejected from the
load. In the infernal hordes, we created a lot of new ways for monsters to ambush the players,
and so I'm pretty stoked to see how our players respond to these. The seasonal quest line and
the eternal quest line, they have lots of little surprises and twists and turns in them,
and there's even some surprises we've buried deep within the infernal hordes that hopefully players
will have a great time.
Hello everyone and welcome to our season of the infernal hordes developer update stream.
My name is Marcus Krets, I'm a community manager here on the Diablo team,
and today I'm joined by some very familiar faces, Adam and Adam, welcome to the stream.
Yeah, we did it. We did it over. We did it over.
We did it over. It's just Adam and he's the Adam and Adam show.
Now I don't even have the host.
Yeah, I don't feel like it feels great.
Yeah, and for everyone, curious and chat, Adam is not going anywhere.
As you all know, there's a ton going on in Diablo. Yeah, Adam Fletcher is going.
This one, the Adam Jacks. I have the Adam Hunter.
There's a ton going on in Diablo right now. We've had a ton of live streams. There's been
so much going on, so it's just a lot easier to share the load amongst all the other.
Yeah, we just finished this very born live stream, so it's a little crazy.
Marcus is here to help out. You guys may see Marcus more here,
hosting some live streams in the future, but yeah, I'm not disappearing.
Yeah, Adam is pulling today.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, today I get to pretend I'm calling.
That's a pretty excited about that.
Some big, big shoes to fill there.
Yeah, that is absolutely true.
In terms of everything that's been going on in Diablo, we just had our season in the Infernal
Horde's PTR, and we got a lot of learnings.
Yeah, we, but we also do have one additional person.
Of course we do.
Mr. Dan Dangway from Albany, New York.
Dan, look at the stream.
Hey, how's everyone doing?
Doing great.
Good to see you.
See, Dan's in like the Cathedral of Light, or in the Burning House.
Yeah, yeah, it's perfect.
It's hot over here, exactly.
It tracks.
Yeah.
Thanks for joining us today, Dan.
And the season five PTR.
We've got a lot of learnings.
This was our second PTR for Diablo IV.
So we have a ton of feedback to get into, but we also have some notes from the community
on the PTR overall and some learning.
So Adam, do you want to walk us through that?
Yeah, most definitely.
You know, this is now our second PTR that we had.
We had one for season four, and of course one now for season five.
And we've learned a lot from these PTR.
PTR is an incredibly important,
they're huge, they're really beneficial for the whole entire team here.
And one thing we heard a lot of feedback, at least from the season five PTR,
is obviously, as you're playing through a PTR,
it's a non-final thing that you're playing.
It's still very early on.
There are going to be more bugs, more issues,
just present in the PTR because we are getting something out there a little bit earlier,
just so we can get feedback in on it.
But one thing that I think we most definitely heard from the community is,
hey, the tools within PTR at times haven't been the best for the most efficient
for players that need to actually test the content that we actually do have.
And so one thing that we did want to at least address and highlight and acknowledge is that,
you know, we do plan on making the PTR experiences better in the future.
We do plan on equipping more tools for players out there.
So they're not having to sit there and grind out, you know,
maybe like all the new legendaries are unique or something.
Especially in like season five, for example, we gave a character copy of the future in this one.
And then of course, we had the boost feature which came back from season four.
And when you boosted your character, a new character,
you would end up getting some of the new legendaries or unique within season five.
What happened though is that it wasn't all of them.
And then we had players within season five having to actually go out and spend their time that
they probably could be testing other things, like trying to find those items.
And obviously that's like not the most efficient thing to do.
So we do want to, we hear everyone, we acknowledge it.
We do want to make the PTR experience better.
So I will say that like in future PTRs and you'll see this gradually over over the next couple of PTRs,
it won't be all of a sudden, like things will be completely different.
But I do expect like and players should expect like that we will have better tools for them
to properly test as we gradually go through PTRs in the future.
And we appreciate everyone like letting us know.
And we must definitely hear you guys.
And we most definitely want to make that experience better from that.
But PTR has been great.
Huge thanks to everyone for jumping in and checking it out for sure.
Yeah, definitely.
Yeah, that feedback is so important.
So, you know, increasing how great these PTRs are is really, really important.
And I know for the season five PTR, one of the huge features that we had in there was the
Infernal Hords itself.
So for everyone who didn't get a chance to jump into the PTR, Mr. Dan Tangue,
can you kind of walk us through what the Infernal Hords is and what players can expect?
Yeah, absolutely.
I'll give you all a quick recap.
So the Infernal Hords is a wave-based activity with
your luck choices in between each of those waves.
So, imagine waves of monsters coming in, lots and lots of monsters.
In fact, and you also have some events, many events that you can also participate in.
Now, in between those waves, you're going to be making what's called the Infernal offer.
And you're going to pick a Boon or a Bane, and that's going to change your gameplay
for the rest of the run.
So it allows you to customize what your Infernal run is going to be like.
And so we probably see right here, yep, we've got an Infernal offer that comes up.
So you're going to select one of those, and that will then change, of course, the rest of the run.
Now, when you complete the required number of waves, then you're able to go
confront the Fell Council, who you can see here.
And the Fell Council, as you saw from the video that just came on right before this live stream,
are former servants, well, actually current servants of Mifisto, that you defeated in Diablo 2,
and have now returned, and you must fight them once more.
And once you beat them, you're going to be able to spawn what's called the spoils of hell.
And these are chests that contain a lot of great goodies.
And so with that burning aether, you've been collecting all through the course of the mode.
You're able to choose what kind of spoils you want.
You've got a spoils of legendaries and yeaks.
And there's some absolutely great new yeaks and legendaries in season five.
And you can probably farm about half of them, over half of them from the Infernal Orts.
You're also able to spawn spoils of materials and buy into that.
And that will get you gem shards that will get you angels breath.
And of course, that'll get you master working materials, which you absolutely need to complete your items journey.
You can also cash out and get a bunch of gold, which for those folks who are re-rolling their items
in order to master work them, or to enchant their items, is going to be hugely beneficial.
And then finally, there's a special bonus chest at higher tiers, where you can get a guaranteed roll
on a greater affix item. And so since that's one of the main chases in the, you know, the final steps
of the end game, you know, we wanted to make sure there was an opportunity for players to really,
you know, get a little more lucky with it.
So final thoughts on the Infernal Orts.
Remember that at Unlocks at World Tier 3, you need an Infernal Compass in order to unlock it.
And there's eight levels of difficulty for it.
And so yeah, that's a quick recap.
Awesome. Thanks for walking us through Dan.
Super excited to jump in and try to grab some of those uniques.
Now I know considering the Infernal Orts was such a big part of PTR,
we did have a lot of community feedback with regards to, you know, getting into the mode,
you know, some of the pacing. So can you walk us through some of those learnings we had
based off the PTR feedback?
Oh, absolutely. So there was a lot of feedback that came in and so much so that we weren't able to
address it all. But we did distill down some big trends and feedback that we were able to tackle.
And so the first off is that we wanted to improve access to the Infernal Orts.
So yeah, it was just too hard to get into the mode regularly to test it.
And folks wanted to get into it very quickly. Couldn't get into it either.
So we pretty much overhauled access to the Infernal Orts at this point.
Compuses still exist, but the drop rates on those have been boosted quite a bit.
We want you to earn around four or five compasses an hour so that you can do about four or five
hours runs per hour. So you've got, you know, 50% chance to get them from item chest and
health hides. Unless it's one of those item chests that costs, you know, 250 senders in which case,
that's 100% chance. I mean, you put in the time. We'll just give it to you.
And then, you know, nightmare dungeon and whispers, there's about a 75% chance to getting,
get one from a dungeon complete there. You know, compass tiers at really high levels.
We wanted to make sure drop naturally from high tiered activities like nightmare dungeons and the pet.
And we've also given you a path to just crafting these outright with the occultus,
with sigilpower and forgotten souls. And then finally, you know, it was a bug that the first
compass that dropped from the eternal quest, it was actually a world tier three. And if you were playing
world tier four, sorry, world tier four, yeah, yeah, just switch back to actually get in the infernal
hordes and that didn't feel great. So we updated that as well. Moving along, the next big thing that
we focused on was combat. The pacing of combat wasn't hitting our goals. And, you know, we had
done a lot of internal testing on it. And, you know, folks who weren't as in game focused gave us a
lot of feedback where, you know, oh, this is super intense. Could we dial it back a little bit?
So we did. But then we put it out on PTR and clearly all said, hey, no, we want more. So we're
giving you more. The first thing that we did though is we fixed some bugs that actually had a
really big impact on the experience. There was a boss, a boss health bug. Man, that is hard to say,
boss health bug that caused all the bosses to be super tanky. And at tier eight, there were some
folks who were spending almost an hours worth of time in the infernal's hord. And that just,
that's not what we wanted. So we fixed those bugs and retuned everything. So, you know, it's a much
tighter experience at this point. Similarly, there was a bug where difficulty wasn't scaling
appropriate in multiplayer. So we fixed that. And then some tuning things. So the pace of many events
are pretty much rapid fire at high tiers now, you know. And so you're going to be spending a lot
of plates in this mode. The monster spawn rates have also been increased to, you know, really capture
that feeling of being overwhelmed. And then finally, we reduced the wave timer down to 60 seconds,
which, you know, just creates a much punchier experience for players and of course, retuned everything.
And then on top of that, we said, you know what? Let's just make it easier for players to pick up
burning a third and increase that pace. So the pets now pick up the burning aether as well.
And that's not all. Now, of course, you know, we're all playing this for the rewards, right?
And so it was really important for us to improve rewards across the board. You spend time with
the mode you want to be rewarded appropriately and we weren't hitting that mark in the PTR.
So we raised the minimum amount of burning aether earned from any single run. First off,
every single source of aether got boosted by one aether. And then we added aether drops to the
fel council so that you're also getting, you know, a lot of bang for your buck just by defeating the
boss as well. And that actually scales per tier as well. Next up, we retuned all the costs of
the spoils of hell. So, you know, the greater equipment that one with the greater effects in it,
used to cost 250. Now it only costs 60. Similarly, we retuned the spoils of equipment and the
spoils of materials. So now they only cost 28 or a piece. And then finally, we retuned all the
rewards that were inside, you know, the the chest as well. So, you know, at your bare minimum level,
when you first start playing the infernal hordes and you're not sure exactly how it works,
we still want you to feel rewarded just for the time that you invest it. And so the rewards at
that bare minimum feel pretty good now. But, you know, if you are spending a lot of time with it,
you know how to optimize this mode. We wanted to make sure that, you know, the rewards reflected that
too. So that that higher, you know, ceiling of rewards has been raised as well. So you're playing
at tier eight, you are going to get significantly more rewards than you would at tier one.
Awesome. Yeah, that's nice. Quite a bit. That's a lot of stuff that I just want to call it. Dan,
your shirt is amazing. I was thinking around, but I didn't want to. Now I dig into that shirt.
And I'm very jealous that I don't actually own that shirt. So, yeah, I think after this stream,
yeah, I think someone on the team made it. So I was like, I needed a new shirt for the livestream.
So that is her art 100%. Yeah, yeah. Now we know. And now I know. And it is totally awesome. I
had to wait. Yeah. I totally know. We will be touching base out of the stream. Yeah. Dan,
that's a ton of changes. It sounds like we're really cranking up the intensity for the infernal hordes.
Really, really cool to see. Super excited to jump into it. So I know for the infernal hordes,
that's one part of the season that's coming. But there was a lot that players didn't get to
experience in the PTR that will be coming with the season. So can you kind of share what's going
to be new for players coming into season five? Yeah, absolutely. So the PTR was really focused on
features that were on both the eternal realm and the seasonal realm. And we have a number of
seasonal exclusive features that y'all haven't had a chance to play with yet. So we're going to
tell you about them now. First up, we've got the seasonal progression. So you're going to see
what we call the reputation system and some footage here in just a second. And the reputation
system is something that we had in season four and actually earlier in some events. And we've
brought it back here because it serves as a great backbone for the season. And we've evolved it
in some significant ways. So first off, how you earn reputation is a bit different now.
It was really important for us in season five to give you more choice in how you wanted to earn
your reputation. So previously in season four, you earn reputation through just playing
health hides as you should because we made a lot of improvements to health hides in season four.
But here we wanted to broaden it out a bit more. So you earn reputation in season five
by just defeating powerful servants of hell, elites, hellborne champions, bosses, so on and so forth.
Right. And so that gives you a lot more choice to say, hey, you know, I can earn reputation in
health hides or I want to earn it in the infernal hordes. Or honestly, I want to take a break and do
a stronghold. You'll get reputation there too. Another small tweak that we made that's pretty
important is that when you pick up reputation, you actually get a small boost and XP as well.
So as you're continually filling out your reputation track, you're starting to level up just a little
more quickly than you did before. Now, another thing that you might have seen are these big green
tiles in the reputation system. And those are seasonal quests. So we made it very clear that
hitting certain tiers of your reputation system now unlocked the seasonal quests. And it actually
starts to weave the narrative through the progression a bit more, which we really like the feel of
and we hope to build on in the future. And then finally, you know, again, it's all about the rewards,
right. So there's lots of great returning rewards in the reputation system. You're going to be able to
earn, you know, unique specifically class-based uniques that are going to help you figure out what
you want your build to be early on in the season. You're also going to be able to get other powerful
equipment, big drops of crafting materials, and of course, at the very end of the reputation track
will be a resplendent spark that you can use to ultimately craft a mythic unique.
Next up, we've got the seasonal quest line. You know, I was teasing it up a little bit with the
reputation system there. So the season of the Infernal Horde has a rather unique narrative flow
because we have an eternal quest line that introduces, you know, a big new feature that takes you
back to hell, right. And so we wanted to make sure that was available to everybody, not just
seasonal players. And that also starts at World Tier 3. Now, those of you who played the PTR have
already seen it. That's the one that features Locrine helping you to get back to hell and confront
the Infernal Horde. But we've developed an additional secondary, well, not really secondary, an
additional seasonal quest line named of lambs and wolves, which we're kind of teasing right here.
And new NPC name Estelle is guiding you to become more powerful before you join Locrine to
journey back to hell. Now, this one's going to be a little closer and tone to the iron wolf's
quest in season 4, but it's going to be a bit more expansive than that. And like I said,
it weaves in and out of the seasonal progression. So how do they relate to one another? Well, the
seasonal quest line is exclusive to season 5. And so you are able to get a really more complete
picture of the story by playing both the seasonal quest line and the eternal quest line.
You can kind of think of the seasonal quest line as almost like a prequel to you unlocking the
Infernal Horde. And, but we also wanted to make sure that our Eternal players don't get left out.
This is an Eternal Mode that we're introducing after all with the Infernal Horde. And so, you know,
the Infernal or rather the Eternal Quest line here, which is named Eyes of the Enemy, is going to
be available for all players and won't go away after the season ends. So it's going to be there
forever. So if you decide sometime down the road that you want to check out the Infernal Hordes
and say, I don't know, season 6, you can do that, right? And so, yeah, that's where we ended up with
the quest lines, the season. And then the final thing I want to introduce are the Hellbreach Dungeons,
which I've gotten a few teases of before, but we can go into more detail here. So these are all
new micro dungeons to show that Hell is started taking root in Sanctuary. Now, since the Infernal Hordes
is an end game activity, World Tier 3 Plus, we wanted to make sure we had some content that targeted
our World Tier 1 and 2 players. And so you go into these, it's going to be a great source of
reputation. It's going to be a great place to get some powerful items. And it's a pretty cool
place to just kind of experience what the gameplay is going to be like down the road. Now, originally,
we had kind of pattern these off the Donheim tunnels, if you all remember those. But with the
introduction of Hal Tide in season 4, we had to change it up a little bit because I don't think
that alone would have sufficed. And so what we did is we pulled in a lot of elements from the
Infernal Hordes. And we're using this as an opportunity to introduce those elements. So you see
right here, we've got a simple Infernal choice that shows that basically says, okay, do I want my
boss to be a little simpler or a little more difficult? And you get to choose. Hopefully the person
playing chose the more difficult one I didn't see. But you're going to be rewarded a lot more
for taking that risk of making the boss more difficult. And you're going to be earning burning
ather in it. The end, there are going to be some spoils that you can spend on. And like I said,
you'll get some really powerful gear that should help you on your journey toward encountering the
Infernal Hordes. So if you want more details on these, I recommend that you check out our blog that
came out two days ago. And yeah, thank you. Dan, that's awesome. I got to say, Chat got pretty
excited when you mentioned Domain Tunnels. They kind of blew up there. Definitely, definitely
a fantasy of everyone remembers the Dopa mean tunnels. Yeah, right. And it's great that there's now
like opportunities for players within like, Walter one and two to actually be able to have other
options involving up and with these new help reaches it's good way for people to tease in.
Exactly. Yeah. Then you get into those Infernal Hordes in
Walter three enough away you go. Yeah, that's awesome. Dan, thanks so much for joining us.
As Dan had mentioned, we did publish the season the Infernal Hordes blog a little bit earlier this
week. We are going to have patch notes that will publish following the stream. So for any details
we reveal across the stream, you can check those out for more information. Dan's going to join us
towards the end of the stream for our Q&A. So if you have any questions, please drop those in Twitch
chat and we'll be pulling them to get into those towards the end of the stream. So we just touched
on a ton of stuff that's coming in season the Infernal Hordes itself. But based off the PTR,
we also have a ton of changes coming across sanctuary. Yes. And to walk us through from the other
end of the stream, Mr. Adam Funcher. Yeah, I get to pretend like I'm the person on the panel.
I'm going to you just like to do all this. Yeah. Exactly. Put in all the changes. We have a fantastic
design team here and I am going to bring in my inner column finer to talk about some stuff.
But yes, as Mark has mentioned, there's a lot of changes. A lot of the stuff that we actually did
talk about in the blog and some of the stuff that people heard from PTR. But there have been changes
even since PTR. And we have a few new things in here that we'll also squeak in here as we're
talking about it. But one big topic I know that everyone brought up after PTR and that we even
brought up even during our PTR stream was held tied specifically. One big topic within a held
ties was Bainful Hearts. If you guys remember back during the PTR stream, we talked about how
season four everyone had a plethora of Bainful Hearts. I mean, it felt like everyone was always
carrying about 100 to 150 at any given time. And you can deposit as many into your hearts desire
and still always have that same amount. We want painful hearts to feel a little bit more special.
And so during the PTR, we actually did take the number down in terms of how many you would be
able to earn. We did hear everyone's feedback. People were like, that feels kind of crappy.
We most definitely readjusted the drop rate of Bainful Hearts to really kind of close that gap
in between season four and season five PTR. We wanted to make sure that was, you know,
it feels better. Like you won't have 150 on you at all times most likely, but you still have
plenty now to be able to summon the maiden as well. So some of the changes that we have coming up
for Bainful Hearts and the rate that will help with this is that we're bumping up the drop rates
off of chess within held ties specifically. Players will also be able to get a guaranteed
hard drop off of Hell-Tie commanders now. And then one big thing is within World Bosses,
yeah, we actually have an image of where you'll be able to now get your hard drop rates guaranteed
is World Bosses. Sometimes World Bosses actually do spawn within a held tied zone. And we thought
it would be kind of cool that, you know, a killed the World Boss there and a held tied happened
to be present in that specific zone where the World Bosses. Now you'll just get a guaranteed
three within that World Boss cut, which is kind of nice. That's super cool. We're also bumping up
the drop chance to like local events, mastery chess within held tied, and of course, Harbingers
within it as well. And then one big change that we're doing within this as well is the Blood Maiden
within World Tier 1 and 2 in season 4 and even season 5 PTR, you would have to deposit three hearts
just like World Tier 3 and World Tier 4. We're actually tweaking that down to just two. So
for World Tier 1 and 2. So there'll be one less like Ultra Pedestool for you to deposit a heart for
for to some of the Blood Maiden within World Tier 1 and 2, which should help out with, you know.
Just makes your farming a little bit quicker in the early levels. Exactly. Exactly. And it doesn't
feel like you're needing to put in that many for those earlier levels. That's much easier to change
in ton of blood mains back to back to back. Exactly. Yeah. So next thing we did want to talk about is
within held ties as Tortured Gifts, another change for World Tier 1 and 2, there'll be less
senders required to open up the Tortured Gift Chess within World Tier 1 and 2. So it's dropping
from 100 to 75 specifically. And then this is something we talked about in the last ring where it
was like really difficult for players to actually kind of go through a held tied and complete,
you know, a full on like, you know, trio whispers like progression line within held tied.
So now you'll actually be able to earn all 10 grim favors within a held tied for sure
when it's in one subzone. And actually deposit that within the trio whispers and get the
root that the whisper cash out of it. I know sometimes it would take like people, sometimes two
held ties actually do it. Or you would have to leave the held tied and go to a non held tied
zone kind of finish it off and stuff. And so we wanted to make sure that was more efficient
specifically within held ties. And then this was a big thing. Big one. So you know, we talked about
during the season five PTR stream that we were that profane mind cages were a season form
mechanic. It was it was only were not. Yeah. And so it was it was removed from from season five,
heard the feedback. And people were like, wow, we really missed mind cages, bring them back,
what's going on. So we did bring them back and we brought them back in like a cooler form. So
now you can actually stack up. So one profane mind cages are coming back for season five.
You can actually stack these now up to three X in season five. This is season only. So this
is only on the the seasonal realm specifically. But now stacking up to three X does actually boost up
monster rules. Yeah. So you'll end up you could knock monster levels up, you know,
30 levels if you wanted to. And you will benefit or maybe suffer. But it does give players
the option now to use that. And so profane mind cages are back and in a kind of a cooler form
for season five. And we really appreciate the feedback we heard from players regarding held
ties on that. Next overall just general game updates that we do have. One big thing that we're
doing is we are boosting legendary drop rates off of really pretty much almost like all
most content like held ties and your dungeons and frontal hordes for any monster that is level
100 or higher. So you'll be able to see and just obtain more legendaries that way. Less rare
things like that. Separately enchanting one big thing we heard is, you know, people were some
you know blocked a little bit with angels breath. And so we did remove angels breath as a cost
towards enchanting. It's no longer required. We've actually now kind of just swapped this over to
the respective legendary salvage. So for instance, armor would be coiling awards weapons,
balehole fragments and then jewelry, upstruced sigils sigils that tongue twister there.
Upstruced sigils. Upstruced sigils. But you now have the ability of being able to do enchanting.
Just note that of course, gold costs are still associated with enchanting. But now it's a little bit
removing a little bit of that friction with the angels breath requirement. And then this is
something that we had talked about beforehand, which is just crowd control overall within season 5
is me a lot better. I know crowd control can be sometimes painful or you know knock down.
Yeah, here knock down and frozen for a million years. It's cruel and then dying horribly.
And so CC duration has been essentially just pretty much reduced like across the board to like
1.5 seconds max. And then one cool feature is you can also spam potions now while you're CC'd.
Really good for like like you know people on hardcore or like maybe it's like it creates more
desperate moments of like I'm still dying. But you now have the ability of being able to spam
potions specifically if you are CC'd which is really nice. Yeah, we were talking about like
and charging like bloated course fans when they like to stun you and they do the poison aoe
as a as a keyboard slammer myself. Thank you. Yes, exactly.
Next update we have is world bosses. So, uh,
finding enough, uh, this actually fell into season 5 ptr but that we forgot to actually put it
in season 5 ptr notes nor are no and we actually forgot to actually mention it. We got a lot
of reports of people going like, Hey, why are world bosses like tankier harder than hell?
To fight back down. Yeah, we had a lot of post-toilets.
Uh, so they actually had a feature called resilience on there. Essentially resilience,
uh, normalizes damage across like all world content. So it's like if you share world content.
So like if a bunch of people are all coming into a world boss you're, you should expect to find
that the world bosses will be a little bit more tankier, a little bit longer in terms of the
experience that you're having as you're, you're fighting against them. Yeah. Um, uh, and less,
you know, like, Hey, I blinked and it's gone. Yeah. Oh, sweet. The boss was here for three seconds.
Nice. Yeah, exactly. So, they barely even spawn in. No, no, no, it was actually present in ptr and
we actually got a lot of people that were going like, Hey, I think this is a bug and it actually
wasn't a bug. It was just a feature for you. We forgot to actually mention, uh, in the, in the
patch and so that is our bad, but we do want to make sure that everyone's aware that we have
bosses now have a feature called resilience and that will end up helping out with those encounters
specifically separately for bosses. Um, Pit Boss damage has been reduced pretty much across the
board. Um, and then one big thing that we did want to call out is, uh, we, we got a lot of feedback
within, you know, um, season four and, and of course the ptr for season five, uh, we, we, we,
well, we saw some people, uh, address the changes that we were having there. Um, but Pit Boss has had,
uh, this tendency within season four to have like very sharp damage, yeah, uh, where it would
scale up really hard and there were times where you would run into a specific boss and you, um,
could potentially just get one shot based off of like those, the, their, the shadow boss like,
like, yeah, the extra one. They left in
you died. Yeah. So now, uh, there is a feature within season five where those shadow pit boss
like affixes will appear and they'll actually leave kind of a stacking debuff onto, uh, players,
now. So, uh, and it can go up to three times and then obviously when it gets to the max, you
have a very good chance of getting like heavily, like, like, punish for, for taking up to three
debuffs from that end. This is really to, um, allow a little bit more flexibility for players,
you know, based off of the feedback we heard regarding a lot of the one shots and things like that.
Uh, you now have the ability of being able to, you know, take a couple of these debuffs and maybe
not like completely get punished from that. It's less about like the perfection kind of involved,
but more so, um, uh, being a little bit more forgiving in some of those, uh, opportunities. Now,
if you are a person that just like, like, face tanks, things and goes in and immediately takes
three debuffs, uh, you're probably still gonna, uh, you learn that, you know, that damage is still
gonna be very sharp with the 3D. Yeah. So, um, but it is something to help out, uh, in regards to
that. Yeah. To be clear how that debuff works is every time that you get hit with one of those
shadow boss mechanics, you'll take the debuff and it increases all of your damage takings. So,
the regular boss is gonna hit you harder and the shadow bosses are gonna hit you harder too. Exactly.
So, you know, you just don't want that to ramp up too much because then everything is gonna be
more punishy. Yeah. Exactly. There's a few people already asking about those, uh, debuffs and
chats. Yeah. It just increases all your damage takings. So, basically, you know, you get some freebies
of getting hit by them. You really don't want to, but then after that you gotta watch out because
the next about is hardest season four was. Exactly. So, um, and then another big thing. So, this was
something that was actually not present in the PTR, but it's something that we've heard a lot of
feedback about and, uh, actually a ton of feedback about, uh, and this is group play in, uh, in pits,
in season four, the way that it worked was, uh, if you were in the pit and you were the party leader,
uh, and you had three friends that joined along, you would essentially get through the pit,
you would get all the master working materials, uh, for yourself, 100% of them, and then everyone
else, uh, uh, that joined you would only get about like 50%. And, uh, it felt pretty punishing, uh,
for, for people to really kind of join up with friends and run through pits. And we heard a lot
of feedback of like, hey, it'd be great if like, if I'm just joining my friend, we can all just get,
you know, uh, 100% of the pit material rewards. And so, that is being tweaked for season five.
Now, the whole entire party itself will end up receiving, uh, 100% of the, uh, the, the materials
that you end up receiving at the end of the pit. Yeah. So, we appreciate the feedback. Thank you,
guys, for, for letting us know, and this is something that wasn't in PTR, but will be for season five.
Uh, next up, we have endgame bosses. Um, so this is something, of course, we talked about during the
PTR and we do want to highlight again because I think this is amazing and we'll save a whole lot of
time. So, uh, you can now resummon endgame bosses, uh, immediately after you end up killing them. So,
as you're going through the different boss ladders and stuff, you can, uh, just resum in the alterable
reappears, you can see in the footage and, uh, throwing the, the, the mats and bam. Again, you're
finding Garryl, which is really nice. No more exiting the dungeon, resetting the dungeon, running
back and then, uh, having to do it over again. Uh, this should save up a whole lot of time.
This should help a whole lot with farming as well, specifically for gear. You know,
we'll be hearing a lot about all this new gear. Uh, different from, from Adam here in a second.
Um, but there were some additional changes as well to some of the endgame bosses that we do have,
like for instance, the, what, first one we're going to talk about is the beast and ice. The beast
and ice, of course, uh, had a required essential to actually summon, uh, you would have worked to
actually create the dungeon to, to go in to fight, uh, the beast and ice. There's no longer a
essential that will be required. Um, and also the beast and ice is now way closer to the dungeon.
It's going to be a short dungeon crawl similar to the other endgame bosses. So you're not having to,
you know, go through a, a lengthy, uh, just to get to the, um, yeah. Likewise, no more sigil dust will
be required for summoning the beast and ice. And then of course, we thought about internal players
in this situation because some of them have actually crafted a bunch of, uh, sigils and now,
since sigils are no longer required, you can still use those leftover sigils to immediately resummon
the beast and ice without needing the, uh, the mats that were, uh, that are still required for the
beast and ice. So it's kind of a nice benefit to them. And then of course, Varshan also got some
updates. Um, or Varshan required a bunch of different body parts. And now, uh, Varshan just
requires malignant hearts. And of course, we thought about eternal players in this specific instance.
Eternal players can convert their old part, uh, their old body parts, uh, two hearts. Yeah. Uh,
by going to the alchemist, that's a magical alchemist. Yeah. Yeah. But, uh, if you have
a need to spare a heart, you just go to an alchemist. That's just how it works. Yeah. That's just how it
works. Um, but yeah, some changes coming to that. Uh, and then separately,
endgame bosses, uh, for, for endgame bosses, the boss ladder, uh, bosses, um, they won't be dropping
rare items anymore. They're actually just going to drop additional gold. And of course,
you, you'll have your opportunity of getting legendaries and, uh, uniques and mythic uniques
from, from them. So, uh, but now we just remove the rare item drop, uh, drops from them. So it,
it takes up like less of the, uh, the drop chances that you could get in terms of, uh, their,
their specific tables. And then on tormented bosses, tormented bosses now drop five time,
as five times as many boss matches before. And of course, uh, all tormented bosses have a better
chance of dropping a, uh, mythic unique. Um, so we are boosting up the, the mythic unique drop.
There, there's actually specifics on all this stuff in the patch. And that's that people can
read afterwards. And we've also reduced the, uh, the Stygian stone cost for, uh, the tormented
bosses before it was two. And now it's dropping to one. So it should help out with players wanting to
experiment, more, try out, uh, some of the more difficult, uh, endgame bosses that are available,
which are their tormented versions. And then, uh, one big thing that is happening, and this is, uh,
this is something that was kind of mentioned in the blog, but, uh, and people see more specifics in
the patch notes, uh, experience is changing, um, uh, in terms of like the XP bonus from killing
higher level monsters. Uh, it's no longer capped in, um, I believe it's now, well, it's, it's,
it's, it's, it's, it's, it's 10 levels actually, it's a, it's a, it's a, it's a capped, shall I say,
it's a capped to 30 levels, that's actually incredible in this slide. But, um, it used to be 10 levels,
it's now 30 levels, and that's across all world tiers. So, uh, if you happen, for example, if you
are a level 50 character and you kill a level 80 monster in season four, you would only get, uh,
level 60 experience. And now you'll get up to that level 80 experience. So, uh, it should help out a
lot if you are willing to go through more challenging content, man, you get more XP for it. So,
it's really cool. And it's also really nice that, uh, because it, it plays really well into, uh,
stacking, profing mind cages, uh, uh, they have a whole burden in the appetite, because that can
actually also increase monster level by 30 levels as well. So, it's kind of a, um, a cool, uh,
anon you could say from this. So, yeah. Pretty sweet. Uh, yeah, I think that's it for general game
updates. Yeah. But we, uh, yeah. Yeah. As I talked about a bunch, yeah. It's all in the patch notes.
You guys will see the patch notes afterwards. Um, but, uh, yeah. Yeah. Really amazing. Have all those
changes. Uh, chat was absolutely lighting up. Uh, cool. So, all the, you know, changes of the
pit. And of course, even though we've shown the, the boss summoning reset again, they got just as
excited. So, awesome to see. And I, you know, we really appreciate everyone's feedback during PTR.
And hearing, especially about the hell-tied stuff. And, you know, we totally hear you guys. And we
want to make sure that, you know, people have to experience still, still enjoy hell-tied to the,
the fullest. Yeah. Like, you know, what I mean? Exactly. No, it's really cool to talk so much.
Yeah. Those profane mind cages that are coming back. But yeah, Adam, thank you so much for that.
Yeah. Uh, and now everyone, uh, hope you're comfortable, uh, because we got a ton to go over with
regards to, uh, updates, unique some bus fixes on a ton of class balance changes. Uh, who better to
walk us through Mr. Adam Jackson. Yeah. Let's do it. So we got a lot to talk about today. I'll try and
go as quickly as possible. Um, so yeah, firstly, you know, thank you all for your feedback and comments.
You know, we got a lot of class related feedback on the PTR, a lot of balance feedback, a lot of
just how it feels to play things. Um, and we actually reacted pretty heavily and did a lot of
changes between PTR and season five launch, uh, some of which I think some people know and some
things are going to be new for you today. So, uh, really, yeah, we have a lot of things that,
that changed, uh, in many ways, honestly, it's going to feel like almost from a balanced perspective
and kind of a what your class can do in your journey. It's going to feel almost like a very
different game compared to what you experienced on the PTR. I'm going to go through a lot of like
the systemic reasons why and then some specific things that we did to every class, as well as,
of course, updating all of our uniques and kind of the impact that you can expect from that.
So, uh, lost to talk about. So, first we'll be talking about bug fixes. Um, we've got quite a few
to go through that I think are pretty notable. Again, we're going to be doing the class balance
updates after that and then the unique changes. So those will be the three things I'm going to be
covering today. So, uh, firstly, as usual, you know, we're going to be publishing the patch notes
right after this. So you can read all of them. I'm not going to cover everything today, but just some
of the more notable ones. Uh, so first, uh, is one on the Necromancer that we've heard about for a
while now. It's a shielding storm. Uh, this is a legendary that when your bone storm damages enemies,
you get a barrier equal to your back's life. Uh, it used to be based on your base life instead of
your max life. And now we finally fix that. Uh, to be clear, this is a pretty huge buff. Um,
we may have to re-evaluate the power of this a little later, but we're going to see how it goes.
But now that barrier is going to be very significant as you're hitting enemies with this aspect.
Uh, next we've got a couple on the barbarian. Uh, the first one is the Twister glyph. This is a
Paragon node glyph. It wasn't properly giving you a bonus multiplicative damage when casting dust
doubles. So dust double builds will be a little bit stronger. We also fix an issue with the temperate
earthquake duration. Um, beforehand, uh, there was a bug where it was actually lowering the DPS of
earthquake because it was increased the duration and then your DPS would go down. So we fixed that. So
it's now actually just going to make you hit harder. Uh, next one, uh, I've got a call on our,
one of our content creators, Woody Joe, uh, here, this is why we have a PTR. Uh, he found a neat little
oversight that we had with a passive called trick attacks. And I'm actually going to go over this
in a little bit of detail. Uh, now, right. 39 and three seems completely unranked. So, uh,
offensive passive is pretty good. So, uh, a little bit background to this. Basically, we change how
this passive trick attacks, uh, what it does. It went from something that was more utility based
for it was around CC and we turned it into damage, but we didn't update under the hood for like
tempering and where it can appear from a utility to a damage recipe of where it would show up. And
so it was appearing on utility, which is a lot more, uh, common than damage. And then you could get
it to silly ranks like this. So, uh, fix this, um, right now, or on the PTR, I should say, it was on
this recipe called alchemist control where it was with chilling weight and shadow crash, which
are also like CC based, uh, passives. Um, four season five launch, we're actually going to be
disabling this recipe from dropping. You won't be able to see it for a patch, uh, while we fix this
bug. And what we're going to do is once we reenable the, the alchemist control recipe to drop,
trick attacks won't be on here anymore. Or we're actually going to be doing is we're going to be
taking flurry size from another recipe called rogue innovation here. Um, we're going to be moving
flurry size, which is more of a utility based thing and moving that over to alchemist control
and then just removing trick attacks from alchemist control. So the net effect of this will be that
now both recipes will have, or yeah, both temporary recipes will have three different options
of what you can have there. And rogue innovation will actually have a little bit of a buff here too
because instead of having four things to, you know, roll for your tempers, we're only going to have
three. So it'll be a little bit easier to get what you want. Uh, next, we're going to be talking about,
some generic class balance updates. So kind of to set you up a high level thing that we're going
to see in our feedback from PTR was barbarians are really, really good. And oh, every other class is
kind of a little bit weak. It feels like compared to barbarians. So we did a lot of things to address
this. So first, I want to go into detail a little bit of how we feel about barbarians and where
they're at and what we want to do. Um, we feel like one of the bigger reasons why barbarians are so
strong is that they kind of have two class mechanics compared to other classes, right? They have the
expertise system, which is like a normal class mechanic where you know, they have this fantasy of
leveling up their weapons and then they get bonuses. But then they also get more item slots
compared to the classes so they get more access to more legendary powers. Um, as far as how we
tackle this, we don't want our only solution to be the nerf barbarians, right? Like a common thing
that we hear is like, hey, they have more item slots. Maybe you should just get rid of the item
slots so that everybody has parity, right? Like that is a way to make parity. But you know, it takes
away from their theme of being a master of weapons and it's not very fun. Um, so that's not the
only thing that we want to do in this situation. Uh, the other thing is that we want to keep their class
identity, right? Um, another common situation we hear is we'll just give all the other classes more
item slots that they're the same as barbarian, right? And similarly, kind of like how necromancers
have minions, we don't want to give every class minions just because, you know, they don't have access
to the cool thing that necromancers do. We don't want to just give every class, you know, more slots
so that they're exactly the same as barbarian. We want to really try and keep what makes them feel
special as a special thing and find other ways to kind of bring parity to the classes. So here's
kind of our strategy of what we're thinking of with barbarians. We have a few different things
that we're going to be doing. Uh, one is we're actually going to be adjusting how much damage all
the classes get from their core stat. And this is going to bring other classes up to the level
barbarian. I'm going to be going over that in a little bit. Uh, we are going to be reducing the
power of barbarians as part of our solution. But again, I want to point out it's not the only thing
that we want to do. And then we also want to target the other class mechanics and really bring them
up to the level of the barbarian effective we have in two and making the other classes feel
cool in the way that makes them thematic and awesome. Uh, we already actually experimented with this
in season four. This was an intentional thing that we did and we wanted to see how it went with
the necromancer. Uh, if you remember, we buffed minions very heavily and we also buffed the book
of the dead, their class mechanic very heavily, uh, not just numbers, but also in the cool factor,
right? You have mechanics like, you know, your minions can throw bone spears or, you know, your
golem can do bone spikes everywhere in the enemies vulnerable. We want to do this kind of treatment
to the other class mechanics. Uh, just to be clear, we're going to be probably doing this after
the vessel of hatred expansion launches. So it'll be a little bit. So we are doing some things in
the meantime to catch them up. But you can expect, uh, in the future, we're going to be doing kind of a
big overhaul to the other classes similar lead to the book of the dead. And so their cool factor and
their power level is going to be going up. So let's talk about that core stat update that I talked
about, uh, previously. So basically what we're doing here is we're going to be changing the amount
of damage that every class gets from their core stat. So if you didn't know on live right now,
when you log into the game, you get about 1% more damage per 10 stat of your class. So as an example,
you know, the, the, I don't know, pick one, the source, you know, with intelligence, you would
have 10 int and then you get 1% more damage. If you had 100 int, you'd have 10% more damage and so on.
So now it's going to actually depend on the class. What that ratio is of how much damage you get per
your core stat. So the burberrying is going to be saying exactly the same, uh, 1% more damage per 10
strength. The rogue is going to get a little bit above, above, above, above here because they do
have a little bit more slots compared to other classes. So they're going to be getting 1% more
damage per 9 decks and then the other 3 classes, the sorcerer's druid and necromancer are going to be
getting 1% more damage per 8 core stat. So, you know, without doing a lot of math, the TLDR here is
barbarians are staying the same. Uh, rogues are going to get a bit of a bump, a bit of a buff and the
other 3 classes are going to get even more damage. So as you get that core stat, which you get very
commonly, you know, in gear and paragon and other places, you're just going to be doing more damage.
It's just a passive way that we're going to be catching up the classes, uh, stat wise.
So next, let's move on to kind of our class updates. So I'm going to be going through all the different
classes and talking about kind of what our updates are going to be for them. Some of the things you can
expect that are different from PTR to launch. So barbarian, um, you know, currently barbarians,
in addition to having more item slots, I have some of the best key passives in the game,
Blackland season 4 and on live. Um, one of the, the very main ways that we're targeting,
uh, bringing them down is reducing the power level. So that really their key passes are comparable
to other classes. Uh, we on the team felt like, you know, they already have all these other
things are really strong going for them. They don't need like overly-stated, way powerful key passives
that do like, you know, over 100% multiplicative damage when the other classes are doing way less.
Um, so you did see that on the PTR. We did see a lot of feedback on like, why are we bringing down
walking arsenal to have parity when, you know, it wasn't even really meta compared to the other
key passes and it's kind of wanted to bring some light to this of how we think about it. Um,
the reason why we brought rocking arsenal to be level with the other ones when we brought them to
be equal to other classes is that, you know, we want all the key passes on barbarian to have parity
with each other. If we just brought down the other key passes that were way overperforming
and didn't bring walking arsenal down to be even with them, then really walking arsenal is just
going to be the best mandatory pick and every barbarian build is going to have to interact with
this system. And we didn't really wanted them to be equal with each other so that, you know, there's
actually a choice when you get to your key passive of which one to take. So I just wanted to clarify
that of, you know, what our thinking was there. But, you know, it's not all doom and gloom for
barbarians. Uh, you know, we did hear feedback of like, man, it really sucks. You know, I understand
that they're being brought down and it's fair, but, you know, we want to have some things to look
forward to. So we did introduce a number of buffs coming in between PTR on lives that you have
some things to look forward to and new bill paths or your, you know, underperforming builds are not
being brought down as well. I'm going to give a couple of examples here. One is hammer the
ancients. Uh, we increase the damage baseline by 10%. Uh, and we also adjusted the of ancestral force
legendary. Uh, one of the trouble troubling things that this bill has problems with is like
single target damage against bosses and things. You know, it does really good in AOE and brings down
enemies, but it's single targets a little bit lacking. So we're upgrading this legendary power. So
now it's going to be doing more damage against bosses. So it'll kind of help you with that single
target issue. Uh, another one is upheaval. Uh, upheaval builds can rejoice and also a little bit
of a preview of kind of how we're changing uniques, which I'll be going over a lot more later. Uh,
we're increasing up people damage by about 15%. And we also, uh, rounded out Hellhammer now. It's
quite a bit more powerful. I can point out a bunch of things here of how it's better, but you
can see it gives more skill ranks of upheaval compared to before. Uh, the damage of its burning on
the ground just baseline went up. It also has scaling on the burning damage. So, you know, before the
burning damage wasn't really a meaningful part of the unique. Um, one of the things you're going
to see it with the uniques across the board is that they're going to be a lot more about the
thematic of what the unique is and that's where their power is going to be. So here the burning
ground actually will scale with your strength at a pretty significant degree. So, you know, it'll
actually be doing meaningful damage, hopefully. Um, you can also see X-inherent aphics now is
damaged a burning enemies, um, instead of overpower damage. So it's going with that theme of Hellhammer
burning the ground. It's also giving you skill ranks of wall up a passive. So that's more
multiplicative damage. You also get a pebble size. So now your burning ground and your upheaval
is going to be bigger. So there there's just all kinds of new things going on. It's going to be a
lot cooler, a lot more powerful. Um, and hopefully a lot more fun. Yeah, Hellhammer. It looks absolutely
insane. Yeah. 300 strength also by the way. Yeah, 300 strength. Yeah. No big deal. No big deal.
It's going to be pretty good. Uh, so next the sorceress. Uh, we got a hold on a feedback that,
you know, the sorceress isn't powerful enough compared to other classes. We got so much, uh, I
I'm going to stop us right here. So much feedback about the stuff. Just a little bit and the
draw it and the other. And then I'm going to answer. I will just know like we hear you guys. We
absolutely do. Okay, now you may continue. Okay. So, uh, for the sorcerers specifically, we heard
feedback that they're not powerful enough. So we did quite a few things to address it. Um,
firstly, they've got a lot of large buffs to their uniques. Um, I would say even more than other
classes, your uniques are going to feel really good, uh, is the hope. And I think we've hit it.
And I'll be going over some of them a little bit later. Um, we also buffed all of their core
mastery skills by about 15 to 20%. So just baseline. Remember, this is in addition to the core
stat buff. All of your core mastery skills are also getting buffed baseline, uh, by a pretty
significant degree. So you're just going to hit harder. Um, we also did multiple defensive buffs.
You know, we heard a lot of feedback that they have trouble surviving in situations that the other
classes could kind of get away with. Um, these are some examples. We did more than this, but
ice armor, your base shield amount is going up from 40% to 50% percent of your max life.
Uh, snow veiled aspect. This one was updated from PTR to launch. So on PTR, it was that your
ice armor gave you unstoppable and gave you armor. And on launch, you're still going to get unstoppable,
but you're going to get damaged reduction, which, you know, anyone who knows how the defenses
within this game work is way more significant than just getting armor. Yeah. When you hit that
subbing cap, it's kind of like, you just want to gobble up DR like Pac-Man as much as you can get
more of the better and this is going to give you the D.I. is going to be huge. Yeah.
Also, we did multiple buffs to the Paragon board. Again, this is not covering everything. Um,
but one of the things is that, you know, we put a lot of caps to make sure that some Paragon
doses just didn't go out of control compared to everything else, but we heard feedback that,
you know, those caps were a little bit too punishing. So we increased them. An example here is
burning instincts where you know, on PTR, it capped at 40% more multiplicative damage,
and we increased that up to 80%. So now you're burning damage that's based on your crit strike
multiplier is going to be going up. Your total amount is going to go up, but then also the rate
that you get it used to be 1% per 50 in. Now it's 1% per 20 in. So you're beginning more efficient
bang for your buck for your end and a total cap that's much higher.
So Drew, a similar to Sorcerer is surprise surprise. Got a lot of feedback that it's not powerful
enough compared to the barbarian or other classes. So we've got a lot of multiple quality of life
and damage buffs coming in. Again, these are just some examples. Also, you got to remember the
unique. So you're going to be coming in as well. Boulder damage went up. We increased the damage
across the board of their like core skills mostly and we missed boulders. So we're, you know,
increasing their damage a bit. We also got a lot of feedback that, you know, we came out with this
really cool unique for cataclysm that made the lightning bolts smart and target enemies.
And then a lot of people were like, Hey, why why does it have to like get a unique to make my skill
be smart? And we agreed. So we just made the skill smart based line. So now those lightning bolts
from the ultimate will just target enemies. Perfect storm. The storm key passive is getting
xdamage boosted from 30 to 40%. Size makes shift. This was an aspect that we think is really cool
where your earth spike kind of goes in a line and does a bunch of earth spikes. You still have a
kiss curse mechanic and it no longer does. So before it used to like give you this big bonus of,
you know, way more resource reduction and more damage on it. Put it out of the cool down. And
now it just doesn't add a cool down so you can spam it and cast a bunch of the first spikes everywhere.
Should be a lot more fun. Also similar to the sorceress. We're buffing their little bonus cap on
their legendary paragon nodes. So an example here, you know, they went from 40 to 60%. So you've got
thunder struck earth and devastation and survival instincts. We've got a little visual there.
The bottom node, but you can see that that top end of the damage is now 60%. So it's going to be
better than PTR. Also, we came out with that new unique I mentioned for cataclysm. It used to be
on the gloves on PTR, which a lot of people, which we agreed with, you know, it kind of felt bad
that you know, you've got the two storm related unique on the same slot. You can't take them together.
It was competing with unsun-acetic wraps. This was the lightning storm unique. But now it's
going to be on the rain slots. Now you can take them both together so they're not competing with
each other anymore. Next is the rogue. So to be frank, the rogue is, we feel like it's in a pretty
good spot. So we didn't do as many changes compared to other classes. We did still do a few that
I'll mention today, but they got the least changes. The first one is flurry. So as you know, if you play
the PTR flurry, you got some pretty dramatic updates, right? Both of their enhancement and both
of their choices that you could pick on the base skill got changed and made a lot better.
We saw that a lot of the output of flurry was related to doing the mechanics that the enhancement
and the advanced flurry were requiring to do, like Cassie had a bunch of times in her own stuff
like that. And we wanted to move some of that damage from those enhancements and things into
the base skill. So the enhancement and the advance for her is still going to be pretty potent,
but we lowered their damage and instead just use the base skill even more. And what this is going
to mean is really just that you're going to be more consistently doing that damage and you're going
to be less reliant on doing the stacking mechanics to get it. Next, Win Force. You know, this one has
had a troubled history of just trying to find ways to make it really good and useful. Instead of
knocking back enemies when it prox, it's going to knock them down now. So you no longer have to worry
about like knocking enemies out of your CC, you know, or you want them to be grouped up next to you
and then you're just knocking one of them or a few of them away. Now they're just going to go in
place. We have a before and after here. Again, a little preview of what we're doing with our
Uniques. But yeah, Win Force, you can see some of the things here as a preview is going to give you
move speed baseline, which is a pretty interesting. There's a stat on a bow. You've got chance for
double projectiles for your barrage. You've got a couple of passive upgrades there. And then as
you can see, the damage went up but also now it knocks down enemies instead of knocks them back.
Last but not least, the Necromancer. We've been hearing off feedback that Blood Necromancer
players are a little sad. They just aren't really catching up to the other versions of Necromancer.
So we've buffed up a bunch of their tempering recipes and the damage on them. We're also buffing
their legendary Paragon nodes. Here's something here that we did a Bloodbath. This one just makes
your overpowered damage go up. It's being doubled from 35% to 70%. So that's pretty meaty. Blood
gets blood. That damage bonus when you're picking up Blood Orbs is being doubled and the maximum
amount is being doubled. So you're getting more Perstack and you need less stats to get to your max
damage. So pretty good there. And then last but not least here, Lucky Hit. We've heard a lot of
feedback from Necromancer players that they kind of rely a lot on the Miyazma Corpse explosion to
get their Lucky Hit prox off and that there are other skills don't really compete. And so they
can't really have fun with Lucky Hit based builds more generally. So we just buffed Lucky Hit on a
bunch of different skills so you can see there what all the numbers are. Again, those will be on
the patch notes but really they're just going to be Lucky Hit more often and getting cool prox more.
All right. So next let's talk about Uniques a little bit. We've got a lot of
things coming up. As we promised in the PTR stream, we said that we had this kind of different
philosophy when it comes to Uniques and we went into detail there and we updated our Uniques coming
into season five but we didn't update all of our existing Uniques in the game yet. So we've done
that pass now. We've updated nearly every Unique in the game and I'm going to do a little bit of
a recap of how we thought and then giving you some examples of what we did. So these updates are
fairly dramatic. They'll be showing you three from each class as well as three generic ones to
give you a really medium idea of the different categories and ways that we thought of updating Uniques
and kind of what you can expect for your builds. Yeah and I know and Marcus is going to remind us
about this at the end as well. You'll be hearing it a lot. But I will say we are showing three here
and three for every class and three generic ones but every single Unique is actually in the
patch notes and we have it before and after in the patch notes so you guys will have easy access
and you can easily compare the two and see what's the difference. So after the stream you'll be
able to compare and so we're just only covering a small amount here. We'll see everything.
Just a little sample serving. Patch notes are absolutely massive so you'll have a lot too.
That would be pretty close to that. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah, so one of the things is your general
power level of Unique affects is up and by Unique affects I want to be clear. That is like the
thing at the bottom that is like your you know deals 40 to 60% more multiplicative damage or whatever.
That number is going to be up on the higher end so instead of 40 to 60 you know it will be 40 to 80
or 40 to 9 year 40 to whatever right. So that power level is just going to be generally up almost
across the board and then really what we targeted for these updates is the stats on the Uniques.
So the stats are going to pretty much break every rule that we had in the game before when it
comes to being a cool item. So some things that you're going to see and I think I got an example
of most of if not all these but you're going to see Uniques that have different inherits compared to
other stats. So you know your boot inherent you know could be something that's not even related to
boots or movement anymore could be something else or sometimes we had more inherent stats.
So something that didn't exist before you know some items can have two inherits instead of just one
which is a pretty big difference. We have a lot more that have stats that break normal slot rules
so you know things like movement speed on bows or cooldown reduction on weapons stuff like that.
Uniques also can now have tempering affixes right none of them really did this at the in season 4
but now the tempering is in the game and Uniques have to compete with these really great tempered
items Uniques can have that too. They can also have much higher potential stat values compared
to normal items. So you know if a normal item has 20 to 40% more damage a unique can be like you
know one to 300% more damage or whatever right and we even do this with the tempered affixes. So
you need to have juiced up versions of tempered affixes that make them solve those problems much
quicker. Also we've introduced a lot of stats that really have powerful effects on them.
Sometimes even a single stat on Unique can have the impact that a legendary power normal we would
on an item as far as what it does to a build and we'll have a couple examples of that where like
a stat on an item is actually giving you a new effect that that didn't exist before that you could do.
Yeah so again we're going to be going through three examples per class and three generics and
I'm going to just try and quickly go through and kind of point out some of the the key things that
are kind of neat about the items. So we're going to shock on this a little bit and yeah you can see
some cool items. So let's get to it. Yeah so first penitent grieves this is a generic unique you
can see here this one now has two inheritance as opposed to one. Another thing that you can notice
is that normally you know the inherent the evaded grants more moves speed is only for one second
and this one is not only has two inheritance but it's for two seconds. So you'll evade and like you
know boost around that crazy sonic speed for a couple seconds which is pretty neat and now you can
run through enemies while you do it. We've also got some neat stats there like crit chance against
chilled enemies and chill potency there that are that are new to the game. Here Fissa Fethis one a
lot of people saw a little bit early and they were very happy about. So one thing I think that's
kind of cool is that with our unique we're really trying to like double and triple down on the
fantasy of the item. So you know something's about cold or something here like this the fate is
about like RNG to the max. So we're really going hard on like what the theme is. So here you can
see like your tax speed can go from point one to point seven and everything on it is like has a
huge range of what you can roll. So like a greater affix to fix the fate could be like a best
and slot item for a lot of builds. So the lucky hit chance on this. Yes this is the one that people
point out that we it's just crazy. I talked with our one of the praise broader team. I want to shout
out Alex our team who did a lot of this work and we had a choice here and we're like are we
going to go crazy or go conservative like you know this is go crazy like this might be insane.
It might actually be best in slot and break stuff but it's really cool. So yeah greater affix
grissa fissa fate there is going to be really cool. Next the grandfather mythic unique example
here. You know a lot of people had issues with the ignored durability loss. You know where you
would like master work hit that or something and then you're not getting anything we just move that
into be a you know a baseline inherent affix now. So you don't have to worry about that and then
replace it with something useful with a max resource. And I will note like even in season four
because that durability loss was kind of was actually hidden stat item sometimes when you found
a greater affix version of a grandfather. Yeah yeah yeah it would actually apply to that that
that that is now. Yeah that's all done. And here it can't be greater. It's something that we
thought of a lot with this. Yeah. Yeah so now let's go into the classes of barbarian. This is
battle trance. This one exists already on live. Probably the the two big things here one is you
know you have two different passives now that you get a lot of times we're adding skill ranks to
passives because that's a way to add multiplicative damage or just buffs to really cool effects on a
unique the other stats. The other thing to point out here is the actual effect before it was giving
you increase attack speed to all the other skills when you had frenzy stacks. Now you're going to be
getting damage and attack speed. You know we heard a lot feedback from players that it they would hit a
attack speed cap and then this unique wasn't really doing very much for them. So now you're also
just going to get damage in addition to making it easier to hit that cap for your other skills.
So it's just you know more stats stronger. Next reign of the raveness a couple things here one is
xk giving you skill ranks of rend which is pretty significant and remember that two to three might
not seem so significant but when you greater affix that and then master work it like your potential
of more damage on this goes up very significantly. We're also giving you skill ranks of brawling skills
thing to point out here is your rends duration. This will also just increase the throughput damage
of it has been doubled. So that's just more damage on rend in addition to the skill ranks and then
also at the bottom small little detail but before you can only apply that special effect of your
brawling skills applying your rends bleed every four seconds and now it's every second. So now if
you're able to spam brawling skills you're just going to be applying rend bleeds to enemies and
stronger rend bleeds like crazy. So it's a pretty big power boost. Next the fields of crimson
the thing that we want to call out here I mean there's a lot of things that are kind of unique and
different but is that one kind of rule that we had with item stats that we're now changing and
breaking is we never really buff the things like enhancements or like the a b like the different
choice upgrades that you can do for a skill. This one actually buffs enhanced ruptures explosion
size. So normally when you're up to an enemy it does that explosion. This will make that explosion
be way bigger. So it's kind of a neat way that we can manipulate player power via stats.
Next let's move on to the sorceress. So the staff of endless rage we actually have a combo here
that we're going to show a little video of before and after with this. Fireball builds. The staff
now does some and the gloves would be doing some unique things to fireballs. One is butt plus
fireball projectile speed. So this is actually going to make your fireballs fly through the air
faster or bounce quicker and so you'll be able to get through them and they'll you know finish
their path faster. You've got the tempering recipe now so it doesn't compete with your chance to cast
twice and you can see there it goes up to 75% just on that one stat. So it basically almost solves it
for you by itself which is pretty huge. You've got some massive skill ranks to fireballs so now
again way more multiplicative damage than before and then you know you see at the bottom that the
upper end of that damage is going up per the same as most of our uniques. And next it's combos
with the gloves of the illuminator. A couple things to to kind of glow down here is the fireball
fireball attack speed is going up by a much bigger amount than other classes or than normal attack
speeds. Sorry on other slots. Also you get mana when fireball explodes. I played with this build and
I think it was season one and I constantly ran into mana issues because you always want to spam
this as much as you can. So when you think of this stat you know you can greater this you can
tempt or master work this and you kind of combine you combine you combine this with the attack speed
here and then you combine it with the projectile speed. Yeah and you get a lot more fireballs and
remember every time that it explodes which when you when it bounces exploding. Yeah and when you're
splitting and getting more for multiple projectiles you're getting more bounce explosions so it's
giving you a resource engine. Yeah you're essentially a fireball machine gun. Yeah so we've got a
little bit of a season four to season five comparison here of what it looks like. A little video
so in season four you can see you know every third cast gives you three but season five you're
gonna randomly get three three and then sometimes even more when it combines with the double project
isle bonus. So you can actually really fill up your screen with with fireballs everywhere and
every one of those bounces is giving you mana back to to cast more. That's ludicrous. So it's it's
pretty cool. It's its own little engine. Next we've got blue rows. Probably the cool thing to
point out here is there's a shafts for ice spikes to explode twice. So this is also something that
we haven't really done where we have these we call them subpowers internally but you know these
things like dust doubles or ice spikes that are like powers that generate when you cast a skill
that are usually through legendaries or uniques. We generally don't manipulate them too heavily
like this but we're going to be experimenting more with that in unique stat affixes. So here you
know your ice spikes can actually like double proc so they get you know double explosions and then
any other things that would proc off that would be doubled which is pretty neat.
And next let's move on to the druid. So waxing gibbess this is the shred to druid unique.
So what we did here that I want to point out you know in addition to the fact that you're getting a
budget skill ranks a shred and toxic's clause which is a bunch more multiplicative damage. So power
level is going up significantly is blood howl grants stealth for a few seconds. So what's really
cool about this is you know we basically added a new mechanic via a simple item stat in this unique
and it combines with the unique effect right. So before on live you know you kill enemies with shred
you go into stealth and then you come out and you guarantee crit. So as you're killing enemies over
and over you're just creating constantly as you go in and out stealth but you couldn't really do
that against bosses you had no other ways to get into stealth but now we've created an alternative
way where if you cast blood howl or get the blood howl effect another ways you'll go into stealth
and get this proc and now you can get this you know against single bosses or situations you couldn't
before. So you we've given you a potential way to create your own engine which is pretty neat to
get those infinite crits. Next great staff of the crown I believe we showed this one earlier to
people but what just wanted to point out you know what was special about this storm strike chaining
to additional targets you know things like this again it's a single stat that does something that
kind of really changes how the unique works right. It's gonna you're gonna get all the different
procs and different effects by chaining to more enemies more often. You can also see here that the
upper end of that damage that you could get is going up from 150% to 200 so it's just better.
And last but not least we got storms companion this one I again wanted to highlight another new
thing that we're doing and I want to call it here is the lucky hit chance for the pack leader spirit
so normally we never really manipulate class mechanics but here you know this pack leader this
isn't like a passive or a thing the skill tree this isn't the spirit boon your class mechanic
and this increases that lucky hit chance to get a reset on cool down on the cool downs of all your
companion skills. So again this is something that you know normally we don't get to manipulate and
now you'll be able to to do and I think it'll be pretty cool. We have also decided that pack leader
is two words instead of one. Yeah everything's getting up. Yeah everything everything's everything's
changing. All right moving on to the rogue eagle horn let me see what did I want to I think just
pointing out here this was about moving the the tempered recipe the penetrating shot project
all this can cast twice again another example of that and we're also giving you a bunch of
skill ranks the penetrating shot again this is a way that we're adding just like raw power and
damage in ways that aren't in the unique effect. So these stats on these things can be very strong
out the gate and then again tempering and master working just makes these go go really really high.
Next word of a con this one was a really silly fun one that we liked um you see there the one
I want to point out well one is the ultimate damage actually ultimate skill damage for the rogue
is kind of a premium because they have that paragon node that makes it turn into multiplicative
damage for all your skills so that's actually pretty meaty. Um it's also way higher value than normal
also the chance for rain of arrows waves to cast twice. So normally we don't do you know
chance to double cast on ultimate but again unique gets to break the rules so now you've got
you know juiced up rain of arrows cool down reduction they can cast twice and they hit way harder
on the rain of arrows themed unique. So again really trying to bring out the theme and the the
fantasy of these unique in the stats in the effects to really create something special.
And next savage were a sign it I was running this in season four I'm a little sad that I'm going
to be doing something else in season five but I loved my stun grenade build but here you can see
a bunch of grenade damage obvious theme for the grenade build we're also giving you a lot of
your stun grenade size here and then again a new afic that kind of creates your own engine you're
getting plus one energy when a stun grenade explodes and this is each individual grenade right so
usually release a cluster of these things so now again I spent a lot of my time in season four
trying to solve resource and get ways to to cast us a lot to throw out the stun grenades and now
this kind of create helps us own engine. Also one thing to point out here is that it's no longer
just a flurry unique it's casting a core skill throws still grenades so it's a lot more
generically applicable you can use this with you know all the different core skills not just flurry.
Next necromancer the big one I wanted to point out here we're going to be showing both of the
blood surge uniques and how they've been updated and they combo with each other we have a stat
here that blood surge drains more times from elites so to be clear this is the drain not the explosion
but the drain does feed into the explosion damage and there's a lot of like synergy and things
based on draining enemies so now you know one of the problems that blood surge has always had is
when you're fighting a single target or a boss you know you only drain one enemy and then you're
not getting your like explosion damage up but now you're going to be draining multiple times from
those elites you're getting getting you know more life back and other prox when you drain but also
your explosion will be more significant now against them. Next death speakers pennant this is the
other blood surge unique we also added another thing that combines with the other unique where you're
getting essence per enemy drained right and so now as you drain enemies for the explosion you're
going to be getting more essence back to cast the skill and spam it more and we're also giving
you a bunch of ranks to blood surge which you know just makes sense so you know 50% you know before
master working in tempering multiple creative damage is already a giant buff to this but then also
you can see that you know the number is also went up on this as well so it's just going to be
going to be pretty significant. Can't wait and last but not least grieves of the empty tomb this is
your sever unique lots of stuff to point out here one is you have multiple inherits so you know
normally you can only get three max of h charges you get more here we also had a fun little thing where
you're a vade now these behind desiccrated ground because this is the desiccrated ground unique
we also have chance for sever projectiles to cast twice we have sever size here we also give you
ranks to reapers pursuits so this is really about just like moving in groovin like going around
one thing I want to point out here as well is this new aspect of creeping mist that came in and
you can combine this with the grieves of the empty tomb so this new aspect you know we heard that
Nuckert players want mobility and boy did we give you mobility so what this does is when you
evade during first one you get a vague cool down reduction so you evade more but when you evade
during blood mist you travel twice as far and both when you enter and exit blood mist it
resects your evade cool down and one of the things that makes this crazy where we might actually
be crazy and I hope we don't have to revisit this but we're going to see is that that reset of
your vade cool down counts for all of your charges of evade so what this means is and we have a video
is that you can evade five times then evade in blood mist and then evade five more times
so see here then you're evading in blood mist and you're leaving behind that desiccrated
ground everywhere and just moving around you know yeah it's like a nice skating right so every
time you cast blood mist you're going to be getting ten of aides it's silly and hilarious um
but we're playing it in the game and I hope we don't regret it
Nekros are going to be zoom it yeah they're going to be zooming with this so wow
yeah so that's kind of our preview of our uniques and kind of what's coming into the game again
we're pretty excited about it I think it's going to be pretty cool yeah but yeah professor Adam
Jackson take him bow that is that is incredible and again that's not even everything there's a lot
of stuff that we need to do at that level patch notes after the stream we will be showing
comparison to every single unique in their changes from season 40 season five
so you can go in there and check it all those changes but that was a great great overview
of all those changes that is really really exciting uh this brings us to our Q&A portion of the show
let's all shift our legs at the same time yeah yeah uh so we've been following along in twitch chat
and we've picked out a bunch of questions and we're going to kick it off tossing it over to Mr. Dan Tangoey
how do reward choices work in multiplayer parties for infernal hordes does the leader choose
their award for everyone or can each player choose all right so yeah let's talk about this um in
the infernal hordes when you're collecting burning aether uh each individual collects their own
burning ether and we did this for the very reason that you're you're asking questions about we
wanted players to be able to go in and choose the rewards that they want to choose not necessarily
what somebody else gets to first or what the party leader wants so every individual party member
will have their own choice at rewards awesome awesome thanks for the honest though
um mark is you got to read the names oh my goodness did i did i not say no trick
there is right i won't forget you thank you out of him
aldrick thank you for that question
i'll be in question or is it stickler for that view yeah no it's a great thing to call out
because our next question is from dartless oh actually i think we have a question here on the
the the lower third which is uh this one this one i we've gotten a lot of these questions so i do
when i actually addressed this one this is when are we going to hear more about vessel of hatred
because you know you know we just had the spirit born reveal we we showed off the spirit born i
will note that uh we also are going to be at gamescom there's actually some gamescom news that
came out this morning uh the spirit born will be playable at gamescoms which go to the xbox
but if you'll be able to play it there so if you're you're you're attending that show be really
awesome there's actually going to be more news coming out uh uh at that time so of course
tune in and and i will say like you guys have only heard a very small
now there's a lot yeah it's fraction of what's coming in yeah uh of uh vessel of hatred so we're
really excited for gamescom so guys will hear more uh then so stay tuned yeah grab your tickets
of coming to gamescom because we'll be there i'll be super sure exactly go to germany go to germany
come to clon come to clon um there was some people confused and chat uh this is a question from
dartless who was saying we can temper unique's now did i miss hear that maybe that was a mistake
being said so yeah hundred times clear cannot temper unique's we want them to be different in that
they do not engage with that system at least for now um but no you're going to be what we what
i wanted to say or be clarified is that you can get tempering aphixes on unique's like they
they'll just drop with those aphixes or whatever but you can't like go to the to the box with them
and maybe lay them in that way you can't temper them not you cool cool thanks for clarifying that
uh at um yeah do do do do uh it's doffy has a question for a dantangue are there any plans to
continue iterating on the infernal hordes in the future since it's a permanent addition are
there going to be more boons and bains coming yeah that's uh uh a great question and yeah just to
reiterate what you'd pointed out there uh this is an eternal realm feature that's going to appear
in the game forevermore and so this is just the first version of it i mean you think back to
what hell tide was in the base game and how we've iterated on that over time to get it to where it is
uh we're going to continue investing similar levels of effort into the infernal hordes too
and so uh boons and bains is something we heard a lot about uh feedback uh during the ptr
and so we absolutely want to make more improvements to the uh the boons and bains and so stay tuned
that's not going to hit in season five uh but we'll we'll figure out where we can get it in in
future seasons awesome great to hear that we're going to continue uh tinkering on that feature in
the in the seasons to come uh got a really interesting question from Mano underscore imp
with regards to those mano imp we know mano with regards to the damage increase per class resource
they're asking is the spirit borne getting one percent damage at seven points if it's their
main stat uh just because they have a lower amount of weapons yeah uh tbd tbd i don't want to go
on a map on spirit borne yet but uh they'll be getting similar treatment to all the other stuff
all of this is kind of evergreen so awesome awesome uh luke we luke we uh when will we see the
overhaul of the paragon system uh would you consider removing the paragon limit uh
there are going to be changes to paragon but we aren't talking about uh those changes
awesome yep awesome tbd tbd stay tuned uh love this name chicken wing 929 uh
can the reputation rewards for season season the infernal hordes be earned on only one character or
all your seasonal characters um i believe it's uh uh uh all characters similar to what we have for
season four uh so you can actually go back in and just play like hey go through the reputation
board and then uh get another respondent's bark you want to have a question really that's
truly the question yeah yeah so you can you can get pretty sure it's church yeah yeah yeah nice
um systematic 5k atom Jackson will our existing uniques be updated with these new unique changes
yeah we we get this everywhere on that we update that makes the same rules as always which is
the unique power when we update that is your your existing uniques will get that right so when
we increase your damage range or whatever that's going to get but the stats those are going to be
legacy on any items that exist so you're going to have to re-farm your unique to get the new stats
that are on them and that's kind of the way that they're going to work going forward
unless you say otherwise yeah it's it's just how things work under the hood um from when we do changes
on them so yeah nice um pudge uh pudge underscore BP are there any plans for clan rework slash
improvements um there are i know there are some uh changes coming for uh some social features we're
just not ready to talk about them now uh but you'll you guys will hear about them soon awesome awesome
uh this one's kind of a design philosophy question for atom Jackson sure Evan's 423 wants to know
how future proof is the system of static uniques when adding new slash better tempering effects
in new content how future proof or static uniques when adding new tempers um let me think
semi right because like i think it is something where if we add like new tempers or new
affixes or whatever we will probably need to go back and update uniques that that we wanted to
apply to and make it you know work again um our hope is that these uniques are going to be pretty
like future proof in that they're going to be very meaty in the amount of power that they give you
um they're also extremely thematic but i think we do reserve the right like if hey if we find a new
idea for uh existing passive or existing tempering that that is introduced to the game and we
want to put it on we we can do that um i will say also one thing that we want to do more is like
just come up with really crazy new ones and aren't even really tempering recipes but just like
crazy effects right like blood howl grand stealth or you drain more with your you know blood
search stuff like that so i would expect we'll probably be updating them as we go forward not
probably as dramatically as this all at once but i i foresee this probably likely yeah nice yeah
always tinkering always updating uh yeah speaking which uh about tempering one thing that we forgot
to mention and i know we mentioned it the ptr stream last time i'm sorry my earpiece just keeps falling
off uh so it's like i'm like scratching my ear but i'm not uh the uh greater af i know there's a lot
of like feedback after season four regarding um uh tempering and potentially breaking items and
one update that we talked about during the ptr stream and i want to mention it wasn't in ptr but
is in uh season five specifically is uh greater aphixes will actually get additional
temperary roles on them based on the greater aphix you know quality of of what they are so uh for
for um like like greater aphix one star ones you'll end up getting one additional temperary
role yeah um and then it grows by how many stars that there are so that is going in season five so
and i i we mentioned it last time i just wanted to reiterate it's like actually for out you
should mention it sweet stuff yeah great great to mention that item that's awesome uh we've got a uh
easy one here from z weapons uh what is a mythic unique there was a purple item
yeah you could tune into our last three four but yeah um basically what was uber unique
there's what people call them um it's basically like you know the really best items in the game
that have like perfect stats and everything we rebranded them to mythic uniques they now have
their own special color special beam when they drop they just got a whole treatment to really
make them feel like the the penultimate items that that they are pretty good yeah yeah that's
awesome uh so fees zero two five seven uh are they going to make it so that we can pre-download the
update or will it be available only on the sixth that's a great question let's go based off uh feedback
from season four's launch the patch will be available to download roughly an hour before season
three infernal hordes launches so that season goes live at ten am and roughly an hour before
you'll be able to pre-download the patch to get into the game and get ready for the season yeah
i know i know a lot of people are probably going like we're not multiple days and things like that
we're getting there we're trying no i know it's it's it's uh we we got a lot of feedback about you
know how things started immediately on the like you could download and actually start the season
of course we want to make sure that people can be as prepared as possible so uh one hour before the
season starts like you should be able to actually download and get that all prepared so like soon
is uh the season the the time for the season began which is roughly like ten a and a specific on
on the day of uh you you can just jump in and without needing to download so yeah yeah
uh skull mtv hey great job thanks uh any plans to rework master working and back it's higher cost
but you know you can choose upgrades and tempering to make these systems have less rng um nothing to
announce at this time uh we definitely have heard the feedback we are starting with the first step of
like you know one of the things that we know feels really bad for players like i got a uh how do i say
the more greater affixes you have on an item the higher stress and investment you have to like make
it work the way that you want so we are relaxing that make it a little bit easier um another thing
we're thinking about that's a little wider is like the tempering recipes making them have like
the rion average instead of four more um some that we're talking about moving towards but nothing like
of overhauling the system and doing a major change at this time that we have to announce cool thanks
Adam uh dan tangway from holy smokes uh their name isn't for holy smokes their name is dan
i thought i was dan tangway asking a question and i was like wait what no no no uh their name is
froto boulson froto boulson but all the ozer zeros uh how does the infernal hordes work in groups
uh do you need one come only one compass per group um so the infernal hordes you only need one
compass per group in order to be able to get in yeah sweet just like uh niamaric dungeon sigils
awesome all right revask any news on reworked niamaric dungeons
nothing nothing to announce nothing to announce yeah sweet uh greens on b studios can we expect
cool new trans mox and season five from salvaging items um i am not sure i know like wait the
the season five does have over has a lot of new legendary aspects and unique like there's like
fifty new legendary aspects and you expect to be added into season five so there's a lot of
of like uh more the the the back end type of stuff that that affects a more so on the gameplay
but i'm not exactly sure if there's a ton coming up uh so we can actually uh there are a couple of
new uniques and help uh that you can earn that will have all new looks to them that you can sell
the jerry go oh how's magic yep bam there you go dan the savior from albany there you go
brodo bolson uh hot pancakes are there still plans for rare in magic items i guess in terms of
like a a rework or changing their functionality in any way yeah i'd say uh nothing to announce today
for that yeah cool nice do do do do do all right uh check through mac and d's uh can we expect
skill trees or support gems to change the way skills work can we expect skill trees or support gems
to change the way the skill works i mean we're not doing any skill tree overhaul right now in season five
um i do think we have talked a bit on on the team about having the desire of the upgrades for
skills being like more impactful and really impactful um nothing to announce today but it is
something that is on our radar and i think it's cool i think one example that that we talk about
along the team is like the kick upgrade for the barbarian where normally you know when we
originally designing kick it was this idea that you have this like skill where you hit an enemy you
care about the geometry of the place around you you want to hit them into the wall and then they
get knocked down take a bunch of damage and all this stuff um that part hasn't really played i
think as well because the pace of our game is so fast but one of the upgrades for kick um especially
i remember in the early beta like way before maybe it was alpha even um kick you know it converts
kick from this cool down based geometry skill into just a powerhouse where it just spends all your
resource and does a buttload of damage to it enemy um and it was like one-shotting world bosses and
stuff like it was it was hilarious i think i remember that but the skill still has that upgrade but
i referenced that upgrade a lot because i think it's really cool when you can convert a skill to like
used to be cool down and now isn't or used to be about this utility and now it's just damage or
vice versa where like really changes what a skill does um we think it's really cool uh it
definitely would be a lot of work to like do that to every skill but i think it's something that's
worth talking about and pursuing so it is on our radar something to do but nothing to announce today
for awesome that's really cool things out of yeah uh that brings us to the end of our q&a so i
want to give a huge thank you to adam and adam and dan asking all those questions out of squared
um how squared back and action hey just like the uh ptr stream yeah screw those joes
yeah damn it name is kidding and that brings us to the end of our season the infernal hordes developer
update stream just a few notes before we close out the stream just want to take a moment to thank
everyone for tuning into our spirit borne showcase a few weeks back yeah uh it was really cool to
show off that new class it was such a huge moment for the team uh so really want to thank you all
for coming to check that out and if you want to play the spirit borne and person as adam mentioned
earlier we are going to be a games comp so get your tickets come to games comm in cologne, Germany
and
um
uh just went up through the roof um but speaking of the spirit borne uh you can pre-purchase
vessel of hatred today and instantly oh oh oh can they hear audio oh can everybody hear us
twitch chat where did the sound go okay we're good now we're good now we're good all right thank you
chat for for keeping us up to date uh speaking of the spirit borne you can pre-purchase vessel of
hatred today to get instant access to some items in game before the expansion goes live this October
for season the infernal hordes this season goes live on august 6th at 10am the patch will be
available for pre-download roughly an hour before and 10am is in pacific time uh for anyone wondering
patch will be available for pre pre-download about an hour before the season goes live so you can
get in and get ready for the season to start uh the 150 patch notes are going to go live after
this stream uh for season five so for anything we talked about uh across the stream today that'll
be available and all the unique and every time yeah check out those gifts they're pretty they're pretty
spiffy teamwork pretty hard on those we also had the season infernal hordes deep dive blog go live
earlier this week so a ton of information there as well uh stick around after this stream because
we're gonna be raiding uh some diablo content creator so go and check them out
for adam adam and mr. dantangway and albany thank you guys so much for joining us uh for this
developer update stream today yeah thank you so much really awesome to go through all the changes
and uh from all of us here thank you so much uh to everyone at home for watching and checking out
the stream and we will see you all in sanctuary yeah yeah unique whoo
uh