Music
I'm going to go to the next room.
In Vessel of Hatred, we travel south to Nahantu,
a region with both deep ancient jungles and vast sprawling plains.
It's the last stretch of land in Sanctuary's eastern continent,
and we've packed it full of experiences for every type of player.
In this expansion, there's a whole lot to explore
under the dark canopy of Nahantu.
Nahantu is the southernmost region of the eastern continent
that Diablo Forest has been taking place in.
It's the last region that we haven't visited yet,
so far in the game.
But it is one that we've been to before in Diablo.
There's lots of new areas.
We have six in total.
Four of them are jungle themed,
and then we have two that are red rock, canyon,
but each one of them has their own unique identity.
When you first arrive in Nahantu,
you're in this place called Lingering Hatred.
This is a high tree tops canopies,
where you're almost walking amongst the branches
high above the jungle floor.
Imagine a thick canopy that the light is just barely poking through.
The whole area has been infected by this thing called the Hollows infestation.
The Hollows are a new enemy that's associated with Mifisto.
They themselves are kind of like a tar-like substance creature
born straight out of the depths of hell.
It feels a little twisted,
there's a sickness to the area itself.
Humans have ventured into this deep part of the jungle
where there's all this poisonous plants and flora.
The dregs actually started experimenting
with eating these hallucinogens,
and it put them into this aggressive psycho rage.
The dregs were pretty fun,
because we were able to push more variety into Monster Family.
You have one of these tall dregs,
and then half of a body of another dreg on top of it,
kind of controlling it,
and telling it where to go,
and tossing poisonous bombs at the player.
When you come across, it's very memorable.
And then we've also got the area of Tengansi,
where you've got the Tengansi Plateau,
which is full of these red rocked plateaus and canyons.
Imagine getting up above the land.
Those gigantic walls have pockets inside,
where monsters could live.
It offered up a lot of opportunity to bring back
a Monster Family like the Lucunite.
We're bringing them back in a new way here
as a fully fleshed out Monster Family with multiple classes.
What a more brute force looks like.
What a cast it looks like.
They are very much apex predators,
and we're definitely in their territory.
And then there's a little sub-area called the Skittering Earth.
The name alone makes your skin crawl.
It's bug infested,
and you can see how the bugs have destroyed the jungles
and kind of input their influence on it.
Within the field of giants,
you have these giant corpses of these long dead demons
that humans have begun to mine away out for their resources.
While they've got a lot of use out of them,
they're also toxic to the land around it.
The notion of massive demons walking sanctuary a thousand years ago
is really thought provoking.
Plateaus also got just this beautiful color scheme to the lighting.
It's really lovely to be there.
And then horrific at the same time.
You know it's great.
The mercenaries in Vessel of Hatred are a group of people who
we like to describe as ordinary people with extraordinary skills.
They have the same level of will to fight against the demons of hell.
And there's four mercs that you can collect over the course of the campaign.
It starts with here a blacksmith and a shield bear is a more defensive fighter.
He's up to go in there and soak up damage.
It uses his shield as a bulwark against the enemy.
Meet him early on in the campaign,
and he's one who introduces you to the mercenary network.
You end up finding acquisition quests for three other mercs
that you can find throughout the course of the story.
Subo the Drunken Archer is going to work really well for people who want
someone who's out of the main melee in the back offering utility
and that kind of range supports.
And we have Variana, a berserker cron who's a melee combat fighter,
a close range.
They've got a really cool combat meter, a massacre meter,
where you need to keep killing enemies to get the meter to be filled.
Just got a bunch of really interesting utility skills that you can kind of build him.
Finally we have the demon child Aldkin,
who's a magic user who can transform himself from human form to demon form,
and join you in combat.
There's this really great reinforcement ability where you can take one of the mercenary skills
and attach it to one of your powers so that when you use that skill,
it calls them in to do a specific skill.
With the mercenaries for Vessel of Hatred,
one of the things we are expanding on is the skill tree.
For Diablo III you had a very basic type of mercenary,
but this time you can actually push a little bit more into the skill tree
and make the mercenary the way you would want to play.
Going through each mercenary progression arc and outfitting their skill tree
so that it's complementary to your character build,
I think that's where the fun in the mercenary system really lies.
The Dark Citadel is a new and game feature that's coming in Vessel of Hatred.
It's an entirely a whole operative, player experience.
All the mechanics within it and are based around you working together
with your party members to solve the challenges and face the first cosrera hordes within.
One of the outcomes of the major wars is this giant crater
and all the souls that were kind of lost in it from those wars.
The goal of the first cosrera who are kind of the original cosrera,
they're using the powers within the Citadel found within this crater
to perform experiments to try and bring back that Dark God.
Only recently people have started going missing.
They head into the cosrera region, they disappear never to be seen again.
So it's clear that whatever their planning is about to come to fruition
and your job is the players to get in there and stop it.
Citadel is a place where we take what is the best part of Diablo,
combat, and we test it in a different way,
which is adding in cooperative mechanics that you have to manage on top of that.
For example, a boss has an attack and as a player,
you have to collect an item that allows you to reflect the attack back at him.
So there's a little bit of a twitch level mechanic there,
we actually have to time your reaction shot.
What's interesting about it is when you get multiple people in there
where each responsible for reflecting that shot once,
so we all have to master the timing of that move.
You can't do that kind of thing without coordinating as a team
and that's sort of the example of what Citadel gameplay feels like.
When designing the Citadel, we designed a lot of really cool bosses.
And so one of the things that we did is we took that design
and made like armor sets for each of the classes.
That way you feel like you took their armor
and you feel like you're wearing a little bit of them after your victory.
We also have a currency that's dedicated to Citadel
where as you play through, a vendor can be interacted with
to buy custom cosmetics that are unique to the Citadel.
You can play with two people, but the ideal experience is for four.
In order to facilitate that, we've built an all new party finder feature
and the community has been pretty vocal about wanting this for a long time.
It made a lot of sense to us to pair it with this new Citadel mode.
It really is an activity that's geared towards people
who love to play together with their friends or with strangers
and enjoy that cooperative gameplay.
I cannot wait for players to get into the world.
I'm really just excited for people to see all the little hidden
storytelling elements that the team has fit in.
There's interesting things to find in the scene, discover around every corner.
And it's just a really great experience getting to explore and how to.
I'm going to show you how to play the new Citadel mode.
Hello, Diablo community.
Welcome to another Campfire Chat.
This is the Patch 2.0 Campfire Chat for PTR.
As you guys can see, we're in a little bit of a new environment.
We're all doing this from home.
We had to do a quick last minute pivot about 24 hours ago.
I was struck by some con flu after games calm.
But I just wanted to give a quick shout out to our production teams
behind the scenes.
Lucas Jaden Rich, they made a quick pivot to allow us to do this
and for us to be safe.
And to be able to still give you guys this exciting information
for Patch 2.0.
I'm going to show you how to play the new Citadel mode.
To lead us off, I do want us to do some quick intros for everyone
here on the actual panel.
So Colin, would you like to start off the ad intros?
Yeah, sure.
I'm Colin on the design team.
Hello, I'm Aislin Hall.
I'm a systems designer with a focus on live balance.
Hey everyone, I'm Charles Dunn.
I'm a class designer working on the live balance for Diablo 4.
Hey everyone, I'm Jeevin Sadoo.
And I also work on the systems team.
Awesome.
So we got a whole panel here way more than what we normally have
because we have so much to actually cover.
We do want to jump into things pretty immediately.
But I did want to recap really quickly.
Obviously, last week we were at Gamescom.
We made some really big announcements for Vessel of hatred
where we announced, you know, the mercenaries
that will be coming to Vessel of hatred,
along with how that system works with like reinforcements.
It's like a new take of how mercenaries play within Diablo,
especially since mercenaries has such a storied history
within the franchise itself.
And of course, we also talked about the cure ass under city
and the dark citadel, along with the party finder feature
that players will be able to actually partake in with Vessel of hatred
and use that for dark citadel and other features within the game.
We do actually have a blog up on Diablo 4.com
that does do a good deep dive across all of those specific items.
So you guys can actually check that out.
But we have a packed agenda today.
This will be a long one.
So we hope that everyone will sit down and grab a snack
and join us as we talk about some pretty large systemic changes
that we'll be coming with Diablo 4.
Along with some new stuff that we'll be sharing as well.
That we'll also be coming with Diablo 4.
So we're going to start off with some progression updates.
We're going to move off into some class and balance changes,
along with some quality of life updates.
And then we'll kind of cap it off with a cool new announcement
that will be coming with Vessel of hatred.
So, Aisling, Colin, I know you guys want to jump into some of these big progression changes
that you guys were talking about last week.
So take it away.
Yeah, thanks Adam.
And I'm sure everyone has no idea what the big surprise is at the end.
So yeah, right.
So yeah, let's jump into the progression.
So when we launched the game,
we had a sort of vision for the game that we felt like was really fun to play through once,
where you'd sort of traverse through these world tiers
and you'd be gaining new sacred items rarely.
And then you'd be getting ancestral items when hopping into World Tier 4.
And as we played the game more and more and as we've gotten feedback,
that necessarily hasn't really been super fun.
So we've sped up a lot of the progression to sort of get you into that space
that where you feel powerful,
where you have autonomy over your choice in terms of difficulty and challenge and reward.
Diablo is all about that progression, right,
and sort of blasting and feeling efficient.
So we wanted to take a step back after looking at itemization.
We've added a ton of itemization progression that we think is feeling pretty good.
There's a lot of ways to customize your character.
There's a lot of ways to progress your itemization.
And we wanted to look at other aspects of the game.
So that came in the form of like what hasn't aged super well,
what are the things that we really enjoy and we see that you all enjoy
and doubling down on that.
So two, those things are difficulty and overall just character progression
from your paragons, your glyphs, etc.
And we've sort of taken the approach of like really doubling down and embracing
again what has been really fun, right, blasting, being efficient,
having control over your challenge and reward, right.
Profane Minecages is awesome when you can stack it to three
and you can hop into those health ties and just start getting tons of experience
and reward for pushing that challenge.
Keyed Dungeons, like Nightmare Dungeons and Frontal Hords,
really pretty much every endgame in the system at this point
has a tearing system associated with it.
And we think that's like pretty indicative of like what has been fun
and we want to embrace that.
And part of that is that idea of I can push really hard
to get more efficiency, part of that's conquering milestones, right.
It's really good.
It's a ton of fun to hop into World Tier III early.
I think I hopped in at level 25 and the latest release just to see
if I could do it and it was a ton of fun.
And it's sort of all about embracing that gaining power
in multiple ways, feeling super powerful.
And then another thing that we really wanted to look at in terms
of making this better is alting.
We made a change to make it so that the mythic uniques
could be equipped at level 35.
And if you've done that, it's really bad.
It's an experience where you know, roll a barbarian,
slap a ground fought there on them.
And you just blast through the leveling experience
and it's a ton of fun.
That being said, we've added tons of sort of power to the equation.
And we wanted to make sure that we also gave you more autonomy
to sort of challenge yourself with all that new power.
And we're adding a ton of new power and the expansion as well.
So to cover it again, we want to look at expanding the progression
in other areas of the game, come patch 2.0.
So with that, Aislin actually has a bunch of exciting changes
to talk about here.
I do. Thank you, Colin.
Okay, everyone.
I want you to put on your thinking caps
because we have a lot of details to cover.
So buckle up.
We in fact have a topic screen here
because there's so many things regarding progression
that we're going to be talking about today.
So the way that we're approaching this presentation is
we're basically going to be bringing you through
what a character's journey would actually look like, you know,
starting by talking about the character journey
and then talking about some difficulty tier changes that are coming.
And then going deeper into, you know,
how you're going to be gaining more rewards
from those sad difficulty tiers.
So, yeah, without further ado,
let's simply jump in and get started with the character journey.
Okay, so some changes coming to how you're going to be leveling up.
There's going to be a level adjustment, first of all,
coming to patch 2.0.
Right now in the live game, you know, you go from character level 1 to 50.
Those are your skill point levels.
And then every level after 50 is a Paragon level
where you're earning four Paragon points per Paragon level.
We're going to be splitting those out in patch 2.0.
And so you're going to earn Paragon points
which are going to be separate from your character level.
Levels 1 to 50 represent those character levels.
And there's also going to be a new max character level,
quote unquote, of level 60.
And that means that you are going to be earning 10 more skill points
from what you had been earning pre-patch 2.0.
There's also going to be a reimagined pace to the leveling journey.
So we have a lot of new difficulty tiers
that are being added to the game more on that soon.
But effectively, lower difficulty tiers
are going to be offering you a slower pace
if you're in your player.
You just want a very casual chill experience.
But you're going to be able to bump it up if you want to.
Like if you're engaging with tempering,
you're engaging with all these systems
that are making your character stronger,
and you want something to test that against,
we are aiming to give that to you.
And these difficulty tiers are going to be offering you improved efficiency,
improved rewards, and the goal is to improve your pace.
You can blast through these difficulties.
Yeah, this is a lot of work.
The mind cages, right?
Like we sort of heard, yeah, we heard you like mind cages
so we put it in the game systemically.
Like from whispers to Hell Tide,
literally everything in the world,
like maybe like doing dungeons.
And really, it's sort of like giving players that choice
to do what they want.
And it's not just Hell Tide now that can push that difficulty.
Yeah, totally.
Like we were just playing on the development team
and we were playing in Hell Tides and playing with mind cages.
And we were like, this is great.
Like I want to just be able to do this,
or like have this option available to me,
like basically whenever I'm playing.
So that's a big part of these changes.
Moving on here to the number adjustments.
So as a lot of you guys found in footage,
yes, there is a pretty substantial number adjustment.
So a big part of this is we want to make sure
that there's room for growth.
And we're adding a lot of player power in Patch 2.0
and Festival of Hatred.
And we want to make sure that numbers don't get so crazy,
that we cannot even fathom them.
Right?
And so a big part of this is giving us a good starting point
in Patch 2.0, where we can't afford to grow numbers.
Yeah.
So yeah.
I think it's really important to have numbers that are like,
when you're doing damage numbers to see ones that are meaningful to you.
If you're increasing your damage like even 10x,
but it's taken it from like an eight or nine digit number to a 10 digit number,
it's almost impossible to see that kind of growth in player power.
So with numbers that are more readable on screen,
that A makes it much more obvious when you're getting more powerful
and just makes the game as a whole easier to kind of comprehend.
Totally.
Yeah.
And it's important to note that like this is relative in that we're not slowing you down in any way.
This is purely sort of one of those adjustments that we're making to ensure that you can have more growth in the end game.
We're not at the top end nerfing things like crit chance or CDR.
Really, this is all about having actually like sort of what we set out to do
and we launch the game and have more grounded numbers for longer.
That's not to say that you aren't going to get insane in the deep end game, right?
Yeah.
You're still going to have a lot of power to game.
And yeah, finally, just going back to this first bullet here on this slide.
We're going to talk more about Paragon later,
but for now we're going to focus on some other things.
So sit tight.
Okay, let's talk about how monsters are changing.
So we've streamlined monster health and damage in a pretty big way.
We took a look at how monsters gain health and how they gain damage over different difficulty tiers.
And we've really like honed in and kind of universalized our approach to how they're gaining power throughout your character experience.
And this is going to be applying to all monster types, you know, normal monsters, minions, which are elites, little buddies,
elites themselves, and of course bosses.
And all of these monsters now have health that's relative to their normal monster counterpart on any given like difficulty tier.
And what this does is it really helps smooth difficulty progression and the difficulty of any experience that you're currently in.
Secondly, we have some changes to monster scaling.
Monsters are going to scale to a pit here, and we're going to talk more about that as well pretty soon too.
So sit tight.
And the big thing here is that monsters are always going to match the player level now.
So on live, we have a world where monsters can be, you know, a hundred levels offset of you and anywhere in between.
And that can be fairly hard to understand.
And so a big part of this pass is kind of removing that elements of the game so that we can focus on what difficulty we're currently in and using that as the judge of how hard or how easy or wherever in between the content you're currently in.
And finally, we have some pretty cool combat tuning changes.
So we've taken a lot of looks at, you know, like the moment to moment combat pacing in the game.
And monster mechanics across the board have been adjusted to really hone in on player momentum.
You know, you're here to slide our demons. We want you to move quickly through the game.
And we don't necessarily want monsters to be slowing you down, especially normal monsters.
And to achieve this, you know, we've reduced instances of getting one shot out of nowhere.
And we've also adjusted boss HP so that they're not quite as grindy after you're moving in from, you know, after blasting down AOE packs in the pit, for example.
Yeah, definitely.
Great. I'll go ahead, Charles.
Yeah, they're just saying, right, that's always been the pain point in the pit so far is like, hey, you're really strong.
You blast through most of the dungeon and then you get up to the boss and the boss takes, you know, five minutes or more.
That's just like such a slog. So we're definitely making sure it's a more consistent experience in a given difficulty tier.
You're going to have a more consistent experience across boss and another portion of the game.
Yeah, and we've already taken a lot of steps towards this and brief the one of the previous seasons.
We said it so that you wouldn't get armor cap penalties as the monsters leveled higher than you, right?
So this is really just sort of consolidating a lot of the, I'm going to get shit for the Blizzard math on the back end to make sure that like a lot of the things are really being reworked on the back end to address the problems we see online with the crazy exponential scaling of boss health from like four different multipliers.
And the crazy exponential damage that some of the monsters are getting.
Yes, the corpse, both, of course, dying in one shot from off screen.
A lot of those things should be much more consistent as you're climbing through those difficulty tiers which we're going to talk more about in the future or in this presentation.
Very soon, in fact, like right now, difficulty.
Let's talk about it.
So this is our beautiful Blizzard illustration, if you will.
Art by Colin.
Thank you very much.
That's a Colin.
Yeah.
We've got a lot of art for this.
This is art.
What are you talking about?
Yeah, this is beautiful.
Modern art.
Yeah, you can see we have the big bone boss very, very sad that the current state of things up there.
So what this is basically illustrating is that there are basically brackets right now on live where various content is relevant.
You have world bosses that stay relevant for a certain amount of time.
You have hell tide that stays relevant, you know, maybe a little bit longer than world bosses do.
Then you have world tiers one and two.
Then you have world tier three, which is very sad.
Sorry, world tier three.
Yeah.
And then world tier four.
You like to find glass, you can see it.
Yeah, yeah, maybe if you look really closely, you can see how long it takes to go through world tier three.
And then world tier four, which has like a bit of a tale, but still pretty short.
And then we compare it to like where our characters power currently exists, which is, you know, you've got level one to one hundred.
And then of course, your journey throughout all of the pit tiers.
And basically what this is illustrating is a lot of these content types fall off.
World bosses don't stay relevant forever.
Hell tide doesn't stay relevant forever.
The world tiers you're living on in the open world don't stay relevant.
And eventually it simply becomes about running the pit.
And that's the place where you can judge your character's strength.
We don't necessarily want the game to work that way.
We want a lot of activities to stay fun and interesting and engaging for as long as possible.
And so to accomplish that, we've got some pretty big changes coming to difficulty tiers.
So let's dive into the meat and potatoes of this talking about pit arbitration.
And that's just a fancy way of basically saying that the pit is going to be something behind the scenes that's setting the pace of all difficulty in the game across all content types.
So pit tiers are going to match difficulty tiers.
There's going to be five pit tiers per standard difficulty, which is just encapsulating four new world tiers pre level 60, which are normal hard expert and penitent.
And then there will be 15 pit tiers per torment difficulty.
And they're going to be four torment difficulty tiers, one, two, three, and four.
Difficulty tiers are going to derive monster health damage and intensity from the pit tier that is associated with that difficulty tier.
And I know that's a little complicated, but we're going to have some some supporting stuff to show what this means a little better pretty soon.
And I do want to call out intensity here. Colin, do you want to talk about monster intensity raising between difficulty tiers?
Yeah, so intensity is something we played around with in the base game and it sprinkled out throughout throughout the game.
But when what intensity is is it's a backend system that controls monster aggressiveness as well as monster intelligence.
So by aggressiveness, it's things like they attack faster. They have lower cooldowns. They move faster.
And then intelligence is they predict your movement more. They'll face you more. So you know, it has a big swing.
It's actually going to try and track you a little bit more accurately.
So it's not just the health and damage that's going up through these difficulty tiers.
The monsters are actually becoming a little bit more dynamic and fast-paced.
And we think that feels pretty good, especially when it's sort of scaling through the new difficulties here, system that we have.
Yeah, this is something we currently we do have on on the live game, but you know in the new patch 2.0, you're really going to feel that difference.
Currently, feel a little bit of difference in between the different world tiers. And that's just going to be magnified.
And your moment moment combat is it's not just going to be higher numbers. The moment moment will feel different and harder at these higher torment difficulties.
Yep, they're going to become bigger jerks as you said difficulties.
Alright, so let's talk about difficulty gating. So this is basically how people are going to be moving through these different difficulty tiers.
So the pit is going to unlock once you hit character level 60, which is the new maximum character level in patch 2.0.
So pit tiers associated with standard difficulties are going to unlock immediately, which is pit tiers 1 through 20.
You're going to be able to challenge all of those immediately once your max level.
And you're going to need to beat pit tier 20 to unlock the first torment tier.
Once you beat pit tier 20, you're allowed to go into the overworld on torment 1.
And then as we see here, there are 15 pit tiers per torment difficulties. So to unlock torment 2, you would then need to progress through the pit and beat pit tier 35,
which point you can now go into torment 2 in all other activities, so on and so forth.
So this is basically creating a, sorry, go ahead, gone.
Oh, I was going to jump in and say like what's kind of interesting is like torment 1.
You can think about as world tier 3 today. And what we're sort of doing is essentially saying now that level cap is 60.
You actually can find some of the best items in the game very early, right?
Imagine if you were able to just start finding the best items in the game in world tier 3.
That's really sort of what we're talking about here.
We're really speeding up when you can actually get to the end game where we've added things like the pit, we've added things like nightmare dungeons and more end game activities for you to engage with and item modification systems.
So it really is sort of getting you into the fun faster, which also makes alting a lot more cool, right?
It's way easier to sort of get to that point where all right, I'm in the end game.
I'm going to start looking for awesome items. I'm going to start modifying my items.
So we think that that like sort of represents a pretty substantial change to how you play the game.
Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
I'm wondering why we kind of built it around the pit.
You know, and why we associated difficulty with the pit.
How do y'all think about that?
Yeah, so right now the pit is a fantastic razor to judge your character against.
And I think that this overhaul is effectively turning the pit into the game's backbone to use kind of a gruesome term, but you know, we're Diablo, so whatever.
It's basically turning the pit into the game's backbone of like difficulty and all other difficulties is kind of derived from that.
And it gives us a very predictable and understandable pace for you to experience all other activities in the game based on the pit's difficulty.
Yeah, not that razor is great for pushing difficulty, right?
You think about how part of what's really fun again about Diablo is that feeling of progression and that feeling of becoming powerful and taking on a big ass demon, killing it, getting awesome loot.
And what the pit is going to do is you're going to push that difficulty then unlock new torment heroes, which is going to unlock more efficiency for you.
And you can sort of think about it as like we've added not just a world tier 5, but a world tier 5 and 6 as part of this torment system.
And it's something we can continue to sort of evaluate and build on as characters become more powerful when we add new ways to sort of play through the system.
Yeah, I think it's also a lot about consistency across content, right?
Currently in the live game, we've got a lot of different levels of different types of things, right?
You've got nightmare dungeon keys, you've got pit levels, you've got infernal horde of tiers.
And we just kind of realize that hey, the pit is something that we have really good delineation between the different levels.
So you've got a wide spread of different tiers for that.
And that's something we can kind of peg difficulty against across the whole game to make a more consistent experience.
So if you're just going to get a certain difficulty tier, you're just going to get a more consistent experience across all activities.
Right. Yeah. Yeah. So like when you're on torment you, you're going to know that all content you're facing is on the level of torment here.
But right now on the live game, you know, you have a, you go into a pit tier 50 and you're like, okay, it's pit tier 50 difficulty.
And then you go into a nightmare dungeon tier 50 and it's a totally different difficulty.
And then you go into an infernal horde tier 8 and you're like, wait a minute, this is extremely hard compared to these other ones.
They're just not similar, right? And so we want to create a more level playing field so that difficulties easier to understand.
It's also like a common language and shared experience for everyone.
Yeah, that's definitely a benefit. And it's also in some sense leveling up all the activities.
I know that there's some people who really enjoy whispers, for example, and whispers just falls off.
Like if you're doing the pit in your level 100, your level 90 in the pit, like whispers are terrible, right?
Like you're not actually going to run whispers when you're pushing that deep into the game.
But now when sort of things are leveling up with torment here, as you have a place to go and sort of juice the efficiency from those different activities, if you like that activity.
Yeah. And this kind of carries over to other activities, not just whispers. It's like, you know, your health hides.
Yeah, the whole world is leveling. Yeah, like that it's, which is another thing like infertile hordes is something that obviously this is introduced in season five is coming back and is a permanent future within the game and is also going up with the rest of the content.
Yep.
All right. So let's talk a little more about the details of difficulty tiers.
So on the right hand side here, you can see this table. It's basically showing off the associated pit tier with any given difficulty tier.
So normal simply starts on one and then like we saw before, it goes up by five each time until you get to torment tiers, at which point it goes up by 15 each time.
So torment four lands on 65, torment one starts on 20.
And in light of this, we have changed the highest pit tier to be 100 down from 200.
And this doesn't mean that the pit tier 100 is going to be the same difficulty as it is on live. It's going to be harder.
So each pit tier you're going up is going to be harder than it was before effectively.
And we also have this pretty neat new system where we have smart keys.
And what that means is your things like infernal hordes or nightmare dungeons.
The keys to enter those activities are now going to follow the current difficulty tier that you're on.
So if I have an infernal hord key and I'm on torment three and I use it, I'm going to go into a torment three difficulty infernal hord.
And the same is true for nightmare dungeons.
So we're pretty excited about that change because again, coming back to all these things we've talked about where just kind of makes things easier.
Just makes life easier.
Yeah, it's a big quality of life change because on live right now you get a bunch of sacred, you know, nightmare dungeon keys.
And I'm sure everyone runs a ton of world three nightmare dungeons, right?
You definitely don't just pop in to get a sacred weapon.
But what I'm getting at is a lot of those keys just end up getting salvaged.
And now when all keys can sort of carry weight through various torment tiers, I'm getting a nightmare key.
Is this interesting choice of like, well, do I keep it or do I run it now because if I keep it, I can just use it at a later time.
And it's really about giving player the players that choice on when do they want to run this content.
We're not just going to invalidate that key and say, oh, in torment two, you need to find a new key to do this thing.
So I think it's definitely making key management a lot easier and more fluid as well.
And one thing on the pit, Hazeln that I think is really interesting is we definitely have rescaled the pit tier 100.
Tier 100 is sort of like our 200 on live.
But I think that's something that, you know, we definitely want to keep an eye out on PTR.
We don't have any problems with increasing the amount of pit tiers.
Like this is something we can definitely revisit if we see in PTR that you're all are insane, which is probably going to happen and you beat tier 100.
We really like that it's a razor and measuring stick and we don't want to take that away from players.
So that's something that we want to get PTR feedback and we could really use your help in breaking that system and seeing how far you can push it.
Oh, yeah, that's a great point.
And, you know, like we've said on this stream, there are going to be a lot of new player power opportunities coming.
And so, yeah, please show us what you got as they say.
Okay, so let's talk about, let's just dive a little more into the details.
I think we went over a lot of this stuff already, but we can kind of go through this slide here.
So, yeah, all content in the game exists within an expanded difficulty tier selection, like we were talking about.
I think an important thing to call it here is that, for example, penitent is if you're comparing it just to like kind of understand what it's going to look like relative to live right now.
Penitent is kind of going to end up being like World Tier 2.
If you added 45 monster levels on top of it.
And that's intended to kind of be the upper echelon of like pre max level character leveling.
So, if you really want to amp up the difficulty to as hard as you can make it like going onto penitent is where you want to be.
And this is just a lovely little visual aid.
We've got some cool new icons for these difficulty tiers.
Normal, hard, expert, and penitent. It gets harder as you keep going.
So, yeah, and we really want this to be like opt in not progression locked.
And so the vanilla Diablo 4 difficulty tiers kind of operated as progression tiers, right?
And what I mean by progression tiers is the moment you get to World Tier 3 as Colin was saying, like you unlock sacred items, maybe you go into a dungeon so you can find the sacred weapon.
And these things unlock so quickly and they drop so frequently that you kind of just got this huge burst of power.
And you never really got to feel that power.
And we want to make sure that you are like feeling each upgrade you get in the game and it feels really, really punchy.
And we really want these new difficulty tiers to be player guided.
Like we want you to be able to make your own decisions on when you're moving on to the next one and what's the right pace for you.
And of course these new difficulty tiers are going to give you improving rewards.
You're going to find more gold, more experience, and you're going to have more loot efficiency per difficulty tier.
So the higher difficulty tier you can fight the game on, the more efficient your experience is going to be effectively.
Yeah, I think that's really good.
Oh, good.
I just say that's really like what I view is the differentiating factor between what current before is and in the new patch 2.0 is if you enter Torment 1, you can find the best item in Torment 1.
You could complete your character and get full best install and everything.
It's just going to take a while.
It's going to be less efficient.
You're going to be getting less loot.
And whereas in the live game right now, you just can't find the best things in World Tier 3.
You are kind of obligated to go to that World Tier 4.
And now if you're able to clear higher Torments with efficiency, that's just going to be the best option for you to find the gear more efficiently.
But you aren't forced into Torment 4 to find the best items in the game.
Yeah, that's something I've really liked about it is that we get to start the end game a lot earlier with Torment.
There's nothing that you're excluded from.
There's no awesome piece of loot that you can't find by Torment 1.
And so you get to really start to test your build after it's gotten some real optimization.
I think much earlier into the journey than before.
I couldn't agree more.
It's a great example of what we're doing with the Latter Bosses or the Latter Bosses.
All of those unlock in Torment 1.
The cost to summon them is static.
It remains the same throughout all the Torment tiers.
And what that means is if you can beat it on a higher Torment tier, you're going to get way more unique.
So you get a handful of unique starting in Torment 1.
Way more unique than obviously Torment 4.
But the cost because it remains static, we're not going to ask you to get anything extra like a Stygian stone.
That just means as long as you can kill that Torment 4 boss, you're getting way more efficiency out of that boss.
And it really is like this, it feels amazing to sort of progress through those Torment tiers and just unlock way more power opportunity.
Yeah, we don't really have this differentiation of like a regular version of the late game boss, like a regular version of Duriel.
And then the tormented echo of Duriel.
That's not really a distinction that we have anymore.
Whereas like previously it would cost more materials to summon the tormented version, but it would give more rewards.
Now it's the same cost across the different Torment tiers.
It's just if you're able to conquer him on Torment 4, that's where you're going to get the absolute most bang for your buck in terms of resources in to loot out.
Yeah.
And I want to just double down on like, Torment 1 is where the end game starts now.
And just each Torment tier that you're ascending is making your end game, you know, more fun, basically.
Because you're going to be getting cooler stuff or more frequently.
Okay, so enough about difficulty tiers. Let's move on to some itemization changes.
So items strength, we have what I like to call the item power shuffle happening in patch 2.0.
Items with item power above 540 are going to be adjusted to 540.
And I fixed bands in lieu of this or in addition to this rather are going to be adjusted as well.
So yeah, items at the new character level max are going to they're going to max out at 750.
That's not actually the highest item power that's going to be in the game and we'll talk about that more in just a second.
But most items you're going to be finding once you hit max character level will be item power 750.
And you're going to be finding much better item power items from levels 51 to 59.
There's going to be big item power jumps.
So once you start leveling your character past those original 50 character levels, you're going to start finding a lot better gear.
Okay, so let's take a look at what an ancestral item looks like in patch 2.0.
Oh, okay, we yeah, let's let's take a look here real quick.
So you'll notice here that this item has 800 item power, which is 50 higher than the max 750 that I was talking about before.
You'll also notice on the right hand side that that is the torment icon.
So ancestral items can be found starting on torment one.
They're going to become more frequent as you ascend torment difficulties, but they're still going to stay pretty rare throughout all torment levels.
You'll also notice that the greater a fix on this item is highlighted.
That is because now whenever you find an ancestral item, they're always going to have one greater a fix.
They can roll with more, but they will be guaranteed a single one every single time.
So let's dive in more into the details.
Right, Hazeln is part of finding a greater a fix on live right now.
Sometimes it's on life per second.
That's like, oh, okay, I got a greater a fix on life per second.
But now when you see an ancestral item, it's always going to have a greater a fix.
And that ancestral eye power bump, the a fix bump is going to feel really good.
Even if you miss that a fix, it's still a huge upgrade to your character if you haven't found one of these before.
Yeah, and sometimes right, you get an item that has multiple greater a fixes on live.
And it's not at 925.
It's not at the highest item power.
And that's kind of a mixed bag right?
Well, it's kind of good, but it's a lower item power.
And now things with greater a fix will be definitely at that highest item power.
Yes.
Okay.
So let's talk about the details here.
So sacred items are not going to drop anymore.
They're kaput.
You're going to be looking at normal items pre-tormants.
And then you're going to be chasing ancestral items once you are in torments here.
So yeah, starting in torment one, they're going to start to drop.
As I said, they're going to become more common as you go up.
But again, they're going to stay fairly rare.
They're never going to, you know, be like the only thing that's dropping.
And ancestral items are intended to be where you're finding forever items.
So when you find like a really good ancestral weapon or, you know, of whatever slot that you may not have an ancestral item for, that's going to be a big moment.
That's going to be an exciting moment where you're going to get something a lot better.
Because they also have their own a fix band as well.
So these ancestral items are going to have better a fixes than their non-an ancestral counterparts too.
Something to note is that greater affixes only drop on ancestral items.
You're not going to be finding greater affixes on non-an ancestral.
So when you see a greater affix drop on the ground, you're going to know that that is an ancestral item.
And ancestral items also have two tempering slots up from one on non-an ancestral.
And their masterworkable up to 12, whereas non-an ancestral are masterworkable up to four.
And finally, they are going to have higher aspect ranks too.
So you're going to find legendary aspects that become better on ancestral items.
And Charles, we actually added a ton of power to legendary aspects to accommodate this.
We didn't just sort of readjust where those power bands are coming from.
Yeah, all of the legendary aspects that now scale a little bit further into the ancestral tier.
We basically just tacked on five new levels kind of on top of the current value.
So you're just going to find even more powerful legendary effects than you have currently in the new ancestral tier.
It's going to be a lot of fun to find those.
Okay.
Let's move on to Paragon.
So we have some pretty big glyph updates coming with patch 2.0.
There's been a significant rework to how many ranks you can earn on any given glyph from 21 to 100,
which is a lot of new ranks.
But we want to make sure that there's still texture in that system, right?
And so because of that, we also have a new, rather a new glyph rarity, legendary.
So once you upgrade a glyph to rank 46, it becomes a legendary glyph,
which you can see here on the right.
This spirit glyph is level 50.
So it's past that 46 markets, legendary.
You're going to get a glyph radius increase at rank 15, which is already in the live game.
But you're also going to get another radius increase at rank 46 when it becomes legendary.
And this is making them bigger than they could have been previously.
So you're going to get more space with your glyphs because of this.
And when a glyph becomes legendary, it also unlocks a significant bonus more so than it did before.
And you can see that on the bottom of this glyph here, it's got the legendary bonus increases critical strike damage by 21.6%.
And it's very important to note that this is a multiplicative bonus.
This 21.6% is not an additive bonus.
So you're going to be getting a lot of power from that bonus there.
The thing else I want to bring up is that glyphs are moving to the pit.
So you're going to be upgrading your glyphs in the pit.
You're no longer going to be upgrading them in nightmare dungeons.
And it's going to be an attempt-based system.
So when you finish a pit run, you're going to go to the end,
and you're going to be able to have some chances to level up your glyph.
And increase their ranks.
And if you are in a pit that is 10 tiers higher than your current glyph,
you're going to have guaranteed success.
And for every 20 pit tiers that the pit level you're in is higher than your current glyph that you're trying to upgrade,
you're going to get bonus ranks so that you can accelerate the process.
Do you want to speak more to that, Colin?
Yeah, I think this is really important, no, because you could easily look at the rank 100 and be like,
oh my god, the grind is even longer.
But based on how that upgrade chance works,
it's guaranteed as long as you're beating pit tiers that are higher than your glyph.
And then how that bonus map ends up playing out is if you're beating, for example, a pit tier 30.
That's roughly somewhere between today's World Tier 3 and 4.
You can upgrade a glyph from 1 to 15 in 3 runs.
So you think about the difference between today's game and patch 2.0,
you're getting those glyphs leveled way faster if you're pushing that difficulty.
And what we really wanted to do here was we've heard a ton of feedback around how the XP system for Nightmare Dungeons feels really grindy.
It also just doesn't serve the Nightmare Dungeons very well.
It's like, how do I get to the end as fast as possible, but nothing in the dungeon matters.
And what that does is in the pit, it's all about speed and efficiency, and it sort of embraces that.
And we think that that's just really going to accelerate your pick lift upgrading speed.
And the chance you can sort of, I want to be really clear with the chance the chance base system is essentially there
because it felt really bad when it was binary.
Like when we said, hey, you need to beat the pit tier or you need to beat a pit that's 10 levels higher than your glyph.
And if you don't, you get nothing. That just felt really bad.
So the chance is not there to increase the grind or slow down progression.
It's actually just there to protect from like it feeling just terrible to not get literally anything from that run.
So again, to be clear, it's 100% chance as long as you're pushing difficulty.
We think that this fits the content a lot better. We've heard a ton of feedback around like the pit rewards feeling lackluster.
And there's not really a reason to push difficulty.
You sort of just want to hone in on like 90 or 101 depending on where you're at in terms of your progression journey on live.
This system really encourages you to push and gives you a tangible reward every single time you do it.
And I think it's important that there's the consistency of like the communication between, right?
So hey, my glyphs are currently level 50. Well, what kind of pit tier should I be approaching to upgrade these?
Well, somewhere in the range of 50 to 60, right? You're just a little bit higher so that you can keep pushing that harder content.
And also if you have a glyph down at level one, because maybe you haven't paid attention to that glyph, it's going to level up much faster if you are already proven yourself proven that you can tangen and pit tier 50, for instance.
You're going to level those up very quickly.
I think it's also cool as if you have a build that you feel isn't doing as well as you go up in torments and makes it a lot easier to kind of snap something back in and catch up faster.
Yeah, the further you progress, the easier it is to to level those up.
So here we have a video basically just showing off what the new UI looks like for upgrading a glyph in patch 2.0.
So you can see that it's showing you the current pit level you're on, the current success chance to get a rank up.
And something else I want to call out is that when you are, oh, yes, right. So this is rank 45 to 46 explicitly, which is the moment where you are increasing a glyph from rare to legendary.
And something important to note about that is that it does cost a fairly significant amount of gym fragments as well, but it's giving you that increased radius size and the new multiplicative legendary bonus, which is pretty sick.
And here we have an example of showing how the radius gets even bigger in patch 2.0.
I want to call out here that the midpoint says level 21, that is not correct. It is level 15 where the radius increases.
But yeah, previously there was only one radius increase. Now with legendary glyphs at rank 46, there is a second radius increase.
Okay, so let's talk about some more stuff related to Paragon.
We have realm partitioning for Paragon now, and this is kind of getting into all things that Colin was talking about.
We have realm based Paragon points now. So your Paragon points are going to be shared across an entire realm.
And remember that what a realm is is like either seasonal soft core or seasonal hard core or the same free turnal. Those are realms.
And these Paragon points are going to stay latent on a pre level 60 character. And what that means is that, you know, if you have, let's say, 150 Paragon points on a realm, those Paragon points will remain inactive on any character that's pre level 60.
But once you hit level 60 on that character, they will have those 150 Paragon points. And it's also important to note that any Paragon points you earn on any of your characters in that realm are going to be shared among all characters in that realm.
So if you earn 25 or 50 Paragon points on one character and then hop over to your alt, you're going to have 25 or 50 more Paragon points to spend on that character too.
And in addition to this change, we have a pretty hefty Paragon level increase. So right now the current max besides renown and ultraviolet bonuses is 200. And we're increasing that up to 300, which is going to give you a lot more levels to chase throughout any given season.
And in light of these changes coming to Paragon, we've made some adjustments to the way that boards work as well. So because we're offering so much more power with legendary glyphs and they mean so much more to your build.
You know, we're looking to set a maximum for the number of Paragon boards that you can equip at any given time.
And this is also because you know, on live right now, the best strategy is to aim for as many glyphs, lots as possible. You just go off, you oftentimes ignore whatever legendary node bonus you're getting just for the glyph slot.
And we want to make sure that you're really focusing on these legendary nodes and that you're focusing on these really cool legendary glyphs that you're getting.
And really think about those choices instead of gunning for like every single glyph, for example.
So complimenting a relational.
I was just going to say this really helps compliment the additional 100 more levels. Like we've heard a lot of feedback that it feels really flat.
Once you hit 100 that there's just no more progression. You don't really need to kill any of the monsters anymore unless it's explicitly to get the the loop drop off of them.
And that that kind of kind of feels bad, right? Like I'm walking through this dungeon and like I get literally nothing out of killing these these monsters.
So with the board limit, we've packed a ton of power with additional paragon levels to grind a ton of power with the legendary glyphs.
But it also creates a situation where once you're sort of you've achieved all those different things, you don't feel so bad necessarily around not getting to that paragon level 300.
At a certain point, you start to really just sort of really need to hone in on your build and those extra paragon points are going to start providing you more of a show of sort of how bad as you are.
And give you incremental progress that's a little bit less sort of demanding that you must grind through all of this content to unlock every part of your paragon board.
Yeah, and something I'm pretty excited about this is that you know sometimes on live, it can feel like my goal is to get a new paragon board.
And as soon as I achieve that, my goal is to get a new paragon board and get off the one I just unlocked.
And I think this change really lets me kind of explore the boards and think about what specific route optimizations I want to take.
And let's me personalize that a little more, which I'm pretty excited about.
Well, I know we have a we just went through a ton of content right here with all the the changes that are coming for progression to paragon to itemization.
I know it was a lot for people here. We will actually have a blog immediately up after the stream that will kind of also explain a little bit more of this to players so that they can actually get a understanding in their own cave and stuff like what it what is going to be changing with patch 2.0 for Diablo 4 in regards to some of the progression items.
I know Colin we're seeing a lot in chat of like, you know, people are noting like, hey, this feels a little D3-ish in ways.
I don't know if you wanted to chat or like comment on that a little bit more.
Yeah, I'm happy to. It's definitely familiar, right?
So we thought a lot about like, what is the right way to address the player feedback of we've gotten a bunch of feedback around like World Tier 5, World Tier 6, World Tier 7.
I want to be able to level up the challenge in the game. I want to be able to get more efficiency.
And we wanted to do it in a way that was leaning into what we saw you all were really resonating with, which is getting to the endgame faster.
And we felt like, okay, well, we could add a World Tier 5 and add ancestral Uber, ancestral and increase the level cap.
But that would mean you just need to grind more to get to that point where you're finding your forever items doing item modification.
And we get out of World Tier 6, Uber, Uber, ancestral, right? And it just sort of made us reevaluate what is important.
And what's important to us is getting people into the endgame, getting people finding their forever items, smashing monsters, getting more powerful sort of item modification and efficiency.
And so that was part of it. And then the other part of it I'd say is I think Diablo 4 more than any Diablo has had a ton of item customization and power along the leveling journey, which really makes the leveling progression feel different, right?
Like if you're tempering, if you're imbuing aspects, if you're really min-maxing your reward scheme, you can really push difficulty tiers early.
If you've played D3 hard, it's really the only real difficulty, right?
But because we have so many different ways to grow your power, we think that represents a pretty fun challenge of like how do I take all these pieces and really push as early as I can to get to that max level faster.
And one more thing that's really important to note is the jumps between torments are pretty enormous. We don't expect you to sort of play it like today's D3, where you essentially log in, get your hatred set and hop right into torments 16.
The jumps are actually pretty enormous between torments 1 and 2, and it creates this really fun progression through those torments tiers, and it feels like a meaningful step forward when you get into torments 2 and then a torment 3.
We're hoping this doesn't necessarily feel like a two hour sort of journey through the torments tiers and then now you're in torment 4, and that's how you play the rest of the game.
Yes, and also one thing I'll add is, you know, shout to Twitch chat, everything that you say, hey, you like what we're doing, big dub, we appreciate it, much love for the response.
Also, all the people in Twitch chat who are like, I don't like this, this isn't working for me. Much appreciation to say, you know, we're looking at what you're saying, we're thinking about it, and we're going to try to incorporate it and make the game better.
And I think it's interesting, I'm seeing this sort of Diablo 3 references, and it's like, from our perspective, if something really worked well in Diablo 3, that's more important to us to do the thing that the players felt like was working for them than anything else.
The fact that we've done it before in any form, to me, wouldn't stop us from doing the right thing, you know what I mean?
Yeah, and I just drew it the right way for D4. Sorry, I'm doing everything around, it feels like it's like a Zoom call, but interrupting each other.
And also, a big, big shout out to Twitch Chef for calling out Given's court banishment.
I've seen that message a few times already, but so thanks, Aislin, thank you, Colin, I know Colin's going to be joining us more on a couple other topics, but we still have a lot to talk about in this stream.
And the next thing that we do want to talk about is class changes and everything, and so Charles will be taking us through all the class changes for Patch 2.0.
Yeah, awesome. So before we get into some of the slides and details, I just wanted to thank Colin and Aislin for talking about all the systemic updates that are coming, how we're going to test your character and how you're going to progress through it.
But my topic is going to be a bit more about what are the exact abilities and skills and new legendary effects and unique that you're going to be getting to take on these awesome challenges that are set up through the difficulty tier system.
And also a slight disclaimer, you know, PTR is a very early build for whatever is going to go live on Patch 2.0, and some of the assets that we've captured here are also still early on, and so some of the exact numbers or some of the wording may slightly be changed.
So definitely refer to the patch notes, which we're going to be publishing right after the stream for the exact details and kind of final and air quotes numbers that are going to go on the PTR, and of course still may be subject to change before we actually launch Patch 2.0 live.
All right, so with that out of the way, let's start talking about some of the tempering changes that are going to come in Patch 2.0.
So tempering is a system that we introduced back in season of loot or born, season 4, that gave you a way to really customize your items and kind of make your build your own.
And we've received a lot of feedback on the tempering system, and we're really committed to iterating on and making sure this system is the best that can possibly be going forward.
One of the key points of feedback that we heard was around weapon tempers, so these affixes that you get to attach to your weapons, your weapons are your big important part of your build and your character.
And there was a big disparity here, where some affixes that were on weapon tempering were multiplicatively increasing your player power, things like double projectiles or things of that nature or bash cleaving, which was a multiplicative bonus.
And others, not so much, right, you had some other ones that were more duration or size effect, and they just were hard to compare against each other.
And so going forward and patch 2.0, we've made all weapon tempering affixes multiplicative damage increases, oftentimes to very specific skills.
And to accommodate this, we already have one bonus projectiles, and now we're going to have new affixes that give skills chance to deal double damage, which means if figures the chance to deal double damage,
the entire skill is just going to do twice as much damage as before. Every hit of it will deal double damage. It's kind of an all or nothing kind of deal.
And then the chance to hit twice is the chance for any time it deals damage, you just get an extra hit of damage. And this allows you to trigger things like lucky hit procs or anything that counts the number of times you deal damage.
That's going to trigger an extra time with the hit twice.
Offensive tempering affixes, these are the ones that can also go on your weapons, but can go on other spots as well. These are going to be additive damage increases.
And these will often be to broader categories like the bonus fire damage or bonus critical strike damage, and whereas the weapon temperers are often talking to more specific skills.
And so here we can see an example with the Shadow Augments execution, where we have the several projectiles chance to cast twice.
But now we've got new ones that are chance for reep to hit twice, so you cast reep, and every target you hit there's just a chance to get two hits on that target instead of one.
And corpse explosion, whenever you cast corpse explosion, there is a chance for the entire skill to deal double damage to every target that it hits.
Additionally, we've moved those size and duration affixes, which we think are really cool and really interesting ways of modifying your skills.
We've moved those over to the utility category, so they're not directly competing with these multiplicative damage increases.
You're not going to feel bad that, oh, I'm missing out on damage, just to make my area hit a little bit larger or have a longer duration on a buff.
So there's not as much opportunity cost to invest in in those size and duration affixes, which are still really cool ways to customize your character.
We just don't want them to compete with damage.
And finally, we know that oftentimes tempering leads itself to, hey, I see this list of five or even six affixes sometimes.
We really are going to try to be limiting tempering recipes to at most four affixes that could possibly roll on them, just to give you a little bit better odds of actually hitting the one that you care about and the one that you want.
And just to be a little bit easier to kind of comprehend. And even so, we're trying to set this limit at four, but oftentimes we're aiming for just three on the recipe, depending on how the grouping them together in ways that make sense.
So this is an active area that we're working on, really trying to make sure that it's not quite, it's easier for you to get the right affix out of the temporary recipe by limiting that number that are on there.
All right, next up we've got changes to ultimate skills. So ultimate skills can now gain skill ranks.
This is probably pretty self-explanatory, but just like every other skill in the game, ultimate skills cannot be ranked up to rank five in the skill tree.
And just like every other skill increasing the skill rank will increase the damage output of your ultimate skills.
But it's also going to give you cool down reduction on these ultimate skills as well.
So oftentimes other skills you just kind of get one or the other, right, sometimes it's cool down reduction, sometimes it's a damage or healing increase.
On ultimate skills you're going to get kind of the best of both worlds. It's going to be increasing the damage output and reducing the cooldown.
And finally, effects that do grant bonus skill ranks on this, such as, you know, Harlequin's Cress, the Shaco, that gives plus to all skill ranks.
These are only going to apply to ultimate skills that you've already learned in the skill tree.
And this is to make sure that you still can only equip one ultimate skill. You can't like it plus ranks to all skills and then suddenly have access to for ultimate skills.
We still want that. We still want you to just pick one, but you're just going to be getting, you're going to be able to really juice that ultimate skill up.
If you really want to make, you know, last rate be really strong. That's going to be a powerful effect that you can invest more skill points into.
Alright, so those are some of the general updates. Let's now talk about the new content coming for each individual class starting here with our barbarian.
Alright, so sometimes you're playing as a barbarian and you experience a problem, right? You are standing here and there is an enemy over there. What to do?
Well, a good barbarian is going to throw their weapon at the enemy over there to kill them at a distance.
Alright, so now we've got a new skill called mighty throw that's going to hurl your weapon at an enemy. It's going to deal damage on impact and then it's going to stick in the ground and do some pulses of damage over time.
So even if the initial impact doesn't kill them, there's going to be some extra pulses there.
Additionally, we've got some upgrades for it just like our other skills enhanced mighty throws can increase your attack speed while the weapon is out.
And then you can either opt into fighters mighty throw, which is going to give bonuses to that pulsing damage, causes your weapon swaps to pulse for more and give you a bit of barrier.
Or you're going to opt into my warriors mighty throw, which is going to dramatically increase the initial impact damage and it's going to stun enemies on impact.
Let's take a video clip of this in action.
Alright, so we've got barb, just simple example here with a few enemies, you know, throws out this, you know, ephemeral version of the weapon, lands deals a big chunk of damage and then pulses over time before returning back to you.
That was a huge fan of double throw in Diablo 2, so this is really exciting.
Yeah, it looks sweet too. It kind of like bluish yellow, like ancient, kind of color scheme to the VFX looks awesome on it.
So range barb is definitely happening in patch 2.0.
For sure, if you want to spec really heavily into this, yeah, you're going to be throwing weapons out like crazy.
Alright, so we've also got some new key passives and new legendary paragon notes for every class year.
So for Barbarian, we've got barbed carapace. This is going, this is a key passive, so it's going to increase your thorns based on how much fear you're spending.
And whenever you cast a skill with a cooldown, it's going to grant you unhindered for a duration, which allows you to move through enemies.
And then enemies that are close to you are going to take bonus, or are going to take damage from your thorns every second.
You're going to kind of pulse damage of your thorns every second.
Now this is really cool. It really enables thorns barb, which we had a little bit of support for, but you know one of the big problems of thorns is that you really wanted enemies to hit you and hit you quickly.
And this gives you another alternative to deal bonus damage or to really pay off for building up all that thorns with this new key passive.
Additionally, we've got a legendary paragon note, the force of nature. Your earthquake has a chance to spawn dust devils and your earthquake damage is going to be increased by your damage against close enemies.
So this is really plays into these, these earthquakes and dust devil effects, which we kind of call subpowers internally.
These effects that are not skills that you cast directly, but you know some of your legendary effects will, will spawn these earthquakes and dust devils.
And then we're just a new way to really power those up and blend them together in the same build.
Additionally, we're adding some new passives to the skill tree.
And this has really helped to give you away along with ultimate skill ranks to spend a lot of those new points that you're getting by leveling up from 50 to 60, you know those new skill points you're getting.
We're going to use some new ways to invest those.
But we also got some new items, of course. We've got the ugly bastard helm, a new unique helm for barbarians.
And it makes you so ugly that whenever you are berserking, all of your damage is converted into fire damage.
And so that's really interesting. You know, bar bars always have this little bit of like light fire theme. You had a few different effects that dealt fire damage.
And now if you really want to play a fire bar, this is the unique helm for you.
Also playing into that, we've got aspect of flaming rampage, which causes your charge to deal some fire damage.
And aspect of shattering steel, which will cause your steel grasp on Iron Maelstrom to do some bonus physical damage.
All right, moving on to the druid. The druid gets a new skill, a new core skill in fact, called Stone Burst.
And this is a core skill that's channeled. It kind of has a very unique kind of input mechanism compared to pretty much any other skill in Diablo IV.
And as you're channeling it, you target an area, and as you channel it, the affected area grows in size over about one second of channeling.
And at any point you can release the channel, and it's going to deal a big burst of damage to whatever size you can land it on there.
You can you cap it really quickly and just do one pulse of damage to a small area, or you can channel up for a little bit longer and hit a much wider area depending on the exact combat scenario you find yourself in, or how the enemies are distributed on the battlefield tier.
Of course, we've got our upgrades that increase damage to the enemies hit in the initial radius. So, you know, really doubling down on that single target capability of a core skill.
And primal stone burst gives you some attack speed and raging stone burst will dramatically increase the spirit cost, but also give it a ton more damage.
So if you have a ton of spirit generation, then that might be the upgrade you look for in stone burst. Let's see a video of this in action.
All right, so you see it takes up. There's like three different levels like small, medium and large in this one that the druid kind of held it for a while, but you could release it at any time.
And so here you see a kind of rapid firing a lot of quick small shots just because they knew that would be enough to clear out the enemies here.
And also by your channeling it does some pulses of damage to enemies in that area as well.
The channel explosion is so satisfying to blow up just so many monsters.
Yeah, it's really just amazing.
It looks so sweet too. I really hats off to the VFX artist who worked on making these looks so beautiful, the new skills here.
All right, so of course, druid also has new passives, a new key passive called one with nature that really empowers companion builds.
You know, we've heard a lot that players love playing with companions, their wolves, their poise and creepers, their ravens.
And this is going to be the key passive for you.
So all of your companion skills gain an additional companion and they deal increased damage.
And there's also a little bonus basically with the you gain the passive effect of all of the companion skills.
Now, if you're taking this key passive, you're probably taking these companions anyway.
But just in case, you know, your build is such that, well, I just want to take, you know, two out of the three, right?
I can put wolves and poise and creeper on my bar, but, you know, maybe you don't have enough skill slots to put in ravens.
You're still going to be able to get the passive effect of that when you take this key passive.
Because we just want you to have tons of these companions really leading the charge here.
We've also got untamed a new legendary Paragon node that plays right into this one with nature key passive.
Casting a companion skill is going to increase the companion active skill will grant you bonus ranks to all of your companion skills for a time to really puff up the damage of those.
Just like before, we've got some new passives coming into the skill tree as well.
I think some of these might have some temporary icons on them.
Like I said, these were from an early build. Some of the icons or very specific art might be adjusted.
So, you know, bear with us. This is the nature of PTR and early development.
All right, moving on to some of the items. Oh, no, we've got a video. Oh, right. A video of...
That's really cool.
Really leading a wolf pack here, right? So this includes wolves with the storm's companions to turn them into light and wear wolves.
And I'm sure there's some other ones here. Like aspect of the stampede is probably involved.
You just have what is that seven wolves following you around? You really get to lead the wolf back with this.
This is the best video in our presentation. Well, actually, no, sorry. This is the second best video in our presentation.
You guys will see the best video in our presentation, but it's so good.
Yeah. For all you wear wolf lovers out there, this one is going to be really sweet. I'm really looking forward to playing with this in touch 2.0.
All right, so new items. So they've got the stone of them in. This is a unique totem that's going to empower your stone burst, the new core skill.
So, channeling it is going to grant you some damage reduction. And the final explosion will deal increased damage based on how long you were channeling it.
So, this just really incurs you to build it up to that max size and let off a huge explosion.
And give you some damage reduction. So you're kind of standing still for a bit. That's okay. Get a bit of bonus damage reduction.
We've got a little bit more legendaries on Druid than the other classes just because stone burst being a core skill.
We know that the kind of bar to make a core skill really viable and useful.
It does need a good amount of legendary items to support it to really make a full build out of it.
So that's why we've added two legendaries here for stone burst. We've got the aspect of anticlimb burst,
which causes stone burst to deal increased damage. And if you cast it at or above 100 spirit here, it's going to immediately be at that maximum size.
So you don't necessarily need to channel it as long as you are casted when you have a lot of spirit.
This synergizes really well with the earth and might key passive, which gives you full spirit when it triggers.
So you can trigger earth and might and then immediately get a huge stone burst.
We've got aspect of shattered defenses, which alters stone burst in a rather interesting way.
It causes stone burst or stone burst causes enemies to take increased damage from your other skills for a time and reduces stone burst spirit cost.
This kind of converts stone burst away from necessarily being your primary damage source to being a bit more of a setup skill.
You can kind of debuff enemies and then you can find some interesting builds where you have other ways of spending your spirit and maybe another core skill or bolder or some other primary damage source.
And then you can use stone burst to kind of set up that build. Really interesting to see how players, well, what kind of builds you make with shattered defenses.
Additionally, we've got aspect of the rapid bear, which empowers your grizzly rage to apply rabies and increases your poison output storm crow, which is just lightning ravens.
You know, your ravens are not lightning. It looks awesome. And aspect of the agile wolf, which gives shred a fourth attack.
Shred normally is like a three part combo and now it's a four part combo that deals even more damage on that fourth hit and it's going to knock down enemies as well.
All right. So that is a druid really looking forward to playing some druid and 2.0.
But let's move on to the necromancer because we got a lot to get through. We've got soul riff. This is a new darkness ultimate skill.
So necromancers kind of had three ultimates already. They had one that was blood, one that was bone and one that was related to summoning.
And now we've kind of completed it and we've added a darkness or shadow damage ultimate.
Soul riff creates an area around your character kind of follows with you that just constantly deals damage over time.
And it's going to be sucking out the souls of enemies who you're hitting. And every time it sucks out a soul from an enemy, you're going to gain some essence and you're going to gain a barrier.
So you can stack up this barrier. It helps you be survivable and it deals, you know, really good damage over time.
Supreme soul riff gives you bonus damage for every soul that you absorb and prime soul riff causes the soul absorption to also apply vulnerable.
Let's take a video of this in action here. Right. So enemies are coming up super useful Charles, right?
Now that like you have another way to give yourself defenses. Necro has historically had some trouble with that. Right.
Yeah, absolutely. I think that's a really important part here. And when we get to the next I talk about some of the passives. We'll highlight. We're adding a bit more barrier into the necromancer's kit.
You know, blood necromancer has always had a really easy time surviving. They had a lot of fortify and a lot of max health.
And really they the other ones like the bone and shadow necro didn't have quite as much survivability. And so now we're introducing more barrier in more places to ensure that that kind of non blood necromancer builds the shadow in the bone and some of the necros have a bit more survivability and are able to scale into that late game pretty well.
Alright, so as I mentioned the new passives so they have a new key passive called affliction that there's this new concept of affliction where applying vulnerable crowd control or shadow damage over time effects to enemies will apply them with affliction, which is going to make them take increased damage from you and your minions.
Additionally, when you apply a cursed skill to someone or to an enemy who has this affliction, you're going to do a big chunk of shadow damage.
So this kind of turns your cursed skills, you're decrepify and iron maiden into offensive skills. You can curse an area and then they take a big chunk of damage as well.
And then this will scale up with the bonus damage that you've dealt or that you the bonus affixes that you have for that crowd control vulnerable and shadow damage.
And along that same theme, the new legendary paragon node frailty is going to cause a curse enemies to take more damage from you and so plays very nicely with the affliction key passive.
And once again, more skill tree passives to spend those extra points on. And I want to highlight an acrotic fortitude here in the upper right that gives you just a generic passive that gives you a chance lucky hit chance to gain a barrier.
And so that's going to be really good for anybody who wants just a bit more bump of survivability and to play into the more barrier focused on necromancer.
Yeah, going back to affliction really quick, I love the idea of using my curses offensively, like as a damage skill, I think that's going to be such a blast.
Yeah, yeah, really cool to just yeah, definitely going to be blast in a home.
I think it's really thematic to love playing with it.
It pairs really well with the utility changes now that we have way more size increases in utility gives you so many more utility options.
Those curses get pretty huge and it feels great.
Yeah, for all of us who just want to win by debuffs spamming, I love that one.
Absolutely.
All right, let's talk about some of the new items coming for necromancer here.
So we've got a new unique item, the unmaker, a unique helm.
This is going to empower the soul rift, the new ultimate skill.
Of course, you gain some skill ranks to soul rift, because now ultimate skills have skill ranks.
And every 30 essence that you spend while soul rift is active will increase its duration up to eight seconds.
So as long as you're active and kind of spending the essence with the unmaker, you're going to have a very long duration of soul rift.
And then for every essence that you gain while it's active, which absorbing the soul does trigger essence gain, you're going to do a pulse of damage around you.
So some bonus damage.
And so it really encourages you to just keep soul rift up all the time, be constantly gaining and spending the essence.
And it's going to be really, really fun to make that build work.
Additionally, we've got reaping lotus aspect. This empowers your sever, your core skill.
Sever will no longer return to you. Previously, Sever was kind of an out and back situation.
Now it just goes out and then it splits into three spectres at the end deals some extra bonus damage.
And then that's the end of the sever.
So it really doesn't power it on the swing out and looks really cool.
You have aspect of Fel gluttony that empowers your golem whenever you cast your golems active deals a big pulse of damage around it.
And your golem will then consume corpses to reduce its cooldown.
So anybody who really wants to build around making your golem as strong as possible, this is going to be the aspect for you.
And finally, we've got phasing poltergeists aspect, which causes your bone spirit to split into three spirits that deal a percentage of the damage as well.
I think we've got a video clip of this one because it looks really sweet.
So you cast bone spirit at one target and then it spawns three little mini bone spirits to seek out nearby enemies as well.
So it kind of gives you increased area of effect.
And if there's just one target, of course, it all reconverged back on that same target as well.
But also just adds a bit more AOE capability for your bone spirit build.
Very cool.
All right. So rogue.
Rogue gets dance of knives.
This is a new channeled skill for rogue.
It's an agility cut throat skill.
And it also has a pretty interesting mechanic where it has some charges that will recharge.
And the how long you can channel it is based on how many charges you have.
It's going to take one charge per second of channeling.
But there's no energy cost or we're just like a normal cooldown.
Here you can just channel it as long as you have charges.
And while you're channeling, you're going to be spinning around.
You're going to be throwing knives at enemies nearby and you're against movement speed and dodge chance.
Really is kind of like a spin to win kind of build on rogue here.
You got enhanced dance of knives, which gives you some charge refund as you're moving with it.
Because that's what you really want to encourage is this constant motion, this forward momentum.
And methodical dance of knives drops some stun grenades when you finish channeling.
Or just blend dance of knives will slow enemies and has a chance to pierce through the enemies that you're throwing the daggers at.
Let's take a look at this in action.
Here we got the rogue just going spin in throwing some daggers around at everyone.
Yeah, this is awesome.
Ah, I like the speed farming.
And that animation.
Yeah, it's just amazing.
Absolutely.
And you can see there at the end they had the upgrade that drops a bunch of stun grenades at the end.
And we're all dead, but you know, if you use this to get into a big cluster of enemies, then you stop the channel.
You drop some stun grenades, reset some of your charges and you're good to start spinning again.
It's fun.
Yeah, those are perfect for like you run into an elite pack after slaughtering a bunch of normals and it just annihilates the elites that feels amazing.
Yeah.
Alright, so we've got new passives as well.
New key passive is alchemical admixture.
This is empowering your non-physical damage.
So, rogues can do poison, shadow and cold through their various imbubments.
And when you deal three different types of that non-physical damage, the potency of your imbument skills is going to be dramatically increased for a time.
And the more bonus damage that you build on your gear for bonus poison, shadow or cold damage, the further that potency gets increased.
And also encouraging you to mix and match the different elements.
It's really thematic with the alchemical kind of theme and really supporting a build of rogue that we've kind of had in the game, but really wanted to give that robust support of a key passive for.
And also we've got a legendary Paragon node, the dense macabre, which encourages this kind of one-two combo of cast animability or subterfuge skill increases the damage of your next skill, whatever it might be, by quite a substantial amount.
You can cast your dash and then position yourself, cast a big rain of arrows, and it hits very hard.
Very cool and actually impacts your moment to moment rotation as well.
And of course we've got the new skill tree passes as well.
All right, new items. We've got the pit fighter's gall. This is the ancestral unique ring.
Or sorry, just a unique ring. It's not necessarily that you can find it before ancestral tier.
And this pit fighter's gall will empower your smoke grenade. So your smoke grenade skill will increase your critical strike damage and then leave a cloud of shadows behind.
And while you're within that cloud of shadows, you're going to be constantly regaining stealth.
And so there's a lot of interesting ways you can play off of triggering going into or out of stealth.
And pit fighter's gall is just going to really enable that when you cast smoke grenade.
We've got aspect of star shards. This is a new legendary to directly support dance of knives.
And the daggers from dance of knives have a chance to shatter, dealing creating more shards of metal that deal bonus damage.
And you can now use combo points on dance of knives to further increase the channel duration if you've opted into combo points specialization.
Aspect of poisonous clouds plays well with pit fighters gall. When you gain stealth, you create a cloud of poison damage.
And aspect of splendering shards, there's just a chance whenever you're hitting a frozen enemy to create some ice spikes.
So if you're freezing enemies because you're playing Alchemic Gladmexture and using Coldimbew, the splendering shards might be a good aspect for you as well.
Alright, moving on to the sorceress. The sorceress gets a new conjuration skill called the familiar.
This is a conjuration skill that is all three elements. It is a shock skill, a piramancy skill, and a frost skill.
So there's three charges of it so you can cast it back to back.
And you summon a familiar of the element of your last skill cast.
If you just cast a piramancy skill, you're going to summon a fire familiar. If you just cast a lightning skill, you'll summon a lightning familiar and same with a cold, you'll summon a cold familiar.
And with the enhanced effect, these familiar will do a bonus effect. So the fire familiar will constantly apply some burning to enemies that it's around.
The cold familiar will chill and lightning familiar will stun.
And of course, their damage type is going to be based on what type they are so that it'll benefit from all of your bonus fire damage.
And that is really great to tap into some of the passive on the sorcerer.
Yeah, absolutely. So if there's a lot of passive that say, hey, you get bonuses against burning enemies, for instance.
Now, if you have the fire familiar, that's going to really easily be able to apply that constantly. And you're going to have pretty high uptime on having familiar result because of the way the charge and duration works.
Let's take a look at this in action.
All right, so initially we cast a frost familiar here, right? It's jumping around and it's landing. It's doing frost damage. Then we cast a fire skill. Now we get a fire familiar jumping around and kind of dive bombing on enemies.
And then finally, we get a shock familiar, a lightning familiar here that's going to be a lightning damage. So you can kind of mix and match these depending on what skills you use, what combination you cast them in.
And it's really flexible. It fits into a lot of different builds. You know, even if you're just a pure, say, fire sword, we just want to do fire damage, just want to do burning.
This could still fit because you're just going to be able to summon the fire familiar, but it really reaches its maximum potential as you're kind of mix and matching these to suit the situation and apply the debuffs that you want onto the enemies.
And you can have quite a few of these out for the Sega demonstration. I think we only have a couple of them on screen, but I think you can have up to six, right?
Yeah, you can have up to six. And that would make a lot more sense once we get to talk about some of the unique items that are coming with this patch.
But first, let's talk about the new passives and we've got enlightenment. This really also plays into the concept of mixing and matching the elements. You see it's got all three kind of colors on there.
Casting a skill grants a stack of enlightenment or three stacks if your skill was a different element to the one before. So you're alternating here. And whenever you gain max stacks, you're going to become enlightened and you get a ton of bonuses for being in this enlightened state.
But then it drops off over time.
It's really a reward for mixing and matching those elements more so than any other key passes we've had on the circle before.
And similarly with the legendary paragraph node, fundamental release, each fire lightning cold attack, you make an increase the damage they take from all sources by 10%.
So you really need to hit them with all three types to gain the maximum bonus here.
All right, onto the unique items. So today bindings, this is a unique gloves and this plays right into the familiar.
So whenever you cast familiar with this unique on, you're going to summon all three elemental variants at once.
However, it does come with a bit of restrictions on it. So familiar duration is going to be dramatically increased and it's cool down reduced.
But you're going to have one less charge of it. So you won't be able to spam this quite as much.
But you know, you press the button once or twice and then you get the max for familiar is out. They're all over the screen and they're going to last for quite a long time.
This is this unique gloves. It's going to be really, really powerful to if you're all about this congregation build all about amping up the power of the familiar.
So an awesome unique for that. Additionally, we've got new legendaries for the aspect of overheating after channeling and sinrate for a time.
You're going to deal bonus damage to the target and cast the instant rate will refresh and maintain the bonus.
So really just powering up your incinerate charged flash. This is in power is charge bolts.
And after you hit a certain number of enemies with charge bolts, your next three cast of charge bolts will no longer send out bolts.
They're going to sound big waves of lightning that deal even more damage and it's always going to be a crit.
And then aspect of elemental constellation. Once again, more about the mixing and matching of all three elements.
Casting one of the elemental skills will summon a matching type elemental dagger that will pierce through enemies.
And if you the damage of that dagger is going to be increased, if you get all three of the different element types in that timeframe.
All right. So I think, oh, right. We've got new mythic unique. So of course, how can I forget new mythic unique items? These are the strongest items in the game.
We've got shroud of false death. And I think the really cool part about this is it's just inherent ethics.
It's going to grant plus one skill rank to all passives. And this is really awesome as we're adding new passes into the skill tree.
This is just a ton of power for this new unique chest. And its effect is if you haven't attacked in the last two seconds, you're going to gain stealth and bonus movement speed.
Now, stealth historically has just been a mechanic that has been on rogues and a little bit on druids with the werewolf builds.
But now every class, if you get this mythic unique is going to have some access to stealth, you can drop out a combat for a little bit.
And then you get in the stealth and you get tons movement speed to maybe move on to the next pack or move somewhere else in the dungeon.
And it's a really simple line, all passives. But it's literally all passes, which is insane. Like it gets incredibly powerful.
Absolutely.
And we've also got the air of perdition, a mythic unique helm. And this one has as an interesting effect, so it says give into hatred and earn lileth's favor increasing your damage dealt by 60%.
So just baseline, this is a huge damage bonus. And the second line here says slaughtering enemies to briefly steal lileth's favor from or slaughter enemies to briefly steal lileth's favor from nearby allies.
So this means if you're playing in a group with somebody else who happens to have the air of perdition equipped, you are able to steal lileth's favor from them.
Well, only favor one of you. And you actually gain double the bonus of this, right? If you steal someone else's favor, you get 120% bonus damage. And they would get zero.
But if you're just playing the solo, no one else out there perdition around, it's just a flat 60% bonus damage, which is still a ton and very impactful for a mythic unique.
All right, I believe that is actually everything. Wow, that is so much new class content, new skills, new legendaries, new new everything. And I didn't even get to talk about some of our other, you know, more regular class balance changes, updates to existing skills and legendaries.
So make sure you definitely check out the patch notes. There is still more changes that come, but we're already really deep into this camp fresh at and we didn't want to extend it too, too much longer.
So make sure you check out the patch notes for all the details on those other changes coming as well.
Yeah, thank you so much, Charles. I know we have gone through a lot of information work in our 1.5 of this campfire check. As I said, and I mentioned on social like this is going to be a very beefy campfire chat.
We still have two more things that we do want to really cover off. And as Charles had mentioned, there are a lot of other class changes that we didn't actually fit within the presentation like a lot of balance specific items.
So that will be on patch notes and patch notes will be available on our blog for BTR immediately after the stream. So please check that out.
We are going to jump into some quality of life items. And so Colin, you want to take us through some quick quality of life items. I'll be coming with 2.0.
Yeah, I'll go quick so we can get to the super exciting cool thing.
Yeah, so the first one here is you can now select your preferred town portal location. So how that's going to work is you're going to open up the map and hover over any of the waypoints and when you right click on it.
It's going to set that as essentially your preferred location and whenever you town portal, it's going to take you there. So this is really helpful for when you're doing whispers, for example, you just set the tree of whispers is your preferred location.
Do some whispers when you press T you go right there. You don't have to open up the map. Then click on the waypoint and click on accept like it's all very seamless and it's just removing a lot of the inputs that you have to do to get back to town quickly.
The next thing here is we're adding a dungeon key inventory tab for things like nightmare sigils. So that just gives you more space for more activities. So much room for activities.
The next one here is we've done a pretty substantial rework of monster CC and this is in the spirit of we want to have really clear sort of delineations between normal monsters and elite monsters and we didn't like how often you're getting slowed down and how mandatory unstoppable can feel.
So you know, I always felt bad to be fighting this huge horde of enemies and you see this elite and you're paying attention to the elite and then like this go man, mallard comes up and like sneak attacks you and knocks you down for three seconds and that's the thing that kills you that always felt like bullshit.
So what we've done is we've sort of overhauled a lot of the normal monster CCs to be quick and snappy like you still feel them you kind of want to avoid them still. But they're much less sort of the reason why you die entirely. So the vampire in pale one like the two hander like comes and stabs you and stuns you for three seconds.
Let's turn it into an immobilized you can't move but you can just smack them in the face and then the werewolf leap is another great example where previously they come out of stealth and like leap attack on you and you get dazed and you'd walk around confused and now they just does it does a quick knockback.
This next change here is small but I think it's a blaster's delight which is all the monsters that had really long death animations all die instantly. You know, after wait for the loop to hit the ground it's very satisfying.
You know, the big S like spider hosts that crawl towards you when you kill them they pop instantly and all the spiders go and hit the walls and it feels great. The zombies feel really good too. Like they pop instantly when you kill them.
I mean, it's a very satisfying experience. So this should speed up combat quite a bit and it just feels really good.
The next thing here is there are socketable inventory tab another tab for you for you to put socketables like gems and other socketables.
And then there's also an additional stash tab that we're going to add. The next thing if we could roll the clip we took out just about all the dice.
All would go up and then like click on the plunger and don't get hit by the spikes. That's all been replaced entirely with just monster packs of varying sizes and it's just way more seamless.
In this case, we only rolled some normal monsters but sometimes it's a couple of elite packs. You never really know what you're going to get. It's like a Easter or a kinder egg I should say.
And it just helps the dungeon flow substantially like to just sort of blast through those things.
And then a handful of dungeons have had their procedural logic updated just so there's more variation in the layouts. So when you play it, just going to roll out differently.
This is really just iterating on our dungeon set to make them feel much more sort of flow inducing not slowing you down.
And the next one here is minor but actually feels pretty good and it has a big impact on the game.
When you get those paragon and level up notifications, we're actually going to tell you how many.
So sometimes you'll realize, oh my god, I have like 15 skill points I can spend and it actually tells you the number.
It's a nice quality of light change. So I think that's ever so.
Thank you Colin for running through quickly. I appreciate the efficiency of going through all the quality of life changes.
Now I know, Given has been very quiet over here. He's only chimed in a little bit.
And we do want to talk about a new thing that is coming to vessel of hatred specifically for vessel of hatred players. So Given, will you talk us through it a little bit?
Yeah, so it's my privilege to kind of talk about a feature that the whole team's been working very hard on that we haven't really mentioned much.
You know, we looked at the expansion. We had all these cool things, you know, torments, new class skills, spirit born, but we thought there was a whole.
And we wanted to particularly give build crafters a new way to play for vessel of hatred.
This is for folks who like me whose dream cooking show has nothing to do with British baking, but instead would be called Collins kitchen.
I'm a quick chat if you would binge Collins kitchen.
So yeah, let's say I think some of you already kind of have an idea.
So yeah, let's let's get into it. Some of you already know we're going to be talking about room words.
So let's start with a little background. So room words were in Diablo 2 and they were a very powerful way of augmenting gear with socketable content.
And there's a lot of good sort of nostalgic feelings. They were popular. They were remembered fondly.
You can look on the right. That's one of the most iconic examples from Diablo 2.
The name is enigma and you would make it with runes, ja, if burr, and it would get you some really cool skills that would come out of it when you put it all together.
And for Diablo 4, we wanted to retain the soul of what Diablo 2 room words did, which is combining socketable components and creating more powerful items.
But we also wanted to do something that felt appropriately fresh and new. And we wanted to lean into what's unique about the modern game to make the Diablo 4 version of room words and make it stand on its own and really feel like the right version to be giving to players.
Yeah, and what was awesome about Diablo 2 room words right was you got the set of rooms that made a god item right and it broke the rules like being able to teleport on other classes like what the hell bar bearing is teleporting across the screen.
We really wanted to embrace that in a way that extended builds and didn't necessarily enforce you must play with this item. And we're really excited to share what that's sort of manifested right.
Yeah, and you all have a lot of builds that you started with from the base game and we want to add on to those.
So, what are rune words? They're a way for you to make your own spells. So there are two types of rooms. There's runes of ritual and they specify actions from the player that they have to trigger.
So you can see the example here of the yule room, which is a legendary quality room ritual. You have to cast a skill which has a cooldown. So you know frost over something like that.
Then you have runes of invocation and these grant powerful effects as a result of satisfying those runes of ritual. So the example here the gar room gives you two and a half percent critical strike chance for five seconds and you can stack up to 10 times to 25% and you can mix and match these.
There'll be a lot of different runes of ritual and runes of invocation and you can put them together as you see fit.
So when you combine a rune of ritual and rune of invocation, you pair them together, you put them in an item with two sockets, boom, you form a rune word.
And as you can tell, there's going to be rarity. We're going to have magic, rare and legendary and the higher rarity runes will have more potent conditions or effects.
So one of the important elements of this is called offering, which is the rune resource system. So your runes of ritual will generate offering and they're meant to feed into their linked runes of invocation so that they can consume that offering.
And the sort of more demanding rituals that we would ask of you as a player, gain you more offering. At the same time, the more powerful invocations that you would try to get require more offering. And so there's sort of a sort of like shared economy there.
So if you can look at these runes on the right, you get 50 offering for casting a skill with the cooldown and this rune only requires 25 offering for it to trigger.
That's where overflow comes in. Overflow is when an invocation receives an offering in excess of what's needed to trigger it. But put more simply, we want you to have a mix and match system, but we want the pieces to be not super hard that they can't fit together easily when they have some rough edges.
So many invocations can get different bonus effects when overflowed. Some of them might get increased radius to the effect. Some of them might get increased duration, but it'll always be proportional to the overflow amount.
So as an example here, the gar root only requires 25 offering and it's getting double that, which is 50 from the old rune. So every time you cast a skill with a cooldown, you'll get two stacks of 2.5% critical strike chance or 5% crit strike.
And so that's kind of how you get to play with the system and you get to optimize it in different ways.
And it creates a lot of flexibility, right, even like if you do a really demanding ritual trigger, for example, on a really low offering rune of invocation, it's almost a way to start scaling that rune of invocation in a completely different way beyond just triggering the rune.
Exactly. Yeah, let's us as developers be more flexible in creating wide ranges of effects, you know, sort of small ones, big ones, and also the same for the rituals. And you get to kind of decide which ones you think fit your bill. There are cool.
And we do our best to make sure that you can almost cook up anything.
So if you rules, ruins can be socketed to items with two sockets.
We've added a new another item to get two sockets for vessel of hatred. So you'll have your helm, your two hander, your gloves, and sorry, your helm, two hander, pants and chest.
They can only be paired with a rune of the opposite type. So you have to pair a rune of ritual with a rune of invocation.
You can have a maximum of two rune words equipped. You can't equip the same rune twice. And they're available for users who own vessel of hatred.
They stack in your inventory in the new socketable inventory tab, which will also have your gents.
And ruins are tradable between other players who own vessel of hatred.
And they unlock with a quest in the campaign, both ruins dropping from as loot, but also ruin craft thing, which we'll get into later.
And they drop at a higher rate in the under city, which is a specific place you can farm them.
So now let's get into some clips here. We get to actually see it in action.
So this is the barbarian. And the rune of ritual they have is travel five meters, very simple.
And they're going to join that to the earthquake, which is a legendary aspect that you've already seen before, which requires a hundred offering.
So you see we'll put them together in this item.
And then all they have to do is just run around.
Boom, earthquake dropping and saying what the paragon legendary glyph we just talked about.
Yeah, the earthquake train is leaving the station.
What I love about this is it doesn't it doesn't just count your normal walking, right?
If you're leaping, if you're charging, that's all counting towards like the distance that you're moving, right?
Oh, whoa. And you can see it here in like the world with for instance, like it's obviously spawning earthquakes.
Is that a druid petrified ultimate? This is supposed to be the wrong clip.
All right, sorry guys, you know, we're doing it live. Let's just move on to the next one.
Okay, so we have a necromancer here with the root of ritual cast a non channel core skill getting 25 each.
And then this is a classic from D2 gain plus three to all skills.
So you'll get to see this necker has got five five skill ranks for leap and sever.
They're going to go out and catch more socketable hard liquid for us. Pretty good.
So a little pew pew is doing your basic core skill usage, filling up the offering needed.
Yeah, I really like the little tracking buff that that fills up as you as you're going to.
So you don't need to really micromanage this. You can just add a glance. See that. Hey, I just filled it up.
And now I get plus three ranks of sever.
Yep. And I hear a plus three. There you go.
What was that?
So yeah, this this neck rose just cooking and.
Oh, what is this another another broken clipped and we just cast teleport. What what?
Okay, I think you're all part of neck rose.
What are you cooking over there, Jeevan?
Yeah, I'll stop making jokes mostly.
Yeah, so what we really wanted to lean into with D2 room words among other things was the ability to cast other classes skills and use their power and harness it into your build.
So with room words, you're going to get to do that.
Each class is going to share two skills and one legendary aspect like the earthquake one that you saw.
And some of them are even going to get get to cast improved versions.
So for instance, you know, instead of the standard decrepify from the necker mentor, you get to cast hard decrepify, which is the upgraded version.
And that's kind of we did that for a lot of reasons.
You know, we wanted to make some of them feel a little better and a little more powerful and a lot of it is about balance.
But one important thing that I always want to highlight here is that you always cast the best version of the skill.
If you have upgrades as the sort of home owner of the class, right?
So what that means is let's say you're a spirit born and you equip the cry room, which is the vortex spell.
If you have points into the upgrade, then you'll cast the upgraded vortex when the room goes off.
So I don't think there'll be any class envy, you know, like everyone will get the best version of their own skills.
And then they'll get to use other classes skills.
And we're really excited to see how people can construct new builds and new archetypes and what they can do with using the power of the classes.
And that says enhanced war cry. So that means neckros can become berserk, right?
That indeed does mean that.
And I mean, enhanced war cries of winter, I got to say, that one's real strong. We've already seen people just chopping up the pit with that one.
Absolutely. Really looking forward to what kind of interesting new combinations and builds you can come up with by by dipping into other class skills in unique ways.
It really just like multiplies the possibilities of what you can do with any given class.
Yeah, exactly. And not only do we want you to augment your builds with other classes skills, but you know, runes will scale with gear.
So when you get more interesting runes of rituals, you'll find ways to optimize them as well and get more output.
So we really feel like people will have a lot of theory crafting that they can build off of the room or system.
And I'm very excited to see how you break the game.
But that's what she do. She's doing PTR for me. Just break the game. See every build you can find that.
I totally destroy everything.
So now we have the crafting element.
So using three of the same room, you can use them to roll a new room.
You go to the jeweler. It might not be the jeweler, but we'll see.
And you will combine three of the same exact room and you'll get a new room out that is guaranteed to be different than the room you put in.
And there's a chance to uproll it to the next highest rarity.
So if you put three magic runes in, there's a chance that it'll be a rare room, same with same with rare.
There's a chance that it'll be a legendary room.
And then on top of that, we'll have the ability to craft mythic uniques.
So you can use runes. Each mythic unique can be crafted with a specific set of runes.
You'll need a legendary rare and magic runes of a certain quantity.
And one, resplendent support.
And this is in addition to the existing mythic unique crafting flow.
So, um, yeah.
I was just going to say this really hardens back to the sort of crafting that was so core in D2.
And with the runes of being able to match three and get the next upgrade.
But in a way, that's a little bit more flexible and gives you more progression out of it.
And this is all tradable, right?
So that match three, those crafting mythic uniques.
What do you think that's going to do with trading?
Yeah, I mean, I think it's going to really build a sort of player community around how to acquire the runes you need.
Whether it's because you want to combine, you know, you have two and you want to find that third one to combine for a new one.
Or you're hunting for a specific mythic unique.
I think we're going to have a lot of player interaction.
Well, someone's going to win the capitalism game there. So we'll see how that goes.
I really like how the rune crafting system makes it so you're kind of always progressing.
Right? If you're getting room drops, then you're getting materials that you know can use to progress towards higher rarity runes.
And potentially towards these mythic unique items.
Unlike, you know, some of the other loot drops, you know, if you don't find a good piece of gear, it just ends up being salvage.
Here with runes, you're kind of constantly getting some of that progression, even if it's not always the perfect room right now.
Yeah, I think that's something that we did talk to a lot of sort of D2 diehards when we built rune words.
And one of the things that most of them tend to mention consistently was like every rune drop is progress, right?
So we're moving up that ladder. And so we wanted to make sure that even if you didn't get the exact thing you wanted, it still meant something to you one way or another.
Well, I know we have we've talked a lot about a lot of stuff today. We had a progression, itemization, we talked about quality of life, we talked about class changes.
And of course, the newest thing, which is rune words, which will be in vessel of hatred. But the one thing we did want to quickly talk about was PTR.
PTR is coming up. And we want to give a little bit or at least some specifics on what that PTR test is going to be.
And also hear from the team on exactly like what they're looking for from you guys out there that are playing like for feedback as you guys play through the systems.
And so the thing that we've actually talked about today is going to be present in this PTR. So all the class balance changes, the progression changes, rune words will also be part of the PTR.
So we actually do want players jumping in and checking it out. So let's jump right into some of the PTR items.
So one knows PTR from even the last PTR that we have will carry over content from your main accounts. So if you've already done all your renown clear your fog of war, your alter will status will carry over onto your PTR account.
We did do a character copy as well. It was a while back though. So there, there, you may find that it might be a little dated from like the character copy that you have on live, but that will exist for players to actually use.
One thing I will note is that we are planning on having two different testing phases for PTR specifically.
The first testing phase will actually begin next Wednesday and will run through Friday about midday where we're going to actually give players the opportunity of kind of just starting characters from fresh because we really need people to try out the new progression systems that Colin and Aslan were talking about specifically in the beginning of the stream.
So Wednesday through midday Friday, we really need players to jump in, check that out, give us feedback specifically regarding anything tied to the new progression systems around midday on Friday though, we will be turning on the rest of the PTR, which will include things like rune words and all the other features that we were kind of talking about are well, all the other features will be part of it, but rune words and things like that will be turning in on Friday.
One thing that we've heard from feedback from players specifically, especially as we have addressed this in the past, is that there is going to be a boost vendor available for this PTR.
So in Kyiv, the shot players will be able to go and visit this specific vendor. This is the best video that I was talking about because it's small and it's dancing and looks absolutely amazing.
This vendor will be available and you'll be able to interact with it and this vendor will actually then be able to provide you a ton of enhancements to your character, which we do have a list of here.
So you will be able to boost your character up to level 50, level 60, of course, which is the new level cap after vessel of hatred and actionships.
We will end up clearing out your whole map, your waypoints, fog of war. We will do your class mechanics stuff and have that already unlocked.
All torment tiers will be unlocked, your postions will be upgraded completely. And then I know based off of feedback that we got from like the last PTR was, hey, it'd be great if we could generate like legendary items.
If we can get all the unique items, all the runes that are well, that's new now, but all the runes and everything like that, including master working materials, that will actually be available.
In this vendor, so this is a way for players to be more efficient, well, testing and being able to give us more feedback, especially around and game related items.
So we really need players to jump in for PTR. One last caveat I do want to mention is, infernal hordes will not be available in this specific PTR.
We are still doing some work on that right now before we actually get it ready, but all the other features within the game will be available.
Infernal hordes, as I mentioned, will be, it's a permanent feature, so it's coming back to the game no matter what.
And then separately, I do want to remind everyone that PTR right now is still just PC battle net only.
This does give us the flexibility being able to upload change things on the fly, like things like turning turning room words on on Friday, for instances, gives us, we have the flexibility being able to do that on on our own platform.
So it's just easier for us to be able to have that additional work from our side to be able to make things like that happen when we can do testing specifically from that end.
But Colin, Aslan, I'd be really curious to hear like what you guys are looking for specifically in this PTR from feedback from players that they can focus in on and provide feedback on as they go into the test.
Yeah, so I think we really want to see people focusing on the new journey.
So starting from level one and feeling out what difficulty tier is right for you.
And if that feels like it's the difficulty tier that you would expect to be on based on how powerful you've managed to make your character and how many of the progression systems you've engaged with, like, if you engage with tempering and you go all out and you, you know, like, you're like, I'm going to make my character a blaster, even though they're only level 30.
How far can you go with that and are you going as far as you expected you would be able to go?
Yeah, those are great points. It really is about, you know, are we hitting that expectation that we've sort of created, right?
Which is we really loved how the mind cage was functioning. We loved how tormented bosses felt in terms of having hard mode versions of things.
Are these difficulty tier sort of meeting those expectations of all the things that we have had in the previous game now mapped to a more streamlined system that should be much, much easier to navigate?
Awesome. And I know on the class side, like Charles, would you kind of looking for what's the team looking for in that front?
Yeah, I think we're really looking at the new skills and the new key passives for each class and how they're usable at all points in your character journey, right?
They should feel good to press when you just first learn these new skills, but they should also feel really good when you're in the late game and you're trying to, you know, make a build all around them, right?
Around your stoneburst, like, does it feel like that has enough support and that you can, you know, make a stoneburst build or dense of knives and, or all the other different skills, like, do they fit in?
What's their appropriate power level and real, really want to make sure that the new skills and the new key passives enabled new ways of playing our classes and that they feel satisfying to build that way.
Awesome. And, Jeevan, I know you mentioned to everyone, break the game with RuneWord. So, is there any, maybe any more extra items you're looking for in terms of feedback?
Yeah, I mean, it's definitely mostly about that. I want to see what people come up with. I want to see, you know, what you can cook in terms of build, you can do something fun or cool or unexpected.
And also, you know, I'm highly interested in this sort of balance feedback. I think we'll get it from all of you, but we've had a lot of people on the teamwork very hard on conceptualizing and making sure this stuff is right on the edge of broken without actually being broken.
And you'll get to prove me, brawl, if that isn't the case.
Awesome. Well, I know we do want to jump into a little bit of Q&A before we kind of wrap up. I know we've been here for a little while, so we'll try to grab some questions specifically from Twitch chat.
I know the probably the most popular question right now from the community is about Armory, and I do want to start off with that specifically.
And I do also want to just confirm that we are working on an Armory. It is it that the team is cooking on it right now. We just don't have it ready immediately.
But soon as we have an update, we will be providing that to the community. There is work for an Armory happening. We're not purposely ignoring it. I promise you, and it is in the work specifically from that. And so I know we have questions from Twitch chat. So this is where I actually like butcher everyone's name. So in standard fashion, I will continue to do that.
It's just a little different now because I actually like have a screen in front of me, which is actually really really beneficial.
But I guess we'll start off with a question regarding the different difficulty tiers. So this from double DHZ, which is since we now have eight difficulties, does this mean with power increase in later seasons, more difficulties will be added.
Are we planning on adding like 20 difficulties like in Diablo 3, like what's the plans around that?
Yeah, we want to be really measured in terms of when we add difficulty tiers. I think it sets us up for adding them when we feel like it's an appropriate time.
We don't want to get to a spot where we have 20 different difficulties here. We want to have just enough granularity to support the amount of power that we're adding.
And what we don't want to do is sort of say, okay, we're going to add things like rune words or add things like seasonal powers and then nerf all of you by making the monsters 100% tankier to compensate for the power.
We'd actually rather create a system that when you get that new power, we're going to add another band of difficulty to get even more efficiency out of that power.
So that's been the sort of guiding light is we don't want to continue to sort of nerf players into a spot where they can sort of use all this new power to push.
A great example of that is previously in seasons we would actually increase monster health to compensate for some of the seasonal powers.
Now if you get seasonal powers, if you're blasting penitent and leveling to 60 faster, good for you.
Like that's something that we think is actually really important to the system.
Awesome. I know next question that we have this is a question I've seen a decent amount. This is from explosive cat. Hopefully your cat is not exploiting.
What's the purpose of nightmare dungeons now that lists have moved out of pit?
Yeah, so nightmare dungeons are going to be where you receive your master working materials.
And because nightmare dungeons are going to be following the difficulty tier system now, you're going to be able to go into higher torment tiers or rather higher difficulty tier nightmare dungeons and get more master materials out of that.
So just like all other kinds of content in the game now, being able to go into a higher difficulty of that activity is going to ultimately be better for you.
The grind sort of putting a grind currency actually fits much better in a nightmare dungeon compared to the pit because it means that every sort of elite you kill, every chest you open or every corner you go into and you find an elite pack.
Those are going to be master working materials as opposed to today where it's like well, the instant I make a turn that is not in the direction of finishing this dungeon has been a waste of my time because I want that cliff that can play completely changes when everything in the dungeon is dropping master working materials.
And we think that feels so much better for that type of content conversely, you know, with the pit, you know, again, we're going to reward you for pushing difficulty and we do want to sort of get there quickly and get that reward and get out.
So we think that'll feel a lot better.
Yeah, so just just for people because I think when they made me heard like well, now it's just moved to nightmare dungeons and it's just at the end.
It's actually part of the whole nightmare dungeon. It's not just the end goal getting to the end and getting you know master working materials there just want to clarify for a chat because I know it really.
There's a good amount of the end when you fill the boss right of course the boss has to have good shit, but like what's really going to feel great is like when you run into a massive elite pack like you just randomly run into, you know, we've responds maybe too many.
Those are all going to represent you know little backs of master working materials, which is going to be huge.
Awesome. This question is from Rxc 105 our ruins reusable.
Yeah, so I just want to say chat I've been reading I've been reading Twitch chat and what you said has struck a chord.
Anyway, yes, they will be.
Can't take you anywhere.
You could unsocket ruins and you can move them into different items. Yes, absolutely.
I saw a few related questions to that. They don't get to exist in the same item as gems. You do have to pick between gems and ruins on the individual item.
Awesome. I know there was a question related to another well at least I don't know I don't know Charles.
You want to answer this or if you have additional details. There's a lot of questions related to one of the mythic unique.
It's a additive damage to demons and angels specifically.
I don't know if you like talk about I will confirm that is the wording on the effect plus damage to angels and demons.
There you go guys. We'll just leave it at that.
No further comment on that additional question that we have related to a paragon is why capped the amount of boards and instead of just capping maybe the amount of glyphs we can use.
This is from hot.
That's a really good point. Something that I think we can take back and really think about we had discussed and we felt like the cleanest solution from the flow perspective was that we wanted to just make it really compact and make those choices about which glyphs and which legendary nodes and eventually what rare and magic nodes matter to you.
That's really good feedback and something we can continue to monitor as we go into PTR and as people get their hands on it.
Again, it's really about making those boards more punchy and the connections between those boards is something that you navigate during your journey.
But the sort of end point is about making those really chunky choices on what glyphs you want and what legendary nodes you want.
And we think that ultimately, especially now that paragon is run wide and all your allts, I think we touched on that earlier, all your allts get to benefit from this.
It's really going to streamline that process of getting your points locked in quickly on those alt characters and get them into the end game really quickly.
So that's a really good point of feedback.
I have a question from WTF, Akalakal, whatever, and I say this is bad.
Yeah, you get the point. Well, everyone need to be in Kyovashod to change difficulty like it is currently.
That's a good question. We've added actually. Yeah, so you could imagine how obnoxious it would be to do the pit and care car and then have to go to Kyovashod to then unlock the new torrent.
Here that you just got so we actually added difficulty tier selectors in carigar as well as Kyovashod in addition to Kyovashod.
And then we also have one in Corrast and there's also another one I think near the dark citadel entrance.
We've added them in a few locations across the game just make a little bit of a better experience.
A question from a few people there's like Corrinter, there's another question from nine tons of pain.
Our list kind of shared between all characters in the realm or do they have to be leveled up separately?
So those are still leveled up separately, but the something like going forward we definitely want to emphasis on like making alt more seamless to play into and we definitely.
There's some underlying feedback there which is wouldn't it be great if the Paragon lists for account wide and it's like yeah that's something we can take back to the team and philosophically.
You know we really want to start moving towards a direction where making alt is really easy to get into and and feel powerful.
So that's something we can definitely take note of.
And also highlight that right the because the Paragon points are shared account wide or realm wide as it were.
If you make a new character you're going to get a ton of Paragon points right away which increases your power level which may be means you think on a higher pit tier and then you get the catch up mechanic on level enough those clips so it is a little bit easier for you're also level up those clips as well even if it's not 100% shared.
Yeah that's very true you can level up you can level them up really fast in the pit if you're pushing deep.
There is a question regarding eternal realm characters like and what happens to them when 2.0 kind of launches what's the like do I'm assuming because they already have like 925 gear if they're at max level they'll be brought down to that to that new eye level that we have mentioned is there like any specific changes or anything or is it kind of laid out exactly kind of how we presented.
Oh I can answer this yeah yeah so we are doing some adjustments to for those eternal players who really like to play the game on one character we wanted to make sure that there is new loot to chase we also just needed to make sure that with the new character level adjustments you know we sort of had to adjust the eye power of items now that the fact that the max character level is 60.
In addition to our goals of really sort of creating more grounded numbers it does mean level 50 is getting an eye power adjustment as well as the affixes are being adjusted.
But we are going to max roll every single affix that we adjusted power wise so for example if you get a fight we're going to take those items and adjust them.
We aren't going to re-roll those affix bands like if you had perfect affixes we're just going to essentially max roll all of them within that band so there's no feels bad about you know I had this perfect item and you ruined it by re-rolling it.
But the sort of main takeaway there is we wanted to make sure in patch 2.0 that there was new loot to chase you know we wanted to make sure that the new unique how to place to sing and that that's all sort of in service to that for that type of eternal player who really likes that sort of long form progression.
Awesome question from ice panther room words are they applicable to all items and weapons or they restrict to specific types of equipment.
Additionally can gems be inserted into equipment with rooms.
Yeah on there they can be inserted into all types of equipment so they're not restricted from being in unique as long as you know you have two sockets for that unique and the to restate the slots that are available with the same type of equipment.
That are available with two sockets used it on base game it's three it's a chess pants and two hander we're also adding a second socket to home so you have four slots.
And you cannot mix ruins with gems in any item and you wouldn't want to you basically be losing the benefit of them.
I know we have some questions related to like some co up bugs I will say that I've gone on I know like forums and red and addressed at least address them that we are working on them I can tell you the team is most definitely working on them right now excuse me as I call.
Still getting over my my sickness i'm and then I know this is actually pretty I'm gonna ask this is a funny question it either runs for G and then bun.
I mean my narcissism certainly would have let me do that but I think I think we can't we can't we can't do that sort of stuff unfortunately I would love to but I will say there are you know the the ruins have these sort of phrases that they unlock when you actually compose the spells and we have some I think fun references and easter eggs to you know the great the oblong games of the past and so hopefully that'll kind of make you smile and see.
Awesome and then ruins are they stackable.
Yeah they are stackable and we we have added a new tab for them as well we have a socketable tab so the room all your rooms and gems will go there.
So there we go you know pretty pretty good for your inventory yeah that it that would have been really messing with inventory of friends do not stack and now that the up.
Yeah and now the other on top which is really really good so cool I know we are going we are very over on time so I do want to I do want to make sure that we let everyone go here so that they can eat because we've now gone well past lunch over here in California.
So just a reminder for everyone that a PTR is actually can be starting next Wednesday we will have patch notes and the blog up immediately after the stream specifically here so you guys can.
Check it out check out the patch notes it's 17,000 words a lot of words so I apologize I will say that for other locales it might be until like early next week before those patch notes will be available.
It just takes a while for us to localize and some of those and it kind of came in a little hot so we do plan on actually having that available in all languages just for now they will be English only and immediately after this specific stream again PTR starts next Wednesday we'll have two different phases Wednesday through Friday will be that first initial phase where we players jumping in checking out the progression changes and testing all that out and then starting on Friday for the the rest of the week specifically.
We'll end up having the boost vendor available where players can actually jump in and you know test out everything that they need to regarding room words and all other things that are tied to end game.
I do want to give a huge thanks to everyone on this panel here Colin, Aislin Charles, Jiven, thank you so much for going through a ton of information.
I do want to also call out the rest of the Diablo team because they have been doing a ton of work towards vessel of hatred and of course patch 2.0 and season 6.
One thing we will say is that you guys actually haven't heard about season 6 yet we still have information to tell you about season 6 will be sharing that more here in the coming weeks as we head towards launch.
So there is still a seasonal theme and mechanic with season 6 that will be sharing here soon so thank you guys everyone and thank you Diablo for tuning in check out Diablo4.com immediately after the stream and we'll see you guys in sanctuary thanks again.
Thanks everyone.
Oh we're ending with this best I love it.
We can't forget the most important member of the team.
You