Thank you.
normal animations.
I was like, yes, that's it.
That's what hatred should feel like.
When you first find the Priestess of Hatred, it's going to look like a lifeless human corpse.
And you're like, this doesn't look like a boss fight.
I'm in a boss arena.
What's going on?
But as you approach, you see that the body gets pulled into a giant pool of hatred.
And then out of that pool of hatred comes this giant mass of tentacles.
And that is the boss.
So after animation, it gets to come to me.
And I get to do all of the really cool visual effects at the end.
Show what those tentacles are doing when they impact the ground.
When they slap something.
When they hit the player.
It really brings the entire thing together.
The vomit attack is really gross because there's like this part of the torso of the humanoid
that has been kind of hollowed out and now has teeth.
The tentacles come out from the mass and they grab the humanoid and kind of pull the body
back so that the slit in the belly opens up and all of the hatred just pours out a straight
beam.
It's pretty gross.
The hollows are just such a unique family.
From the moment they spawn in on your screen, you can tell that they are different.
They have just such unique behaviors and animations.
We were able to execute on a vision that's really just so different than what we typically do.
The whole process made me feel very proud of our whole team.
Everyone just got it.
They understood what the monster was.
They got the vision.
And it just worked.
The eye on the screen has many functions.
It keeps me in the right frame of mind.
What we are doing is dark.
It should be horrifying.
I should feel the fear while I'm doing it.
It's a reminder of that.
The eye also serves as a warning.
Get moving.
Don't dwell too long and wander around.
Get this thing moving.
Get the work done.
I'm just shuffling papers trying to grab something really quickly.
Welcome to another Diablo 4 campfire chat.
My name is Adam Fletcher.
Of course, I'm joined by two familiar faces on our campfire chats.
We have Mr. Adam Jackson and Mr. Colin Feiner.
Hello everyone.
It's been a little while since we've seen everyone.
We obviously have lots of it has changed since our last stream.
We ended up launching Vessel of Hatred which is really awesome to see.
Tons of players online checking out all the new features within Diablo 4 and of course
the Spiritborn as well.
We've been hearing a lot about the Spiritborn.
It seems a little obvious.
Awesome.
Yeah.
It's too weak.
That's what we've heard.
That's apparently what we most definitely heard.
But no, it is a little strong and we've heard that from a lot of people.
We'll be talking about that a little bit today.
But first, before we do jump in, I do want to talk about some plans, upcoming plans that
we have for streams.
Obviously we're doing this stream right now for the mid-season update.
The mid-season update is actually currently scheduled to release next week.
We won't have patch notes immediately after this stream.
As you know, we're doing this stream on a Tuesday which is a little bit of a different
day for us.
We typically end up doing these streams later in the week when we do release those patch
notes.
But you will have patch notes later this week.
We just need to get them through localization, make sure everyone sees them and we get all
the final changes in them before we actually do release them.
But you will have the final patch notes for mid-season update later this week.
And then again, mid-season update next week.
We will be back next week for another stream.
Yeah.
So back-to-back weeks for streams.
Lots of streams coming up.
So this one is going to be a pretty quick one to go over mid-season update.
And then next week we're actually going to talk about the Season 7 PTR.
We are going to be talking about all the changes that are coming with patch 2.1.
That stream is also going to be a little earlier than when PTR is planning on actually starting.
That's only because for those here in the US that are aware of it, the Thanksgiving holiday is coming up towards the end of November.
And we won't have people in the office.
So we want to make sure that we can do the stream a little early and talk to everyone about the patch 2.1 PTR before the end of the month.
So PTR itself is planning on starting after the holidays or after that Thanksgiving holiday in the US.
And then for the notes regarding PTR, we'll have that before the holidays.
So everyone can get to, at least in the US, they can eat turkey, read patch notes.
And then elsewhere, they can just read patch notes.
And so we have a lot of stuff coming up and a lot to talk about.
But before we do get towards some of the other items, I know, Colin, you want to talk a little bit about where we're at with D4 at the moment?
Yeah, absolutely. So I'll try and keep it short and sweet.
For the midseason, we actually think, I just wanted to talk a little bit about how we think about the game currently.
You know, we've changed a lot over the past year. We've changed itemization. We've changed all of the progression.
And generally, I think, you know, we've seen a ton of positive feedback around a lot of the progression changes made in X1, which is fantastic.
We're really excited to make a lot of these changes.
I think it's hit a lot of the goals in terms of opening up what builds you can actually play and experience a lot of the endgame, which is great.
Of course, there's, you know, Spiritborn, Kicking Ass, and Pit Tier 150.
But, like, otherwise, there's a lot of builds that sort of can cut it in the endgame, starting in Torment 1.
And I think that's been super, like, sort of successful for us.
And I also think, like, a lot of the sort of itemization changes we've made in terms of ancestral items, we think that, like, they're a little bit on the low side.
We'll talk a little bit more next week in the PTR in terms of buffing those.
But we think, like, it's actually pretty cool that there's those chase items that people are looking for.
And I think just generally we're pretty happy with how a lot of things landed.
And right now we're sort of taking a step back and seeing, okay, now that we've made a lot of these changes, what are the more iterative steps we're going to take in the next year in terms of, like, tightening up a lot of things?
You know, full disclosure, I think we missed the mark a little bit on material tuning and things like that.
So we're not looking at...
Had to do a couple updates on material tuning.
Just a couple.
Yeah, just a couple.
So we're really looking at tightening up a lot of those things and sort of making more iterative changes to the overall progression of the game.
And we hope that that creates more stability and that sort of lets us, you know, sort of put more time and focus on, like, balance and adding more things and sort of leveling up the game in that sort of way.
Yeah, just thinking back a year ago, like, so much has changed in our systems, right?
Like, we did all of our combat math over again.
We changed resistances.
We changed how loot drops and, you know, the whole upgrade system there in Season 4.
Unique's got a big overhaul.
Like, there's been so much change in things.
I'm looking forward to having a chance for things to kind of settle down and we can fine-tune and refine the existing systems that we have now that we have so many ways of progressing your character, making yourself stronger.
And I think there's a lot of room for improvement inside of these systems to make them kind of better, which I know people have been requesting a lot.
So we're looking forward to that.
Yeah, yeah.
It's really about refining what we currently have.
We feel like the structure is really strong right now.
Yeah, most definitely.
And I know with this mid-season update, we, of course, the biggest topic that we've been hearing a lot is around class balance, specifically around, like, Spirit Born right now and how it is performing very well compared to some of the other classes.
And so, Mr. Adam Jackson, I know you wanted to talk a little bit about some of the class balance.
Yeah, let's talk about classes.
We've got a lot to go over today.
So first, just to give an overview of kind of what I'm going to talk about.
First, we're going to talk a little bit about kind of the state of Season 6 and kind of how we see things and how things are going.
And then we're going to give you a preview of some of the changes that we're going to be doing for all the classes.
Normal disclaimer here, you know, we're not going to be covering everything that we're going to do here in the past.
There could be a lot more notes than what I'm showing today, but just to kind of give you an idea of what's coming for each class and kind of what you can look forward to.
So, yeah, the current state of Season 6.
So, you know, a whole lot of people are enjoying the Spirit Born.
I think this class has been really successful.
You know, we've been hearing that it's a lot of fun.
People are really liking kind of the way that you build, the way that you play, and just the class in general, which is really gratifying for the team.
Just for some stats here, 62% of all players have played the Spirit Born.
So, you know, when you think there's six classes in the game now and 62% of people are playing it, you know, that's kind of a lot of love for the class, which is pretty exciting to see.
And to give you a basis of comparison here, the Sorceress in Season 5 was the most played class, and she was at 32%.
So, you know, I'll give you an idea, and that was, you know, Lightning Spear meta, and, you know, this class was really, really good.
A lot of people had fun.
And so you can kind of compare there of just how many people kind of logged into the expansion and enjoyed that.
So, that's pretty exciting.
Yeah, just a few, right?
Yeah, so kind of the state of the game.
You know, the Spirit Born is performing quite a bit better than other classes, which we want to dig deep, you know, do a little bit of a deep dive into how and why and how we think about it.
Largely, a big culprit of this is actually due to unintended interactions that the class has with how some things scale and other issues.
But then there's also another component that there are some balance issues with the class itself.
And so it's pretty easy to conflate these two and be like, well, how much of the power is due to, like, you know, bugs or unintended interactions,
and how much of it is just some things have high numbers?
We do think it's a bit of both, but the unintended interactions, I think, are the lion's share of what's going on here.
But on the bright side, the other classes are actually performing fairly well when compared to one another.
So, if you look at, you know, Barbarian compared to Necromancer or Druid compared to Sorceress,
they're actually pretty close and competitive when we see, like, pit tier clears and other content how they're doing,
which is a really good sign for us.
So, when we're thinking of kind of what we're going to do going forward and how we balance the game,
there's kind of two really statements that we need to think about when it comes to balance.
The first one that's really important is we want players to feel strong and powerful
and to kind of feel like they can break the game and find these crazy builds and do awesome things with.
And then on the other side of the coin, we also want kind of, you know, class balance and parity
when it comes to a power level with one another, right?
You know, we don't want a situation that exists for a really long time where, you know,
the only answer is to play Barbarian, for example, compared to everything else,
and that's all that you kind of be pushed into playing.
So, these two things are kind of at odds with one another,
and we've kind of gone back and forth on our strategies here.
If you remember back when we launched Diablo 4,
we really actually prioritized class parity and harmony over, you know, everything else,
over the power fantasy of the game.
And what this resulted in was every time that someone found a build that was really strong and crazy,
we just kind of would fix the bugs or nerf the build,
and we ended up kind of playing whack-a-mole every time that players found something cool.
And it ended up being that Blizzard kind of turned into the fun police,
which players really didn't like.
We got a pretty big reaction at the end of the launch period and into season one
when we tried to only think about class parity over kind of the power fantasy of Diablo.
And in season two, we kind of really turned things around in the way that we thought about the game,
and we really prioritized, you know, power fantasy
and this idea that our players kind of want to break the game and be crazy.
The big shining example there was Ball Lightning for you Sorcerous Mains,
where that skill, you know, had an unintended interaction.
It was really, really good, but players really liked it and had a lot of fun.
And so if you remember a long time ago, we came on livestream and we talked about this,
and we kind of said that we were going to allow players to kind of break the game in this way
until the next season, right?
There are some exceptions that we'll make where we'll fix things in the midseason
if it's impacting, like, the performance of the game or the experience of other players,
like if your build is causing a bunch of lag or something, then we'll fix it right away.
I think in season six, we had this example with the Evade build with Spiritborn.
But overall, players really liked this strategy a whole lot more, right?
They got to enjoy this kind of, the point of playing ARPGs and Diablo in particular,
of really making a powerful character and being able to smash faces with it, right?
Yeah, and the sort of philosophy here is, sort of goes even beyond classes, right?
If you remember in season one, we were just nerfing every dungeon that was to perform in,
and like any time there was content that was a little bit out of budget, we'd nerf it.
So it's really about sort of establishing a trust with you, the player, during that season
and not trying to sort of force you to exploit the fun early and often.
And it's really about sort of making sure that when you play a season,
you know that that season is going to work the same throughout the season
and we're not going to change things midway on you.
Yeah, I think another factor to think about too is that now that we've added a lot of progression
or like tempering and masterworking, that there's a lot of time investment that goes into making a build,
even if you know something that might be unintended, but it's really, really good and crazy
and you spend, you know, 40 plus, 100 hours, whatever, making it.
And if we kind of pull the rug out from under you, it's worrisome to do that to players, I think,
in the middle of a season.
It's all about respecting your time, right?
Yeah.
So in that vein, we are not planning to nerf the Spiritborn in the midseason patch,
which I think is the thing that's on everybody's mind.
Like, is Blizzard going to do it?
And we've decided that we think it's best for the game to not do it in the midseason.
So in Season 7, and we'll be talking about this a little more in the livestream next week,
we are going to be fixing all the unintended interactions that we found with Spiritborn.
We'll also be making balance adjustments to bring them in line with the other classes.
So you can expect a lot of change there.
But until then, you know, enjoy what you've got now while it's there.
I think it's worth digging into the unintended interactions part too, right?
Because it's not necessarily like you picked one legendary Paragon node
and now your build is ridiculous, right?
It's like you're sort of, you know, for lack of a better word,
abusing some of the mechanics, right?
If we know, you know, Viscous Shield is scaling off of max HP,
players have poured tons of time and effort trying to max Masterwork their max life
and getting all the perfect tempers and item affixes,
we don't want to take that away from you, right?
That's not something that we're trying to necessarily destroy
all the time commitment you put into your character by fixing these things.
So it's not as simple as just fixed unintended interaction, right?
But just reiterating, it is that those unintended interactions
are things that we will look at when we get to Season 7
and we start off with Season 7.
So obviously with mid-season update, enjoy it.
Enjoy it through Season 6, but come Season 7,
you'll see a preview of some of these changes with Season 7
in our PTR stream next week.
You'll see some of the changes that we plan on.
Yeah, there's a lot coming there, but this isn't about that.
This isn't about that today.
There's a lot coming there for everybody that'll be really exciting.
But yeah, so...
But the caveat to all of this is if something does come up
that impacts other players in regards to the game's performance
or you're causing lag for the server or whatever,
we will be fixing those types of interactions as soon as possible.
Like the evade build is our example, right?
We will fix those right away because we want to make sure
that the game is, you know, performant for everybody.
So in the mid-season, though,
we are going to be buffing all of the other classes in the mid-season patch,
but I want to caveat this a little bit with
it's not going to be to the level of Spiritborn right now
because a lot of that power is due to bugs and unintended things.
So we're really going to be buffing the classes
to have more parity and harmony with each other,
but then also to kind of where we plan to bring the Spiritborn to
after, you know, the bugs and stuff has been fixed.
So you will be seeing number buffs,
but, you know, I wouldn't expect to be at the same level
as what Spiritborn is doing right now in the mid-season,
just to be clear, because of that.
The bugs are actually a big part of the power level.
Yeah, and we don't want to create an arms race, right,
where it's like, okay, everyone gets to be pit tier 150,
then the next natural ask is like,
okay, I guess we're adding Torment 5, 6, 7, 8, right?
So we don't want to sort of get to a place
where, you know, you're cheering through 12 different Torment tiers.
So we're really being cautious about the arms race here.
We actually think the rest of the classes are in a really good spot.
Yeah, and I think you can count on that going forward, too,
not even just right now,
but this is kind of the way that we think of things in general.
It's like if all the classes are kind of in this realm
kind of close to each other,
and then one has something unintended
that brings, like, way up here,
everybody is always like,
well, let's just bring everybody else to this.
But if we do that every time,
like you start with this difference,
and then you're here, and then you do this,
and then you do this,
and you're exponentially going to increase the power level of the game
just insanely high really fast, right?
And that's not our goal, right?
So if there's something that stands out,
we'll let people do it for a while,
but then we're going to bring it back the next season.
And that's kind of the way that I think
you can mostly count on us doing balance
and how the choices that we make and why.
Definitely.
And the same goes if there's, like,
an underperforming class.
It's, like, 20 pit tiers behind everyone else, right?
We have no problems with, like,
bringing that up to where the rest of the classes are.
Correct.
Yeah, the real goal is to get everything
in a pretty good realm of having harmony with one another.
And, you know, when something's out of balance,
it's okay for a season,
but then we're going to try to bring it back, right?
That's kind of always our goal.
So, yeah, let's get into the class updates
for all the classes.
We're just going to be going through one by one
and kind of giving you a preview of what to see.
Again, this is only a preview.
There's more than what we're going to show on screen.
Yeah, way more, right?
This is just, like, a couple examples
within the stream itself.
And, again, just a reminder,
patch notes later this week,
once we get everything kind of sort of
at normal time for a stream on a Tuesday,
normally we do it on Thursday
and usually have patch notes then.
So I expect the patch notes later this week.
Yeah, let's get to it.
So starting off with Barbarian,
we got some baseline core skill buffs
for pretty much all of them, right?
You can see here, Upheaval, Hammer of the Ancients,
Double Swing, and Rend.
Basically, you know, we always hear it
that they have a little bit of trouble leveling.
Their late game is really good,
but just getting there can be a little bit painful.
So we're just going to be squeezing up
those numbers a little bit more.
So you'll have a better time leveling.
You'll also be a little bit stronger overall,
but all the builds will get a little bit better.
And then also we have some buffs
to underperforming legendaries and uniques.
Here's an example with an aspect, Battle Mad.
You can see here in the before,
kind of what's on live right now
is it's basically just a way to give you berserking,
rewarding you for weapon swapping.
And now we're adding a hefty multiplier to it.
So now this is going to be a real offensive aspect
that's going to give you, you know, a bunch of power.
You're going to get up to a 40% damage buff
when you're doing the weapon swapping mechanic.
So we're kind of finding these places
where we can input damage
or, you know, these underused legendaries or uniques,
and then adding a reason to make them more compelling.
Next we've got Druid.
So all of the Druid's key passives are getting buffed.
I've given a couple of examples here,
but I'm pretty sure all of them, the numbers went up.
So Lupine Ferocity, you've got the crit damage
going from 70 to 100% bonus,
and then the bonus damage to injured enemies
going from 140 to 200%, which is pretty meaty.
And then the one with nature passive,
that buffs your companions.
That bonus damage is going from 60 to 80%,
which is a pretty big amount.
And then also legendary unique buffs
in the same way of the Barbarian.
So here this is an offensive aspect,
even though I'd argue it's kind of more utility,
but the Storm Chasers aspect
where it makes your Tornado smart,
where they seek enemies.
We're just adding a pretty good multiplier to that.
So Tornado builds Rejoice.
You're going to get up to 50% more damage now
just from taking this aspect
that you were probably taking anyways.
So just making you happier to take the same things.
Next one, the Basilisk.
This is the Earth Druid dealing with Petrify.
So before it was that first time
that you hit an enemy, you'll Petrify them.
And then every time you Petrify them,
it deals a bunch of damage.
We're just making that a lot more usable
so that way you can feel more comfortable taking it.
So now it's going to be when you hit a healthy enemy,
you'll Petrify them.
And also this will work against bosses.
So every five seconds that you hit a boss,
you'll attempt to Petrify,
and then you'll get that bonus damage proc.
So basically this unique now will be giving you
a damage proc every five seconds against bosses,
which will be a lot better than now
where it doesn't really do much to bosses at all.
Next we've got the Necromancer.
So they're getting buffs for all their basic skills.
I'm showing Decompose here as an example.
The damage is almost being doubled.
Your essence gain per second is going up by quite a bit.
And also now it'll scale with attack speed bonuses.
So now if you build attack speed or you have it,
Decompose is going to be generating essence for you quicker,
which it didn't use to before.
They're also getting some buffs
and kind of some simple functionality changes to some passives.
So an example here with the Evulsion passive is
before you would get increased crit damage to vulnerable enemies.
And now we're just going to remove that double requirement there
of focusing on crit and vuln.
So now you'll just get more damage against vulnerable enemies.
So it's just a lot more usable.
It's now used, you know, you can use it more generally.
You don't have to worry about critting all the time to get the bonus.
So it'll just be more consistent.
And then we've got some unique buffs here.
These are just number buffs.
Some examples, we've got Mordekrux.
So their chance to spawn the Skeletal Simulacrum is going up.
And Howl from below, you're just getting, you know,
more corpse explosion damage out of it.
So just tuning up these numbers to make them competitive.
Next, we've got the Rogue.
So similar to the Barbarian,
the Rogue is also getting buffs to the core skills.
Penetrate shot damage is going up.
Flurry damage is going up as some examples.
Also, their key passives are getting a bit better too.
Victimize, the damage scaling is going up
for your vulnerable damage bonus.
And precision is going up by a pretty hefty amount
from 15% to 20% of your crit damage bonus.
So it'll just be a lot more potent.
And next, we've got the Sorceress,
kind of keeping on the theme of buffing key passives.
So this one, we're actually doing a bit of a functionality change.
So Combustion before used to be that, you know,
you get a big multiplier to your burning damage, 60%.
And then after that, we kind of wanted to reward you
for putting different burning sources on enemies.
And you would get a little bit of a bonus per source.
Now we're doing away with that second part.
So you're still getting the burning damage buff
just across the board.
But now we're actually going to tie it to itemization.
So now you'll just be getting an additional multiplier
based on your damage to burning enemies bonus.
So now you're going to be looking for that, you know,
in your gear and your paragon and other places.
So you can now just really buff up the burning damage.
And you don't have to worry about
putting a bunch of sources on enemies.
Next, a similar vein, Avalanche.
This key passive is just getting better
and is going to be tuning into a damage bonus as well.
So before it was that your frost skills have a chance,
a lucky hit chance to make your next cast
of a few different skills consume no mana and be stronger.
And when you hit vulnerable enemies,
it just made the chance better.
And now we're just buffing up the chance baseline
going from 10% to 30% to get that free cast and bonus damage.
But now the actual damage that you deal
is going to be increased by your damage
against vulnerable enemies stat.
So now we've added basically a scaling multiplier
to this key passive.
So it should be doing a lot more damage over time.
Next, we got Aspect of Piercing Cold.
This is for you Ice Shards enjoyers.
This one's getting a whole lot better.
So before it used to be that the number of pierces
was part of the random roll.
And then also the roll made it deal,
your subsequent hits deal less damage with Ice Shards.
And now we flip the script now.
And now the amount of enemies that's going to pierce
is going to be static.
So you're just getting more consistent value.
But instead of doing less damage,
you're going to deal more damage per enemy hit.
So that actual difference of going from less to more
is going to amount to a substantial increase
in the amount of damage that this legendary
is pumping out for Ice Shards.
It's a huge spread.
Last but not least, for the Sorceress,
we introduced a couple of new legendary aspects
in Vessel of Hatred.
We've got them there scaling with Charge Bolts and Incinerate.
And both of these aspects were dealing
what we call flat damage,
or it was like a certain damage amount.
And it didn't really scale up as you scaled the skill up.
And we've changed that for both of these.
So the Aspect of Charge Flash
and the Aspect of Overheating
will now both scale.
As you get more Charge Bolt or more Incinerate damage,
these ones will be dealing a lot more damage as well.
So these ones will just scale with you
and be a lot better over time as you get stronger.
And next, last but not least, we got the Spirit Borm.
So we did do some changes here.
We really mostly did small buffs to skills
that haven't really been being used or seen less success.
So we got Razor Wings here.
The damage is going up a bit.
And also Razor Wings used to have
actually a set cooldown between casts.
And now we removed that cooldown.
So now you can actually cast Razor Wings faster
as you build attack speed,
like all other skills in the game.
We also did some small buffs to Withering Fist.
The poison damage went up.
The slow went up.
And one of the upgrades will now spread to more targets
when you use it.
And then we also got some buffs to Toxic Skin,
which isn't really seen much play by players.
We basically just did some small buffs to its damage,
both baseline,
the enhancement,
and one of the upgrades,
the variants of it.
And these are mostly just
on the skills that people aren't actually using right now.
Correct.
The archivalism to make the Spirit Borm even stronger.
No, this is tuning within the builds of a buff.
We're most definitely seeing Chad
and they're like,
wait, Spirit Borm buffs?
And these are skills that really no one is using,
so we want to make sure that...
I mean, I can just buff Quill Volley.
There you go, Quill Volley.
Most definitely needs buffs, apparently.
No, but it's for things
that we just haven't seen a lot of play
within Spirit Borm players.
I know a lot of players
are looking at some of the numbers
and they're also...
These are just like baseline numbers
on some of these skills.
Obviously, there's a lot of interactions
that happen beyond that
from tempering to the gear that you have
and everything like that
that will end up obviously enhancing those even more.
So we're expecting to...
As Adam mentioned before,
we're not expecting to see
the other classes jump up
to the same power as the Spirit Borm
because the Spirit Borm, again,
is using some unintended interactions right now,
but those will be addressed in Season 7.
So with these classes specifically,
they will get some additional buffs
so that they can stay competitive amongst each other.
They're staying together as a pack
but being a little bit stronger here
with the Mid-Season.
Yeah, the idea with Mid-Season,
this is probably going to be true
with most Mid-Season updates,
is that we're trying to move everything
a little closer together
and also to set up for the next season
where there will be a lot more upheaval.
Yeah.
So we're like prepping everything
to be kind of close.
Ha, ha, ha.
Upheaval.
Oh, yeah.
I was like, ha, ha, ha.
But you know, we're getting ready
for Season 7.
Is that a hint?
Is that an Easter egg?
Cool.
Awesome.
Well, I know we have a...
Again, Adam had mentioned
that this is just a very small...
Yeah, it's a lot more than just that.
There's a lot more than just what we showed here.
That would be the shortest patch notes ever.
But we do actually have a patch notes
coming out later this week
that will have all the different class changes
and everything with the Mid-Season update.
We do have a few other things
that are actually also hitting
related to Rune Words
and a thing that a lot of people
have been talking about,
which is Shrines specifically.
Yes.
So we can Shrines.
What's wrong with Shrines?
What's wrong with the Conduit Shrine
that I don't purposely ignore?
Yeah.
You mean the real Cursed Shrine?
There you go.
All right.
Jumping into Rune Words first.
We are doing some tuning changes to Rune Words.
I will tease a little bit
that we do have some more impactful changes
coming in Season 7,
so tune in next week for them.
But in the meantime,
we did do some Rune Word buffs
to ones that aren't being used as much,
mostly by lowering offering costs.
Some examples here.
We got the Moni Rune Word.
The offering that you get
is increased from 25 to 35.
The Ahu Rune Word.
The offering is being increased a lot
from 10 to 25
when hitting injured enemies.
And then I'm just going to butcher it.
I don't know how to say it,
but the Seh Rune Word.
The Wolf Spirits are now always going to be unhindered.
So we often run into issues
where companions and things like that
have trouble getting to enemies,
but since they're spirits,
so why would other things get in the way?
So now they'll always be moving through enemies
and getting to their targets a lot quicker.
And then Shrines,
you know,
heard some feedback
that they don't really scale too well.
So the Artillery,
Blast Wave,
and Conduit Shrines
will now deal more damage
and they're going to scale with you
based on your level
and your Paragon level.
So as you level up,
as you get stronger,
the Shrines will be getting
more potent with you.
We're going to kind of test it.
You know,
let us know how it goes,
see if you actually enjoy getting them
and want to get them now.
We do see some room maybe
to do some more things
and buff them further if needed,
but we're going to be trying this
as a first step
to see how it goes.
Yeah, I know.
We've heard from a lot of people
about like,
especially as you get to later levels
and you're towards like Endgame
and Torment 4
and a Conduit Shrine appears
and it's like,
don't touch it
because maybe that will make things slower,
which it currently typically does
for a lot of players,
especially Spirit-born players.
So it's cool to see updates
to these Shrines
and again,
feedback is really important
for us to know like,
hey, did we hit the mark?
Do we need to do additional things
or do we need to tweak anything?
So let us know
after you guys get a chance
to check out
the new adjustments to the Shrine.
So that'll be really important for us.
Some other things
that are coming down the line,
we do have some
in-game specific events
and items
that we'll be hitting here
in the coming weeks?
Weeks?
It's a little bit
after mid-season update.
We do actually have another,
we're bringing back
the Red Cloak Horror,
which is part of the
Midwinter Blight event
that we had last year.
And we'll actually have
a blog that details
all the benefits
and rewards out of this.
It's like XP benefits,
of course,
that do come
with this specifically,
which is really great
to have on top of
another event that's coming,
which is Mother's Blessing.
And Mother's Blessing
will also be,
we'll have that in the blog.
That blog is going to be
hitting on Thursday,
I believe.
So keep an eye out.
For Eternal players,
we also have
a cool little thing,
kind of like a welcome back
booster type of event
for them,
or maybe it's not an event.
I don't know how to coin it,
but Colin,
what does that entail?
Yeah, so we wanted
to put together
just something
to get you back
into the action.
I know part of X1
ended up sort of marking
a bunch of items as legacy,
so we just wanted
to give everyone
a one-time booster
to come back.
We're going to level you to 50.
We'll give you a build
that we've made.
We've made three different
ones per class.
You'll be able to use it.
I'm sure everyone watching
probably doesn't care,
but we have,
you will care about this
if you haven't done this,
is we're going to unlock
all the altars
of Lilith
as part of that boost,
so if you log in
and just use it
and you haven't got
all your altars,
get your altars for free.
Just get it for free.
Easy peasy nuts.
Yeah, and if you're
a base game,
Diablo 4 owner,
you'll end up getting,
I believe,
one of those boosts,
and then if you're
a vessel of hatred,
you'll end up getting
two of those boosts
on eternal characters,
which is kind of cool.
So if you want to
jump back in
or anything,
especially after
the changes with,
there goes my earpiece.
I've been fumbling
with it all day
and now it's gone.
But I know
a lot of players,
specifically with Season 6
jumping back in,
they notice,
as you mentioned,
a lot of the gear
went to legacy gear,
so this kind of gives them
a way of being able
to kind of recover
some of that.
Yeah, refreshes it.
Exactly.
And then I believe
we also have
another free trial
coming up for any
new players
that want to check out
the Spirit Born.
The Spirit Born
will actually be part
of the free trial
and that will be
coming up here
in the coming weeks.
And so all this
will be in a blog
on Thursday,
which is really cool.
And then, of course,
as we mentioned
at the start of the show,
we have another stream
next week.
We'll actually have
a date for the stream
later this week
for players
so that you guys
can keep an eye
out for that.
But that is our
Patch 2.1 PTR stream
and that one
will be pretty beefy.
We have a lot
to talk about
regarding Patch 2.1
and, of course,
everything that's going
to be coming
with Season 7.
We are super stoked
for that.
The stream, again,
will be a little early
because of the
Thanksgiving holiday,
so a little bit earlier
than when PTR
is going to start.
We do plan on having
those notes available
for players before
the Thanksgiving holiday.
And then I would
expect that PTR
to start after
the Thanksgiving holiday
so when everyone
is back in post-holiday
and is able to monitor
and see how everything
is going with PTR
and taking the feedback.
So we'll have
a stream next week.
You'll see, of course,
some of us back
on stream next week
for that.
And I believe
we'll be joined
by Mr. Dan Tanguay again
who will be in Albany
and chiming in
on all the stuff
that's coming with
Season 7
and Patch 2.1.
So lots of big changes
coming specifically
with that.
I know we do want
to jump into
some Q&A
really quickly.
So if you guys
have any questions,
we have chat enabled
on Twitch,
so twitch.tv
slash Diablo.
If you're watching
on other channels
and stuff like that,
that's where we do
take in specific questions.
But feel free
to drop in any questions.
We'll try to get through
as many as we can here.
Again, this is just
kind of an abbreviated stream
for the mid-season update
and then we'll be back
in a week.
Next week, yeah.
I get it.
We took a little bit
of a break from streaming
so it kind of makes sense
so that we'll be back
pretty quickly.
But I know
our first question
that we have
is related to
ancestral items.
We get a lot
of questions
about ancestral items.
I've seen a lot
of questions.
Oh, this earpiece
is driving me nuts.
Question number one.
Adam, fix your earpiece.
There's a plant right here
which you guys can't see
so I'm having to read
the screen.
Any updates
to ancestral items?
Do you guys have any updates
or news to share
regarding that?
Yeah, I know
we saw a lot of confusion
in terms of maxing out
a lot of the codex of power.
In X1,
we actually added
roughly what we call
ranks, five ranks
to a lot of the legendary
aspects that were
ancestral only.
And I know that caused
a lot of confusion.
So currently how it works
is ancestral items
have a higher upper bounds
on the rank
that you can achieve
for that aspect.
And we have seen
quite a bit of people
struggling to max out
their aspects.
Generally that was
the goal
is that we do want
to grind, right?
Like we think it's good
that you can sort of
get an aspect right away
but we like that
once you have that
play style assembled
we still want things
that you need to work on.
That being said,
we think it's a little bit
too aggressive right now
so we are going to be
making some changes
which we will detail
next week
in terms of
how that actually works
but just know that
currently ancestral items
are the sort of
where you find
the max rank
of a lot of those aspects
but you can still find
them on anything else
that isn't ancestral
the lower version.
Yeah.
I know
and we'll be
talking more
about ancestral items
next week
specifically.
Yeah, the drop rates.
Yeah, a lot of stuff
regarding that.
Is there any plans
this is
I'm taking a few questions
from the forums
and of course chat
because we did post this
on the forums beforehand.
Urza from the forum
says can we get
boss materials
to stack
like runes
or maybe even higher?
Are there any plans
for something like that?
Yeah, we are
looking into it.
There's things
on our side
in terms of like
storage and duping
that we're a little bit
worried about
but we're looking at
making a change
sometime in the
longer future.
Question from
a couple people
like Archangel890
and Dragonage
says any chances
that you guys
will potentially
change like XP gain
maybe the growth
to Paragon 300.
Is there any plans
on maybe making adjustments
or tuning specifically
on that end?
Currently not
at the moment.
I think it's something
we're monitoring though
in terms of the feedback.
We do like that
you can get just about
everything within the first
200 Paragon levels
and everything from there
has a pretty steep
diminishing return
in terms of power.
So what we don't want
to say to you all
is like you need to grind
200 hours to unlock
your build and do all
the things that are
sort of play style
defining which we define
as like the sort of
glyphs and the
legendary nodes.
So we've seen actually
a lot of positive feedback
that like you can get
your build online
and that you still have
something to work towards.
The sooner we sort of
short circuit that
Paragon grind the more
we sort of get back
to that pre-expansion
one state where you
just don't get anything
from killing monsters
because you're Paragon 300
in the first two weekends.
So currently you know
we're looking at
monitoring it and we're
super open to the feedback
but so far we've seen
a good amount of
positivity around it.
I think it's kind of
in line with what you're
talking about with
the legendary powers
right now like those
last five ranks
are on Ancestral Items
only and so our idea
is like we want you
to get your build online
and play the way you want
within a pretty you know
pretty quickly or whatever
but then you have
something to work towards
like incrementally
to become stronger and
stronger and that we're
okay with taking a long
time.
Totally.
As long as it's not like
cutting you off from the
build at all.
Yeah it's about getting
you into the fun
and like making sure
that your build is
blasting but you have
things to sort of use
that build to blast for.
That makes sense.
Yeah and I think
there's like the other
thing that people are
probably forgetting about
is like we do have
these events coming up
and stuff which also
benefit XP and
everything like that
which will be a good
opportunity for players
to like be able to
you know if they
they really want
because they're
as we've seen
there are
there is a reward
for getting to
Paragon 300 and stuff
so it allows players
that opportunity
to kind of use those
events to be able to
boost that and we have
obviously Red Cloak
Horror stuff coming up
here and of course
we have Mother's
Blessing so there's
opportunities to help
with some of that XP
based off of those
events specifically.
so there is a question
regarding like materials
again you know can we
expect any additional
buffs for drop rates
on Rawhide, Iron,
Forgotten Souls
anything like that?
Yeah so actually it is
in the midseason but we
did buff Legion events
I know that was a
personal favorite of a
lot of folks for the
midseason.
For season 7 we're
taking a look at just
sort of buffing the
various sources and
also really drilling down
on like what are the
bottlenecks players are
having and iterating
towards that.
There's no major
changes coming in season
7 like we're not going
to quadruple the amount
of materials across the
game but it is
something again in the
spirit of like tightening
the things that we have
we are actively looking
at a lot of the
material inflows and
outflows and we want
to give you the tools to
sort of get the
materials that you're
looking for.
Sort of what we're
trying to do is ensure
that there are things
that you still care about
right and you still want
to grind.
It's still in that spirit
of like it's walking
that fine line of there
things to work towards
without it feeling super
tedious.
So that's what we're
trying to tighten and
work towards.
There is a question
regarding this from
Remster Ma says do you
have any plans and start
bringing in new midseason
mechanics?
I think for that more so
I would expect like
larger mechanics content
changes and stuff like
that to happen around new
seasons as opposed to a
midseason update.
I think we look at
taking midseason updates
making tweaks to you
know balance items or
anything that we're
hearing feedback from so
that we can spend most of
our you know concentration
and focus on really
putting in some of these
newer type of content
pieces around new season
specifically.
Yeah I think you think
going forward is midseason
is a time to just like
tweak and iterate and
you know use it rework
existing things but we're
really putting all of our
books on like bigger
upheavals you know larger
changes lots of new stuff
into the beginning of the
season.
So next week will be
pretty exciting.
We got a lot of new stuff
coming in but that's where
we're kind of targeting
that to make that kind of a
big moment and exciting
time to come back and
play.
There is a question from
Casual Dragon regarding
Undercity Drops and
asking is there any plans to
potentially fix those make
those better specifically
on that end.
Yeah so this sort of leads
into there are some
ancestral drop rate changes
that we want to talk about
next week but in general
what that'll mean is all
the loot across the game
will generally get better
so it is something that
we're working on.
I'm about to take this
earpiece and throw it
across the room because it
just keeps popping out and
it's driving me insane.
That's a question from
PezRadar.
The question from
Finamdar says Diablo
at Diablo any stability
fixes coming?
Been seeing a whole lot
more crashes since the
last couple patches.
I will say that we've
been monitoring.
We can actually see
whenever a player
actually crashes.
We know it.
We get logs from it on
our end.
I know that the
engineering team here
has been doing a ton of
work on working to get
the game more stable.
You've probably seen a
bunch of different
small client patches go
out.
We actually just re-enabled
like DLSS in a client
patch that went out
yesterday.
There are additional
changes and more
reviewing that's being
done from our side to
ensure that the game is
running very stable so
expect to see more of
that as we get through
this season and of
course into next season
because our goal is to
make sure baseline everyone
can jump in without any of
these types of issues and
everything.
Shout out to our
engineering team.
I know they've been
working long and hard on
figuring all this stuff
out.
They've been, that's like
their top priority right
now.
They actually behind the
scenes we even collaborate
with them a lot on doing
various things related to
game performance under the
hood like making skills
cleaner, making
interactions cleaner.
like we're constantly
doing stuff to make the
game run smoother in the
background pretty much
every patch like we're
fixing multiple things so
it's definitely something
that we're always working
on actively.
Why so blue panda bear?
Any chance on tempering
schools can be used more
than once?
Investing time to finally
get a rare drop and it
bricks kind of doesn't feel
too great.
Any thoughts on tempering
schools, how that's been
going?
Yeah, I think it's
definitely something we
hear a lot of feedback on
and it's something that,
you know, we were sort of
taking an incremental
approach, right?
Like with the expansion
one changes, we made it
so that a lot of the
recipes are three.
We also added, of course,
the scroll of tempering or
restoration in expansion
one to see how that sort
of changes things.
So we're just really taking
a measured approach.
If we see still there's a
lot of feedback that it
just still isn't hitting
that mark, we're absolutely
open to changing things
like potentially letting it
be used more than once.
And we're just sort of
monitoring at this point.
We are getting questions
about the Armory.
Stay tuned.
TM.
Soon.
We'll have information
on that.
As you guys know, that
has been in development.
It's something that we've
already confirmed about.
We'll be talking more
about it here soon.
TM.
So, keep your eyes peeled?
Is that the term?
Keep your eyes peeled?
I don't know.
There's a saying that,
you know, stay tuned.
I don't know.
Last question here that we
have before we head off is
Holes Transition says,
will Dance and Gnize get
buffs and any changes to be
more compatible with
collecting loot, like
opening doors, etc.?
You know, when you're
spinning to win with your
Gnize and stuff, is there
any way or any plans of
potentially having them
seamlessly move around
a dungeon or something
like that from that?
Nothing on my radar
right now, but that's a
good note to take.
That's a good note to take.
It's a good note to take.
Rogues want to spin to win
and never stop.
You have to do all this
setup and snapshot and
then you have to open the
door.
So, we do know it's a thing.
Yeah.
So, we'll see.
Stay tuned.
It's another thing to stay
tuned.
So, again, thanks again
everyone for jumping in,
providing questions and
everything from our end.
We will have patch notes
later this week.
So, stay tuned for that.
The blogs for Mother's
Blessing, the Red Cloak
Horror, our Eternal
Boost stuff, everything
will be out on Thursday.
So, also check out for
that blog.
Mid-season update hits
next week.
So, patch notes will be
out before the mid-season
update.
And you guys will also
hear about our stream
date next week for the
Patch 2.1 PTR.
So, we'll be talking a
whole bunch.
That will be another
beefy stream.
This one I know is a
little bit short.
There's going to be a
little bit more beefy
than this one.
But look at this.
Two streams in two
weeks.
We're about to do it.
So, we will see you
guys next week.
Again, huge thanks to
Colin, Adam, for
joining us.
Our wonderful mini
Cosroy over here.
Super awesome.
Super cute.
Love you, Aaron.
But thank you guys.
We'll see you guys next
week for our Patch 2.1
PTR stream.
And, yeah.
Check out the blogs and
patch notes later this
week.
See you guys.
cause you.
Um, no.
Cause you're not
good.
See you.
Ooh.
Thank you.